many Brands will spend mid six figures
sometimes up to close to a million
dollars on an amazing Shopify set now
this may sound crazy but do you actually
have to do the same thing and what are
your options as a brand we're going to
hit all that I'm going to show you
exactly how I'm building the site that I
just dropped for my brand with the exact
Shopify theme let's dive in first let's
take a look at a site that justifies the
cost this is Pink Friday Nails it's
Nicki Minaj's site you're leading with
great art directed fullcreen video and
then look at what we have here the
quality of the imagery the integration
of social media friendly like
photography that works for this the
ability to pick your colors and have it
change on the same page can add to a
cart like this and you see items in cart
and you're seeing big large upsell right
within there on checkout same thing on
mobile nice big interactive image
Galleries and then this one of my
favorite items where you're actually
moving in between
stories can drag and drop it and you're
basically seeing the video experience
you would see in short form like on
Instagram and you can see even at the
top of what we see here with that
timeline they're actually showing the
length of the post like a story but
instead it's a little shoppable video
where I can then go interact with an
exact thing I see in a video and go to a
product detail page it gives me
significantly more information and the
opportunity to check out they're
mimicking the experiences that we have
on social media and the content that's
integrated in social media and content
is a really big part of what sells
products now into a Shopify experience
and so looking at something like this
whether you sell nails or clothes or
whatever it is these are the kind of
experiences where you want to have an
amazing upsell experience you want to
show your products in a super particular
light you want to have the integration
of art Direction and brand that's the
experiences that justify a certain
amount of cost I've been working on
websites and e-commerce websites in
particular for man almost 15 years now I
started as a designer I was a web
designer for hire for a long long time
and now I'm actually the creative in
Residence at the firm that made that
Pink Friday site I just showed as well
as The Road Site hexclad a bunch of
others I'll pop up inside this video or
you can check out called van group in
addition I've made a significant amount
of my own projects on Shopify continue
to do that now work with major brands
that are on Shopify regularly and so I'm
just immersed in what does it take to
have a successful interesting Ecom
experience with that I've been working
on my site for the valuables brand this
is like a trial site which I'm using to
evaluate what I'm doing with customers
to test a few products make sure the
warehouse works make sure checkout works
and this is what we created here so a
couple cool little features uh little
rollovers for each products you know
just the the scrolling nature there you
can see same kind of ability it had on
the Nicki Minaj site where I can go show
like a lifestyle image on rollover see
this little archive here induction some
photography we're doing all this
ourselves to start so this is all
photography shot by myself and my my
wife who's who's pictured here um
because we're trying to do things on a
budget and as such I'll show you exactly
the toolkit we used and what we spent to
do it because none of this required any
custom code a little row of our our
logos and then some some kind of Deep
dive blogs Etc so if you want your site
to look like this like exactly like this
and you'll see see kind of what we have
on our product detail pages I don't have
any upsell or anything fancy in the cart
yet that i' add through through a Plugin
or something custom but we use the
Baseline theme for this so Baseline is a
great theme that a bunch of brands that
you probably know have used uh and so
it's here it's $350 so basically what
happens is you pay $350 and you get a
backend editor that gives you almost all
these exact things without having to
edit any custom code there are a bunch
of Cheaper themes we'll get to more
Shopify themes later but really you're
buying your way into a base level store
and BAS line has one of the best
experiences if you want like a More
Design forward less simple site which
may not be for everybody I understand
that my site was it's a little chaotic
it's a little bit more design Centric
it's not 100% focused on just converting
you and some people may want that but if
you want a more aesthetic look it's a
good one to choose so I'm going to view
the demo store here and you'll see they
have similar options in these theme
Styles you begin to see the things that
I chose this is one of the different
variants they have in this style um I
believe I don't if I chose the minimal
or which one I did of those four you can
see they have a couple versions and you
when you load it in it's going to give
you the same fonts the same items that
you're going to be able to actually work
with for your brand you can just load in
your various items all right this modern
is the one I chose you'll see I changed
some of the fonts I changed some of the
amount of things that are featured but
overall you'll see a lot of these are
the same and it's pretty much off the
shelf and so to me to be able to do this
and then come up with my own ideas ins
and inside of it and have that done that
did this in about I don't know let's say
8 10 hours that is 100% worth $350 to me
and the the only downside is that
there's a lot of other people that have
this site I actually first found this
theme because Akila the sunglass brand
had it uh maybe this is probably like 2
years ago and I was using a plugin I
don't think it works anymore it was
actually show you what the Shopify uh
theme is think it's called koala
inspector but if you want to pay 350
bucks and get one of these styles to
have that more look like you should go
ahead and do it and I have a future plan
for I'm going to do with my site that
involves a slightly different uh
approach to this but for now that got me
across the Finish Line to where I want
to go so what are some examples of good
sites you should aspire to at e Commerce
so Ridge has a great one um this is a
product that I am like not a personal
fan of I understand it's not for me as a
consumer but they do super well they
have a really interesting approach to
many things they do they care deeply
about e-commerce super successful
company and you'll notice they've put a
lot of time into presenting thems in a
tech forward manner to their particular
customer and it's got this like halfway
between Yeti and uh you know and kind of
like more recognizable te technology
Brands almost like unrate feel to it
that is perfectly appealing to their
kind of male demographic they're a great
one to look at if you have a lot of
products and you want to appeal to this
more kind of like mainstream guy
demographic they're a great one to look
at um because I feel like their website
does a really great job at establishing
credibility another one I want to talk
about is represent um because this is
one that I actually think would be very
simple for people to use and do inside
Shopify and I like what they've done
with their order here really they go big
graphic call out into row row of of
items big graphic and call out row of
items repeat and this gives you the a
basically a storytelling format that
kind I feel like makes people want to
scroll uh you get your simple roll over
here and you actually go onto the
product detail Pages nice clean branded
everything changes when they move it
this is obviously a lot of custom
involved here this is another thing
where like it may look simple this is
definitely a sixf figure website um but
if you did want to go take some of the
default Builders inside Shopify and
replicate something the ability to do
this base navigation they have on the
homepage where you say big hero section
products big hero section products is
something you can do inside most paid
themes um that gives you like a nice
aspect that will be immedi have that
feel of being more of a brand unless
just a store showing you things a brand
I love and I don't know if this is
Shopify or not but I think it's really
worth showing is the Gia brand because
they're super focused on content right
so for a cpg brand where you may may be
buying some stuff online but a lot of
that you're buying inside store you know
they're selling these bundles here to
help get their average order value up
because shipping and stuff like that is
very expensive on beverage uh nice these
full screen super well art directed
images with these rollovers but what I
really like here is what they're doing
with editorial if you watch my last
video on the brand creative Direction
Trends I talk a decent amount about
editorial and how you use kind of
content as part of the consumer
experience and this is a great one
because these are all recipes and first
let's like take a moment to appreciate
the art direction of these drinks and
the photos that they took of them
because it's completely excellent uh
it's both on theme within itself to be a
uniquely Gia experience and then each
one of them individually looks like
absolutely delectable and what they're
doing here is they're presenting a
number of recipes you can use with geia
and so non-alcoholic beverage has very
particular taste and the fact that you
can go in and very quick quickly come up
with something that you would want to
use you want to make a cocktail at your
party or you want to do something like
fun at home um and you can just kind of
go and browse through that gives a
utility to their site that keeps people
coming back because if you are a
non-alcoholic beverage paking person you
want to you know you have a wide
selection I got like 50 drinks here I
can go try on any given night and at the
same time enjoy like a beautiful visual
experience it's not like I'm dealing
with everyone's done this on Google
where you'll like literally be like
margarita recipe I'm just going to click
the first link that comes up I didn't
prep this at all um and it's just going
to give you like a bunch of these ads
coming down in between I have to keep
going before I even get to like how to
make it like you're getting these just
like it's not a great user experience
it's just a bunch of things trying to
sell you via AdSense and they're saying
hey we can give you a more simple
consumer experience with content with
what we present here it's not even video
content right this is literally just a
photo and a recipe now we're going to
talk a bit about gen Z websites and so
white fox is a great example super
popular amongst jenzy females and they
have a busy website and I think that's
for a number of reasons I'll get into
one in a minute but one thing that I
think is is interesting to show here is
the sheer amount of use of editorial
photo like these are all their product
photos we're not talking any white
background no just product it is all
people actually like wearing and
utilizing um the products themselves you
see it here this is all lifestyle
photography and a lot of it candid like
this this photo right here you know
they're participating in their
day-to-day the fake selfie photo um
quite the trend that uh that we saw a
few months ago a lot of folks doing but
they're presenting a much more Chao otic
view tons of links and things in view
lots of things happening in the NAB lots
of things packed on screen and that's a
trend I think that we've noticed amongst
brands are appealing to a younger
mographic and one of the reasons I I
think why is because of the ubiquity of
things like teu so like this is the web
experience where people are shopping for
cheap things we're spending a lot of
time on timu on shien on Amazon on these
much more complex sites and so if you
are trying to you know follow the
concept that you should be designing
what people are used to spending time
interacting with online which is roughly
known as Jacob's law then if that's the
experience that your customer is used to
then that's an experience that you
should be designing around giving them
and for more Millennial Focus Brands you
know definitely represent 1,00% Ridge
you know a few others there they are
focused on presenting that more clean
larger experience you know what you're
looking at you know what you're
interacting with but a busier experience
may be better for your demographic
especially if their geny those are
pretty sweeping generalizations but it's
worth thinking about worth looking at
especially when you do things like
customer profile creation what are the
websites that our customers look at and
can I ask them that via survey can we
check it out and deep dive into some of
their Tik Tok reason to Google your
customer understanding what they partake
in now is going to help you shape where
your brand should take them online
another site I'm a big fan of is this
Warren Lotus website so Street Wear
brand super particular look and feel uh
love when you this is like an nft gated
or whatever don't want to give that
rabbit hole but like just the Blurred
out effect on that is great you know
super branded in every aspect of it um
this is we're actually basing some of
what we're going to do with the valuable
site a bit around this but what I
particularly like is the lore so you see
these drop downs here they have like
characters in their own little Warren
Lotus world I can go click on this and
I'm going to see like a bio of this
crazy cartoon character same thing here
they have themes that are under that
there's no products available to them
for now this whole drop is based
underneath this character uh and they
all have that their kind of backstory
and this is the kind of thing that this
lore these extra items this like all
this that goes into creating something
like this is what can give a brand who
has that cult following who gives people
the ability to brace like a bigger story
is what gives them like an in
interesting deeper element to the site
that makes people feel an affinity
towards the brand so if you do have lore
like that or you have interesting
experiences you can integrate like at
one point in the valuable site we were
looking at coding like a browser based
like old school racing game right and
it's like how do you come up with those
ideas where you might be able to get
people to participate or have just that
one more level of fandom come from it
then when it comes to websites that
really have a more luxury experience
this is this is the road skinite this is
another one by Van group uh and
everything about this website to me for
like screams luxury right from the
choice of colors that we have here to
the all little elements like the rounded
shapes to the presentation of the
products again we're still incorporating
like the actual photography um obviously
like with the celebrity involved little
things like like the swipe icon here all
this justifies the price point of the
products and the kind of exceptional
nature of the brand the popularity of
the brand you know the photography the
typography every choice here is
intentional and represents a brand
Essence like in a very particular way
and I think that if you're going to look
at how do I position myself to a wide
demographic like multiple generations of
people but and I want to be appealing to
them and approachable to them but then
also still have that like sense of brand
this is like a bit of a master class
inside how you would put something like
that together and I'll contrast this
with the remova site where this is a
very straightforward site that you could
make in a default Shopify theme in you
know this would be an 8 to 10 hour site
you're not looking at things super
complicated it does not necessarily
represent the brand in the way that I
think the brand should be represented
online uh they are relying on their
brand Equity to do that and they have a
lot of kind of content underneath this
um and a lot of like things that you can
explore inside the site but when you
come into this they're presenting a very
basic Shopify experience but with that
in mind that's because I'm sure they're
spending the time looking at what
actually converts for us and if they
they are focused very much on DTC sales
they're they a popular d2c brand even at
their price point and I'm sure what they
found is that the very simple website
that is extremely easy to navigate and
understand that does not have a bunch of
complexity is what sells them the most
products and tested their way into that
and so it's worth looking too when
you're at this scale the amount of
traffic I'm sure that their website gets
how much of this matters right how much
like is it is that extra small
percentage of conversion rate worth that
kind of more premium brand experience or
you completely focused on your sales
experience and where do those worlds
match so let's drop into unique Shopify
themes so this distinctive theme um
which I believe is by Fuel themes is
another one that I think helps brand
stand out for and have an interesting
website gives you video backgrounds out
of the box the typography that's coming
with out of the box is also interesting
the ability to have video on Ecom images
which I think is excellent as an option
is coming default out of the box and uh
I think they have a this is a great
option for a theme with a couple
interesting different like looks that
they have here I greatly prefer um the
first one they have but these this is
pretty solid if you want something more
straightforward as well again love the
integration of like the shopable video
the idea you can shop the look right
from clicking the video that coming out
of the box in a Shopify theme is is
awesome um um same here kind of video
Carousel scroll I like to bring up these
themes because this is the easiest way
for someone to get a good looking site
people often like how do I get a
good-looking Shopify site and oh I've
started with this theme I use this or
that go hunt down one of these it's
worth a couple hundred bucks to do it
it's going to get you to a certain ratio
and I'll going talk a little bit about
your other options and kind of what
things look like when you incorporate
that last theme I'm going to show here
is um this shapes theme uh which is by
the same people that do the Baseline
theme I showed but this is one if you do
have like a more if you really want a
more interesting brand experience out of
the box like this would have to be a
certain type of brand but if you really
want to be bright and stand out they
have a pretty wild out of the boox theme
set that again with the topography and
stuff where if you just want to
immediately have a Vibe you can
basically pay the money and get there
with uh something like this and then
they have a couple different like
applications of that I don't
particularly like this one U then like a
more muted version as well that have an
interesting approach for you so one
thing I work a lot on is testing so
basically getting a theme to test a
single product where we'll put a product
up on Shopify run a bunch of Tik Tok
organ meic or run a bunch of meta ads
and then just see if it has any level of
response even just sign up for email or
pre-order or if we actually have a
couple do this and origin is a great
validation site believe this is one of
the free Shopify ones I don't think you
have to pay for it uh or it's like super
cheap but this is a great like onepage
shoppable like literally we will cut the
product image out pop it on here follow
this exact here's your options nice
little mobile layout simple and again
I'm 90% sure it's free uh to get started
and just gives you a very basic building
blocks that's a great free theme if you
want to look at that to be like let's
give it a shot so if you want to build
custom and you don't want to buy a theme
and you want to have some custom website
there's a couple ways to do that so this
is a project I actually worked on worked
on this landing page um for this toy
product and so this here is built in a
backend editor so Shopify has a couple
different backend editors there's Shogun
pagefly but this is in gem Pages which I
like a lot and the downside of these
editors is they're clunky the code
you're not going to have the fastest
websites there's going to be a lot
you're going you kind have to work
through from a performance perspective
but you go peep in the back end of
something like this it's literally row
popping your images it's just like any
WordPress editor Squarespace editor Etc
that you've seen whereas a normal
Shopify back end is not like that at all
and you can do things like this row that
was a persistent scroll at to cart um
that we saw over here where like as I'm
going down now I have that persistent
ATAC card across an entire page like
things like that are built in and it's
one of those like for a monthly cost
you're getting the ability to turn any
page including product detail pages into
like these comprehensive experiences
that you can literally drag and drop and
if you don't want to go uh if you want
to go like fully custom which is what
I'm going to end up doing for valuable
what a lot of the sites I work on are
that don't get like a full treatment
from like a more expensive firm you want
to go get your um designs done I'll go
mock up either myself or with a designer
like this is what I worked in with um
with another designer inside figma um
that they put together from some
inspiration that U myself and the brand
owner had and we basically put together
these Pages here in design and then we
worked with a developer to turn them
into Shopify where we can literally pass
the figma designs to the developer with
some notes and references from sites
that were looking at of how we want the
scroll or this or that to be and we uh
use a company called Prime apps uh we
found on upwork I've used for like six
or eight years they're they're great
it's like 35 bucks an hour type thing
where they will code the entire piece of
it and if you with that process
especially if you're working overseas
like we are like sometimes that can take
some time but if you're willing to go
through a couple Cycles go with those
notes back and forth you can turn Custom
Designs into your exact website with any
functionality and be doing that in the
like low thousands of dollars it just
requires a certain amount of dedication
the ability to have designers either on
your team or dedicated to it and be able
to just work through the user experience
and progress which not everyone's cut
out for but if you are like that type of
person and you want to do it in your
best bang for a buck like that's
definitely the option and so one thing
I'm doing with a similar team right now
is this bite side is what I love for
more uh detailed product detail Pages
like you have a lot you want to tell
people like this has a whole usage
section um it has a whole ingredients
you know like deep dive ingredients
they're showing off all these items
around different certifications they
have like all the reviews are custom
like this is a really nice setup for a
more expansive product detail page and
with literally sent this to the
developer and we're just like clone this
here's our ingredients list here's our
text here's whatever it is here's the
fonts we want to use and they made this
exact site and in about 2 days and we
were using this for a product detail
page to test a new product and so it's
nice to be able to like have that back
and forth once you do get in the flow to
develop almost anything you want but
overall at the end of the day most
brands are going to be able to start
with one of the Shopify themes and build
out from there that's going to be your
kind of best bang for buck have
something functional option uh then from
there you can do things like those
backend editors but you can be doing
some of that at the expense of like your
site speed and your site performance
when you use like a g Pages or a Shogun
or a page fly or you can get whatever
you want done but it's not going to be
the optimized thing that if you're
getting a ton of traffic is going to get
you where you want to go and then your
choices to really like learn in lean
into custom Dev and go into that which I
wouldn't touch if you don't have a
design or development background
yourself or then start getting into
firms that can provide you luxury
experiences and with that like it really
just depends on what you're looking for
there are some teams that are focused on
cost there are some that are focused on
you know cro that like optimization for
Speed and there are some that are
focused on you know brand and design and
incorporation of all those pieces
together and a great example of a fully
custom site that I think is really
interesting is this entire Studio site
where you get this mix of editorial uh
and product have everything cut out you
see here and then when you actually
navigate it they'll show you the Styles
goes with right there and you can go
kind of buy you know specific
Collections and outfits I thought
they've done a great job of really just
you know they're cutting out pgs of each
of these various items and uh I thought
they done a good job of making a unique
interesting look like and this is their
upcoming drop with the launch and how it
previews that's a good example of a just
a unique site that can get executed this
will be fully custom code and the kind
kind of thing that you would go to um a
van group for or another kind of
Boutique website agent anyway that was
my deep dive into how you can approach
web design what the right themes are to
buy how to think about it for your brand
a bit of how I'm thinking about it I
hope that you use a bunch of this inside
creating your own sites so thank you for
watching