what is art Direction whether for brand
content or personal content the
difference between great creative and
mediocre creative lies in the art
Direction this video I'm going to hit
what it is and I'm going to go through
100 examples from my favorite references
and talk about why they work and then
how you can use them yourself this video
is both great to learn the concepts of
how to think about art Direction and to
look back on as a reference for any
campaign or anything you do to generate
ideas cuz we just have tons of them
throughout our direction is zoned in on
the visual production of photo and video
assets where creative Direction looks at
the overall themes across everything a
brand has to do since we have so much
more content to make as individuals as
creators as Brands and it's become a
Non-Stop churn of content that has to
come out art Direction has become a part
of the toolkit that every Creator and
creative needs to have so diving right
into the examples I'm going to walk
through a large amount of different
types of Brands within this we're going
to go through jewelry Brands food brands
fashion brands all kinds of different
categories you can find applicableness
to whatever it is you're working on and
to yourself as an individual for what
you done document so this is from a
jewelry brand called Aron idz I she
wearing one of their chains right now
they're one in my face and what Drew me
to them was their art Direction every
photo has an intentional interesting
thought so whether it's presenting their
jewelry wrapped in asparagus or attached
to bread what we see here with this
leaning tower of glassware whatever we
have going on with these hands every
single photo has an idea behind it
instead of saying I'm going to just make
a beautiful photo of this put it on
white put it on a basic background there
is a concept behind every single thing
you see and then tension has been put
into that and that is a core of the arch
it separates the photo from not is is
this just a person standing or sitting
there is just a head shot is it just
someone in some natural background are
we just documenting or getting something
candid are we shooting something basic
or do we have an idea and that presence
of an idea can give your photography
videography whatever it is something
special and then you begin to develop
motifs and identity of your brand that
revolves around some of these special
ideas recurring and mixing with each
other and all of this helps in its
success it helps a on social media feeds
because things like this stand out
resonate become sharable commentable in
a way that more basic content does and
second it resonates with the consumer it
makes them think for even a second it
gives them a bit of an understanding of
what the brand might stand for and for
instance for me for this brand these
particular kind of like Artful displays
of it really made it ST stand out to me
it was something that resonated with me
as a consumer and how they were
presented to make me look at the brand
further our Direction doesn't have to be
complex this is a standard shot you
could see of any jewelry Bram or you
have a manicured hand with the jewelry
on it but by putting the glove on it
they've just added one thing and if
you're thinking about art direction for
the first time or you're thinking how
could I incorporate this in shoots when
I have a lot of oversight and I don't
have some big budget the minimum
requirement for art direction is just
select one thing you're adding to your
shoot that you're adding to this piece
of content that is going to make it
somewhat interesting or special or
different and for instance this glove
didn't cost any more than they would put
into a normal photo shoot but it
transforms this photo in an interesting
way another example here of not just
showing the model but showing the
model's head coming through an orifice
faka better
term this ties a bit into how can you
use these things for your own brand and
so for instance if you want to look at
an idea or look at Art direction or any
of the references I have here you put it
on your mood board what do you actually
do with and so this is a great example
where look I don't work super in- depth
on any jewelry currently but this
concept of someone coming out of a space
or coming out of an odd space is a
concept that I would put down like
inside my notion like brainstorm I have
for Arch Direction and then it's an idea
I can come back to and say for whatever
shoot it is I'd be shooting headwear
like how can I find a space like this or
a portal of sorts that is on brand for
what I work on you know for instance
obviously my valuable brand has a lot of
car themes on it I look at this and I go
great for one of these hat shots I'm
doing I need to be shooting the model's
head coming out of like the passenger
window like like they're hollering or
whatever it is and all of a sudden this
becomes a transplant of I put into the
context of my brand so you think about
that one different thing head coming out
of a scenario and you go what scenarios
make sense for my brand to put them into
and you can even go one degree removed
it what do I actually have access to um
and you can list out the items and
things you have that make your brand
special or that you have access to in
your studio and or in your life and
begin to work around that so this is
another example of the jewelry displayed
resembling a face uh part of what really
drew me to the brand this kind of
recurring series they have and that's
why I love about the idea of art
Direction one off versus working for as
a brand or a series you're going to
develop motifs as a brand and your
trademarks as a creative and you're
going to find things like this that
resonate you love to do you have some
theories to do that you repeat and these
are the through lines that create Brands
visually embedded in people's
subconscious over time where you see
that and you immediately think of the
brand and whether someone else does it
or not if they think of you then that
begins to have you've built your brand
standard to a certain level and I'm
going to show some exact um creative
directors and some of their work across
Brands and how they have some of those
through lines and how they work and so
worth thinking about what are those
statements for and as you look back if
you've already done a bunch of work like
this and you're an art director trying
to Brand yourself to think about where
your future lies look back at the work
you've done and go what is the most
successful things most exciting things
the things I like the most or the
through lives I have and then how do I
lean into that how do I make that a
trademark part of what I do how do I
become associated with it it's part of
the visual branding that goes both for a
brand and works just as well for an
individual creative and leaning into
those through lines and adding new ones
retiring old ones or adding variations
is part of what gives you an arc that's
memorable as a creative possibly my
favorite of all those So speaking of
arcs as a creative this image is by
eraser world this is a high production
image you this has some serious cost to
you know get this many people and
actually do this edit style and maybe
not cost but certainly top I believe
racer is from Estonia they do an
excellent job of having like cemented
themselves as kind of a counterculture
Estonia representing you know uh like
chaotic brand and they're obviously
standing out with some iconography
they're not a religious brand if
anything AR they might be anti that um
but it creates conversation of what they
do but when you look at the creative
director of this shoot um there's
something I love to do is go if they do
credit go check it out so we went and
check out emna you get to see that all
the way back in 2016 she' worked on this
so it's obviously part of her kind of
toolkit uh her aesthetic is being able
to portray bod's overhead in scenarios
and in symbolism and that's a really
interesting through line for someone to
have and it's one of the things that has
gone now it is eight years between those
two campaigns but continues to be a
thing that is present in her work and
something she knows how to do and
executes that was jewelry now we're
going to dive into like more common
objects like drinks um and I this is
this is going to be useful for basically
anything that has a container so if you
sell glasswar um if you sell anything
that is kind of like a homegood uh then
also you sell any beverage of any kind
some of these examples are going to be
really so Gia excellent career Direction
on this brand overall uh visuals are
always on point and you've seen them
probably in my website video I brought
this up before but these photos of their
product they have recipes is a core
content that they do and each of these
are shot in this incredible
fashion
I they have that perfect Haze over them
I think these the lights are are added
than
post or if they're in camera good for
them but they've created this visual
style where they are styling each one of
these Beverages and when you have
something like Gia where you have a
handful of cans there's only so much you
can do as far as showing your product in
a certain way there's an infinite amount
of variations you have when you show it
in a class and styled in a class from
the matter of the color they chose with
the olives with the glass happens there
they have an infinite number of content
and art combinations that come from this
all shot in a signature style and this
is something uh in my last cut 30 cohort
that I did we had a glasswar company in
there that sold really nice ornate
glasses and they were always making
content around their glasses but I was
noticing there was never anything in the
glass and so one person I brought up was
this woman bevs by Beverly who uh does
recipe content online and what stood out
about her content what makes it you know
resonate really well is it's always sh
this is always like golden hour lighting
so it's really intentional around what
the lighting looks like and having it be
what I believe is is real light but the
presentation of the visual look of both
the simple glasses with the visually
intense recipes everything has an
intention around the glass that's used
whether it's for actually creating the
recipe or presenting it and the
intentional light and framing of how
this is put together and her art
direction of these shoots is what makes
it stand out from other recipe content
that's on there but again if you are a
company that has any type of Beverage
whatsoever that being able to create
something aesthetic like this is a
Surefire win for Content also if you are
any container of this especially you
make glass or you you make any table
good being present or around this any
ingredient from this you are taking what
you have and adding on a whole aesthetic
World on top of it I think that's a
really powerful concept to think through
and allows you to make more common
objects into much more interesting
content and so going to f where you tend
to have the best examples um of this
house of Errors relatively newer brand
one you probably see me wear a decent
amount they've had some basically every
shoot they've ever released has been
really intentional they thought whether
you know they are using on the higher
budget end of this I want to show a
whole range of this on depending what
kind of brand you are things you can do
simply just with attention things you
can do if you're already doing shoots in
elevated or things you can do if you're
going to spend money time and resources
and they're great example of look
they're hiring actors and models for
these campaigns these are out of the box
ones they're putting them in the unique
scenario they're having great creatives
capture the content and everything is
conceptual the locations are incredible
when they are the locations the thought
through of how they interact and I have
a whole little section here about how
people interact this is just a great
example of like if you have two guys
standing there what are they going to do
how do you make it stand out like a
headbutt is certainly a interesting one
especially when it's presented in
context of the other images there we
have like a mountain again I don't know
how they're accomplishing this image but
you're taking something relatively
normal making it stand out you're
leveraging your location to the fullest
all the way to just like complet
completely ornate fully expensive
produce shoots to what you can do in
post with editing to even the basics of
like this shot could be anywhere but the
intention of the lighting and the outfit
and what he's doing again with the light
source coming and him looking towards it
it just has a lot of implied story
without having to do too much to one of
their best shoots I've looked at it's
called um was you know Black Friday
Market drop or something like that uh
where they're playing on the the
financial crisis stock drop back before
yeah they took a lot of people to go
execute and do something like this but
an immaculately thought through and
concept aced shoot executed with like
full budget and intention and I think
how standout this image and campaign was
and how popular it was for them and how
many people showed it the fact that like
Outlander is taking the time to like
post their content and and boost their
brand shows me you do take things this
seriously the power it has for your
brand if my voice is fading here I've
I've been sick all week I apologize but
the the value will still be in the
content I promise and I may even put try
to put captions on this video we'll see
if I want to dig through 20 minutes of
editing that we'll see another example
badon this is a great example of like I
don't think this brand has huge budgets
for this kind of stuff this is an
incredible image and it's comped uh they
show you it's comped you know for what I
can tell this is a 3D model or like the
base of the 3D model that they use to
create this but you're able to create
one person move them around in space and
in blender or whatever they're using
here and they created something like
purely off of the concept but another
thing I liked here is them presenting
the images in a format so for instance
they have like this lookbook presented
on cdrom and that's a fascinating way to
think about we're going to capture
images and then we're going to present
them like in another format we're going
to comp them into something and doing it
in an interesting way and displaying it
even the way they chose to have multiple
uh or versus putting it in the case or
wherever you choose uh and then also
taking that AR Direction then putting it
across other things so for instance like
they have the pricing and the size
charts portrayed in the same fashion and
this is an interesting thing to think
about is when you do these kind of
things for these shoots how can you
extend them so if you've done it for
that concept can you add that to your
product detail page can you then include
that in whatever manual you have how can
you extend your art Direction Concepts
as through lines throughout other things
you do for the brand some of those
things that enter into like the creative
direction that is the brand and
tangibles that really make things
resonate speaking of big budget I'd be
remiss if I didn't talk about shcm shcm
who have just done a series of these
launches and they often use oversized
items as part of it so they're
announcing a new location here uh they
have all these big oversized items
created this is incredible content
perfect for social media uh I think is
one of the most common winning
techniques still now just go make bigger
versions of things you sell or viral
things on you they do a lot of that they
had a successful postcard in their
previous Campaign which was just a few
weeks ago uh for another store opening
all the way to like this large map that
they have here The Branding on it like
the large item is a part of the motif of
their art Direction but equally as much
is these kind of like outrageous
scenarios like my guy ironing on the
stand up paddle board and an inflatable
you know it's got that balance to this
idea of her enjoying a cocktail on a
chair being transported between location
and what I like about showing this
contrast is that this is something that
requires some degree of production it's
actually probably cheaper than you think
to go get this printed out like I love
art Direction ideas you could execute
for a couple hundred bucks like right
like this didn't take maybe they have
models here where you could do it with
your team they printing that map alone
is a thing that cost a couple hundred
bucks you can execute content you could
have this image you could have it be a
bump shot where people are kind of using
it to navigate you have people selling M
out as a way to create that into a real
or a piece of content that should be
able to manufacture a good views for you
you can take a couple stabs at uh
because you can do that content where
you show the behind the scenes then show
the reality there's a way to do multiple
iterations every time you use this has a
couple hundred bucks and that is the
sweet spot for new brands especially or
people that need to get creative or
people that need to make content like
every week where you could actually
afford it and it pays for itself but
overall these ideas where it's like all
right like the stand up power board the
ironing board the guy out there on an
iPhone video is very achievable for this
is a conceptual look if you know anyone
that has a stand up paddle board if you
have an ironing board you know this
isn't some crazy outfit this person has
on separate than this like this is
something that's executable then to a
lesser extent getting something like
this done but obviously the impact could
potentially be higher all the way to
more silly stuff like this The Stills I
catching for the internet and they get
to a more expensive scenario but they
are you know doing the ultimate end of
this where this is one Carousel it's the
entire use of this for them and they are
they're taking 10 shots at having a
viral item inside what they put together
because they have the maximum resources
to be able to go execute something like
this that shows you how serious they
take it is they're like we are so want
to make sure we are destined for Success
here and we want to get our 544 th000
[ __ ] likes which is insane and we are
going to go hit 10 shots and every every
one of them cost money and time and
produ and it was totally worth it and
you can do this with Studio shots and
things as well so Bandit um we
interviewed them in our hyper newsletter
interviewed their creative director I
believe he's one of the co-founders Tim
in there and he had talked about there
doing these these Studio shoots and i'
believe in there like comping these
backgrounds in uh sometimes the
backgrounds are generated with AI and I
always think that that's a an
interesting approach too to be able to
take some normal things you're doing and
you have to get some new offs to kind of
color match things correctly but it's
impactful on the feed and more subtle
all right Switching gears a bit um this
is a vape brand and they're utilizing
viral items this is another another
interesting thing that a lot of Brands
can do so this is a whole Carousel of
tabies that are holding their product
and so another good example of you don't
have some beautiful aesthetic product
you something more normal leverage more
viral things around it to help it
succeed and this is a great little art
Direction choice for a social carousel
there um that is just kind of like a fun
idea and they're in a restricted
category so you're always going to have
a hard time with social media but I'm
going to show a bunch of like restricted
category stuff because they tend to have
to try to do as well as they can
organically because they're limited on
what they can do paid
so another great example the brand pure
beauty just a purely excellent Ed brand
all around and they have this kind of
like they're showing their product in
this like almost quas fetish scenario
that just makes it a standout
foot but I want to show another good
example this is a brand that like
doesn't have some hugely compelling
thing to look at every time it's in a
photo this is a large version of the
small box that their product comes in so
they made like a shoe box size version
probably not that expensive but is akin
to what they've already created here and
they now presented in multiple different
scenarios as a recurring Motif in their
art direction again presented here and
so if you do have a product where again
it's not some crazy aesthetic thing you
don't have tons of variations doing
something like this where you say
whether it's the actual product itself
or an oversized version of it or an
undersized version of it and putting in
scenarios is an arous strategy in itself
I also love this shot here I love AR
direction that adds in the concept of
like what are people doing every day but
just make it slightly off like this here
like he's watering the pool uh where
it's just conceptual and again something
it doesn't require a huge budget it was
just a this was just purely a concept
all the way to more orchestrated product
shots where you know macro shot super
wide the way it's styled they've created
a really particular look and feel
another approach you know using their
example but if you had a more standard
brand the idea if you're going to take
their branding and you're going to apply
photography of the things that happen in
the background of the brand but make it
really elevated photography like they're
doing here with the soil that uh they
use in the product if you're trying to
storytelling beautiful imagery of the
everyday things that happen and then
having a branding application is an
interesting art Direction method quick
tangent on related to this brand margin
who I'm about to show some examples of
what they done they've put basically
Incorporated art into their packaging so
there'll be this kind of like limited
art that's available like onside what
they print and release which I think is
a fun concept that when I did my
packaging survey with Hyper where we had
like 600 people talk about you know what
kind of packaging they like and a lot of
people were interested in like art and
additions and recurring series and what
the new thing is think of like Jones
Soda people like that uh and I think
that they're an interesting brand that's
kind of done this in in their but
they're like a smaller Cosmetics brand
uh but I think that's something to think
about as well is when you're thinking
your packaging look like is there an art
Direction component or recurring
component to that so cool example of a
margin shoot here uh is what they've
done here so basically their cream is
just applied to this Letterman and it
doesn't make sense it doesn't have
reason but it's gorgeous and it's
impactful and it's thoughtful in a way
that I think really speaks to a certain
customer type and this is the kind of
out- of the Box thinking I feel is good
for brands that do have something that's
really common like skincare where it's
like how do I look at this in any other
way and even just putting it in a
foreign complex scenario artfully
executed gives it that degree that's
just better than yet another product
shot but then I hunted down Michael who
took this shot and so he this is part of
his recurring motifs as an art director
is he has tools the way you saw
previously and you see here interacting
with more common products and that's a
really fun interesting recurring theme
for a a creative to have that he's
developed into his toolkit another shot
from him I love which would be a cool
for any you know again brand that you
have here is just you're just you're
taking your product and attaching it to
something that is an inherently more
interesting image briefly talk about
like the art of a carousel overall like
this is a great just example if you're
shooting a product shot and you're like
intentional around like the colors and
backgrounds like having that matte Shear
on something the strong really helps it
pop and they're tying that to these like
ingredient shots to the macro of the
product like the ability to create a
Carousel and kind of think through some
of that storyline is a key part of the
toolkit another from that brand Rose it'
be cool for all kind of food brands or
brands with ingredients is the way they
have these Peppers Incorporated here
like in the shot and they build I'm
swinging back and forth between two
photos in the carousel right now uh but
like really showing that background and
ingredients process that goes into it is
what this brand Rose does well where
obviously if they were just taking
pictures of these gummies all the time
that wouldn't be as impactful as what
we're seeing in the mixer you know them
on top of a collage you the ability to
kind of put product and process next to
each other is a bit of our Direction in
itself tools of presentation is a whole
thing there as well where it's just like
just a choice of what you're using to
hold a product or like the uniqueness of
like the cutlery choice you have if
you're at a table or whatever it is is a
big thing that can help separate
concepts of now I want to do a quick
dive into one of the goats of art
Direction which is stucy Stuy have for
Generations just had standout photo
Direction on everything and a couple
Concepts there I'll share the first is
like the brand in action is just always
just a no-brainer where you can show a
model or you can show a person skating
in the in the gear and just like having
that moment is just a pure separator for
any brand that does have like a
performance connection same with the
lifestyle integration that you see here
where like they're in it they're in the
mud literally all the way to the
Simplicity of like this dude is just
live in life in LA or Orange County or
wherever they are but like giving some
everyday the casualness of this is is
interesting inherently enough and and
ties this overall Stuy idea of like I've
seen like three stucy photos that are
indoors like 90% of the photos 99% of
the photos are outside you are catching
some rays when you are in stucy and that
is an important part of an overall theme
of the brand that's carried through in
almost every component you see in their
art even this as a uh just as a
conceptual shop you think about location
and what you can do what you can do on a
budget this is a great one and then one
of my favorite recent ones is they're
just risky they shot all these models in
between two vehicles and the vehicles
change pretty regularly and what I love
about is you can't see enough of it to
really know what the vehicles are if you
want to look or get more info they're
different each time and the vehicles
themselves just cause you to look in and
be more interested in it while still
framing this like important subject in
like a very like classic photo lineup um
this is just a great shoot concept and
idea I think they executed amazingly
another one back to that initial Aon AA
shot where the head was coming out of of
the wall like the person emerging from
the hole whatever it is like like it's
could be a contrived photo like
obviously he's not living down there and
coming out but it makes you think think
about what that implied story is that's
happening we going through some other
Concepts this one from Kappa is really
interesting like presenting it like a
team photo uh for their model shoot was
a really cool and fun idea some the
ideas of how you can do things kind in
post but again it's just a singular
concept applied to like a brand launch
this Alexander Wang shot and this like
amorphous object that's included like
back to the one thing idea if you have a
studio shot it's like what's the one
thing I can bring in like let's yeah let
let's bring in the silver orb or
whatever it is at the end of the day
like you get a couple guys you can
probably make this at Home Depot in a
day like what is this thing that we
could create that could be a centerpiece
of something we do in studio is like a
Surefire winner same thing with this
where like signage like anything you can
get where you actually get a sign with
your brand name or you get something
reusable like this just like turns this
studio photo shoot into something that
could immediately be more compelling and
you could have a bunch of variation to
try actually another good example of
like if you have a budget on a studio
shoot and you're like what are we going
to spend our $1,000 on our $4,000 on
whatever it is like all right cool we're
going to get tons of stuffed animals and
we're going to have them dropping and
we're going to have someone on a mound
of them whatever it is like that ability
to basically say we are we have X amount
of funds what are the things we can do
with it is just a key way to think about
how you're doing your shoots and then
just have tons of references like these
and be like all right let's go to the
store and figure it out um I think the
selfie is a awesome vehicle to turn any
photo different where all of a sudden
the perspective is someone's showing
themselves off which is just an
intrinsic concept to look at differently
when you're like what about the thing
that they're wearing makes us so they
feel comfortable enough to show
themselves off as an immediate thought
that's transferred to the audience and
this backdrop scenario here as well
where if you do do studio and you could
comp things in behind it making an
interesting contrast have so many
options here now with like what you can
then create a mid journey in the
background is a great way in my opinion
to approach like getting the most out of
a studio shoot versus just putting the
person on the white background in other
simple Concepts like the single bug like
the presentation of a menu in a common
way that you actually see it out there
in the street one of my favorites is
like the interruption of spaces like
this is an excellent shoe shot and you
could do a lot with tables things like
that of like it's somewhat it's
disrespectful it showcases the product
super well it draws you in it tells a
story uh it's about putting things in
the environments where they're less
comfortable another one is excellent
shot where like interaction with food I
feel like in general probably one of the
key things here like anything plus food
especially if it's not normally around
food is just such a plus whereas like
with this for example like it's not only
it's food it's a unorthodox interaction
with food the same the last photo was
it's showing off the actual glove here
and that's one of those things that
again this is a this is a $100
idea post production simple ideas this
is what I like where they just pixelated
this car it's a simple photo besides
that but that gives it everything you
need to know that like something's
happening um another one here where uh
if you were shooting a model like this
and then putting these in here in like
mid Journey but this idea that you're
like putting someone in a really
uncomfortable scenario um and you're
able to surround you're able to surround
a subject with things that are
inherently complex Al again objects
presented in uncommon areas like the
ring when you're opening up a CD player
like it doesn't make sense long enough
to catch attention which could be the
Simplicity of something same thing with
attaching stuff to more viral stuff this
is for the actual lip kit we have here
but like the tooth gem makes the photo
back to that the brand we shown before
Bloom um a good example they B just
blowing the product up and they I like
this this is a useful one where I I you
know people that just blow the product
up for the sake of it being viral is
like is one thing but they were
announcing a bigger size um like a like
a second variation like then it becomes
like that much more makes that much more
sense and then the idea of like
presenting your brand in context so I
like when you're just looking to I we to
create more content do more things like
St laurant over the matcha in context
like just the that existing it's less
about selling that individual item if
that's even an item they sell and more
about like the brand in context also
this idea of the absence of something uh
like what you can do in post-production
with that person without the head Etc
and the action of what people are doing
like the easiest ones that basically any
brand could apply and shoot for for
cheap is food interaction games is
another great one um this is an
advertisement for a bag like including
the chest the model like barely in the
photo ex excellent shot this idea of
like okay what can we do in post-
production like put things on screens or
make it so it's got this inherent like
digital feel uh just the idea of
composition you that's an an immediate
theory if you have nothing else going
but you are at a location with models
are showing off your product what can
you do from a composition standpoint to
stand out this is a pure great example
of that uh both from like where they
have the model located to like is this
the same person or a second person to
the fact that that's out of focus
there's a lot about that photo that is
meant to draw somebody in and then
pattern whether they done afterwards and
post or done and how you shoot it is a
great one that immediately draws the eye
on social another fun jewelry example
but that use of common things you have
around there and like what can you do to
make it inherently complicated with four
HS instead of one I love this just
interaction with of elements and things
uh a good exercise when people say we
don't have a budget for a shootter like
to do is like list out everything
strange or weird that any person in your
team has or that you have in your office
or we may have access to like going and
buying a fish in a bag is like a very
easy option for that and all the way up
to like angle and location and the
things you can do like within your
toolkit like as a photographer or
creative to say we have a completely
normal scenario um but we could put a
person in a perspective that makes it
interesting to how you display the
product there one thing I like about
those blanked hangers which I'm going to
use a lot in my stuff is like by really
buying the hanger yeah the hanger is 30
bucks a hanger whatever it is your photo
is going to stand up as the same thing
for like this winch and display here
then I love this idea of having
something concealed or making something
a secret uh is for any small item it's
just an interesting way to portray it
and then there's the like displaying
photo with other photo and whether it's
a similarity in here or creating like an
inherent contrast I'm back to some we
talk a bit earlier with the interaction
of people like one of the most important
things that you have two people on a
shoot is what are they going to do
together and I think there is any amount
of contact makes it interesting and
someone at this OB or someone's jumping
over somebody or someone's headbutting
someone who's a handshake or you know
like there's Punch or whatever it is
that implies an action or someone
feeding another person just gives it
like an innate difference between two
people just staring at the camera and
like that whole toolkit is a big part of
how you can make those shoots s so
anyway that was aund examples of
different art Direction Styles I Breeze
through them relatively quick cuz really
I just want to give you a toolkit of how
someone thinks about this when they're
applying it a reference point you can go
look at in your brand and just examples
of a lot of quality art Direction
because there is so much out there and
yet there's so many brands that still
don't do it and I think your role as a
creative uh as someone with a brand
working in this is to bring that out of
how that you're working and make
something interesting I'll probably do a
deeper dive like second video on this at
some point in the future so if you have
like art Direction questions or ideas or
thoughts please drop them in the
comments and uh we'll get to them thanks
for watching