All right, welcome back. Today, this is
a video I am doing by request and it is
about creative systems, putting docs
together, organizing your life and your
workflows. Essentially, 11 ways to get
your life together in 2026. I just got
off the road for tour. We had 50 brands
come to Toronto, Miami, and both New
York days each day where I was coaching
brands on exercises for their year, for
organizing their content, for organizing
their marketing funnels. I'm going to
get a whole video on doing things like
this to organize your brand live from
one of those dates that you'll see soon.
But on this, I want to concentrate on
what are the things that can have the
most efficacy to get you systematized,
organized, and making the most impact on
your creative work. Whether that is
[music] being an artist, a designer,
owning your own brand, a writer, and
even just working in a creative field
[music] at a job. So, we're going to
cover building a reference repository,
managing your ideas list, getting a
content calendar together, folders and
workflows for content creators,
capturing stuff in your phone, doing a
weekly update for your bosses, having a
team tracker together if you have a
small agency or group working together,
putting together process docs, planning
and putting together your content,
managing emails out to leads. This is
the kind of stuff that you really need
inside your creative life, but there's
no way to learn it if you're not really
in the job and have really organized
people around you. and I'm super excited
to [music] share it with y'all. Let's
lock in. So, for the majority of these,
I'm just going to show you my workflow
so you can see an actual example of what
goes on there. So, first I'm going to
start with a reference list. If you've
watched some of my older videos, you may
have seen this before. We'll show it to
you in action. This is one of the most
important things that any creative
person can do that will really genuinely
help you get your life together over the
long term. So, for instance, this is a
notion doc that I have that has a bunch
of references I can pull from for the
creative work I do. So, as many of you
know, I do creative strategy for brands
as well as art direction and creative
direction work where I am working on
briefs and ideiation for specific
campaigns and I have a large amount of
things, bookmarks, etc. like everyone
does that I need to be able to bring
into that work. And this could be
certain specific writing styles, essay
styles if you're a writer. This could be
techniques or things that you like or
want to try as a designer. You need a
way to organize them. I use notion for
this and I really like notion for it. It
could also just be a spreadsheet, but
really this has the name of the asset
has a type. So for instance, for me,
this is a content tracker for me. I have
content for events, content for emails,
content for carousels, content for
launches or content that's product
specific. I have a separate one of this
for personal brand. We have like
different expert stuff. There's a link
to the actual asset and I have a status.
Is this a reference or have I used it?
And if we used it, was it a winner? Some
notes around it there. That is a pretty
thorough. You don't need to be this
thorough. What I would recommend is you
have a name for it. You have all of your
types added. Um, again, you can just
click and add a type. You'll see I have
a hell of types in here. And then a link
to it there. You don't necessarily need
to track whether you've used it or it's
a winner or a reference, whatever. But
it's important to think, okay, I am
going to be doing creative work for a
long time. Every time I do it, I'm going
and gathering references or trying to
find that one link. As soon as you start
building this library and adding
regularly to it, all of a sudden, that
time goes so much faster. And then
whenever you're applying for a job or
you're showing people why you should
work on a campaign and you pull up,
you're like, "Oh, here's my master
matrix. Let's pull up all my event
examples. Let's walk through how we
could use this." You are coming across
in a way that most other creatives
aren't and setting yourself apart. So,
how to put this together. So, first,
choose your weapon of choice. You can
can do a spreadsheet. I do a lot in
notion as you can see here. We have hell
of stuff inside here. So, it makes sense
for me to do that. Create a table and
set a time regularly to add to it. I do
this every Sunday night. I would get a
time on your calendar where your job
specifically is to take your bookmarks
from your web browser, X, Instagram, Tik
Tok, see if any of that's relevant,
label it, and put it in here. So, the
other half of this, you have to actively
be doing that bookmarking and that
finding when you scroll and find things,
which I think a lot of people actually
end up really enjoying because they feel
more value and start to be more
intentional about their time online when
they have a system like this. Which ties
really quickly into an ideas list. So if
you are a content creator or you are
doing work or putting out work
regularly, I recommend just having a big
dock for ideas. If you have no other
organization, just getting a massive
doc. So this is basically what I have
for this is an older version. I've moved
this now, but is one I'm willing to
share where I basically just have bullet
lists of things I like. So these are all
carousel ideas I have. So all oneshot
ideas I have, ideas of things I was
doing in Paris. I'm just basically
putting out anything that might be a
good video idea inside this doc. But
importantly, it has a calendar on top of
it. And in notion, you can go from
calendar view or even item view. And
item view, I can basically go and have
the same kind of table format. What was
the name of the item? What date did I
want to publish it? Is it a video? Is it
an ad? What's the status? Edit, record,
who's the editor? This is how I used to
manage all my content. We do this in a
sauna now, which we'll get to in a bit.
But that combination of list and
calendar takes you from no organization
to some organization. There's way more
robust stuff there. But if you are
struggling to put that together in a
basic way, this is the best entry level
and I find where you basically have all
your ideas in one place and you can
assign your ideas to a place on the
calendar. And again, if you want to put
this um together, you would open up a
new doc, you can just add all your text.
Then if you have a table, turn that
table into a database and you have all
these types of columns underneath a
database. You are functioning inside
notion for something like this related.
People are always asking, "How do you
capture content?" If you're doing vlogs
or you want to be organized or you're
traveling, what's an effective way to
capture content? I want to talk about
content folders. Just a simple structure
you can have on your phone for when you
do this. So, two ways to do it. First,
if you are traveling a lot, setting up
an album when you travel. If you're
really organized, you can do sub albums.
I tend to do people, places, and things
cuz it's really easy for me to find, but
often times I'll just do one album for
the place. And then the other key
workflow hack is to heart or favorite
anything that could be a hook. Like any
awesome shot that you have, hit it with
the heart and then you have an easy
access to all of those on your phone
whenever you need like that banger hook
shot. But the flow that I have when I'm
not traveling, just my day-to-day is I
literally have a folder for me, folder
for people, places, and things. Those
are four folders on my iPhone. So I know
things are easy to find. So whenever
I've shot for a day, if I'm just in an
Uber or whatever it is, I will organize
that footage. So, I will say basically I
will make sure all of the videos that
I'm in go in one place cuz typically
that's actually something I'm hunting
down for carousels or B-roll for
whatever things. I shoot a lot of
packaging and stuff and food [snorts]
and stuff like that. Put it all in one
place. Easy to find. Place is another
good one if you're trying to get
establishing shots or like visuals or
facads. Put it all in one place. And
then people. If I'm with other people or
I'm shooting individuals, all that goes
in one place. So, when I'm getting
videos of any kind, I can easily know if
okay, I can grab more footage of me. Am
I trying to find that packaging? I need
a quick shot of a China trip. It's all
there. That's another one where if your
phone is disorganized, you're trying to
find footage, you're doing lots of
edits, it's a lifesaver. Today's video
is in partnership with Zero, who are a
perfect fit for what we're talking
about. Zero provides accounting, tax
calculation, and invoices, payment
acceptance. Then in Australia, New
Zealand, and the UK, they even offer
payroll. Built for small businesses,
perfect for freelancers and creative
agencies. It's helpful to businesses of
all kinds. Zero helps you organize all
your financial operations from invoices
to accounting to tax in one place. If I
can recommend one thing if you're
building a creative business is you want
to start with systems you can grow into
as your business scales. You don't want
to have 10 different platforms for 10
different things. A few of my favorite
features are that you can connect and
import transactions from your banks,
track inventory levels, collaborate with
unlimited users, and you have an
accounting dashboard for a real-time
view of your business performance. Being
able to handle invoicing, payroll, and
accounting all in one place that you
simply use more of as you need it is
going to give you a lot of relief. And
Zero unlocks that supercharged feeling
that as you grow, we've got an
all-in-one platform to help you make
complex tasks simple. So, if you want to
stop piecing together your business
finances in the new year, you can get
90% off for 6 months using the link in
the description. And thank you so much
to Zero for partnering on this video.
But getting more tactical, if you have
clients or if you work at a job, the
weekly update is something I did all
through my professional career because a
boss asked for it and I just kept it
going. but will save you so much
heartache, especially if you do
freelance or client work. So, what do I
mean by this? At the end of every week,
you send out a simple email. It says,
"Too long, didn't read. Here's like two
or three highlights of this week." You
pull from the below, which is what got
accomplished this week. So, just a
checklist. We these are the things that
happened. This is what's going to happen
next week. What the plan looks like. And
then blockers, anything that's holding
you back from achieving a goal or
anything that didn't go as expected so
that people know and if there's
something that needs to be resolved,
it's being escalated. So you've
identified it, you've pulled it out. I
still haven't received that doc. Jenny
still hasn't gotten this or that. So you
can very practically call out where
things are. So then whoever client you
have knows what you've done, knows what
their expectation is of you next week,
knows if they or their team or anything
else is blocking you from getting the
things they have done and can adjust
from it. And if you follow this pretty
simple structure, you are going to have
way less issues with clients, people
being mad about this or that. And it
doesn't take long. And if you are
managing a team, this is a great thing
to ask for from them because then you
have a view of what everyone is looking
at and what everyone's doing and what
they're doing next and where they're
held up. The blocker section is really
important. You are able to compile those
things together in terms of what your
team did to then present to a client or
then present to an executive team and
you're beginning to level all of that
up. And this ties in this idea of a team
tracker. So this is one of the tracker I
have for carousels where basically it
has a process dock up top has another
database down here with a name who on
the team is the designer what's the
status what's the due date what's the
link for the final if you are working
with multiple people in any freelance
scenario as a team in a small agency as
a team at a company as a team on a shoot
if all the things that people are
supposed to do are tracked in one
database if they all have dates and
people assigned to them and they're
getting checked off you can easily look
at you can even autogenerate reports
with stuff like notation Notion AI will
just give you a summary of this of
what's gotten done, what remains, who's
assigned to what. At one of my previous
jobs, we managed a pretty big creative
team. We had four graphic designers. We
had three people on the video team. And
it was a very assetbased. What asset are
you doing for who? There's tons of
assets coming in and out. All the people
around us were complaining. They weren't
getting their assets fast enough. When I
came in to manage that team, one of the
first things I did was put something
like this into place where we actually
had a form on the front end where people
could request assets. The managers of
the team would then review those and
assign them to individuals. Then a date
would get added, the person that
requested it, had visibility on what the
date looked like. We did all this in
ClickUp, and then you could literally
see what the queue looks like, how many
were in front of it. We could review how
many assets people were getting done
each week, are these requests tedious,
was there already an existing asset that
was that was done. Does one person have
more bandwidth than the others? If new
requests come in, we're logging it all
one place. And importantly, I could go
back to the sales team or the product
team or people requesting it and being
like, "Hey, there's 21 assets done this
week, 11 for your team, seven for your
team. We have these many in the queue.
would you like to rep prioritize any of
these ones remaining and all of a sudden
everyone feels better about that
process? But it starts again with just a
simple database like this with the
people you're working on for some
accountability. And that relates to the
idea of a process doc. So if you ever
want to hire people or have people help
you to do stuff, whether that's video
editing you want done for you, writing,
social media posting, whatever, most
people assume, oh, I'm just going to
hire this person. They're going to do it
all for me. But the more you have
process in place, the better off it's
going to go to actually bring them into
your org. So the simplest way to look at
process because everyone gets a little
turned off by that word is for every
single thing that you want someone else
to work on there is a document in that
document there is a loom just a video
screen share showing what you do. So for
instance how you log into this or the
different walking through whatever board
you're showing just give people video
documentation doesn't have to be fancy
or greatl looking is really helpful so
they can watch and that's step-by-step
breakdown. You can take that loom,
transcribe it, put it into chat GBT, and
it will give you a step-by-step
breakdown that you can review. But for
anything, even from those like that
carousel example I showed, those
carousels, the first slide is very
specific. The core text needs to fit
within the square in the middle. I need
to have a photo inside each of those
needs to be readable with a size on the
explore page. So having a checklist for
that where people have to say, is is
this in the middle? Is orange in the
photo? Is it readable with a small size
on the explore page? Same thing on the
back end. We have two variants for each
one. One is a mini chat with a comment.
One is just a go find whatever
deliverable we have in a BIOS. We have
two variants of all those. That's in the
doc. We always do two variants. And then
we have a Figma board of existing assets
that we have. And so being able to have
a loom and walk through what that looks
like, show examples so people can look
through it visually. They have a
checklist of all those steps. That
becomes a process doc. So anytime a new
designer comes on, we can add that into
it. The last step on there, if you're
hiring multiple roles, you begin to add
FAQ on the bottom. What comes up every
time when you're onboarding, what are
the issues we hit? You add it to the
process dock. So whenever someone new
comes in, you're beginning to have to
handle less of those same repetitive
questions. So anyone who has scaled an
agency, has scaled freelance work, has
worked on a lot of shoots, has brought
on remote help, has begun to do that
kind of process. It's literally just a
folder inside your drive or your air or
inside your notion where you basically
have these for all of the things that
people are going to do to help you. They
do not take long to set up. It will save
you tons of time on the back end. And so
if your goal this year is I'm going to
get help or I've been trying to have
YouTube editors or whoever and it hasn't
worked out, it's usually not the editor.
It's usually that you don't have enough
process and documentation in place. So
this is a key thing to wrap your head
around that will really help. And so
those have all been really tactical
database driven stuff. And that's not
all the ways that you can get your
creative life together. One that is
still the best use for stuff like this,
this best promotional tool for creatives
is signature series for content. So if
you're looking at how do I improve my
content this year? How do I have a real
plan? It's all around what is the most
effective thing I've done. How do I
serialize it? So, for those of you that
know me, you know I have this ser
series, product versus brand. I review
different products as a signature series
that lots of people know me for. I want
to shout out David. He's in Cut 30 right
now. I was crushing it before he came in
in Cut 32 and he has a signature series
where basically brand building lessons
like behind the brand and he's done
Gentle Monster. He's done Beams, but he
sits down. He has a very similar style
each time and he walks through in a
similar visual way and a similar
structural way. the stories behind some
of these brands and in particular their
founders. He taps in there. It's a
little different than everybody else,
but he's kind of found his signature
series. You can see him going from
talking about all these different things
to, oh, I found my thing. And so, if you
are doing anything this year, is
thinking about from my signature,
whether it's something in my portfolio
or it's a content piece I'm making. If I
was only to make one thing a week or one
thing a month, how can I have that
signature that unique thing to me and
then actually act on it? And then if you
are working on social media for yourself
or for a brand, etc. A content pillar
system is the system that I teach all
the time. It's what I work with brands
on. It's what we teach inside Cut 30 for
individuals. Instituting a pillar system
will get you good. What do I mean by a
pillar? If you don't know, pillar is a
concept. Talking about food, I'm talking
about my portfolio videos, design,
whatever. Plus one or two formats.
Carousels, green screen, vlogs, videos.
Every good creative who's online has
three to five pillars at any given time.
Same thing with brands. They have three
to five types of content. We do
carousels documenting our journey. We do
product reels that are art director
whatever it is they have three to five
things but how you get good at it how
you can basically make the plunge this
year to be excellent at this is measure
that pillar system so it's a spreadsheet
that actually breaks down the views of
each pillar each month their average
views per the saves the shares the reach
to new audiences versus old audiences
and the hook rate I will put my pillars
doc down inside the description here so
you can see it if you measure those
every month and you look at if it's
going up or down then you decide are we
going to improve our hooks are we going
to change the production value or are we
going to double down and swap this video
some other way every month to see how
you improve it? Don't change anything if
it's steady state or remove it. You
basically have a decision matrix
wherever every month you choose one of
those improvements, you choose to keep
it the same or you choose to put it away
and replace it with a new pillar. Within
3 months of being like, we're going to
change hooks. We're going to evaluate it
the entire next month. Your social media
will be in extreme better shape. This
works for any brand, too. And it'll be
defensible. This wasn't working, so we
changed this thing. This was working, so
we kept going. This wasn't working, so
we swapped it out. And putting a
framework like that in place for you or
the brand you work for for the year is a
surefire way to actually quantify things
and get to improvement that I cannot
recommend more. There's a ton more that
I want to walk through, but I know in
these more like technical videos that
often some of this can be overwhelming.
Um, like I mentioned before, I will put
the content pillars [music] kind of
spreadsheet template I have down below.
So, if you're looking to do something
like that, you can have an example for
it. But overall, I cannot encourage you
enough to just pick one thing, one thing
here. Similar to my start of the year
video, concentrate on adding one thing
to your life. I'm going to organize the
footage I shoot in my iPhone. I'm going
to put together the reference database I
have. Oh, I'm working with a small team
and we're chaotic. I'm going to put the
tracker together and I'm going to stay
on people to do it. Facilitating that
stuff, acting on it will have a major
impact [music] in your creative life and
I cannot recommend it enough. I
appreciate y'all so much for watching.
Thank you again.