all right in this video we are going to
walk through 50 content Styles you can
use for your brand every single one of
these will be an example video all of
them will be linked in the notion doc
that you will see below as many of you
know I work with a program called cut 30
where we train Brands and creators so I
am constantly pulling references we've
trained over 1,200 now and we are in
that constant mode of what are good
references what are good things people
can create as well as all the content
I've done for Brands I've worked on as
it a marketing consultant or CMO the
number one question we get asked is what
do I actually make content about how do
I make content for my service or about
my product or oh that's fashion content
how I make content for my consumer
package good my makeup brand whatever it
is we're going to cover the Gambit here
it's going to be Instagram content and
it's going to be Tik Tok content and by
the end of this you're not only going to
have just a wealth of examples you're
going to be able to go back to anytime
that you're stuck making content you're
going to begin to think through how you
can understand repurpose content Styles
and help make them your own regardless
of what you sell I'm stoked for this
video I've just pulled together all
these examples to have a new set going
into the new year so they're fresh in my
mind I'm excited to share it with yall
let's lock in so this first video is
from Joe diver who's an awesome Creator
he's more of a designer but it's an
excellent example of something I think a
lot of brands have in their toolkit that
they don't utilize enough and that is
all of your existing photo assets that
can get made into content this is a less
useful strategy on Tik Tok but it's
great on Instagram so he has about a
10-second video here has at least 40
shots inside of it and you'll notice a
couple tricks about what they're doing
to roll through all this content the
first is there's two visual Styles in
here one is there's black flashes at the
beginning and there's blur towards the
end the third is there is a graphic
overlay in the but this video Moves
super fast it isn't just photos moving
all at the same speed there's also those
effects brought in it has that visual
capture of the design element on top of
it and this is an excellent way to go
take photos you have and then share them
in a design forward and compelling way
the core thing I want you to take away
here is you have these old photo shoots
is that you can't just put them up and
expect them to people to watch them in a
carousel or put them in a video and have
them each last a second and they go
thing the thing it needs to have that
visual Vision that moves at the speed of
reels and reels move fast one of the
Marquee lessons I teach people all the
time in Cut 30 is that no shot unless it
has a reason to should ever be longer
than 1 second and more likely it's
probably better at half a second and
with still photos like this this could
be even be moving at like 0.1 or2 second
each now this second video style that I
love is a luggage video not talking
about TSA bins or any of these videos
you've seen all the time but this is the
ability to take your product in context
with other products this is a great
video whether you have a makeup brand a
food brand clothing whatever it is if
someone is packing it you can put it in
context and context is a great marketing
tool your brand becomes What It's
associated so if you're able to surround
it with either expensive items or
interesting items or items that tell a
story you're beginning to capture some
Essence in your marketing so you'll
notice this is one shot up front with
the title on it my winter Essentials and
then it flashes in on all four corners
of the luggage and then two side shots
so I believe it's six shots plus the
intro total and you notice all of these
last for about 1 second 7c video back to
my rule before and so I would highly
recommend staging something like this
you can have some luggage you can have a
cool bag telling a story with it this is
equally as fun with obviously this is
like nice luxury things that tell that
kind of story as it would be for
something that's really similar to your
Niche or if they're like exceptionally
weird or interesting things or if
there's a contrast among them those are
things that help catch people's
attention so another photo video this is
one is based on color they're using
pantones color of the year we'll get to
my opinions on that a different time but
the idea is if you have a color theme
from a lot of your photos or existing
collections or whatever it is you can
put that in the middle put that panone
graphic in the middle as an anchor
graphic you notice it's a very similar
style to what the Joe diver video did
it's anchor by some kind of visual in
between it moves super fast but the
technique that they're using here which
is worth your editor taking into account
or calling out is they're roughly
framing everything with that person in
the middle they're all Runway shots or
Runway adjacent if you have for your
brand you've always shot a lot of model
shots where they're in the middle or you
shot a lot of tablescapes if you're a
food brand or a lot of shots of your
store in front inside different whatever
uh different seasons you can then Stitch
all those together to feel like it
almost has that like intrinsic through
line in the motion that helps make a
video like this really compelling versus
just a really fast slideshow but that
color theme is great I would also
consider do that same thing like get
this little panone mockup for whatever
like one of your core colors is and run
a bunch of 5-second video clips behind
it for 10 seconds as well can be equally
as impactful as a Content idea and we're
going to get to all kinds in this don't
worry if it hasn't nothing's pecu your
press yet so this video is a POV Story
video my type of going out and this is
obviously a female Centric video she's
showing off-road products you could do
this with any demographic or look or
feel regardless of age or background but
you notice the shots are well lit they
all have a similar lighting to them
they're a bunch darker than any other
ones they all have that nice kind of
bright feel to it similar color palette
on it and just a light story I want you
to think about what your POV story would
be but A good rule for this this is
probably a 10-second video they're all5
second shots so again you need 20 shots
that tie together from a color
standpoint and a light story standpoint
that can show a day for one of your
customers or show an experience of any
kind is in great easy style and the more
relatable or the more aspirational it is
the better it's going to this next one
is a BTS compilations this is behind the
scenes of a photo shoot they're doing so
I highly recommend if you are doing any
kind of content even if you're in a
white background Studio or you're
shooting content in your house or at
your store or whatever it is the behind
the scenes cont content is more valuable
than the content itself in many cases
cuz you can make more compelling
interesting reels with it so obviously
this is a pretty cool photo shoot fridge
escaping you got a model but even just
having those one or two behind the- scen
shots and then shooting all this in this
vintage feel I think they use an effect
on this but it's also really cool if you
use like a PIX Pro or like one of these
like $80 cameras to shoot it I'm
obsessed with this idea I'll probably do
a different video on it of things that
can make your content smash for under
$100 is like a huge theme at for Brands
right cuz eventually you just need more
things to help your content work and you
start to realize you know what it's
worth it for me to spend money to have
those things and like a little cheap
camera to be able to shoot stuff like
this and have this kind of vintage feel
is a good one of those again all this is
a compilation of those shots some move
fast some move slow showing that
something's happening in action it's a
good complement to the actual shoot
results there a no-brain or if you do
any kind of shoots to capture and the
core thing I would recommend is to have
a plan for this when you go to do your
shoots so most people say we're going to
capture a bunch of BTS they don't
actually do anything with it I would
think this through before you do it so
we're going to do a video like this
which means we need two shots of people
actually shooting we need a couple
closeups we're going to get this digital
camera the more you prepare for this
kind of stuff the more you actually make
something a fun one for the more graphic
design oriented people in here is you'll
see the core of this video is that
whenever they put the mouse over the
title comes up and this is something
that is very easily doable uh in any
kind of design software screen recording
if you have like some design background
you want to spend some time Googling you
can easily figure this out what I like
about this is this also works for like
any genre right whether you're selling
wine or acupuncture or massage or
whatever it is microphones Electronics
assemble some things together that are
interesting and tell a story either it
could be what's in your bag like this or
it could be what's on my table or it
could be like what's in our office
what's in our cubicle whatever any
conceptual idea this is the key takeaway
inside the stuff is anytime you look at
one of these ideas you're like oh I
can't do that I'm not a fashion brand
I'm not a fashion influencer what
context shift can you give it so the
context shift if you're an acupuncture
Studio of you laying out all your
needles and supplies before you go do
the acupuncture or if you are a
electronics brand your everything that's
being prepared for a photo shoot or a
makeup counter or a shower or whatever
it is you have the ability to shift that
and then this is just a fun way to go
call those things out with the mouse
that people want to follow because they
things like this to have a sequence
people like to watch because it comes to
a natural end for all my Builders and
creators out there I love this one 14
months and eight samples later so call
it the lengthier production process have
a little catchy video clip whether it's
of you like he does there or whatever
you have to push it through that's like
a two second hook clip and the rest of
these are all about 0.5 seconds just
showing the product that's all is they
just have a couple like five product
shots in here and so obviously he has a
visually compelling pretty cool product
that people are going to like and be
into hopefully you have done the same
thing and invested in your product ID
and look and feel uh and are proud of it
but again these you're just well-lit
shots on concrete you're not doing
anything special all these videos you're
going to see here I'm I'm emphasizing
low production videos for the majority
of now we're to get into some explainers
CU I really like to uh encourage people
to talk on camera about their brands uh
this is actually from a cut 30 student
what's wrong with our product the hook
is our product doesn't work and then
they go into all the things that that
they're doing actually make this amazing
product you take a misconception and you
turn it into a Storyteller what I like
about this and why I encourage people to
do when they're going and telling their
story is certain people can sit down in
front of a camera and just Yap and have
it be successful if you do that you're
probably really funny really charismatic
have a wealth of knowledge or
entertaining in some way or you're
really hot if you aren't all of those
things because most of us aren't you
need some perspective he is walking on a
treadmill he's got some Vlog footage
this is a great thing to do is just put
Vlog footage you can obviously fill it
with contrived stuff in there and they
have a couple shots where they of there
of them talking all have a different
angle like the guy opening the fridge
the guy talking on the treadmill looking
up adding some action or some interest
those shots where you're talking does
not take a ton of time it makes a huge
difference in the video remember you
will have the links to all of these so
you can go through and embrace come down
it's a probably a good time to take a
little break and give you a little
exercise right so one thing um I always
encourage I actually do constantly is
what's called copy work so for instance
on that video if you wanted to say I'm
going to make a version like that for my
brand you would actually write it out
you'd say cool this is a 31 second video
first two seconds treadmill walking shot
talking the next three shots are all one
second and it's all b-roll and then the
third shot they have a zoom in of the
product the four shot someone's talking
again whatever you basically write out
shot by shot the type of shot it is is
someone talking is it a Vlogs at a macro
shot whatever it is and the length that
it is and you begin to piece together
your story the things you have in a way
that follows it as close as possible and
you can shift it around obviously you
want it to be unique but you are taking
an existing working template and running
with it and this is the most effective
way to learn social media and then when
you're good at it you begin to have a
knack for it you can begin coming up
with your own formats and IDE all right
so I want to call out some process I'm
I'm doing when i'm researching some of
this stuff as well and how I tie some of
this strategy together into like overall
brand strategy so bear with me for for a
second this segment is sponsored by
particle I shouted particle out in my
market research video a while back it
wasn't like a sponsored video or
anything uh and they agreed to come on
and sponsor this one so I'm going to
break down a little bit of how it works
and how I use it which is actually like
Ultra valuable and I use constantly so
when you actually go to a page for a
brand in particle you'll see you'll see
these these big old sales numbers you'll
see the bestselling products you can
break down all this info about how much
things sell what are the most popular
products what's the rate of discount Etc
but for market research it's not just
about product sales as useful as this is
and one awesome way that I use this is
you go to these tabs there's an events
tab which is when they launched products
and there's an assets tab this becomes
really useful so the assets tab shows me
like time a day what's happening posts
are happening so I can actually see what
social posts happened on what day and
Link right to them and same thing I can
actually separate that out I can see if
they send an email and what the email is
like when their emails are I can see a
homepage screenshot of their homepage
change go back and look at campaigns at
different dates and times and this is
like a super super useful toolkit to be
able to go and actually plan say okay
when someone did this launch I can go
back and look at events and be like hey
when they launched X product okay and
that's go back they did X posts and X
emails and going and going through that
in your Niche is like a very useful
thing to work and same thing they have
this marketing asset library that I use
all the time where it'll actually show
you different like discount emails
restock alerts like companies of certain
types there's all these different
filters that you can go through okay
here's a bunch of just food and beverage
emails I can be using as an example like
pulling ideas from and pull that by
discount so I can look at all the emails
that are actually promoting a discount
what do the sales look like how big is
the discount what am I competing with
and they have the same thing with assets
of different types I can go look at
homepages again so going back and saying
here's all the homepages that have a
discount right now that's the filter
that I have on here and then same thing
go through your vertical for Instagram
and for Tik Tok and so with Instagram in
particular to search is so bad this is
actually really useful Tik Tok has
decent search you can kind of do it
there but if you're like hey I just want
to look at this is all the post from
today in food and bed
um and so you noce there's like a reason
I'm calling this out as a tool is
because this is like actually very
useful and it's aggregating things that
not a lot of people are able to research
and people always are asking me like how
do you stay so up toate on X or Y what
people are doing and it's because
literally I can go scroll through like
with dedicated time on things like this
like to see what's happening also I'll
be linking particle down below too so
you can go try out uh try out their
product tons and tons and tons of brands
in here really useful data point uh and
big shout out to them for sponsoring
this video so recipe videos recipe
videos are pretty obviously like super
saturated and hard to crack through on
so I'm going to break down why I like
this one and what makes it particularly
interesting so speed and light are
crucial in this these shots move they
are zipping they are like 0.1 second to
3 second I don't think there's longer
than a 3 second shot in the entire video
speed moves so that's number one number
two it's light there's great light in
all of this I would just recommend 4
p.m. to 5:30 p.m. near a window you're
going to get good light whether it's
your house or your office plan your
shoot times accordingly and the third
thing is when we look at the hook so POV
making the most viral matcho recipe skin
loving and high protein banana pudding
matcha so skin loving and high protein
this is key here so it's not just we're
making this recipe make banana bread
with me they are giving two reasons two
pain points for the user being like hey
I I not only like banana bread oh I'm
interested in high protein they're
connecting the dots I'd recommend you do
that too this goes for any food beverage
if you have a beverage of any kind or a
supp of any kind that you're selling or
marketing or food you need to be doing
recipe content some of the best recipe
content out there the three things that
are going to help that content succeed
are going to be the lighting that you
have in it the speed with which it moves
and if you can include that value
proposition reason for someone to want
to consume that content and ideally two
reasons I like the way they did here
with another fun one scanner video
they're literally scanning their product
I like this cuz it's a a WTF Hook is
what we call them where you're like what
is happening why are they doing that why
are they putting this boot in the
scanner and so that's always a good way
to get people to stop the scroll a
scanner is an easy thing most people
have access to or can buy yeah these
photos are like cool but they're not
like amazing um but it's just a fun
Concept in Hook it's very product
forward that you could do with pretty
much any product in fact the weirder it
is the more funny it is if if you have
like an oversized product you're trying
to scan and the photos didn't come out
that's like almost funnier and more
interesting than actually having it come
out well so I'll call out that one CU
like I wouldn't want to lose the like
the WTF factor or the OB ball factor is
like something that people always
underestimate with brand content like
just if you're like oh this doesn't work
for my brand and you're like okay well
it does it does it not work in a way
that's like funny or catchy that's
interesting to me the different font
video this is great if you have multiple
people on your social team or you have
friends or whatever it is obviously
they're playing into the racial
combination here too that's also kind of
a win you can do this in any way you
want could be people in outfits
different looks no tattoos versus
tattoos young versus old types of dogs
whatever it is but this idea that same
girl different font and this can be
again anything same guy different font
same cat different whatever it is how do
you find a couple things where again you
start with the same shot and you kind of
alternate things back and forth and so
you could have your this could be a pro
a video for the earrings could be a
video for the wine there's like 20
things that could be featured in this
video but they're giving it context
around it people are going to continue
watching to watch what comes next and
all it needs is for you to get a bunch
of contrasting items you probably have
around your house or office another
great Builder one I couldn't find the
blank so I made the blank is a this
gives you a reason to talk through your
product which is a great I think I love
in videos anytime you can give a reason
as to why your stuff exists um this is
one that I put on the board for stuff
I'm doing for my brand I'm be doing some
videos like this about the heavyweight
te's that I have but that hook shot is
important where she rolls out all the
fabric swatches you have to have
something compelling that you can do
there that tells the story that's
interesting to people visually and then
you ideally if you're solving a problem
people actually have like oh I can't
find a you know zip up that is cropped
in that way or whatever it is and you're
able to hit it I know this is she's a
controversial Creator or whatever cuz
they stole somebody's idea but like so
I've go and don't worry we've done a lot
of Instagram to start we get to Tik Tok
here in a minute uh because of the
potentially pending Tik Tok ban I've
been more Instagram forward recently on
the things I've been pulling as content
and completely unrelated but that
shorter faster kind of snappier content
and probably end up doing pretty good on
Snapchat people move that way as well
this is the printer video same thing as
the scanner video but take the photos
you have of your products if you have
good photos and run them through a
printer like this this uh zoom in
probably happened in post this is one of
those things where if your printer
doesn't actually move that fast you may
need to do some behind the scenes
Wizardry in terms of how you crop the
edits of this um this is a super easy
straightforward again reuse of your
existing photos I cannot recommend if
you have enough enough you have any
social ideas or a budget just doing
stuff like that the legends that get
saws I'm going to shout out my friends
at the dark room you know they work on a
bunch of my design they did the saws
brand ID I believe so big shout out to
dark room you're looking for an
excellent brand ID holler at their
agency they are telling their story I'm
going to restart this we're a small gen
Z team that got our product in Target in
less than a year so what the core of
this video is celebrate a milestone and
Milestones that you might think are
normal are exciting to other people like
getting getting to Target is obviously
exciting worthwhile but even if I'm
getting into my first retail store we
got our first inbound inquiry from a
wholesaler I mean there's a there's a
whole bunch of like we passed our
thousandth order it doesn't necessarily
have to be like super critical to you
like or like something where you're like
oh I'm ecstatic about it it just has to
be the hook for a video Target's
obviously a great one any retail thing
is a great one but really you start off
with this exciting thing and you break
down the story of how you did it this is
a good one using Target is the hook and
they just literally run you back through
their story as a vlog using the same
caption Tik Tok caption style everyone
else does just roll back through that
origin story and this is a good thing
like I also wouldn't be afraid to do
this multiple times people will run
their origin story video once and like
tell their story in a carousel or video
whatever then not run it back like run
run your origin story again and again
this thing I wish I had a good origin
story video as a creator for in short
form because I get new followers all the
time right like I don't know how how if
youall are familiar with like the short
form game when you get to a certain size
but I have you know 400k on Instagram I
lose 7,000 followers a month unfollows
just natural churn and I'm gaining uh
past that all the time but people 7,000
just unsubscribe so all there's so
there's a constant new 7,000 kind of
coming in plus anyone I'm gaining on
that and those have no idea on that
story who be retelling res sharing your
story is a key key idea man I thought I
was going to get through all 50 in this
in a reasonable time I'm definitely
spending more than a minute on these
we'll see how many we get through we
have to part two this and have an
inaccurate title we'll see but we're
going to keep rolling all right another
photo shoot behind the scenes there's
100 examples of this online but
literally it's like when the inso is
blank or when you use a whatever I gave
this type of camera to my friends at X
and then just show the the photos and
again this is about a 3 seconds each
roughly in there but literally you're
just giving the info giving the results
you should be doing this for every
single photo shoot you do and obviously
this is like not even like I think he's
shoot it's like him and a contacts in
the RV you know if you have some decent
camera equipment or a decent
photographer on your team you could be
like doing stuff like this every day
with a concept you can see all my AR
Direction videos for ideas on that that
video is the kind of thing where I wish
I had a workflow to really Hammer that
personally cuz I would be doing that all
the time all right so this next one is a
print out video you will see they made a
poster back to my idea what are things
you can do that are sub $100 that will
help your brand go and they're unveiling
the poster of the thing that they are
promoting and and what makes this video
work and I recommend you doing there is
the crazier the places are the better it
goes there's also some color matching
they're doing on that first Subway scene
that makes it like a good hook shot like
the blue and the blue I think is a
really nice touch that's the kind of you
know little things to think of that are
intentional um but really like the
crazier the shots are then the better
this is going to go this is a this is a
great little winning video to add uh to
Your Arsenal then we have a BTS
compilation video I'm going to restart
this with the music on because it's it's
worth
it said you belong the streets but the
streets belong to me it's life home to
me the it's like
home I tied your pass for up you get the
idea again this is literally has what do
you do for living I would take this
audio go to JW Studios use the audio
it's how audios work on on reals and
then just go to the compilation of like
what do you all do for a living right
and then this is all. 3 to 0.5 second
shots of the coolest stuff of the their
business that they're working on you
should run that guys i' probably seen
this before too a lot of brands have
asked this you need to do the framing
and stuff right um but another one to be
able to show off your photo shoots and a
real format is the ability to say cool
they have that folder that folder gets
clicked to open this I'm seeing again
people kind of half ask with the way
they do desktop and stuff you have to
kind of get that graphic right at the
beginning or it's not going to work but
it's just a good winner one of my
favorite ones this video is insane this
is an unhanged explainer and this is
like a very high production thought out
just took a minute and a ton of
personality if you have anyone in
personality on your team or you have it
do an explainer of your product and make
it unhinged make it like just completely
out there in whatever way it is weird
humor weird application what can you do
and twist it to be surreal another one I
love is a camera scenario video giving a
film camera to guess at the clubs they
give a film camera and they come out and
they show all the film results same
thing you'll see this common theme like
setup results it's a way to keep people
watching it's a really common social
format great way to think about
everything you do and this is I contrive
they didn't just give it this is like
people that they know right and so this
is something you could do like whether
it's in your your coffee shop or an
event or in a party or whatever it's an
easy easy format and a fun format to
have where it had takes you that just
the costes is that camera one of my
absolute favorites we're into Tik Tok
now obviously is what would you make for
X now this is another one where you can
do this for any business what type of
massage would you give to blank what SEO
offering would you have for whatever it
goes for B2B it goes for whatever what
watch would you choose for blank and so
they're asking what drink would you make
for Lana Del right and I think the
funnier and more interesting and more
relevant person you choose and then the
more tied into it your answer is
probably the better but this is a great
just conceptual thing that you can do
have one of your team members interview
another and then just give that really
that little show breakdown and this is
having a humorous angle is always good
but also a dead serious angle can work
as well this is one I love from away
this is a comment Awards video so
basically a lot of people are asking for
a feature or whatever it is they
actually show them like screenshotting
it printing it out and actually sending
their customers who commented about this
thing like a result and this thing you
even for a small brand even this is two
people it's like this person's been
commenting on 155 of our videos or this
person's been asking for a blue version
of the w l forever and you just shows
you following up on that and like
sending it to them or whatever it is
it's just a really interactive way to
also get people to like man I should
really be interacting with their social
media love this one I'm about to do this
one
too another photo video that's
significantly harder to do I love this
the photo going into video it's all
about the placement of the product right
and people will do this by putting a
grid or some tape on their camera when
they go shoot the stuff it's the easiest
way to do it so you can then see how
everything's framed that's your pro tip
for me here uh but the photo going into
video and then the speed with which it's
executed is kind of the winner there
super straightforward one the more
people should be doing and again if you
have multiple of any product just walk
up with them and then take a shot and
just um alternate through it right same
person standing in the same place
wearing whatever it is say you had eight
beverages hand in the same place the
beverage switches uh or it just rolls
through it real quick super fast video
this is a good one POV you designed is a
great one and just look it has this long
hook here POV you designed a dress that
has floaty fabric over the tummy that
sits fitted around the waist and bust
because you want to feel sexy even when
bloated maybe I shouldn't have read that
one out loud not really a good one for
my brand voice but you get the point you
have a POV you designed X whatever
problem you're solving for your user you
put it on there while you're actually
just showing the product they do a great
job with this and you have solved any
problem I made a drink that does X and Y
I have a t-shirt that fits like blank
and blank if you don't have any actual
user differentiation for your product
then you have some other things this
aesthetic it's a great one just take
your camera roll and run with it over
some kind of good music tied to the
aesthetic of your brand this is a brand
that's I think very soccer driven so
they kind of have that natural relation
to it plus a couple luxury items this
isn't like you know it's funny you might
look at this like most people will look
at this and be like like this isn't
particularly well done it's not
particularly like interesting photos
it's like verging on corny doesn't
matter their demographic is younger
people who think it's great and the
demographic matters not what you think
and so proportion things towards your
demographic another good one to use your
photos like print out the photo books
and literally just just turning the
pages like that is a is a super uh super
fun one obviously they have a bit of a
cult following already this is I think a
good one for a more established brand
this PowerPoint response thing is great
I think more brands should do this she's
the main one I've seen do this but
she'll like Stitch something like
basically your approach to be if you
want to like Stitch a popular video or
respond to a popular thing and then make
some like slides or some memes like
talking about like the your issue with
it or like why something's wrong about
it or like tying in how their problem
could be solved by your service or
whatever it is like with a little deck
like this is a super fun framework this
common complaint format is great I don't
like blank it's blank I would just hit
that stuff head on the modern era hit it
on social media some self awareness is
good and then show off how it's
different like this is actually a great
one look I think van CLE is is tacky um
but then I watch this video and I go
that's actually really nice and so they
are getting the point across influencers
is doing this obviously instead of the
brand but uh this is a very strong way
to approach any issue you're having with
your brand and then just showing the
result visually and sparking that
convers those negative hooks like our
worst products this another one here
worst sellers in our store may 2024 this
Brand's like know known for this if you
have a big catalac big X like roll
through that and be like I don't know
why this is the worst seller but like it
is and talk through it here's why I
think it should sell or hey we should
throw this out or here's a mistake we
made just actually talk through the
results of like all that and why it is
is a is a great one like those like
little negative hooks where it's like oh
the I don't like blank it's tacky or the
worst things that happen in there or
like you know our whatever that first
product development one we had is like
great way to start stuff uh is a great
like hook option here people should use
so a storytelling Vlog with the team is
another great one where they give a
little context and they're hey we're
going to talk about the specialty
product that we're doing like hey it's
blank I'm a blank I'm the head chef at
whatever if you don't show a lot of
behind the scenes like jumping out with
something like this for once teally fun
then telling the story of a product um
this is this is someone who uh was in
Cut 30 and they've done a great job um
telling some stories around this I have
another example from them here shortly
too so this couple made their Lord of
the Rings chocolate come true this is
another one from that same brand same
people that are in Cut 30 and if you had
doing any custom orders or custom things
or just have interesting orders or
someone ordered 41 of our blank I had to
get down to the bottom of it telling
those little customer stories is awesome
and if you have any business that sells
custom things or does like client
projects or stuff like that like just
have that little story and just get walk
through in a vlog is is should be doing
more and if you don't have any ideas for
like go back through your go look at
your orders like the most of something
or order where like you're like what is
going on like Google that person or
email that person and be like hey just
curious why did you order like I had
someone to order 18 of my shoe bags the
other day I'm like all right cool I just
email them be like hey someone order you
know why what happen what was up there
hey you cool if I make a video about the
fact you did that and like you know I'll
send you some more and they'll probably
be cool so these are two that uh when I
was CMO gel Blaster these are ones that
we did POV storytelling so basically
you'll take a problem someone has what
do I do when I do blank it can be a
contri problem note that transition shot
there shout Leo who did this but POV
like so first- person view you see the
hands in there you see it happening like
oh you know what if my denim doesn't fit
right what if blank and blank like can I
actually drink one of these with X and
you show it from a your hands
perspective makes people feel like
they're solving their own problem it's a
really cool effect another one you've
probably seen this if you've SE all my
other kind of brand content videos my
absolute favorite another one I did
while I was a jail Blaster is tutorials
in action right so this is she's doing a
tutorial about something related to gel
blasters while she's in a gel Blaster
battle I also have done this when on the
surf brand I worked with we we do like
tutorials while they're actually on the
surfboard these people were like this
this whole content like are they going
to fall in the water there's like a
microphone like a whole thing uh it's
the say if you have any fitness
equipment you're doing the tutorial
while you're like running or power
cleaning or you doing whatever H
athletes do same thing with chefs
whatever it is any tutorial you do or
walkthrough you do if you do it while
you're actually engaged in the action
it's going to go 20 times more better
than if you're just walking through it
high recommended format little attention
hack there all right now we have a timed
challenge I'm using bodon as an example
this isn't a brand content this was like
a show and they obviously have a pretty
high production but it's just for the
concept walkr is can you get one person
to complete something within a set
amount of time some sort of challenge or
ideally get two people to compete
against it is an awesome thing to do
with branded content and as long as
they're in your product or related to
your product put an outfit together in
60 seconds how many pull-ups or burpees
can you complete in 60 seconds if you
have a good host someone yelling back
and forth or any like little jokes or
things you can add on top awesome format
you can repeat I would high like little
Challenge videos like that are really
fun how fast can you do an oil change
whatever it is and this one it's
probably the last I'll walk through in
here for the sake of time is problem
documentation midday squares does a
great job with this you do not need to
do it as high production as what they've
done here if you say we have an issue
with our business something was delayed
something whatever you have issues all
the time in your business actually talk
through it dramatize it the way a
reality show would they go back and tell
with the Vlog and you could again do it
half of the production of this you'll be
fine go actually tell through that story
of what happened make it a big dramatic
thing go back and tell story of how you
got there what you did to solve it and
then what the resolution was you're
giving people a complete story an
episode of reality television about your
brand what I love about this is do not
to be current you can go back two years
to like you know in 2021 our business
almost fell apart because blank and then
we walk through how we solved it like
right it can just you can look at it as
moments in time you can use so again in
the interest of time and also I think
I've edited a number of these out in in
post just to make sure that this flows
and isn't like the longest video of all
time there are 50 references like inside
this dock but that is just a whole bunch
of ideas of things you can do for your
brand that are not high budget they're
not super complicated that if you just
put a little thought and intention and
think about how you cross it into your
Niche that you're going to be able to do
some some wonders with I have that doc
Linked In the description here I
appreciate y'all watching hope you got
some great ideas out of this please like
subscribe share all the above let's go