This is the video about dark marketing
techniques to hack success, why people
seem to be doing better than you, and
the things that marketers don't talk
about, the software people don't know
about, and things that are in a gray
area that are questionably legal. I'm
making this video not so much to
encourage you to do these things, but so
that you understand what is out there,
why certain brands and marketers bend
the rules, and the complete extent of
what the landscape is and what we're all
up against. This will certainly be one
of the more interesting takes that we've
done. I'm excited to lock in. But first,
I'm going to talk about pixel email
retention. That might sound like a nerdy
phrase, but it is the some secret sauce
and one of the reasons you see a lot of
these brands scale massive email list.
We will start with retention.com. So,
what does retention.com do? Well, it's a
gray area. They basically based on who
comes to your website can retain emails
that come to it. Not people that opt in,
just people that show up. What people do
with services like retention and they
have a if you just Google them you will
see a bunch of competitors pop up is
they basically upload mass amounts of
emails for people that visit their site
but have never opted in into their email
marketing. Is this a violation of spam
laws? Highly likely. Is this something
that brands still do and mass is a
massive part of e-commerce marketing and
why some people have way more emails
than others? 100%. This is just one of
those things that marketers need to be
aware of that is a thing that is
happening out there that they are
competing against. And there are lots of
these tools for uncovering what a bunch
of this different data looks like. This
is one where people actually then put it
to work inside their funnels. Related to
that comes Import Yeti. You may have
heard me talk about this before, but if
you want to know anyone and who makes
their products, if it's imported to the
US and you know either the company name
or the holding company name or it's
imported through, you can find who
supplies them. So on import yeti.com,
you can go to Rare Beauty or whoever it
is and actually see, oh, they are
importing from this Italian
manufacturer, from this Chinese
manufacturer. It states the goods, you
know, what's a cosmetic versus what's a
soft good. This is something that I have
used extensively to find manufacturers.
You can get denim from the same people
that are making major brands in Morocco.
You can basically find out who these
folks are and then you have to get savvy
enough to then hunt them down because
what you'll notice is that most of these
aren't on Alibaba. They aren't easy to
find and there's a reason for it. A lot
of these good manufacturers are hidden
in plain sight without any websites, any
contact info. How I usually get around
this, giving it a pro tip, is I will
hire people on Upwork in those
countries. I will find someone in
Portugal, in Morocco, in whatever that
speaks the native language, give them
the company name, whatever info I can
find, address, and be like, "Get me a
meeting with these people." And that is
actually a tactic that's worked like 80%
of the time that I've run it, no matter
where it is around the world. We're
going to cheat code throughout this
video. Next comes cold outreach. If
you've ever gotten an email that you
didn't want to get or a DM you weren't
expecting, and it's just someone trying
to sell you a service, people do it
because it works. But how did they get
your email? How did they actually figure
all this out? I'm not ashamed of it.
When we were building our product
development agency years and years ago,
we did a absolute ton of cold outreach.
Part of building an agency, you can get
so much from marketing this or that, but
we would also just reach out to trade
show attendees that were within our
niche companies that just raised funds.
We were constantly in an email funnels
and call funnels around that. Before
that job, I actually worked in a leading
a outbound sales team, a glorified call
center where we literally ran sales loft
at the time. It's like an outreach
competitor. We were booking leads
through some of the software I'll talk
through before and we were dialing down
the list every single week round robin
as much as we can to set up meetings and
we built a massive pipeline. So I have
been in the f like in the exact belly of
the beast actually doing this is a way
to scale your company. It is way more
saturated now than it was then but still
works super well. And how do actually
people do it? What is the soft? So the
software everyone knew from a long time
was Zoom Info. Zoom info you pay a
couple thousand bucks or whatever it is
and you get X amount of leads and they
catalog everyone's email and phone
number in there. But now I want to shout
out the guys at Apollo. We're actually
some people that are from OG Money
Twitter if you are back in there. So
they have created like the perfect
system for this. Way better than Zoom
Info. Tons of phone numbers, tons of
emails for every executive. Don't know
how they get as many as they do, but you
have so much company info in there and
they've built like a full stack outreach
platform where there's like auto
dialing, AI meeting setup, email
outreach built in. It is like the
software for cold outreach. And so if
you want to figure out how are people
hitting all these folks up, where are
they getting my contact info? they are
getting it from Apollo. This is like the
least gray area of one of the things I
can I I'm going to list on this, but
this is a the way to brute force your
agency or your service into the world is
to run a funnel like that. Less, you
know, the lighter end of the scale here.
We have Mixmax. Mixmax is a tool I used
to use forever. There's a bunch of
similar tools out there. Yeswear and a
few others, but basically what this is
is it's Intel for autoresponse and and
mailmerge on Gmail. And so what does
that mean? What are those terms if you
haven't heard them? So mail merge is
when you can write an email, put in a
placeholder for a field, like a formula,
and then put in a list in a spreadsheet,
things to fill in that field. So you can
basically put a list of 50 emails, say,
"Hey, blank, I'm coming to talk to you
about X or Y because you're a decision
maker at Z." That's a terrible cold
email. Don't use that.
And then you can actually from having a
CSV with their first name, their company
name, you can then populate those emails
and then send them from your Gmail, like
one to one email. What's also nice about
services like Mixmax is it shows you who
opens your emails. So, you can actually
see who actually opened it, who actually
clicked it. That goes for your
day-to-day email, too. Great for the
co-workers or whoever it is that says
they haven't received it or the person
you sold says they haven't gotten the
invoice. You can actually see if they
have or not. It's a sneaky little
tactic. And also, it can do auto
follow-up. So, you say, "If someone
hasn't replied to this email in two
days, send this." And you can have all
these triggers and segments and snippets
and things like that, the auto repeat,
which are a super useful part of if you
are someone doing a bunch of outreach,
it makes you super human. These are
tools I still use to this day. The whole
theme of this video is cheat codes for
marketers. And in this next segment, I'm
going to walk through Particle, who
sponsored this video, who are an
excellent tool I use all the time to see
exactly inside what brands are doing.
So, if you go into the Particle
interface here, I'm going to bring up
Cole Buckton, just using this as an
example product. We'll walk through two
here today. I'm going to click over into
bestselling products, and this is going
to show me over this last month what
their sales look like. I can look at it
over a longer period of time. Let's look
over the last four weeks, and you can
actually see the volume that's being
done. So, for instance, if you're ever
curious how much a brand sell, how much
inventory you should be ordering,
they've sold 57 of this Wilson sneaker
in this last four weeks, 100 of this
address t-shirt. As you can see, most of
their products are selling between 40
and 100 of in the last month. And they
have about 70 excuses are selling well,
and 300 overall. You can go in here,
look at the products, look at the price,
look at how many they sell per day, look
at their sellrough rate, their color
distribution, when they go on sale. What
I also love is they have this events tab
now which basically summarizes when they
launched stuff. So you can go back and
look at what they launched when and it
will actually give you some summary
about hey this website launched sales
reached 75K. You can see what promotions
that they ran and it's a very useful
tool to be able to strategize for your
own brand. And then coming over here to
Cult Gaia. This is a women's wear brand.
This is always great to see basically
what a brand is hyped on versus what
they actually sell. So, for instance,
this brand is known really for their
bags, but their bestselling product is a
sandal, and they're selling way more of
their dresses and their clothes than the
bags that you might know them for. And
if I click over into the assets tab,
it's going to show me how they're doing
it. So, basically, it's going to pull in
Instagram posts that they've made. It's
also going to pull in their email
marketing. So, you actually go and check
out what email assets that they
published and how they're promoting
different things. Also grabs homepage
changes. You can see editorial and then
homepage design and layout changes over
time to see what they did for particular
campaigns. Another really useful
reference point. All the same info on
price distribution, color distribution.
I can look at their chart over the last
year, compare the volume they have, see
when their seasonality is. All of this
can happen within particle. And then
last, they also have this little trend
indicator here which aggregates a couple
pieces of data around showing search
volume and things like that. I always
like to look at this on a two-year
timeline so you can account for
seasonality because obviously there'll
be some if you have a big spike in
November and then another November then
it's something that's purely a holiday
spike. But you can see this one here
like dog shirts for instance like this
is the thing that is growing and people
are looking for and you have the ability
to put in terms and categories to narrow
it down. So anyway, if you are looking
at competitive research or market
research to help plan a brand you can
check out particle at the link in the
description. Shout out to them for
sponsoring this video. Now, related to
things that I would never use, but you
should be aware they exist, is LinkedIn
growth boosters. How do these people get
all these comments on LinkedIn, they
blow up similly out of nowhere, there
are like three services out there that
have these farms of e-commerce people
and marketing people on LinkedIn where
you join them. They're pretty expensive,
$500,000 a month. And you basically have
a pod where when you post, they will
comment from their accounts. They will
comment from other people in those pods.
And it boosts it cuz LinkedIn is such a
dumb algorithm. really rewards just like
pure comment-based interaction that
people will basically blow up out of
nowhere if they have really hooky
content and they engage with these pods.
But this is how people crush on there
and blow up and why you see them all so
intertwined with each other. And this is
something I actually don't recommend
participating in because then you get in
the echo chamber of people who are
recipients of that content which tends
to be not the savviest crowd of target.
It's kind of harder to break out of. And
I do think that building your own
content to your own network that's
commentable and scaling out that way is
really going to set you up much better
for like long-term success because once
you're caught in that echo chamber who
those people are, the ripple effects of
that I do not think are super strong.
But that said, if you want to quickly
hack your way to looking like you are
legit on LinkedIn, those boosters are
part of the way to go. Related to this,
another one that I would not do, but you
see it all the time is what we'll call
the YouTube podcast method. You will see
all these podcasts uh this is extremely
saturated in the marketing space in
particular where basically they'll have
tons of views on YouTube and you're like
how are they getting so many views?
There's only a handful of comments. Most
of the comments are from people
participating in the podcast. There's a
little bit of likes but there's way more
views. How did this happen? Is it just
they have that many passive listeners on
the TV or listening to the YouTube app?
It is not. That is a fallacy and it gets
people to believe that there's this huge
entrenched community of people into
those things on YouTube which there
really isn't. So what are they doing?
They're actually not doing anything
particularly wrong. they're actually
doing something that's very good for
their sponsors. So, what they will do is
they will take a sponsorship per
episode. Say they're getting 2,000
episode, 4,000 episode. They'll put a
lot of that budget towards running
YouTube ads on the episode. The ads may
not even go to the full episode. Might
just use a snippet. They will go to the
sponsor. So, they're driving traffic to
them as part of the deal. This is a good
end for the sponsor, end for the pod.
They get more views, they get some more
listens, maybe they convert a handful of
them, but then the actual software that
they're promoting, whatever it is, gets
all those clicks and all that attention
as they're getting as part of the deal.
It doesn't even have to happen
organically. This is a hack that people
were using to kind of push quality leads
to sponsors and also just makes their
podcast look really good. But this sets
you up to basically make it look like
you have a really engaged audience or
podcast when you don't. And then you
really never know where you're at in
terms of like real resonance in terms of
building that. So you're already
building something that can succeed, can
make you money, whatever, but it's
almost like a fallacy. It'll never
really be communitydriven when you're
building it like that. but is a kind of
tool worth knowing that if you are
starting that you have access to
sponsors, you want to drive results for
them and gain your leads, you can run
that YouTube podcast method because that
traffic is relatively cheap. And if you
want to say, how can I tell if they're
doing it? Again, just look at it. See
how many comments there are versus how
many views there are. Then look at sweat
equity. Sweat equity is what I bring up
as the gold standard for this. Alex and
Brian's pod, I've been on it a few times
where you can tell it is a community
built from YouTube, built organically.
Some episodes can get up to 10, 20,000
views. A lot of episodes have 1,000,
3,000 views. We have a bunch of comments
each time. who are asking questions,
people who have a relationship with
them, who are noting about things. Oh,
congratulations. You got married or
excited to see you back talking about
this, commenting with each other,
arguing about stuff. They have a
legitimate community and they have way
more natural organic views than a lot of
these podcasts that will show they're
getting 60 100,000, but it's all being
run through the ad funnel. Next up,
we're going to talk briefly about link
building for SEO. Now, I'm going talk
about buying social accounts. Then I'm
going talk about real farming and we'll
see where it goes from there. SEO link
building. You know, SEO becomes less and
less useful over time, at least in my
opinion. and I'm no longer investing in
it in basically almost any business that
I have. Uh because of the nature of
people just searching more from chat GPT
and the results that come from that is
going to be a different world. I don't
have a concrete plan for that either.
But that's going to be coming soon and
something I'm actively monitoring is how
to succeed in search inside that
platform. But basically to rank inside
Google, you need a combination of
things. You need to have your actual
content optimized to show up on Google.
You need when people actually click that
content, interact with it, they interact
with it in a natural way that is
rewarding and and actually follows what
Google feels like is the right user
experience. And it needs to have links
from around the internet that are
interacting with it, sending traffic to
it, sending signals back to Google that
this is a thing that has authority. And
so, how do people accomplish this?
There's a lot of natural ways to do it.
You can go, you can reach out to blogs,
get them to feature you, put on social
media. You can do the hard work of going
down the list of anyone who has a
directory or a feature and being like,
"Hey, please add me to this." There's
all these manual ways, but really what
people do is there's these massive
account blocks. They will charge you per
backlink. They will say, "Hey, I have
all these sites." They'll send you
spreadsheets and spreadsheets and
spreadsheets of sites with hundreds of
sites on them. and it'll be like, "Hey,
uh, if you want to rank for this
terminology or you want this domain
authority, whatever it is, you can pick
x amount of these links for $280 or
whatever it is." And they'll be $40 each
or $100 each, whatever it is, depending
on authority, sometimes more. And you
will basically buy bundles of those
links and continue buying bundles of
those links and and watch your pages
rise over time as more authority comes
back to them. And this is how people
have cheated SEO for generations. It's
almost impossible to stop because a lot
of these sites are very legitimate or
some cases not, but it's impossible for
Google to tell. And they can begin to
build networks up on that. Again, this
is a tactic that if you really did want
to build SEO now is something you could
do. But I do think SEO is shifting so
much that big investments in that right
now is a complicated thing to do unless
you have a really strong reason for it.
An easy way to tell if people are doing
this and what site they're doing it from
is if you use a service like HFS or SEM
Rush, you can actually go and often see
all the backlinks to individual pages
and to sites that are being run um like
where they're linking to. If you see a
bunch of weird sites or sites that seem
like odd aggregator blogs, often at the
bottom of the footer you will see like a
network name or X or Y. You can
basically keep kind of going down the
rabbit hole and you'll eventually be
able to find who the owner is or who has
the block of all these and they'll have
the kind of a contact info and you can
get in touch. Then we're going to go
into account buying. This is against
terms of service on basically every
platform. You can't buy and sell Twitter
accounts or Instagram accounts there,
but people still do it all the time,
whether it's for handles or whether it's
to get accounts. Theme page accounts and
selling and moving those and monetizing
them has been a business now. It's kind
of been booming for years and people do
it a lot now. A lot of this happens now
in groups. It happens on all these
different services and in masterminds
there's people that kind of collect it
and do it as a service. That's
definitely the best way to buy this is
through the people that know what
they're doing. But for the people that
don't and you're kind of getting new to
stuff, there are a few things to be
aware of. One is Fame Swap is a escrow
site where people will list these
accounts and you can buy them and
message them back and forth. Another one
is called Swap. Swap is an escro site
for all kinds of things on the internet
from verification services. These are
kind of getting into that darker gray
area of the web where you can begin to
go in and participate in that. they'll
hold money in escrow so that potentially
you don't get screwed and you can go
through and begin to move through
accounts. The tier and quality of the
things that are on these networks is
kind of lessened over time as the rise
of gurus who are moving these in private
communities has kind of moved forward.
But it is kind of worth noting what that
looks like. And there are also services
that are kind of way more legitimate
that do this. Often you'll see people
buy businesses that include a website
and a social media account as a way to
kind of get around it where you're
buying a full LLC. And there are
services like microacquire and others
where you can actually buy and sell
small businesses and SAS like that that
are really useful for being to play
inside this world of like smaller
acquisitions to for internet things.
There are now a lot of services that
basically generate mass content. You'll
see all these brands um that have 75 Tik
Tok accounts all running the same
carousels or running really small simple
videos. Some of them are AI, some are
just replications. Real Farm is one of
the first tools that I know a decent
amount of people using. They're churning
out like hundreds of AI carousels and
this and to put this in this is like
dumb content. This is not content that's
going to pass a litmus test for most
users. But if you are selling really
oddball or simple things or you're
selling things have a kind of mass
audience, this is a way to be able to
put out a lot of content, test those
ideas, get them to work and really scale
them. So real.arm is a good example
where you can actually input get a bunch
of this AI generated content, get a
whole bunch of variants, whether it's
like little video clips or whether it's
carousel versions, they are they really
care about generation and what's
happening and are very much on the cusp
of what's going on. So it's an
interesting play there, but that's how
people are doing all those things. if
you stumble down the rabbit hole and see
it. There's also some other brands. I
got served really weird obvi Tik Toks
and Instagrams where it's like an AI
person talking telling an obviously
fabricated story. There's people doing
some of that kind of stuff that I feel
like is only going to end up in an FTC
violation. But uh I don't know the
services or anything that are doing
those and wouldn't talk about them if I
did. All these other ones are you're
kind of playing again in that gray area.
Some of this is all right, some of it's
not. But if you want to begin to
understand the full landscape you have
of what the tools are available to work
inside these conditions and why people
speed up and others do and begin to have
that conversation with yourself with the
companies you work with around what what
do we feel like is you know is right or
wrong or can we do it's worth knowing
all these tools and things that are out
there. So I don't think I'll ever make
another video like this but I think it's
worth just having everyone know and be
on a level playing field about what's
out there and what that potential is and
what you are up against. So I appreciate
y'all watching and We'll be back again
soon.
[Music]