welcome to Art Direction 201 we're going
to dive deep into how to take amazing
photos whether of you for your friends
or for your brand in my art Direction
101 video I talked about the very basic
how to use things like location action
and perspective to make photos stand out
but that was just scratching the surface
so in this video we're going to dive
deep into what it takes to make standout
art Direction and have that as part of
your toolkit as just a normal person who
creates content or as something that's a
foundational point of your creative
career let's lock in so in this video
we're going to talk about reference and
using references we're going to talk
about the concept of displacement we're
going to talk about parasite marketing
and what you use inside of your images
to be able to connotate a feel or
provide a context for a brand we're
going to talk about perspective go
deeper on location and then tap into
World building and I'm going to do all
this through the framework of two
different types of shoot and we'll end
as always with some home but this first
type of shoot was one of my favorite
ones and this shoot is a refrigerator
shoot a kitchen shoot it's something you
can do for a product or for a person and
we're going to dive into and the second
shoot we're going to talk through is a
reference shoot where I'm actually going
to go through a shoot deck of something
I'm working on where we're replicating a
video game and doing a GTA style shoot
with people so first let's talk about
reference so I got to this idea of the
refrigerator shoot by browsing through
reference I was going through Cosmos
Cosmos has a feed based on your boards
actually enables you to see different
images that come up so I'm always doing
things like some key searches I'll
search for vintage fashion ads I'll
search Brands like helmet Lang I'll
search product photos I'll just search
art Direct ction and I'll also browse
through Arena which has a great
reference set for specific art directors
and creatives often have a lot of their
work organized down there you can go
through and so these fridge shots caught
my eye and they caught my eye a lot
because of this concept of displacement
this idea that you can put an item into
an unfamiliar environment and it stops
the scroll on the feed this is a
technique that anyone working in
marketing photography social media
should understand that if you want
someone to stop give them something
unusual something that doesn't make
sense in their brains this is a key part
of almost all the art Direction
techniques that you see major brands do
is something just feels different or new
or exciting about what they put on there
you can do this with Nostalgia you can
do this with scale like oversized items
you can do this by just plain being
weird but what I like about this is it's
almost subtle it's an object that
doesn't belong you see a pair of boots
inside a refrigerator and you wonder how
do we get here so let's dive into what
you do to put together a shoot and think
through it from an art Direction I love
the fridge idea because everyone has a
fridge for the most part you can use the
actual inside of it or you can use your
door and you have an infinite kind of
world of creativity you play with within
a couple key scenarios so the first one
we're going to look at is this
refrigerator door this idea that you can
put almost anything inside one of these
slots if it's a product you can fit in
it and think about what story are you
telling so what do I mean by that I love
this shot from Lolita swimwear because
it's a contrast you have a bikini
hanging inside of someplace cold so
there's almost like a sense of a feel of
touch that comes with that and the
senses are a key art Direction thing to
think about can you through what you're
able to present visually get someone to
feel something that isn't visual can you
get them to smell the environment you're
in can you get them to feel cold all
these are things in your art Direction
toolkit you can use to connotate emotion
and they can be done through what you
visually present and when you begin to
think like that and think what of the
senses could I through imagery bring to
life you're beginning to have part of a
toolkit that makes creatives rate create
really interesting things and with that
you have the idea of really cold or
really hot as well things melting inside
a refrigerator is an interesting concept
because something's not right the
extremely Frozen thing inside of a
freezer is something that people feel
Auto automatically when they see it you
get almost a visceral connection to
seeing everything iced over even more so
if you see a hand touching it these are
little pieces of sensory action you can
apply to almost any concept but they
really come to life inside of a
refrigerator shoot and you can use that
concept of steam or ice or whatever it
is to begin to create a visual
environment so now let's talk about
what's around the object on the Shelf so
there's a couple things that you can do
whenever you're kind of dressing a scene
and one of the concepts I talk about a
lot and I've done short form videos on
is this concept of parasite marketing
which you'll see a lot of brands do once
you see the concept and you know it and
that is associating their brand with
brands that they want to be like much
like how some lower-end Brands will
always try to place their stores near a
Gucci store they're associated with it
this is the same thing if your brand is
shooting a stocking or something and you
actually pair it with a Gucci bag inside
the shoot you are using parasite
marketing to take the power of Gucci's
brand and associated with your brand now
the same thing can apply on almost any
level so let's look at it in terms of a
fridge if you're inside this context and
say you had a food product inside here
and then you surround it with diamonds
or you surround it with moette champagne
or super expensive and exclusive things
then you're creating one Vibe you're
drawing like a luxury environment into
it surrounding it all by bottles of
moette Might imply that you're creating
a celebration and that that's the
context someone's going into that a
party is about to happen surrounded all
with the finest organic fruit a bunch of
airw boxes and immediately you begun to
create a vision of a customer so I love
this idea that you could use your
customer Persona in what's on the fridge
to get something or some inside joke
that they understand so that dressing
around it becomes one of these
fundamental principles of how you apply
your art Direction what contextually do
you do with the objects around it and if
you have a displaced object like a boot
in here what do you creating that then
gives this scene something more
interesting now you're establishing
multiple layers to your visuals you have
this displacement effect you have this
kind of persona coming to life with
what's surrounding it maybe you're
actually playing with some of the senses
like this is the essence of like doing
real interesting visual creative
Direction and the same thing can go
multiple say that you want to create a
contrast so you have a bunch of
Tupperware you have bunch of you know
Chinese food boxes that you know look
old around there but you have one object
that's perfectly lit or brand new now
you're contrasting between you know this
beautiful protein bar you put in the
shoot and all the things that surround
it they're unappetizing you have all
these different ideas from drawing
positivity from things around it to
creating a standout from things around
it or even Nostalgia say that you had an
item inside of a fridge who was all
surrounded by things from a certain
period you have this lifestyle element
all these are tools that again we're
applying to a fridge but can apply to
almost any shoot anytime you set up a
table anytime you set set up a room this
is how art directors can really think
about creating interesting environments
but now we have perspective so all the
shots that I've shown so far are just of
this fridge door right or the interior
of a fridge now let's look at how you
can look at this from the other way so
so Carl Shakur who's a really popular
Creator he shot this shot he's not the
first person to do it there's lots of
shots like this but it is a wide angle
shot shot from inside the fridge now you
can do this in a few ways if you have a
camera with an ultra wide angle lens you
can capture this you can put your iPhone
on wide mode in there is an easy way to
do it but you are now setting a scene
you are saying I'm inside of a space an
unexpected space I'm viewing a person a
person generally in a vulnerable
position in opening a fridge and looking
around maybe it's the middle of the
night maybe it's in the day you can
begin to storytel around what's
happening there and with anything that
is shot in a wide angle gets this
exaggerated feel you can complement that
with exaggerated emotion someone looking
skeptical or excited or sad gets
accentuated when you add that
perspective of the wideangle lens to it
then you can experiment with the
lighting and the storytelling there you
have both the lights within the fridge
and you have the lights in your
background if you shuttle the lights off
then it can be a midnight snack
environment or you can create that
contrast of light on the face maybe you
only light the shot with what the light
that's emanating from the fridge maybe
you can play with the dimmer all of a
sudden you have a toolkit to work with
or if there's lights on in the
background if there's things going on in
the background the light's not as hard
you're telling the story of something
happening where the actual environment
may not may have a different story being
told and I love this fridge example
because you have the control of these
elements in such a simple way where you
can say I have this lighting I have this
on and off I have all these environments
people think of the way we eat the way
we consume the times of day there's
immediate storytelling that's built into
something that we all experience and
then you have the little things like the
location or Essence of the fridge if
it's a mini fridge or a nice one or a
big one or inside some kind of
environment you can put all this
together and before I step into the
second example where I'm going to kind
of introduce like a different approach
to it I want you to really think about
this because if you are uh trying to
come up with an interesting idea or
shoot something and you want to take an
idea like this and bring it into the
world like I suggest you do it like your
homework for this video will be to go
out in the universe and shoot a fridge
video whether it's in your house or
somewhere else cuz here's what the idea
of location comes to mind like for
instance I have a fridge indoors in here
where I am now I have a smaller fridge I
have like a Roco smart fridge and I can
shoot something in there would tell a
very different story of like the little
fridge also has a very different feel
and Vibe but then the same thing would
happen if I went and snuck a few things
into like my local Ralphs or tried to do
the same shoot inside of an airan or we
were able to take over a bodega in New
York and do something with that Essence
there shooting from inside or from
outside or what that looks like or the
commercial environment all these ideas
you'll see in a reference like if we
start with just that single reference
image and now we've added on to
perspective we've added on to it the
story of all the things surrounding it
we've added on the idea of location and
where we could take that idea to this is
how you think when you're really doing
creative direct all right so now we're
going to go on to concept two this is
one I'm working on for my valuables
brand right now this is uh when I'm
shooting this this video may come out
later this is the week of Black Friday
so I'm trying to add some extra
Firepower on for a shoot we're going to
do on Monday so that right after our
Black Friday Cyber Monday we're coming
back hard have some new inventory coming
in and as many of you know my brand has
kind of like a racing them theme and a
lot of the content we've put out has
like a heist theme around it we're sort
of playing into this kind of World
building there and I'm looking to kind
of connect the dots between this kind of
vintage fuel I have inside these
products this idea of like creating some
characters and a story which I'm like
slowly rolling out and then connecting
into the world of the things that I feel
like my customers really enjoy my
customers are very into car culture I've
started to notice that the younger
customers a lot the kids I met at
complex con are really into gaming are
following people on streaming and on
Twitch so I'm connecting the dots there
a bit with this GTA shoot and kind of
building a little bit of a world around
that that will intersect with this real
world kind of heist idea I've played out
in some of these films so to do that we
set up this this shoot and I'll give you
a little idea of the brief I put
together and like how that works and how
we're art directing it so we started
with the perspective of environments and
this is a great idea to look at a
refence if you want a reference a film
or reference a video game that an
excellent place to look for art
Direction examples because what you're
going to get there when you use a
reference that's from something people
know is that you're going to have people
feel like they're in on the joke or feel
like they know or be like oh I recognize
that that means that they have a moment
with the Brand This is why I love movie
references you see me do this all the
time all the titles and all my stuff are
like odd cormic mcarthy references for
like insiders and there's like four
people who get those jokes but they like
really get it and those people like like
the brand right and that's the world you
can create so here this is Grand Theft
Auto screenshots right and you'll see
this unique point of view you
immediately recognize as Grand Theft
Auto you're behind a person you're about
4 foot feet back you're a couple feet up
looking slightly down and there's all
these things like cars are always angled
a little bit too much there's like a map
in the corner this is something that
we're going to create recreate with the
art Direction and what I love about
video game Recreation is that by just
bringing it into real life it's
immediately interesting and so we took a
couple different perspectives I'm doing
a male and female model inside this
shoot so I have some other female ones
you'll notice like she has like an
aggressive stance in this grand auto
screenshot I'm like cool that's the kind
of stuff that I'm putting in this deck
because that's what I want to reference
I want to say hey how can we take these
models and have equally an aggressive as
a stance if we do something like this
can we have a superar right there like
right we don't need to rent a super car
for the shoot there can be one on the
street if we position the person just
like this we can get a shot like this in
Miami or in LA and that's the kind of
references I'm putting into into the
look and then same thing when we're
doing that shoot I want to start World
building and so when we talk about art
Direction things I've talked about
before this idea of World building is
how do you develop characters how do you
give the people in your shoots a story
Beyond just looking at it seeing
something visually cool and especially
if you're going to use similar people
again and again or if you're painting a
bigger narrative and so I am painting
this like larger overall Heist narrative
with some recurring characters within my
brand with lots of things that are going
to emerge you don't have to World build
that deep but I'd even think about in a
single image what are all the stories
you can help tell what can a prop add to
a shoot that makes it not just weird but
makes someone actually start to think
about why does that exist maybe come up
with a story in their own mind so these
GTA shots someone counting the stack of
money my guy with the baseball bat over
his shoulder Trevor with the lighter
pulled out each of these is using a
single prop to tell a story and I love
this idea and you've heard me talk in
these videos about my one thing concept
where if you're doing a shoot if you
just add one thing just make one
decision that's int itional you
immediately Elevate the shoot all you
have to do is just do one thing zero to
one either you have a normal photo or
you have a photo with one idea and you
can add a bunch more on top of that but
one idea like takes you from normal into
something art directed or creative
directed so for this shoot I'm going to
have a zipple lighter if I can get
someone to mimic the attitude of this
character who's kind of relatively
notorious like replicate this scene but
even if they didn't even if say I had
the female model do that and had that
same kind of look in her eye and we
framed it a little bit differently that
idea of that one lit lighter and that
look sells a story inside the photo and
so this is why we put these reference
together cuz I'm going to let the
photographer cook he's going to come up
with his own ideas how to pose this and
Stage this and do this within the
context and things that he's given and
but having this to set him up is the
beginning of how we're going to work on
telling that story and then you can look
at some of these other perspectives I
also put these shots in here of like
cars and motorcycles and stuff like that
where I want to get some video clips and
be able to say cool if I just shoot from
this perspective a couple feet behind a
couple feet up people immediately know
where they're looking at they feels like
they're in a video game now I'm going to
get the design team um who you've seen
me document the videos that the guys at
dark room are going to have them create
like a little map view a little bit of
stats and stuff that's on there so when
I actually put these reels out they're
going to feel like we're creating like a
valuable video game and so this is a
very stark contrast to the fridge shoot
right where we're beginning to like
start with a place add on some context
add on some perspective here we're
starting with a reference and we're
saying hey we're actually going to
duplicate this like relatively close but
then how can we do brand storytelling
around this I'm going to introduce
vehicles that are they're key to my
brand in a certain way they're going to
have the clothing of the brand on within
it I'm going have models to represent
the brand I'm going have storylines and
props to tell to other things in the
brand like we're going to use Heist
masks inside it some of the props I'm
going to hand off because that's
connecting to other video parts that
I've done so think about what your Brand
L is what those things are what those
products are if you were to do the same
shoot and you were graza for instance
you have the graa potato chips like in
the shoot like you could immediately
begin to introduce it in your own way
and you have to have that visual
language and as a brand that has a
visual language of racing has a visual
of like of being connected to some of
these like like plot lines or people
that are scheming I have a world that I
can help build and you'll see at the
very end of this I have some of the
models that we're talking to and like
who we're considering and you start to
see like how does this all tie in to
bring it to life but this is a very
straightforward example this is a quick
shoot I saw my boy at complex con he's
like hey we should shoot again soon I
was like awesome here's a concept I have
we put together like literally this is
some Google Slides I'll turn it into a
full brief in like Adobe Express before
we do it but like this is a like this is
kind of how you begin to think and go
back and forth with people to kind of
create original ideas and then I also
just again let them cook be like hey
this isn't like locked in apply your own
Creative Vision we' talked through a lot
of Concepts inside this video like the
basics we talked about before like
action what do models do like location
where they're at but now we talked about
displacement we talked about parasite
marketing we talked about scale um we
talked about World building and
characters utilizing references like
this is your toolkit no matter what kind
of creative you are like having a art
Direction toolkit is going to be super
useful to you even if you're creating a
graphic image you're taking a photo of
your girlfriend you're trying to get a
photo shoot for anything you do using
all these tools are super useful so like
I mentioned before your homework is to
go do a fridge shoot for anything you
have a cool product you have something
you like photos of you whatever it is
and then also to write down the things
you like from this video start to build
literally make a dock that's like this
is my art director toolkit you're going
to hate some things I showed you're
going to love some things I showed
you're going to say I want to do that or
you're say I'm going to avoid it the
things that you want to do or you want
to try like put them in that doc so go
back to it the next time you have a
shoot you begin to have your references
for it so anyway that was Art Direction
201 appreciate youall watching we're
going to continue to go deeper I did all
these basic videos so I can do more
expansive videos on them now once
everyone's kind of learned it I'll link
the art Direction 101 Here video as we
end it and thank You' all so much for
watching let's go