all right so we are back and talking
about the principles of art Direction
this is one of my favorite topics I do a
lot of passionate videos on this because
I love Creative Direction and art
Direction how you can use its principles
to elevate your brand photos Elevate
photos of anything in your life and how
to think about content in the world
around you with this artistic and
creative thought so in this video we're
going to tap into a few things this is
another level two video I have a one1
video I'll link at the end here if you
want to dive in from the start at what
is art direction we're going to be doing
a level deeper here we're going to be
talking about white background shoots
these are the corners of most Brands
shoot white background stuff we're going
to be talk about how you can apply art
Direction and tension to them we are
going to be talking about the bell curve
of art Direction and content adoption
and where your brand fits and how to
think about where you're executing art
Direction where you should fit in terms
of like reusing Concepts actually really
interesting conversation and we'll pull
up some reference Brands like aritzia
and Gia and a few others we're going to
talk about video ideation with art
Direction and kind of content for ads
I'm going to open up my foreplay account
and go through a bunch of the links that
I have inside of it and we're going to
dive into luxury references some of the
things that I'm pulling in looking at
for content and why they will give you a
little bit of an art Direction toolkit
of things that you can use for your own
brand so without further Ado let's dive
into white background shoots so I want
to pull up this first photo from a brand
called lunge this is what I mean by kind
of white background anything happens in
a white Studio we're going to talk about
photos that are on you know just a
product place and how you can make those
stand out but I anything happens in the
white Studio white studio is one of the
easiest places for people to shoot they
are across the country and everywhere
everyone knows it how do you make these
interesting so what lunge did here this
is an incredible photo and it's comped
together right this is photoshopped from
from many photos together but they have
a super wide angle approach they've done
here and they've pieced together a
concept executed well I like to look at
as a great example of how do you do
something different in those
environments by having you know a camera
placed one time and then being able to
build a story around it in multiple
photos and obviously some post-
production and I love this photo from
Marne because again they're using the
same shoot of where a model could be
there and they're telling a story with
it they're doing it in a number of ways
like the wires across the screen here
almost make you think your screen is
cracked there's just a lot that would
make you stop scrolling on the feed from
this and again the models are doing
something different and this perspective
you gain here of one standing behind the
other again they don't have to be in the
same shot if you kind of thought through
and planned this right but whenever
you're choosing to do like a model shot
having them engaging in an activity the
way they're doing photos shows off the
clothing just as well but is inherently
more interesting I'd love to think about
that action so like on my valuable shoot
my first shoot I had the model reading a
book so I had him reading Catcher in The
Ride inside of one of the first shoots
and one of the other shoots I believe
there's like a Bukowski book or
something floating around as well but
again doing any activity comes
inherently more interesting as a photo
than if not and they took this a step
further because the wires you begin to
you know Wonder like okay why does that
exist and what does it mean what is it
connected to a Story begins to build and
this third one is from Futura 2000 times
off-white again just getting in that
same idea of we're shooting all these
things in a white background gives you a
canvas with which to play right you can
shoot from the same location you have
your camera on a tripod and anything you
do there you have that sense of
perspective and shift where you can
combine the photos to try to create an
interesting scene and then last we have
this from Shantel Paris which again is
is a just the idea of how do I do an
activity but they've upped this right so
she is on a treadmill here she's on a
treadmill and heels say something is
naturally going to stand out she's you
know got the pose nail but they're
taking this device from social media
right we've seen these treadmill walking
videos all the time they're bringing it
into the photo shoot they're making it
like uh like seem it's it's almost
absurd and it's just a really great
example of like whatever it took to
transport this to the shoot and to make
this work was worth it right because
this is a true standout image by just
adding that prop and so I would
encourage you again if we look at some
homework from this we looking at this
like you are doing a WI background shoe
what is it that you can bring like let's
just do the Craigslist exercise like
could you find a fitness machine like
this and like buff it to look as nice as
you can on there and probably get it for
a few hundred bucks in a truck yes like
what are those things that you could
look at do you want to comp in a number
of things like what are those props that
activities you can do to turn your next
white background shoot into something
interesting and so let's also take a
look at what some of the luxury brands
do with this I always find that
interesting as well so this I'm inside
my foreplay account forplay is
sponsoring this video I asked them to
because I think they're the perfect
software to combine this this is where I
actually store all my ads and references
so we'll dive into that for a second
here essentially for players a Chrome
extension like you see here that allows
me to save any Instagram organic Tik Tok
organic or Facebook ad Library post to a
board so I can kind of cruise through
them I can add them to boards I can save
them to boards directly so this is what
I use to save and organize mood Boards
of paid and organic content because it
lets me really easily send them to
clients and partners I can just grab a
link like this and then share it and
slack so right now I just put in
balanciaga and I'm scrolling through the
balance Yaga ads so in foreplay you can
basically pull open every ad that a
company has in here we'll look for one
in a second we'll get it but all right
so we have this shot here you see okay
cool they're doing these where they're
falling in so again just applying an
effect to it simple enough they're doing
photos obviously this is like they're
doing the opposite of a really well
groomed photo they're doing an
unmanicured photo love this where
basically they're using that like
spinning in that comp this would take
some work and planning but again this is
one where if you talk to your editor or
anything ahead of time they can likely
put together a plan of how you execute
something like that this is actually a
great example and you'll see they're
doing some relatively straightforward
shots in there as well so let's actually
take a look at Jac moose as well as I
mentioned before inside forl you can
basically go into any company's ads that
are in here and it will show you every
ad that they're running I can go sort by
newest to oldest the longest running Etc
and there's L I think jacm has like
2,000 or 6,000 ads running different
languages whatever but now we can see
their white background sheets right this
is a really interesting one because it's
a size perception one like they have
this purse on top of this desk and I
literally have no idea what the size of
either of these things is is this a
massive purse or is this a tiny desk
that's a really like subtle interesting
kind of variant of this uh that I
thought was uh is kind of well done and
begin to look at okay they're taking a
like a much more basic approach to this
which is interesting to note right why I
like to pull references when I'm doing
this because Brands will often choose
things to perform in a certain way or
not and they're saying hey we're
actually better off on our model photos
doing something straightforward whereas
we're doing kind of a a visual trick on
some of what we're doing with our
product photos I'm going to pop over
into my swipe file here to look at some
content we're going to kind of go
through a bit of it cuz one of the
things I want to note is you begin to
think about these Concepts I've talked
about all these art Direction Concepts
and location and position and all the
things that you've heard from me about
how you can Elevate to shoot or Elevate
what you're doing for your Brand's
content but you have to think about
where your consumer is at is a key one I
like to bring up aritzia when I do that
so over here in my swipe file I Rec did
a TSA bin video for Black Friday right
uh and we've all seen the TSA Bin videos
the TSA Bin videos are washed torched
completely done right they we have seen
them to death if you are anywhere in
fashion there's been a thousand TSA Bin
videos but aritzia chose to do it and
they did totally fine good good video
for them 180,000 views or whatever it is
because they know where their customers
at their customers not on the bleeding
edge their customers likely seeing this
they've seen it once or twice before
maybe or even if they've seen it a bunch
of times they are at that point in the
bell curve that is not early adopter
where they don't care where they're
going to find it good the Ria knows
their place I tie that into this same
video as well they released this kind of
right after this a December video for
them where they're doing a 3D animation
we've seen every fashion brand of like a
major house do one of these 3D
animations videos and they are doing it
late and guess what it doesn't matter
cuz they know where their customer is
and this is actually a great spot to be
if your customer is a middle of the bell
curve customer it means all these
references and things we're looking at
you don't have to be like oh how can we
make it original just do your own
version of it literally the TSA B video
has been ripping it's everyone's been
doing it it's seems like it's too late
perfect run it if it's worth
acknowledging where your customer is cuz
for a lot of people their customer is in
there and they shouldn't be afraid of
doing things like this it's interesting
to think about now if you're on the
bleeding edge you have to think about
that as well so another brand I have
saved in here is imgia and this is is a
relatively risque brand they sell kind
of like a lot of lingerie and swimsuits
and things of that nature but they are
on the edge so they have this campaign
they did they did this office core
campaign and they have excellent AR
Direction inside their videos they
understand exactly what's happening they
did this at the cusp of office Corp they
have these two in here who are major
ticktockers you may not recognize them
but she's got like millions and millions
he's got millions and millions and he
makes food for her is the whole idea and
they've brought them into their art
Direction Cannon they've said here's
this thing happening in the world Corp
core here's these people that are
popular that is on the kind of The
Fringe the only people that are really
terminally online know about we're
bringing those together and that is a
core part of our shoot and also in that
shoot they shot like 20 or 30 different
types of of content around like you know
like that brand the different things
around that concept and the things that
they do and so they're a brand that's on
that far end of the curve they're trying
to make sure they are ahead of it
they're the first major fashion brand
that's using these influencers like that
type of thing and that's an important
one to acknowledge as well if you want
to see a different angle of it so now
I'm going to go through a couple
references of the things I have saved
inside foreplay so you can kind of see
what we're looking at there so one thing
is so they have this part of this app
called spider where you can basically
see all the brands stuff and they will
actually like track and analyze it and I
have skims saved in here cuz I look at
skims like a lot as a example of
excellent content for kind of a number
of reasons you'll kind of see like these
split ads where you have the girl and
the outfit next to it great and this is
a good example how to use those
references right I'm going to go through
this and skims doesn't care right they
are sex cells everything sells this
before after ad you know again like they
are unafraid of doing anything that is
uh even like a little bit risque and
these are just really interesting like
approaches to it and even look at like
you know like the C there the bump is
what matters here like nothing else does
and so this is one thing I like to do is
kind of just go through these ads and
then say what are the things that you
can take them from your from your own
style and so so far not going to click
anything too risque a in here the number
one thing I've gotten was that top ad
where I was saying hey that split of the
outfit in 9 by6 with that like a third
range is actually a really interesting
shot and I'm looking down here being
like all right cool I'm kind of seeing
how they're doing like this like the
minor styling like this is a white
background shoot for this um for this
apparel this is an interesting one too
for white background Stand Out Bandit
running does this really well too where
they shoot white background and they AI
comp in the background like cities and
interesting places and textures and
that's pretty sure what's happening here
they're bringing some to the Forefront
with this like snow blur again that's
interesting thing to think about for
white background as well is shooting and
cing into it and then you get all kinds
of options if you're using like visual
electric um to generate images behind it
but I would encourage you to find those
brands that are your Muses and look and
it's about looking regularly at what
they do right because ads is kind of a
current thing certain types of ads are
hitting or popular at a certain given
time and I think it's an important tool
inside your art Direction toolkit to be
able like monitor those regularly to be
able to add things to your list of
things you want to try in a shoot
especially when it comes down to like
basic things like Ecom shoots like this
so popping back to my swipe file here a
few more things I like I love this video
another Jacamo one where they're just uh
taking around this book that is also
like the name of the collection I
believe and this is a great example of
if you have a brand object or create a
brand object and can tell a story with
it or use that as an announcement this
is an really interesting example and
they just put this through a bunch of
really interesting shots I think another
good homework exercise or thing you
could try is what would my brand object
be could I create a book for my brand or
for my shoot and then what are all the
scenarios I could put up on it they took
this a level further this is another
kind of tool when you start to think
about this for video creation is they're
actually trying they're teaching people
how to pronounce chamus behind the video
so that's what the voiceover is even
while they have this entirely different
visual story happening and that's kind
of a that cognitive dissonance is
another useful kind of art Direction
tool especially as you get into video
content and that's what we're going to
kind of focus on here I know I've done a
ton on photos so I'm going to talk a
little bit about video so I'm going to
talk about this brand gun I think it's
probably the last brand that we talk
about here but they're a really
interesting one because they have done a
bunch of different styles of content I
think are very well done so the first is
like they don't have a model doing like
a standard shoot to show off their
clothes like this one is they have the
the the model who is not a great actor
he just looks good giving a style lesson
right like in inside this where he is
choosing to show them how to style the
clothes not just pose in the clothes I
love that angle of Leaning into the fact
he's not particularly good at this they
are kind of engineering something that
has some value and a tip and that is
watchable versus just showing it this is
kind of the basics again translating
these art Direction principles into
video is like all right let's just put
this into a scenario and they're doing
this almost in a classroom with a
mannequin this is a way to embrace like
having a model on a shoot that actually
does something versus just being there
and again that whole video is is quick
it's about 30 something seconds the
second one I love is this postcards
format we'll break this down in a minute
but they are taking location-based
storytelling and they are saying hey
we're going to present our brand like in
a location you see they're in the close
the entire time but but they're choosing
a vignette of a place that anyone who
feels nostalgic for kind of old Italy or
that version is able to kind of lean
into it through this content and so I'm
going to break down this quick so I
actually think this is a good ide anyone
who wants to create a vignette if you
want vignettes in your art Direction
toolkit by vignette I mean you're
telling a story like likely around like
a place or a thing that's happening the
way they've done it is is perfect and so
it really comes down to uh fonts is the
first thing to choose they have fonts
for the title and they have fonts for
the subtitles choosing something is on
brand there that's kind of your category
one then they have the video style right
and so they've chosen to shoot this has
this kind of like this this more film
and kind of traditional look again you
could definitely choose any number of
different styles for something like this
but it has its own kind of signature
style and everything shot with
relatively the same close kind of
cropped framing throughout the entire
video which is actually a really
interesting choice and then there's
lifestyle to this right this whole video
is based around them kind of exploring
and cooking a meal and so like what is
the lifestyle you're showing and
obviously they kind of have this like
affluent like country club European
lifestyle that they're showing so you
get fonts you get video style you get
lifestyle those are the three things
like inside the vignette so far you have
the people and who's involved there
obviously she's kind of the main
character there's person she visits at
the market there's the other people at
the table like how do they perceive the
brand and then they're all wearing the
brands how are you kind of integrating
it and then the narrative like what are
they doing I love the idea of like
sharing a meal in a place because you
get to show off the place and people
love like the food porn shots of like
pasta and then the setup and the
resources they had to do this like are
location food vehicle the market they
went to and so it's all about breaking
things down right I love breaking things
down into like a repeatable style so if
you went and side on your fonts the
video look you wanted to have for for
this the lifestyle you're trying to
portray the people that you have
available The Narrative you're trying to
get across and how you're integrating
the product and then you say all right
what are the resources we have in this
case like a location a vehicle the meal
Etc like that is now a organization like
a foundation for you to be able to
execute like an interesting shoot and so
I just wanted to walk through a few of
those examples from from white
background to the kind of this more
luxury stuff just give some more ways to
think about your art Direction toolkit
like I mention I save all this stuff in
foreplays where I use for my swipe files
they have all these kind of research
tools the ability for me to organize
this attach some to briefs share it with
other people which is a really useful
tool for me so I will put some link and
some more information of them down there
in the bio and I highly recommend you
check that out if you are trying to
organize ads and organic content like I
do on a regular basis and please any
other kind of core art Direction
Concepts that you want to tap in on for
future videos I know we've been covering
a lot of ground on this recently please
let me know and I'll prep in another one
for next month thank you so much
[Music]