This is a creative director's guide to
cameras. Now, I'm not a camera reviewer.
This isn't your average camera channel.
We're not going to teach you how to be
an amazing photographer. But if your job
is an art director, a creative director,
a strategist, and you want to make
standout content on social media, or for
your personal brand, I'm going to give
you all the tricks I've accumulated
through 15 plus years of this in one
video. We're going to cover your social
media toolkit, how you can make shoots
and campaigns pop by your camera choice.
We're going to talk about cameras for
photo all the way from entry level and
fun to how to make your campaign smash.
I'm going to walk through a bunch of
what I own. Then we're going to talk
about cameras for video at all different
price points and levels that are built
for effective workflow. There'll be lots
of tips and tricks throughout this
video. Tons of stuff you may want to
come back to when you have some money to
spend. And I live in this world every
day. Argue about this, work with all
kinds of creatives. I had a lot of fun
deciding what to put in this. So I hope
you enjoy it as well. Let's lock in. So
first of all, why listen to me? So, I've
gone through every part of the gambit of
having to use equipment and creative
work. I started as a designer and
creative, had to take a lot of my own
shots. Then, when we had our own agency,
not only do we have a video team, I was
both leading the team, helping pick the
gear and the workflow and having to
shoot myself and deal with all the
process that went around that. And then
now I rarely shoot at all, but I keep a
full toolkit to help make the shoots I
am on as platinum as possible cuz often
I'm booking newer or younger
photographers, want to be able to hook
them up with great gear or I'm going on
a shoot we've already booked and I want
to have stuff in my bag of tricks to
make it pop. And overall with the
creative strategy work I do with brands
where we're helping them try to make the
best social media content possible. I
and all the people I worked with are
obsessed with workflow. How do you get
the most out of the least amount of
money? How do you shoot the most in
camera and not have to worry about post?
Now, how do you get the most bang for
your buck in terms of social media
performance? And I'm stoked to break
down the tools we have here. And I'm
going to start with the funnest part.
What is going to get your campaign to
look unique or help it pop on social
media. You'll probably notice that lots
of brands are running camcorder footage
right now as a core part of their
strategy. 2JS is doing it for most of
their shoots. New Project was doing it
for a lot of the hook videos for their
mansion. Jewelry brands like Sedrine are
running that. Creators are going viral
with it. My favorite camcorders include
one, this JBC Aario. I got this for $55
on eBay. It's part of over 12 I've
gotten in the last few months cuz every
time I go on a shoot, I tend to bring
one and then the brands always want to
keep it and ask if they can keep it
after. So, I basically just got a bunch.
So, I'm always the person that can pass
one off to their team. So, this JVC was
55. It came without a battery. I hunted
a battery down on eBay. This is an
excellent tactic you should consider.
finding the gear that's missing
something and then filling in the dot
will get you a better price. But what I
love about this camera is it's got a
hard disk on here. You can plug it into
your computer, change the file names,
and it'll work right on your Mac. Got
30x zoom. It still has that really
vintage feel of the footage, but it's
also very HD. It's like that perfect
amount of time where it still looks like
a camcorder, but you're actually getting
some quality, so you can even shoot in
horizontal and have it hit for a video.
Extremely underrated pick. If sub $100
you're getting this in your arsenal,
it's going to help videos that you do go
viral or help compilations be
interesting and unique. This is a hard
one to turn down. Now, slightly more
expensive, but an oddball one that
almost no one has, is this digital
harazoomi. I had this camera in 2011. I
was in a band. We actually filmed music
videos with this camera in that era. For
better or for worse, but is from a
Japanese company called Superheads. This
is the triple plus edition, and this is
closer to 300 bucks. It's pretty
expensive, but it shoots both stills and
video in a pretty wildly unique look in
this super inconspicuous package, which
is amazing for being able to really
quickly or candidly capture stuff or if
you want to go shoot in a grocery store
or do things that would kind of be out
of the normal or be weird to bring big
gear. This is a really fun one for BTS
or for complimentary or to be a
conversation point. Now, I've also used
tons and tons of point and shoots. We
were shooting behind the scenes on point
and shoots for a while. I love point and
shoots that incorporate flash, but
honestly, we are doing this less and
less now. that content doesn't seem to
pop as much on social media, but this
Fujif fine Pix E900 is one of my picks
there. But standing out on social media,
often less has anything to do with the
camera and more to do with the lenses.
So, a couple things to have in your
toolkit. The first is a fisheye lens
like an ultra wide you can use to
establish good perspective. And then one
I'd be considering all the time for
shoots if you can is renting a probe
lens. People forget you can pretty
easily rent for shoots. Lens rentals is
one I go to all the time. I have no
affiliation with them, but please feel
free to holler at your boy so I can rent
that hustleblot. But they have probe
lenses for most mounts of cameras. What
a probe lens does is it gets ultra
close. You can get inside something. You
can get in someone's mouth and you can
pull all the way out and reveal and it
makes for a really compelling social
media hook. But your job in an art
director, creative director role is to
have that toolkit to be able to say, "We
need to make this piece of content
better. We need to try to make this go
viral. Can we use a camcorder for this?
Should we use a pro lens to get this
really cool shot to use as a hook? What
if we did a fisheye here and kind of
tested it? What are the different
options you have to make something
really unique? And so you can do that
with your actual strategy or sometimes
you can lean on some hardware to get you
there. But moving on to photo. I'm a
huge fan for the casual user of Fuji
cameras because the color coming out of
them is so great. If you want to focus
on taking your photos and having them
good in camera with as little postwork
as possible, their color science, the
automatic filters and stuff they have
are excellent. You've heard about the
very popular Fuji X1006. There's a
reason it is so popular. I personally
prefer cameras like the X-T series or
some of their more photographydriven
ones because you can swap into the
lenses of the Fuji ecosystem. But if
your goal is to do the least amount of
work and get the best looking photo, it
is really hard to beat that Fuji X100 6.
And there's a reason that it is so
popular. It's a great entryway into
better photography. If you are trying to
have a hybrid system where you get the
power of being able to shoot on Fuji
like that, but also shoot on video
forever when we had a broke boy agency
workflow, we ran on the Fuji XH series.
It's awesome for both video and for
photo. You get all those Fuji out of
camera colors. You can still shoot in
log and a lot of those cameras are
running around in the sub,000 price
point. But the real conversation I want
to have here is why everyone's photos
look better than yours. So, you can pick
any camera, any photographer. you're
shooting Canon, you're shooting Nikon,
whatever it is, you can get great
images. A lot of that depends on the
photographer itself. But at some point,
you'll be like, man, I'm hiring these
people or I'm shooting this stuff and
the stuff that is actually in like true
editorial or like big boy lookbooks
looks that much better. And the answer
to that is often they are shooting in
medium format. So, this right here is
the Pentax 645Z. It's one of my favorite
cameras I own. Is probably the cheapest
medium format camera you can get. Medium
format just has a different look than
any other camera on the market. It
immediately looks more editorial. It
looks more professional. You can tell
when you see people shooting with it.
It's why their stuff looks better. But
it requires a lot of knowledge. This is
a hard camera to use. It is heavy. It is
complicated. It is slow and it is old.
And if you don't really understand
lighting and aren't dialed in on getting
good lighting, your images are going to
be whack. But if you do understand
lighting, understand how to take good
photos, but you just haven't had the
gear to really take it to the next
level, this is $2,000. works with all
645 manual Pentax lenses from back in
the day which you can get. They have a
75mm f2.8 which is like $200. This is
the autofocus 55. It's like $500. But if
you're $2,500 all in getting a medium
format sensor to get that look that is
an absolute steal if you are trying to
level up on a budget. If you are trying
to level up without a budget, you have
Fuji and you have Hustelblot in the
medium format context. The Fuji's are
much easier to learn and use on if
you're not like a super experienced
photographer, but you want that medium
format look and you're experimenting.
Fuji is kind of your only choice. You
have to really know what you're doing
with Hustelblot or with that Pentax. But
you will immediately see such an update
in quality and look when you are
shooting on medium format, especially
when you are shooting with prime lenses
at a low f-stop. If you don't know what
that means, this is probably not the
video where I'm going to explain all the
concepts of camera photography. You can
start elsewhere for that, but come back
here when you do know a bunch about it.
Actually, you know what? I'll give you
like the quick crash course right now.
So, your aperture, how much light is let
into the camera, functions on a system
called f-stop, up to a number like 16 or
11, that's high, all the way down to a
low number. The lower it is, the more
light is being let into the camera. But
you don't care about any of that. All
you care about is what it looks like.
When you get to a low number, like this
is an f28, this is an f12. These really
low numbers mean that a very, very small
amount of your shot is in focus. It has
a very shallow depth of field. You also
get what's called bokeh, which is that
effect around whatever is in focus that
has these very like kind of interesting
textured effects to it. The lower that
you shoot, you shoot on that f12, etc.,
the less is in focus, that's how you get
that really cool effect you've seen in
so many photos you may not be able to
replicate. And you may not be shooting
fully all the way down, but say you're
shooting like an f2.8 or an f4. That's
how you get that really strong
separation between a subject and its
background. versus if you're shooting at
a higher f-stop, that's where everything
is going to look as if it's equally in
focus. You want to shoot there if you
want something sharp. I'm assuming that
you're not a photographer and you just
need to know a little bit about this.
Now, it's a really key one to know
because on lenses, you are often giving
up a certain amount to be able to get
that. For instance, if you want to get
that really low f-stop, it means you
often have a lens that is at one focal
length. That means it can shoot at one
distance. And if you have a variable
lens, it's more flexible. You're often
giving up some of that power. Why you
will see here I do not have a single
variable lens on any of these cameras
because for the stuff that I work on we
are very much focused on how do you
achieve that certain depth of field and
look because of the work that I do. This
video is brought to you by framer. So I
recently procured a new domain. This is
my friend.com moment. But since I do not
have a millions of dollars budget for
the domain, I actually got creative
director.net. It's about to be the new
home for a lot of the things that I am
working on on the internet and this new
business you may have heard about that I
am launching. But I actually made the
landing page for this website in Framer
just recently and it's a good excuse to
actually walk you through what the real
process is to put up a website on
Framer, how you edit it and how it
works. So if you're unfamiliar, Framer
is a noode website developer that is
built for businesses, not just for
casual websites. They have a beautiful
library of templates. So as I built out
the whole website, I wanted to put a
weight list together. So I went through
their themes and I found this weightless
template which I liked and I thought
would serve me well. It was also free. I
put that in my backend in framer. And
you can see what I got here. I have a
different view of the desktop, mobile,
and tablet website that I can then go
edit. You'll see what I've done here is
I've actually reduced the number of
elements versus this draft just in the
editor. Uh by just grabbing them, either
moving them or deleting them. I'm
literally able to move these around the
screen in the different variations. I'm
able to edit things like put my graphic
in there, edit the text, change the
font. Got instrument serif and general
sands in here just as placeholders. and
then using the framer forms to be able
to capture information. So, right now,
this landing page is just a promo for an
upcoming webinar that I am doing. You'll
see how easy I was able to go directly
from what they had in the template and
then literally just click and edit the
text, change the fonts here on this
sidebar. But I actually want to adjust
some of this even further. I want to
swap an image. So, I'm going to take
this image here. I'm actually choose an
image, change it to fit, get rid of the
initial image. Can simply kind of drag
it to display. And also, if I want to
put this across, I can move it to the
other pages that I have and can kind of
control what that experience looks like
on page. But it just gives you an idea
of how simple it is to go from one of
these good-looking templates to an
actual reality. But I was able to go
from having my domain to finding a
template and having that template live
in about an hour because Framer is built
for speed. So, if you've been looking
for a solution for your business that
has amazing looking stuff that will let
your website stand out, but that also
you can edit and create yourself,
especially if you are a creative and
don't have a de dev experience and you
can use the code orin for a month of
Framework Pro for free. Related, if you
want to learn photo or you've had one of
these cameras, entry camera, but you're
not actually good at it yet, I cannot
recommend enough going full manual. If
you have money to blow and want to go
full manual, Leica cameras are
incredible. This is the Leica M240. This
is my personal camera I use in my life.
But basically, you have no auto modes,
no autofocus. Everything is manual in
the camera from focus, aperture, f-stop,
ISO. You have to learn how to capture
everything yourself. And I cannot
recommend this more highly to actually
learn how to be a good photographer.
than by trying a full manual camera. And
it doesn't have to be this, but you do
get amazing images and extremely unique
color out of a Leica. That's why you
find so many people actually end up with
that when they're passionate about it or
save their money for it, is that you can
look at specs and sensors and all this
stuff all day. When it comes down to it,
these cameras simply just look and
deliver better because of whatever odd
witchcraft that Leica has mastered over
time. This M240 is the cheapest one. You
will find I am the king of trying to
find deals for this kind of stuff. I
traded in multiple lenses and other
cameras in to get this. It was about
2,400 bucks at the time. They get up to
about 3K now. That's the cheapest Leica
system you're probably going to get
that's any good. This one also has a
discontinued battery now. You need to
get it with a battery. They don't make
the batteries anymore. But this is all a
positive thing because it means it is a
more attainable than trying to get a $6
or $7,000 one. And again, you will be
shocked at the quality of the camera.
Their lenses are also super expensive.
But the plus side of this particular
M240 is there are two Voitlander lenses
in particular of the 50 mm that are
relatively affordable that have a look
that is just as good as anything Leica
has which I cannot say about any of the
other Leica models. Leica also has a
really interesting world of oddball
lenses. Like I mentioned in the creative
toolkit, this is important things if
you're an art director or creative
director to think about is how do I have
a unique look to me? So, there is a
company called MS Optics that make
lenses for Leica in Japan that are pets
lenses or really weird lenses that they
have. You get interesting effects on
weird types of bokeh, strange lengths.
They're just kind of oddball craft
lenses that only kind of Japanese
enthusiasts are into. That's a really
fun way to elevate your art. So, now
let's move on to video. And I'm going to
give video thoughts in a couple price
ranges. This is the Osmo Pocket 3. I had
high hopes for this to replace my iPhone
for the vlogs I do while traveling. That
did not really happen. and I'll be
honest about it, is super finicky and
that if you hit or tap this gimbal
system at all, it just doesn't work
super well anymore. But also, it is just
not that much better than the iPhone for
vertical video. And for ease of use, I
found myself shooting on the iPhone all
the time and just do not use this for
short form vlogs. Now, that said, if you
shoot in log, which means you're doing
your own color correction and you really
care about it, this is an awesome little
machine for YouTube B-roll, for
horizontal B-roll. You can get stable
cinematic footage and just snatch up
tons of extra content with this really
well. It is also a great little trick
camera where you can do things like face
tracking or really interesting panning
shots in a really small form factor.
These are like 4 or 500 bucks. If you
want to play into the strengths of this
again to have it in your toolkit or if
you're using it for a lot of YouTube
B-roll, I think that's one of the only
cases I would say this is fully worth
the money. I'm also not a big fan of the
DJI mics. I think they sound
significantly worse than the road
wireless mics. I know they're very
popular, but I think it's mainly price
point and convenience of workflow. Their
audio does not live up to the hype. My
budget pick for most people who want to
get started and film video for social
media and want to have it look way above
what they spent is the Sony EV10. You
are getting these for $6 or $800. You
can use the full ecosystem of Sony
lenses. You can get into that world of
Sony color correction. And you'll see
really awkward stuff like a camera
that's way smaller than this with a lens
this size on it because that's what
you're going to end up when you're using
EV10. but is an awesome way to get
started in that ecosystem. And I've seen
now creators and brands be shooting
essentially movies on the lowest quality
kind of Sony's like that just with some
good lenses. If you want to move a step
up in between getting those kind of
entry level cameras, but getting
something like an FX3, which this is
shot on now, and then this is an FX3
here, which we'll talk about in a
minute. A lot of people talk about the
FX30. This is one of those that's in the
middle of the Sony line. I actually
don't think that this is the value to go
in the middle with. I think the S52
Lumix. This is the one that everyone uh
I know in the creator world is talking
about because it's sub2K. It's closer to
$1,500. It has what's called opengate,
which means you can shoot in horizontal
and vertical very well together. And the
quality, bang forbuck, is uh I think
it's significantly better than the FX30.
It's not as good as an FX3, but at the
price point, that is a wonderful
mid-range camera. And look, this stuff
changes all the time. It'll be different
last year versus this year. But if
you're looking for these calls like
right now to build out that toolkit, I'd
say this video will be ultra relevant
for the next like 6 or 9 months and
it'll be a whole different world. But
that is the camera of the moment. Rare
Panasonic W. And then now we need to
talk about the FX3. The FX3 is a miracle
of modern science. Do not let anyone
else tell you that anything different.
The quality you get out of this camera
from a cinema quality is incredible. If
you look at these incredible series on
social media, you might think people are
shooting them with an REI or a Red or
some crazy expensive camera, they are
probably shooting it on an FX3 that is
between three and $4,000 and just looks
truly too good to be true. So, I've shot
all these YouTubes on. You can tell the
ones where I don't. And if you want to
go make a pro series looks as good as
humanly possible on social media, there
is basically no better system for you
than to get that camera. What I have
seen a lot of now is people getting that
and then getting some lights. They'll be
getting like two Amaran 300's or one
Aperture 600 because an aperture light
isn't an aperture light and they will be
able to shoot those full series. You
might see series with multiple people
talking or angle switching back and
forth. I've been on sets where it is one
guy with an FX3 and one lens and one
light just looking and then turning it
the other way with the tripod right away
shooting back and forth and making
literally these videos that that look
like you've had a high production shoot.
Like this is the world that we're in now
where one person with that can do the
absolute most on social media. And so if
you are looking to get the best bang for
the buck at the higher end, then that is
the system to go with. Now I'll end this
video with a really really important
concept because there's this whole idea
of gear acquisition syndrome. You always
want to get more gear and more stuff.
It's how I ended up with hundreds of
thousands of dollars worth of camera
gear floating around my office. The
answer for 90% of people is the best
camera and system for you is the one
that you already have. getting one fancy
thing isn't going to change your life. I
love this idea of a toolkit, especially
for art directors and creative
directors. Say, I have all these things
in my toolkit I can use to make a shoot
better. I invest in those things. But
you'll notice the ones I listed there,
$100, $300, $400. Those are cheaper
items you can have that you, it's okay
if it serves a purpose once in a while.
Investing in those big systems and
cameras when you already have something
decent is an excuse to not create. And I
cannot repeat that enough. Now, if your
company is like, "What package do we
get?" or "We need to set up our own
internal studio. What do we buy?" Guide
them towards the capability to say,
"Hey, we're going to get two of these
lights. We're going to get this FX3,
this tripod, and two or three primes."
And you will be in literally the best
shape of your life. And it's worth it to
know that like as a strategist to
understand who's being taken advantage
of or what shows up with who when. But
don't get weird. If you have
videographers or photographers you book
that show up and have some oddball stuff
or something you've never heard of or
I've never talked about in these videos,
they're picking that stuff cuz they have
it. They're using it for a reason.
They've probably gotten really good at
it. Anyway, I hope this video saves you
some time as you make some of these
decisions. Helps you think a little bit
more through what the camera journey
looks like. For someone who may not be a
photographer, but wants to have gear or
be in the conversation around this or be
able to shoot a bit on their own to
complement what they're doing,
understand it from a marketing level. I
appreciate you all watching. I will link
all these. So, down below, I will have
like a worksheet where I kit all these
out. They probably won't be affiliate
links or anything. I've never done
anything like that. I'll probably just
list it so it'll be easy for you. You
can find that in the description. I
appreciate y'all watching so much. Thank
you.