today we're going to talk about creative
careers and advice that I would give as
someone in my late 30s who's achieved a
lot of what I consider to be creative
success for people at any stage whether
you're 16 18 25 35 but you're looking to
make that transition into a more
rewarding creative life and figure out
your trajectory so why am I qualified to
give any level of advice to you about
this uh this was a video about making
money which is not a little bit but not
like go make money online I'd Flash the
G wagon and the cybertruck and talk
about you know this or that how much we
make a month but this is not about what
creative fulfillment is like and I've
gotten a lot of those things but not
necessarily from creativity from the
entrepreneurship that spawn by
creativity but the biggest Flex that I
can give is that I only work on
interesting things I get to select every
day the really most interesting stuff
that's come into my life I've been able
to find period and work specifically on
that little to know direction that I
have to take that would be bad from
other people this for a lot of creatives
is a real Grail and you combine that
with the fact that you have freedom you
can say I don't want to work on this or
I do want to work on that and I have the
time in your day to actually go position
yourself whichever way you you know
whether as long as you're making enough
money to survive creatively and you have
those freedoms or you can say no I don't
want to work on that you're working with
direction that is decent and
collaborative versus someone telling you
what to do and you're working on
interesting things that's an amazing
life and it's really hard as a creative
to get there without really positioning
yourself and we're going to walk through
a ton of different ways and times in
your life and decision points and things
you'll need to do to kind of build
yourself into that Mark so I'm in my new
studio space I've been converting my
garage into a better film and working
Studio I'll document some of that in
some other videos but uh for those of
you that have watched a bunch of my
stuff before hopefully you're happy I'm
out from behind my unreadable whiteboard
and you'll see a bit of how my creative
environment more spased on the things
I'm working on and how we adjust this
space over time so first off if you're
creative people often focus on one thing
you want to be a designer an art
director a photographer whatever it is
videography creating influencing but you
need to develop a more holistic skill
set and the sooner that you jump into
that and just do the basics and it's
truly easier than ever with the things
we have online to give us a baseline the
better off you're going to be you need
to be able to design you need to be able
to edit video you need to be able to
compellingly write it is an amazing plus
if you can sell and I would highly
recommend to learn to do it as painful
as it is and then email marketing Basics
we're going to talk about all five of
those things and why they matter and how
you learn but really you can learn it
through jobs where they actually help
you learn those things in the real world
you can learn it through courses is I'm
a decent proponent of like going and
buying something that teaches you how to
do stuff I did my first Tik toks because
I bought this guy Jimmy Farley's course
I had no idea where to begin and it was
some of the best money I ever spent now
he's blown up and uh you can go check
his Lambo on his page and then just
YouTube and the internet which is how
like I went to school for graphic design
but I've learned way more about
illustrator on YouTube than anywhere
else and books mentors however you
choose to learn doesn't matter just go
chase these down if you can do those
things you will be able to make money
for yourself or at good jobs forever you
will be be universally useful in any
branding or creative job if you're
starting out and trying to master these
new skills I'll dive in that in a second
so first what do I mean by each of these
so design if you are a creative and you
want to be a creative director or an art
director or you want to actually manage
and execute projects the ability to
graphic design is absolutely imperative
you might want to argue that oh I don't
need to have that skill set you should
have that skill set it will make
everything you do significantly faster
and better so how do you actually learn
to design what does that mean just
really learn how to have Photoshop
illustrator canva for for Basics like
locked in my favorite way to approach
how to learn this is tied into how you
can learn all these we'll get to there
in a minute but you should be able to
open illustrator and create almost any
idea that you have in your mind take it
to like a 70% version because a lot of
design when you get to management and
finishing is going and passing it to a
specialist who can take it to 100% you
should be able to bring that Vision
enough to life that someone will see it
and be like that's sick I understand
where you're going and then take it to
the completion rate or make it better
then we have editing and I don't mean
need to go into Premiere Pro and be some
like insane video editor but you should
be able to have cap cut make quick edits
of stuff piece a couple Clips together
add music cut things to the beat know
how green screen effects work do the
basics and a lot of this is around being
able to document your own work or to be
able to understand and explain to people
how to make things succeed on social
media because whether we like it or not
a ton of creative work is going to be
shown on social we're going to be judged
by social and your ability to say Hey
what if you just edited this slightly
different is almost imperative to making
sure that your stuff gets seen and that
some of the things you work on actually
have success in the world and it is
really not that hard cap cut has changed
the game for how easy video creation is
and you can can be a full professional
like in a sick and twistedly short
amount of time now we get to writing
writing is just having Clarity and depth
to your thoughts and for a lot of visual
people they kind of ignore the writing
side of it some of them have leaned into
writing early and you'll see people that
have them intertwined but if you aren't
you consider yourself a visual person
it's worth developing the Frameworks
with which you can convince people or
explain your decisions and rationale
through writing I'll talk a bit about
strategies for that later in the video
then we have selling and this is the
hardest one but the idea that when
you're in front of somebody you can
pitch stem on a thing and understand how
to not make it about you make it about
them and their pain points and explain
the value of it and try get money from
them is a huge difference between being
able to get the work that you want and
be able to get compensated the way you
want for what you're doing and not and
this is one of the hardest skill sets to
learn and I learned this by literally
being in outbound sales which is truly
brutal like call center level hey we're
just dialing down a list and a lot of
people don't want to do that totally get
it that is the easiest way to do it but
there's a lot of like psychology and
courses and Basics on this online that
will at least get you somewhere but the
number one thing you can do in that
position is just be in the pitches and
in the sales process at wherever you
work and I do recommend anyone who wants
to have serious creative career even if
you want to be more entrepreneurial or
freelance go have some of those jobs at
agencies or places where you have to
sell and try to insert yourself as part
of that process because the sooner you
learn how to have a compelling pitch in
front of somebody to make a compelling
deck to price your services in an email
to know how to respond when someone says
that's too expensive or to know you know
when you have an opportunity to continue
a contract or expand a contract and ask
for more are like critical skills to get
and then email marketing Basics and this
is basically I just mean the ability to
create a campaign in any email service
create an Automation in any servers
which is when an automatic email
responder comes when someone signs up or
does an action if you can do those
things you are both very useful inside
companies you have because surprisingly
few people do I kid this now it used to
be like five years ago no know how to
make a PDF right but making a PDF is
very easy now tons of people don't know
how to send an email campaign but it is
also very easy and you're going to want
to in your career whether it's for your
business or whether it's for you as a
freelancer or whether it's a company you
work at or you start your own thing or
you become a Creator or whatever it is
you are going to want to do email
marketing and it is dumb easy and if you
have just gotten that basic level skill
set and you know to implement it all the
time it is just an immediate double
digit increase and however much money
you can make at almost anything you are
working on so how do I learn all these
things especially when you have your own
life around you and I'll say uh I always
used to think I didn't have enough time
and now I'm a father and I really don't
have enough time and so all that time
you think you don't have unless you're
sitting around with like three kids and
even then you probably have the time you
have it like there's so much ability to
spend time working on things and on
improving yourself and if you're tired
or you rather zone out or scroll or
whatever it is like that is not a
valuable use of your time you could take
15 minutes 20 minutes to do what I'm
about to describe to you and that is
complete one thing a day in your
educational journey and this is
something I still do absolutely
constantly I'm working on this right now
learning how to sketch better but
literally I mean one thing a day to
learn how to do any of those five things
I talked about prior design edit write
sell email Market pick and learn how to
do one thing a day and here's how so I
talk about this with people who want to
design all the time because all these
people ask how do I become a creative
director how do I do what you do and I
go like if you haven't learn how to
design don't even talk to me but if you
do want to learn how to design here's
how you do it and I would literally
start with YouTube tutorials with
illustrator in particular learn how to
make illustrator shapes that's one day
learn how to curve type that's another
day how to round corners how to make
threedimensional objects how to name
layers and folders intelligently how to
make things proportional to real life
how to make gradients complex gradients
how to erase backgrounds the basics of
how to retouch how to make a thumbnail
photo treatments collaging layer merging
that's just a start just go through that
list you learn that you have a really
decent Chuck of how to use illustrator
and you're going to kind of be a weapon
but literally pick one thing in
Photoshop or illustrator every day same
with cap cut and I'll list some things
out for a cap cut how to add captions
how to use key frames how to use a green
screen effect how to fix audio how to
retouch a person how to edit a bunch of
Clips together to music again just roll
down that list capcode is a free app you
can learn a bunch of that on canva free
or on like Photo which is free and in
the cloud it's a version of Photoshop if
you can't dive into illustrator but one
thing a day literally for the rest of
your life 15 minutes to learn one of
those things and if you do that 365 days
maybe we'll do a challenge on this
sometime but 365 days you're going to
learn from 0 to 365 the skill set it
takes to be a successful creative if you
have spent 365 days and you've done 45
things in illustrator 20 things in
Photoshop 30 things in cap cut you know
20 writing exercises of of X or Y if you
actually gone through 365 days of
spending 15 minutes to a half hour of
improving one skill in your life every
day you are going to be a weapon in one
year and you know cool you don't have to
do every day yet you kind of do if you
just make it a habit and a routine in
your life where you're always spending
that time to do something that's how you
actually get things done and like I
mentioned I'm 38 I'm for all intensive
purposes very successful I still do that
all the time because I'm adding to my
toolkit I plan to be relevant and I want
to be relevant when I'm 65 as a designer
as a creative as a Creator and if I keep
upping my skill set and understanding
how the world changes around me I am
knocking things off that list and all it
takes is one thing a day now we're going
to get into a mind State and that is
archive all of your work online this is
something I wish I'd done I do a decent
amount of now and plan to do more of in
the future but really you need social
media and you need a Blog I talked in my
previous creative Direction video about
when Virgil reached out to Samuel
Ross about working on some stuff and was
just like hey do you have a portfolio
and Samuel Ross was like here's
portfolio one here's actually this sub
portfolio of other weirder stuff here's
a Blog I explain all my decisions about
this in depth here's my theoretical like
he just had like a list of like here's
all the references that show not just
how I work and the quality of my work
but how I think and when someone fires
that back when they're interested in
your work like that is a sure fire
higher that is the kind of thing where
you're like oh like these people not
only have the ability to design like
this they also have the ability to
explain it and then they are taking the
time to actively showcase themselves
online even if the work is mid compare
that to anybody else and you are at
least putting through the process to get
somewhere so for every single single
thing you complete whether it's
something you're working on at work
something you work on personally or just
hey when you actually went and learned
some of those things in illustrator you
created or made an exercise put it
online and write about it to write about
it we're going to talk about why you're
going to talk about the inspiration you
have behind it how you did it what
you're proud of about it and what you
would do better about it and this is
important right CU When you write about
things even if the things you make
aren't good when someone sees it and
they see the ability for you to say
here's what I like about what I did
here's why I did it and here's what I'm
going to do to get better that shows the
ability of someone to take the steps up
inside their design career or inside
this would be video editing art dire
whatever it is that you're doing
photography but being able to think
critically about that both establishes
you to other people and to yourself
because now you're thinking every day
here's why what I did could be better
next time or here's why I like this or
didn't but you have to have that thought
of here's what I would do better because
then you're consistently improving and
you're basically giving yourself a road
map to enable your own success and a lot
of this comes from having to write about
it being able to articulate these things
as a skill not many develop and all it
takes is reps if you're weird about it
you don't want to showcase your stuff
online just be anonymous we live in this
amazing world where people don't have to
know it's you you can literally say
instead of John putting stuff online
it's going to be JJ Studios or whatever
it is come up with a creative name put
stuff on the internet and just make sure
you're continuing that process because a
lot of this isn't just for other people
it's for you for you to look back the
reason I wish I had this is I'd love to
look back on every single thing I
designed websites logos you know
restaurant menus from the beginning of
time and look at that Arc and I don't
have that scenario for me and the
computers disappear and go away being
able to look at that archive and then
watch your work and your life transform
along with it is a really powerful thing
and if you do become someone legendary
or you do work on things that are
incredible and you're going to want to
go tell that story you now have the
ability to do it and the best upside is
people are going to follow along with
your journey Journey either as fans or
potential clientele and then to become
something bigger than yourself that
really enables you to succeed in the
world this world we have is so heavily
built on network effects and network
effects from unknowns just people that
find you on the internet that it's worth
leaning into if you're wondering where
you're going to get the time for this
that's next I'm just going to tell you
right now you have so many hours create
instead of consume and when you consume
consume intentionally I mentioned it
before but I look back at life before
kids and wonder what did I do with my
time and now every single moment I am
humming because I have to to be I was
out with my family this morning I set up
and hit these this video and a Tik Tok
that I was doing earlier I'm going to go
out to another activity I will be back
and I have a whole set of like six or
five things it's a Sunday I'm organized
to a tea because I have no other choice
to achieve my goals and still spend
great time with my family than to do
that if you're not in that scenario you
have the time if you are in that
scenario you need to organize and want
the success to that level and if you
know you have time you should do one
learning a day like we talked about one
design a day or creation a day again
photo shoot video whatever it is that
you are passionate about and post every
day if you have 2 hours to scroll or
watch TV what I just talked about is now
your 2hour process that replaces that
and it is so so so worth it imagine in
100 days if you had designed 100
t-shirts or whatever it is you're into
or made 100 outfit videos or drawn 100
logos or made 100 animations how closer
to your goals you'd be now multiply that
by if those hundred things were online
okay I I'm already successful I also
still try to design a thing a day I have
hundreds of things in the archives like
I worked on a bag this morning just
sketching it with my son this mind State
and that ability to to put in reps on
anything you do all the time instead of
Netflix or whatever it is is hugely
impactful and a lot of these things you
can kind of do at the same time as long
as you're intentional but this ties into
the bigger challenge because a lot of
people can shift that mind state from
consumption to Creation once it's just
sitting there in the back of your head
and it's pounding you I need to create
instead of consume I need to create
instead of consume but it does lead to
something in your life that is hard to
tackle which I'll call Creative
loneliness this is the biggest challenge
it really sucks because you need to
separate your time and goals from those
around you unless they share the same
goals in which case you're really
blessed cuz most people don't often have
that you need to find people in your
life that do things to completion and
then do things with them if you have
people in your life that share the same
interest in things as you but they don't
ever actually do anything that's almost
more of a harm than a good and either
you're pushing them to complete things
with you or it's a hard weight that you
may not want to have if you don't have
any people around you that actually
complete things or do the projects or
that are bettering themselves you need
to find them because you need that
community and luckily we have online to
actually make those friends and have
those relationships online you need to
have everything with a purpose you can't
just DM people like hey D I like you
whatever you need to dm with a purpose
right you need to connect to other
people that actually do things to put
out a scenario with which you do things
together I recommend finding people at
your level or slightly above you can
find on the internet and sending them
messages with a purpose say hey do you
want to try to do a thing hey I'd love
to collaborate on a t-shirt design with
you whatever that is how do you make or
succeed in a thing or hey I'm try to
start a book club whatever it is do a
thing with intention that allows you in
that person to do something together
versus just messaging about stuff and it
may just be hey want to join a creative
group chat talk about packaging all the
time whatever that is but it needs a
prompt and a finish but people you have
creative action with make the world go
around not just creatives you know or
people that share the same likes people
you can do creative action I'll say that
again because that becomes your whole
world if you have two people like that
it's better than zero if you have 100
people like that you can make the world
turn and this goes to the next piece I
ask about this a lot can you be
successful as a creative without living
in a major city some people can but it
certainly makes it way easier to at some
point especially earlier in your career
be in New York la London Paris you need
to break out of your comfort zone learn
big city operation and speed and be
around the people in inspiration and
also choose to interact in places like
that which is important if you can
figure out New York like that is the
place that is the Tried by fire La is a
good place to go later on or a good
secondary and also think about those
transitions every time you move your
network expands if you're stuck in your
town or you're stuck in a place for
Comfort there's such a big effect I've
moved a lot of times in my life I grew
up in Hawaii a college in Arizona I
moved to New York after that to Austin
after that I moved to LA Southern
California
now Orange County I've moved a bunch I
have a network from each of those times
I do business with people from each of
those eras I still make money from
across all of those and have friends and
network from without those people often
ask me how do you know so many people
how's your creative Network so big how
do you have all these work and a lot of
it just comes from the fact I was in all
these different places met all these
different people and had a reason to
stay in touch with them and to be
someone interesting to them every time
you move your network expands and in
these places you will find people that
are more akin to what you are looking
for and you will be able able to prove
to yourself a lot more than staying
whatever small town you're at and there
are distraction cities like Miami is a
distraction City and there's places that
seem more artsy that might be a step
from where you are if you are somewhere
super small to go to like a Portland or
whatever but there's a massive
difference between what happens there
and what happens in a New York or LA and
if you at these places and you're trying
to be around people or make friends or
just feel more like a community like the
number one and two advice I give there
sounds so simple is smile a lot more and
compliment people if every day you are
complimenting people wherever you go
like your
amazing fit oh you're reading that book
that was a great whatever you are just
engaging and putting more things out
there and you'll be surprised how much
comes back the last thing I'm want going
to talk about is working if you're a
creative I really believe before you
strike out on your own to go freelance
or be an entrepreneur you should have
brand experience and agency experience
at least two years or so at each and be
the person when you do that like choose
to be a working person for x amount of
your career I'm going to do four years
I'm going to do six years whatever it is
and be the person who takes that super
seriously even if it sucks even if it's
the wrong place whatever it is be the
person that is friendly down for
anything there early leaves late being
in those environments where you learn
how those work and then being the person
that's just doing a little bit extra
there where so few people are doing
extra now and are so against what that
looks like will'll open up a ton of
doors for you and show you the
difference that working makes versus not
and you'll have the Frameworks now for
how decisions are made in a brand side
company or an agency side company and
ask those questions be the person that
wants to be it sit in the extra meetings
do the extra things jobs exist as
learning experiences to prepare you
better for when you make your own money
take as much Advantage as you humanly
can in in those scenarios and try to see
both sides of the coin because for a lot
of people when you go to make your own
money you're either going to want to
have an agency and provide services or
you're going to want to have a brand and
do your own thing and then either way
you'll probably be retaining or working
with the other ones and so that
understanding even if it's just for a
few years or the basics of how those
work will go a long long long way and
for some people might be a decade like
in my own journey I was doing a lot of
things and freelancing of it the
beginning of it and then worked
full-time for about a decade before I
really got entrepreneur and that was
because of me and the things I had to go
through and my financial background and
certain things that like made it I had
to get to a certain place but that 10
years was Ultra valuable to be able to
be more entrepreneurial and it's okay to
take that much time you have a ton of
time in your creative Arc and don't feel
bad if there are younger people doing
better everyone's circumstances are
different but with that when you work
those jobs I think it is hugely
important to make your own money
separate from those jobs and this could
be $100 and that could be the goal make
$100 a month outside of your work from
doing something directly and here's why
this is important is you begin to juggle
cuz real entrepreneurship real freelance
real creative stuff you are juggling
even if you're working on one thing
you're kind of always working on a few
things just the ideas in your head or
whatever comes up or you got brought
into this with a friend it's going to
happen learn how to juggle it and
figuring out what it takes to even
receive your own1 $200 a month th000
5,000 whatever it is how do you make an
invoice how do you avoid paying
self-employment tax I need to get an LLC
and maintain it how do I set that up
business bank account versus a normal
bank account having an understanding of
how that works once you've gone through
it once you've done it once you can do
it at infin them forever and you realize
both how easy it is and how much of a
gate it is that people are always
dealing with oh m know how to do X or Y
as soon as you figured it out as soon as
you have gotten your first LLC put your
first invoice out there in the world
gotten paid back filed your business
taxes whatever it is and gone through
that list of things you go okay you know
what the first time was annoying but now
that isn't that hard and all of a sudden
if you need to have seven company
structures because of all the insane
things you're working on you at least
have the ability to know how to do it or
enable somebody else to do it these
things become less intimidating by doing
if this sounds like a lot it is but It
prepares you for your creative future
and it is better than consumption it's
better than acceptance of working at a
job forever it's better than not
preparing yourself for something better
and that's really what I'm focused on is
just betterment of yourself as a
creative to put yourself in those
scenarios because if you do the things
that I talked about you work in those
types of jobs you move to a major city
you work on your skill set every day to
improve it you put that out there online
you can be literally whatever you want
to be how bad you are at your skill set
now you will be better than that 365
days of putting that work in later four
years of working throughout that those
are all realistic time frames those are
all ways that will actually be impactful
and I cannot encourage you more to go
chase that down any questions you have I
can hit in future videos definitely drop
in the comments and I appreciate you
watching and I really hope that some of
this uh Sparks some fire