if you've ever lost yourself or even a
brief moment in a really beautiful piece
of aesthetic packaging then this is the
video for you I am an archist some might
call me a hoarder but I get brought in
by luxury brands in particular and
Brands who want something special when
it comes to their content their design
their packaging whatever it is so I
collect all these things that I think
stand out whether that's references on
the Internet or in real life and today
I'm going to walk through a ton of them
all my favorite pieces of packaging that
I have physically and talk about what
makes them special interesting unique
and work and throughout that we're going
to learn a lot about marketing about
standing out on retail shelves about the
consumer experience what the little
things can do as well as brand
positioning and some of the logistics it
takes to create this I have most of
these in a notion database online so you
can actually go investigate the brands
and even if you're not as interested in
The Branding and marketing part of it
it's going to be a real exploration of
lots of beautiful standout packaging and
what makes a tick so I'm going to start
with two of my favorites this Orca water
in the CL so Orca is an interesting one
because they take a familiar idea the
idea of any tin can and they apply that
nostalgic transparent fact there's a
photo that was going around on Tumblr
forever that had a regular siiz soda can
like this with this same looking feel
just clear with the top it would go
viral on Tumblr all the time which I
assume inspired this design the whole
idea is when you look at it on the Shelf
it's something completely different
something unexpected and in addition
they've paired it with an unexpected
product 150 milligrams of caffeine
inside water no calories water and
caffeine as God intended a new brand
we'll see how they do but a standout
form factor that had people excited to
buy it before they even launched that
when they go to retail they're able to
show people hey look at the attention
online we're getting just by virtue of
the form factor of our packaging that's
an important part of the conversation to
have because something unique you'll
notice about everything that I have here
is almost all of it that's sold at
retail is meant to stand out on the
Shelf it's part of two to three key cont
Concepts I'm going to walk through here
today the first is shelf appeal the
second is sharability the third is
luxury experience and the fourth is
consumer experience before we dive too
deep into shelf let's talk about luxury
class isul is a controversial alcohol
you've seen their white and blue bottles
equally as gorgeous and from tequila
purus there's a lot of conversation
about the quality of what's inside as
there will be when any Bland blows up
and charges a premium but for every
detractor there's someone who enjoys it
and spends money on it and has increased
in popularity exponentially when I saw
this Mescal bottle was when I was really
interested because they put all of these
bottles are handmade ceramic by one
specific area in Mexico this is a
handknit yarn top something like I
forget if it was hours or days goes into
every single one of these getting
constructed heavy ceramic you can see
the yarn coming out it's absolutely
gorgeous it's a statement piece what
you'll notice about this that keeps it
stand out is if you go into any
apartment of uh men of a certain age who
partake in the night life you'll see
several of the white and blue bottles
that are on the Shelf but when I got
this bottle this is one that lived on
the Shelf it's in all my videos because
it is essentially an art piece when
you're investing into something that is
a multi hundred bottle of liquor the
idea you could keep the bottle and turn
it into a vase or have it live on the
shelf and have it look good enough and
potentially be classy enough that you
could do that in an adult household
versus the white blue bottles in a a
party house is an interesting concept
that drives longevity and luxury value
for a new brand one of the concepts I've
always been obsessed with is the speed
of luxury cuz I feel luxury takes time
to really cement and there's brands that
have skipped that that can charge a
premium to feel luxury almost
immediately and the bottle is a huge
part of that success for class aul
perhaps my favorite example of this is
Ace of Spades so for those of you who
didn't live through the millennial
nightlife cobra snake era Jay-Z felt
dissed by perer jouet I don't know the
Deep dive story but basically invested
in or partnered with this company to
promote a more lifestyle friendly
version of a premium champagne so in New
York I worked as a a graphic designer at
a bar that had a wall of these all up
and down so when you walked in you
immediately were kind of shocked by the
value of it it was an expensive bar gold
flakes and the drinks $30 drinks back
when that was uncommon now that's pretty
common this was this was very new very
small location L celebrity driven Justin
Bieber was there t pay was there I met
more celebrities there than I've met in
my life you'd be working there one night
and You' be next to Kesha and country
stars whatever it would be they come
there because it was Private there was
no photographers it was small and they
had this premium Vibe and it was
cemented by Ace of Spades as of Spades
wall and this is one of the dummy
bottles from the wall there's not real
champagne in it that I've you kally kept
as a souvenir once that bar got sold and
and moved on but they basically
engineered through the look of this and
celebrity endorsement a speed to Market
of a brand no one had ever heard about I
may have existed forever prior I'm not
100% sure did not research this prior
but was immediately cemented as a luxury
staple and a part of the lifestyle from
the look The feel and the perception cuz
a big part of packaging the luxury
experience is justifying the price point
with the cardier box for example you
spent x amount of money on a watch and
you pull it out of something cheap
you'll probably still feel great about
the watch purchase but opening it inside
this kind of luxurious clasp the
gorgeous inside and the pillow and
whatnot just makes you feel like you're
engaging in a luxury experience and
adding that extra $20 $8 whatever it
cost them to produce that box at scale
onto that purchase really adds that
perception to that storage to the
feeling that hey I made I made the right
choice from the moment that you open up
that package and so for anyone that has
a premium price point is really worth
thinking through what that experience
looks like to the point on reusability
one of the things I like most about the
class isul is you again you'll see it in
homes you will see people keep it Beyond
its usage cuz the underlying
conversation that's hard about all of
this is the sustainability element we
still create so many things to Simply
get thrown away but any brand that puts
the intention and the cost in something
that might get kept is circumventing
that in at least some nature so another
approach beyond the pure luxury approach
is the objects as art let's take a look
at this Skelly tequil so this is one
where Unknown about the the quality of
the tequila this is another one has
stayed in the house that is a sculptural
element that is moving beyond a brand
perception the class zo on the Shelf is
also a statement about a lifestyle this
is more about a statement about an art
something that jumps off a liquor
cabinet shelf A Conversation Piece an
adaptation of the original kind of
Crystal Skull Vodka that many people may
have seen for years it was a you first
rendition of this this is now a
sculptural small edition of this where
for anyone who does make a product in
low volume or low batch adding that
artistic element to it that again might
get saved that makes it a conversation
piece adds to the interest and
perception of the brand that can be
applied in other simpler ways too so
these are host cocktails love this
bottle and the label application of it
premium the labels are super nice look
at the metallic in here I love that
style of the 3on and they come in these
art Edition boxes another brand that
does this in interesting way is margin
Global they're a Cosmetics brand they
really interested piece of art Direction
on each of their different packaging and
they'll change it this becomes a vehicle
for collaborations for interest for
change immediately Associates the brand
for people that want to have that kind
of creative support it's a it's a tactic
on the Shelf I like to break down
packaging I break it into a couple
different styles one is like
straightforward if people just want to
get what's out there the other is
Extreme this brand corova that I I
worked with for a long time is a good
example of that liquid death another
good example of that how do you position
against everything on the shelf by the
extreme angle it's got like hipster New
Wave angles minimal obviously like
overly feminine or overly masculine and
then and then there's always what I call
the art angle and there's this whole
really interesting look from from madre
that was pioneered by the design firm
that did this is firm called land who
did a lot of Brands they did old pal if
you're familiar with them Stumptown
Coffee all their things look vaguely
like because it's a style that they have
they're very prolific they like an
Austin design firm who basically
pioneered this look and feel we now see
obviously not just them do but all kinds
of different brands do it's very
traditional kind of two color old school
line drawing that really feels uh
familiar and interesting and speaks to
like a whole segment of the population
that is intrigued by it both from a
nostalgic perspective it has like that
70s feel that works with older people
down to kind of like a younger hipster
feel at the same time it's probably a
whole another topic for a video but that
firm the idea that we're going to
specialize in a visual style we're going
to apply that to all these different
categories I believe they had some of
their own projects in these categories
as well and then we're going to take our
visual style as a firm and turn it into
a a a trend or turn into something
that's going to stay it gives us power
it gives us facilitation as someone who
visually sets part of the Zeitgeist is
something I think that true kind of
design Visionaries and firms could
really be thinking about if they're
interested in pushing you know like that
angle something that can separate a
design agency apart so as many of you
know um I didn't drink for many years I
actually drink a little bit now so why
do we have so much alcohol so much
premium alcohol and all this packaging
um and I made the choice for about six
years to stop drinking when I had my son
was born I just wanted to be more
present I really realized I was losing
hours to drinking at night I was losing
time being hung over in the morning uh
it was a cost center I really wanted to
optimize my life and make a change that
come came with Parenthood and so I
didn't I stopped uh now I'm back into it
more from an experiential perspective
I'll have something once a month I like
to try new things especially when
there's culturals places like you're
over in China it's hard to even avoid it
and so I don't have strict rules we have
so much in our house because I really
believe drinks and experiences are
facilitators my wife and I love to host
I love to have conversations with people
I love to facil conversations between
groups of people and all of this is a
are conversation starters right from
opening the like the Roco fridge we have
there um and pulling out a beverage no
one's ever seen before or giving them a
choice for having a conversation about
or introducing them to something new is
something I enjoy same thing with
alcohol if you come over you're able to
have a premium experience hey we're
going to pop this $600 bottle of mcal or
we're going to have this ready to drink
cocktail it's really interesting like
we're have a bunch of options that
people can partake in they're going to
think about they're going to talk about
they're going to remember that's the
kind of experiences I want to create and
then also I'm fascinated by how people
perceive things and how their background
perceives things and what things are
like in other places and so getting
people's background or what they enjoy
and why or what appeals to them why is
really interesting to me and all these
things are facilitators of those
experiences and you'll find if you are
like a hosting type you love to have
people over you like to have those
experiences that that pH tell in those
conversations and having tools with
which to do it is a really fun and
interesting angle but then there's
getting to stand out in the retail shop
and this is a really interesting one to
talk about and actually one where I have
more experience so my actual background
I've done a lot more I've done a lot of
small Ecom break Brands and medium Ecom
brands or Ecom for larger brands at
retail but my background is very
traditionally in retail consumer
electronics like in specific
specifically and then some work in cpg
and so I think a lot about the shelf and
what happens the difference between
Boutique retail and mainstream retail
what happens when we sell at a sporting
goods retailer versus when we have that
same product in Walmart is different and
the last brand I was at for those you
don't know when I worked at I worked at
gel blaster for a while as um as sdpa
marketing we were in heavy heavy retail
I'd been in a camera drone company in
heavy heavy heavy retail that prior we
been in Best Buy we were in fak and
France we were in virgin and Dubai we we
were across the world and all these
places and then before that in Outdoors
Brands we were in Bass Pro and Cabellas
and all and like that and then small
specific outdoor shops but with gel
blaster in particular we are selling
toys you're selling them at Walmart and
you're selling them at Costco and
there's a huge perception in the
categories of like what that looks like
and what happens on shelf is almost
everything how do you get your message
across and so what you'll see there that
gets important especially in toys things
like color blocking so I'm to bring this
up here this is a package I worked on I
was there for the product called the
Barracuda it's a gel Blaster you will
notice that this is a very green and
black and that was our identity for this
brand green and black for the vast
majority of products with some tertiary
colors and things that came in there
swap some things up occasionally but
that's because we were positioning
against two products Nerf and zuru who
were both red and orange and when you
look at you'll see basically waves of
shelves taken over by how people do
their color and so if you buy one thing
inside that color scheme and you like it
you're going to go by and buy the same
thing there some consumer perception
around that and you look at how do we
get everything we need to get across
like on the front of this box of this
package when you're buying you're
choosing a toy or something complex and
then the cost element like okay actually
showing this having an open box like
this is actually cheaper than having a
full blister cover box and all the
factors that go into that and then the
same thing with what I call the
consideration this is how every retail
Shopper Shops look at the front of the
package they have a package they like if
they're considering it more they flip it
around and they take a look at the back
it's a cursory look and you have the
opportunity to grab them with a couple
items of Whatever Gets set on the back
you we here have call outs and diagrams
and the ecosystem and all this other
stuff this is the same exact experience
that happens on the shelf for most
consumers they're going to pick up this
energy drink they say look I like this
look I'm going pick up in the back and
I'm going to go okay has 50 calories two
grams of carbs no sugar okay great let
me read the ingredients and but they're
looking at the ingredients panel maybe
they'll look at this like okay there's
uh 10 grams of plant protein that's
actually crazy they get 10 grams of
protein in this thing you know zero
sugar whatever like maybe you'll get
some of the actual panels but that is
how the vast majority of people shop so
you have these opportunities to get
someone step one get it off the shelf
that's hard step two just reinforce it
enough don't mess up enough that they
don't put it in the back right because
the thing that they grab first is most
often the thing that's going to get
purchased and that a big part of the
retail experience and different things
appeal to different people but color
blocking like I mentioned here is really
important so one thing you'll notice the
way this brand United stes of America
has stood out is you go to coffee shops
and all these different places around
the US they have this I first noticed it
at this spot Ola AOS that uh is here in
Costa Mesa you'll see a bunch of these
colors next to each other inside a
freezer that has nothing else with big
color blocking in the same visual style
and it pops you go oh this is a soda but
you look at it next to any traditional
soda it looks absolutely nothing like it
and this is a positioning choice and
they have this organized by Flavor with
a whole variety of colors so you have a
single color positioning and you have a
color blocking positioning that's
important to think about and they're all
aesthetic one by one I think they did an
excellent job with a very simple minimal
look at this brand this someone who's
not often a form of minimalism one of
the most interesting categories to me
inside positioning is hot sauce because
when truff came out with hot sauce they
changed how people perceive it they said
hey we're going to charge three times
the price of what everyone else charges
for hot sauce when you go on the Shelf
it's going to look premium you're going
to see these labels they have the white
one right next to it now they have small
sizes next to that they have this cap
and it's funny when you see traditional
hot sauce caps look kind of like this in
Wood like chalula and stuff like that uh
but now we're going to take it and we're
going to make it premium right so they
basically took a premium approach to a
shelf that had nothing premium on it
charge that price for it when you look
at it you see all these chaotic labels
see all this wood and then you see black
in this sculptural top and you see a
whole block of solid color that is
positioning against everything else is
on the shelf and then pricing higher
than that now that's EX sit on the shelf
for a while which has introduced people
to the concept of a premium hot sauce
then in comes one of my favorite
packages recently nepotism project Cloud
23 i i w be a hater but it's a uh it is
is one of the Beckham children it is in
fact I won't be a hater because uh I'll
keep the comment in but it's an
excellent hot sauce this is a great one
the sweet jalapeno I actually use all
the time they did a fantastic job with
this this bottle is gorgeous and
expensive this top is pretty much like
the other tops like a chalula or
anything it's familiar it implies that
it's a hot sauce but it's elevated and
the label is like nothing else in the
category it's standing out through
virtue of its illustration look and feel
and then the product is excellent so
they had that Trifecta celebrity
endorsement incredibly high quality
packaging someone else that paved the
way for a premium category I don't think
this could exist on the Shelf without
truff on the Shelf to trailblaze that
and so now they're giving an alternative
for people that have tried this category
and go well you know I don't want the
truffle taste every time I want to try
some other things and this is a really
good sauce we're both of these fall flat
is in the consumer experience in my
opinion hot sauces are great these caps
like leak and the dispenser of it is
like just not you can see there's like
stains on across the board so I've used
these so some work there but excellent
job in the positioning on shelf that's
some of the psychology you think about
why people make these things this way
and what you should think about if
you're putting together your brand and
then the cost for this is interesting
this is a relatively standard bottle get
a rela standard glass bottle here and a
sculptural cap and label this cap was
expensive to get a onetime mold you'll
see they run the same mold in two
different colors in white and black they
had a onetime fee for that other than
that this is not like yeah maybe they
got a custom glass mole for this bottle
but it's pretty straightforward and so a
little expens a little more premium than
your average one but nothing absolutely
crazy this this is very expensive
default cap maybe threaded differently
for the top but like this bottle was not
cheap had an expensive mold and it's not
cheap per those are the kind of things
to think about as a brand but if you
don't say you're a marketer and you're
putting together your packaging how do
you think about that if you don't have
that price point that's where I love to
call out brands that can stand out
another way so like visitor is a great
one this is a uh like a low Al beer or
like a molted water near beer literally
just a sticker on the raw can or a print
on the raw can looks like a sticker well
print on the back for the label this is
an excellent way just picking it down to
its element it's it's gorgeous this is
not an expensive can didn't even have to
have a wrap I was there's some cost
differences between WAP and and print on
Direct maybe it's slightly you get get
the point someone like Gia they're
taking a premium positioning they have
multiple stickers a sticker placement on
here again default can just with a
choice of what they print on with labels
these are really nice matte label with
an actual finish on the actual lettering
so that's actually probably pretty
pricey there are all different ways you
can approach how much you want to spend
on your packaging versus a custom form
factor that's going to be expensive
speaking of custom form factors this is
the freaks of nature bottle this is
sunscreen love this color reveal one of
my favorite tactics when you have
products we'll look at that with blanked
here in a second I have a dispenser in
here this look and color pattern what I
like about this is a it's a cool form
factor for sunscreen where I always used
to these tubes but if you are actually
anybody that like is surfing or rolling
out anywhere this is actually an easier
form factor to like pocket or put in a
simple bag or anything like that then a
longer tube this looks cool on shelf
again will look nothing like other
sunscreens that are on it to that point
I'm going to do a quick call out for
vacation one of the best brands in my
opinion of the last decade they present
everything vintage and it's funny when
you go um I did this beauty Report with
uh with band group we did all these
Trends in Beauty and I went to different
stores Ulta Sephora all these places
with people I know that work in beauty
or take Beauty really seriously to shop
with them just to as part of the
research of the trend report we did all
these visits and vacation is in Ulta
with a whole display and just looks like
absolutely nothing else in the store it
has this vintage nostalgic appeal across
all these different packages this is
just one here tied into a brand that
leans all the way into that where they
literally said we're going to be a
period piece and we're going to have fun
with it and all our packaging is going
to look like that and we are nothing
like anything else in the category and
they have dominated that's a strategy to
think about when you look at a cool pack
packaging this leads us to the extreme
angles so I'm going talk about corova uh
briefly corova is a brand that I worked
for I was the president of the company
that owned it for for a minute and we
had all these packaging in our Niche
it's a niche I don't want to get banned
for saying but you can probably guess
where we chose to go this all black
metal Acid Trip route on everything this
is a hot sauce package we did Heavy
iconography the idea being that there's
always people on the shelf that will
look for that extreme angle or that dark
angle or that counterculture angle there
always a position Brands can take now
let's move over to a few of my friends
over here the David protein bar may have
seen these they're very popular online
right now does it look familiar well um
Andrea from the snackshot pointed out
that it really resembles the old school
Power bar means it's innately familiar
to a wide variety of older users which I
think is critical when you think about
things are universally appealing like we
have with the the Madre Mescal over here
and some of these things that like can
appeal to older people who find it
somehow familiar while to younger people
that feel it's cool and this was a uh a
great choice of branding I feel like for
them simplistic familiar and when you
see the package because how proliferate
is on Tik Tok like you know immediately
what it is and that's important so they
did took a Tik Tok shop strategy I've
heard some conversation around this
because they're so ubiquitous on Tik Tok
shop they are everywhere they have
creators just hammering it because it
works and I've done hundreds of
thousands of dollars in their first
month on Tik Tok shop and when you see
things that are that ubiquitous there's
just a muscle memory of like gold
package gold package gold package gold
package that when some that comes with
this Grand recognition when you combine
those two things of this standout
package and this repetition of people
seeing it even just it being so basic as
it being gold is a thing thing that
works in consumer Minds quick shot some
coffee packaging I like project coffee I
like the little guy is the sticker big
fan of stickers with little people on
them little personality things like that
I don't have a glow nuts package here
but glow nuts has like the founders
faces on the back and they'll have
little like their aisle interrupts and
stuff at retail those little like popups
you have in there we'll have the
founders on them be like we need to sell
more glos to pay for our wedding it's
like a married couple or something it's
it's really fun and interesting same
those little characters putting little
pops of Personality like that is fun
another great package I love for coffee
actually dented this dropping it walking
in here that they have this like matte
in leg for Onyx and this like display on
it that uh I quite like that again is
standout let's get into body for a
moment we'll end with uh with blanked so
first this is muscle go this is a
product I have with landforce this is
one of mine you can buy it at muscle
g.co it is a competitor to things like
Biofreeze and B that have like really
terrible ingredients so we made a whole
bunch of ingredients that are actually
good for you it is 87% organic 19
essential oils and there's an opening
like that in almost any category to say
hey are these things bad for you let's
make a healthier Alterna which is what
we did with this and then you'll notice
why we have this packaging the way it
does we made it big we use this raw
silver look that we like as you can tell
I have it in a lot of packaging focuses
here that we took some inspiration from
nice big big logo on here we'll probably
move that cap to Silver over time we
went with a default cap to start we went
with this big size because there are
some consumer feedback that like you
know we want to charge a higher price
point for this because it's expensive
it's organic we're competing against
cheaper products I'm like okay what is
one way that we could stand out from
that and one is you kind of feel like
you're always skimping when you go put
some stuff on like a muscle cream River
because you're going to run out you're
using through a bunch of it you're
squeeze some out the tube you want to
put a ton on so we're like great you
know what let's give people what they
want let's give them the biggest tube
the biggest option that you can get like
as a standard option which justifies
being able to charge slightly higher
price point makes people feel like they
can use it liberally which is the whole
idea how it works better and then if it
ever goes up on a retail shelf next to
the competitors that we have it both
looks visually striking at that scale
and you'll go all right well cool like
hey it might be a little more expensive
but I get a ton of it and so those are
kind of things to think about when you
have some considerations now Cosmetics
is one of the most interesting ones this
is ker Weiss I'm probably going to
butcher that pronunciation you'll see
they have these metal reusable compacts
that are super premium that are
geometric there's this like design
approach to doing anything in this
industry but being something that the
reason these objects are so important is
because if you choose one a compact and
you keep it yes you may get refills from
another brand you're probably going to
get refills from the brand you have the
compact for you know the sizings right
you're reminded of it every day every
time you use it this Cloud compact that
they have excellent see it flips open
here it's cool amorphous shape
completely you see two different
approaches to the same product with the
same overall look how different they
could be and both being super social
media friendly that's where we're about
to get to when I get some of this recap
here BYO they're taking a normal item
like a lipstick holder and they're
taking like a sculptural approach to it
and I really love that idea how do you
take a form factor people are familiar
with and how do you make it art Samaya
Beauty does these crazy ones some of the
other ones I won't show because they're
nuts but obviously like they know this
horse top and they have all these
different themes and motifs again
extremely social media friendly Half
Magic another one more gen Z focused but
these like crazy pill bottle looking Y2K
era is again just a super social media
friendly unique looking that is that is
the standard with which you have to come
as a new brand to stand out and you'll
see something like like ESOP which is
again a good example of this branding
traditionally you may not think is good
it's hard to read there's a lot of
information it's black and white but it
succeeds as a line you know an asop
product whenever you see one whatever it
is and there's something to be said for
that too as far as the differentiation
is the pure standout appeal and then
running that through a myriad of
products something they do an excellent
job with so we're going to talk a bit
about the social media friendly nature
of this why does this matter and a whole
bunch of this packaging why is it why
does it matter what is it worth if
someone gets your product and sends it
to a friend or posts it online on their
story whatever makes a Tik Tok those are
things that happen all the time people
DM stuff to their friends all the time
they message stuff and if your stuff is
cool enough to Warrant that you have a
absolute exponential effect of that
Beyond if you just didn't have it in a
world that is driven on recommendations
is driven on social media you are giving
the opportunity for organic growth and
that a really important thing to think
about speaking of tasteful things I'm
going to pull this out from Brandon at
blent so he's a good example of a
packaging family right CDs love the
color reveals I mentioned on freaks of
nature his packaging all looks feels
like a unit is not cheap we'll pull this
out here but you custom foam and these
cuts and again he is coming at you with
a premium experience for his like
sculptural objects brand it was a new
brand and every moment of it experience
from moment one is helping Drive its
perception of can he justify the price
points and can he continue to sell you
interesting expensive objects and the
way he presented the product and
packaging from day one was probably
worth the investment because it comes
across feeling more like an apple than
it does something that you bought it
like a CB2 no shade to CB2 watch my
house is from there all but thanks for
bearing with me inside this video I love
talking about packaging I love
collecting and these are conversations I
have with Brands all the time as you can
see a bunch of the projects I've worked
on I catalog a bunch of my favorite
packaging at this directory I will link
down here it's a hyper directory it's
free I'm just shouting out a bunch of
things I think are interesting so you
can go to the links and you can actually
find them and hunt them down I don't
believe I have a sponsor in this video
so if you do want to support in any way
muscle. try out some of our muscle
relief gel and if you have any packaging
you love please drop it in the comments
cuz I'm adding to that directory all the
time I want to do this video just with
stuff I had on hand and not reference
bun of stuff that's online if this video
does well and youall like it I will
probably follow up with going through a
bunch of things that are in that
directory and what makes them stand out
and interesting but thank you so much
for watching hope this drives you think
a little more about the aesthetic things
in your life and what you enjoy or not
and why inspires you a bit for your own
Brands thank you so much