all right so weird truth you're going to
be taking picks of your bras your girls
your girlfriend etc for the rest of your
life and if you're creating content in
any field you're going to be continually
involved in taking pictures of people so
this is my guide for anyone to learn to
think like an art director and make
photos whether it's personal or for work
great we're going to cover concepting a
photo shoot from just making the most of
shooting with friends to communicating
full production in a team and we're
going to Deep dive and I'll share tons
of references on composition action and
going pro with things like lighting
we'll go into concepting we'll go into
breaking down a shoot with a cheat sheet
for how you can actually make it work
and I'm going to share tons and tons of
references across a ton of categories
and then we'll go into how do you
actually do this what are the strategies
you can take to get better we're going
to include some homework and some
exercises some example tutorials from
people I really enjoy at the end of the
video you'll walk away with the
intention references and framework to be
able to Arch direct anything in your
life let's do it so we're going to kick
off with a framework what the things you
can do whether you're just out with
friends and pulling things up on your
phone or planning for a shoot to make it
special so the number one rule I try to
use across everything is you need at
least one concept you need one thing
inside a photo to make it different or
stand out you scroll through a feed of
normal and you see one thing that is
different you immediately are able to
capture the eye so we're going to call
this the one thing rule every time you
do a shoot what is your one thing that
separates it from two people just
standing there smiling and then inside
that there's a framework for making a
good shoe and this goes composition how
are you actually framing the shot are
you using an interesting angle or an
interesting position I'm going to break
down references for all these and then
we're going to talk about action and
activities that can make a shoot pop and
if you are not a pro photographer you
don't want to think a ton about
composition the action and the
activities matter the most you'll see
when you talk about a normal image
versus an image when people are doing
something immediately has some kind of
inherent magnetism one of the biggest
ones I like to talk about is food if you
show people eating something or holding
food or in around food it's inherently
more interesting than not same thing
with interaction between people two
people standing next to each other
versus if they're putting their heads
together or they're facing sideways with
their heads together they're holding
hands they're jumping at the same time
whatever it is the action begins to
separate the shootout and that's why
you'll see in a lot of our Direction
people are engaged in an activity and if
you've ever worked with models work with
models on shoots you'll realize one of
the hardest things to do is figure out
what they do with their hands I would
give them something to do hold a bouquet
of flowers playing dominoes whatever it
might be we have your composition you
have your action then there's location
if you do know location ahead of time it
gives you some ways to plan you can look
at other shoots that have been done in
similar places other interesting angles
what you have to work with inside of an
actual place I'll have a bunch of
references that we'll go through here
interesting common ones that you can use
and why they stand out and then's the
pro framework which is lighting we'll
talk about some very basics of this here
today this just get you thinking in the
same way and then provide references in
this other one for what you can talk to
a photographer with so lighting comes
down to some simple things like making
sure that someone is half lit like I am
here there's some light coming on my
face with nothing coming from this way
is a really great way to do it or just
making sure that light is on the person
instead of there being in Shadow or
being intentional about what the light
looks like so when you're going into a
shoot with any friends you can basically
go to that cheat sheet and go okay what
is the composition do I want to shoot
this in wide angle do I want to shoot it
far away do I want to try one of these
things out do I want to take a downward
angle and then what are we doing all
right can we actually get people to
engage in something funny is it actually
a better photo of they thumb wrestling
versus just standing there because just
standing there should you be holding a
bouquet of flowers and smelling them
whatever it is you get an activity how
can you use the location to your
advantage and how do you make sure it's
lit it's basically your cheat sheet to
make something from okay to good now
it's the same thing when you go to do a
shoot with a photographer if you book a
photographer for something and you walk
in you're able to say here's the
location that we're shooting at here's
some pictures of it to set the stage
here's the type of lighting that I like
that I think would make this kind of
photo stand out and let them figure out
how to do it here's some of the
compositions that I like or angles they
know to be able to bring specific lenses
or have different perspectives and
here's some of the actions and
activities that we could be doing while
engaging in the shoot all of a sudden
you've given them a framework they can
work with you be one of the most
organized people they're talking to and
they're going to be able to say oh I
with these ideas I can use these
techniques I can take this wide angle
lens oh I'm going to need to bring a
really specific tripod it'll hold
something for this downward angle oh
this location is great because I can use
this thing and this thing inside the
composition oh they actually want the
light to be a flash instead of natural
and so you're providing that framework
which really can just be a mood board
and you're immediately in the game all
right so now we are going to go through
references for all those topics I put
together and I would encourage you to
duplicate the workflow I have here by
creating your own folders on a mood
board app I'm using Cosmos here a lot of
them are linked into Arena you can use
Pinterest really whatever it is you
prefer and begin putting those together
yourself so you can always go back to
them literally for the rest of your life
for these these shoots so we're going to
start with composition so again what I'm
doing here is beginning to look at what
could I potentially use in a shoot and
this idea of like multiple people
spilling out of a car there's like
lighting directly on them on the car uh
is a really interesting idea same thing
with this one we like out of focus
animal on the front like InFocus model
in the back and this is something you
could replicate with people but I really
like it with the with the dog in
particular and just the downward angle
of like a production floor and this is
where like especially for me I shoot a
lot of BTS Like where things we're doing
on a shoot is like a thing that's really
common for me so when I look for a
composition I look for inside things I
may be doing like this is a shot that I
could definitely just replicate on set
on any number of things I work on same
thing what we have going on here like
the same thing with like the table angle
and obviously you can see the um the
tequila bottle like right there is
awesome downward angle like I If you are
uh shooting a lot of photo like
investing in a stool or like a really
portable ladder or if you know anyone
that lives on like a second floor of a
building there's a lot you can do there
and again this is just like literally
having the model stay still while having
people moving and then lowering your
shutter speed another great one on the
outside of the window inside the window
I'm putting a lot of these in here as
references that you can easily do
they're either using a table they're on
a show Flor like any car obviously this
is like in like a nice Studio
environment you can shoot the same shot
on any like in any vehicle like
underneath the glass is an awesome one
if anyone has a glass table or something
like that you know or that's the kind of
thing you could pick up at Ikea or
Thrift to do a shoot like this that's a
harder one another if you're shooting
wide angle like getting the animal close
and the person backck in the person back
is awesome another foam one where you're
using the hand to to set the framing and
you have some distance like is really
cool more used to that wide angle if you
do have something this is a reflective
or a 3M it's like an easy way to make a
fit pick Stand Out downward staircase
side Way's face is something interesting
you don't see often wide angle and you
can do this on the iPhone with the 0.5
too like getting like the oversized arm
and things like that is always really
interesting to me another one we're like
what can you use to actually frame
something interesting the same way we
saw with the hand being able to do that
again with the blinds or looking through
something I you see I have these
shutters here in my house I could pop
someone outside in the light and like
crack the shutter and like shoot through
it there's interesting things like that
that just again make it a more
interesting visual example if you do
have mirrors digg the two sides of
somebody on that it's great you'll noce
like that downward angle like just being
able to get two steps up on anything
with the stool can really just add so
much to what you're doing just another
great one now there's a lot of tools now
uh in Adobe and similar be a comp people
out of a scene like this so you wouldn't
have to like shut down the street to do
it in fact you could even do this by
like shooting a studio shot or shooting
just a well lit regular shot then cing
it in stuff like this that like you it's
a an easy flip when you do have it but
like someone on the ground like this
there's any number of things you could
do there again the same concept of what
do you have that you can then use to
frame obviously this is a gorgeous scene
but again shooting from inside the tent
wherever you end up being will
inherently make it interesting more car
shots everyone has a car with one of the
easiest Vehicles you can do to make
something interesting no pun intended on
the vehicle reference sitting here you
can guar to yourself some comments if
there shoes on the bed high angle makes
almost anyone look good low angle uh
especially like this is a good way to
make something look almost intentionally
bad this is a reference I actually used
in a valuable video shoot that's coming
up like a straight Diner where we
actually see like the valuable hat on
that it's zooming down but but love that
and you can get I'll show in a different
video how there's like an arm um they're
cheap they like 40 50 bucks where like
you can basically attached to any
surface the arm will go up over it this
probably you probably need like an even
bigger one but there are some pretty
easy ways to get that shot but just
scrolling through this board and you can
see kind of the different ways and
themes we're thinking about it what you
can do with perspective when you're
looking down shooting from buildings is
just a winner any way you can build in
perspective thinking like a film frame
we talked about that that upward angle
view obviously this is like kind more
intense version of that but it's an easy
way to build like a lot of drama and
there's so many examples with with
mirrors both the ones that I show where
like your someone's back up against it
or being able to shoot like into it or a
rear viw mirror it's just a fun thing to
experiment with again that most people
likely have and so when it comes out of
that one thing that we mentioned is like
all right can I what can I use to frame
it can I use a mirror each time can I go
from a downward angle or an upward angle
can I use my vehicle those are all
examples of just adding in that one
thing oh wide angle if you have a camera
with a wide angle lens awesome if you
don't the 05 on iPhone is like a
legendary cannot describe how important
that is for being able to just make
anything stand out like almost
inherently as long as you do something
interesting with it don't just turn it
on if I had a lot more production time I
would have gone through this entire
video and just shot it from all kinds of
unique angles but uh I'm not one of
those people who has who has that skill
set sadly so that was the composition
reference board and I will link all
these as well so you can easily grab
them I would click through to them just
because Arena images pull into Cosmos
kind of odd so I you know I'm like
clicking through it doesn't bring the
fullsize image in but now let's break
down action this is where you really get
things to stand out but again eating
something and being in the scene of
eating something even having just food
in the scene is such a huge win again
this of staring at Art going to a museum
and having people in motion is awesome
obviously climbing but again just
holding something like having whether
it's a vintage video camera something
doesn't need to work another camera we
used to start off shoots when I was
younger we would just literally go
thrifting and see what we could grab and
then like work from there reading is
another one you'll notice I did this on
my on my valuable shoot as well or
basically just the the act of holding a
book like it was a studio shoot but like
it's inherently more interesting and and
uh obviously like a bit of like
everything I do has this kind of
especially when I put the content out
has this like very self-aware like like
almost joking tone and so like reading
catcher of the rise obviously like you
know wearing Louis Vuitton shoes this
this whole like little existential
crisis in action but like again made a
made a studio shot versus him just
sitting there inherently more
interesting by adding the book so books
are are a good one to do inside the
bodega this is a great shoot uh you know
a lot of people reference all the time
like literally just going to the store
and having someone especially if they're
fitted like inside that environment is
awesome inside the lab for screen
printing again the downward angle adds
adds a ton to it the gas station shot
like with a chair I like this idea of
bringing a chair to any interesting
environment I just did a shoot the other
day like put a chair up a hill it just
to kind of inherently add something
interesting to it and there's a lot of
dynamic shapes inside gas stations as
well this one in the pool is awesome and
flowers just the obviously this is like
overwhelming version of it but there's
it's super underrated again like that
furniture in odd places if you do have
the ability you're like one of your
friends has a pickup or whatever it is
like throw something in there really can
take any photo immediately interesting
it's just there's a cognitive dissonance
to things that are outside of their
place cognitive dissonance gets people
to stop scrolling one of my favorite
shots uh embodies basically everything
that I talk about inside this and Stuy
AR directions obviously goated might be
a whole video at some point on there but
like giving the model something to do
they're playing a game the game has the
symbolism of the actual brand logo which
is amazing they're lit incredibly like
the lighting on here is just awesome and
you get that downward shot and doesn't
need to have anyone's faing it doesn't
need to have anyone's emotion in it
purely off of like the characters they
chose the fit and like what they are
doing makes an incredible action photo
and that's so I think games are an
awesome one especially like when it's
unexpected right like getting people in
the you know in the full like aesthetic
lifestyle stuff playing risk or whatever
it's like a just an interesting concept
inherently dragging the garment rack
like outside get anything outside of its
place is is just such a good way to work
through
things all right so I'm going to walk
through a bit of how I actually put
together creative like I use on social
media where I find footage to do that
where I find music and a bit of how I
edit so for me it always starts with
inspiration so I will typically go on to
Pinterest or Cosmos or those and I will
search so vintage ads I'll scroll
through and try to find some layouts I
like like this is a cool layout I look
for something there um actually you know
what I would like this so these kind of
big ones with like a logo a tagline and
like a product that's something where
I'll basically say okay cool I I want to
keep these same elements and I'm going
to think about what I could do that
would be interesting and I'll pop over
to artless so so my brand has like a
pretty good set of like recurring them
so I'm going to search here on Art list
for like drift cars and dust basically
and you can see they have tons of like
pretty high quality footage like this is
a great shot I could 100% make something
out of this that's interesting I don't
if I like the Drone that's sick I could
definitely do something that as I see
like the tight stuff I will star like
this one's already my favorite this is
perfect so reason I like shots like that
is I think aerial shots break up the
feed on reels like really quick it's an
immediate kind of hook and this is great
cuz like the motion goes one way through
the other so I can already see in my
head I'm like cool I can actually put
text and words around this so that like
the car kind of cuts through it in a
cool way and that's an ad idea so I'll
click into this here gives me options of
how I can download it uh I will download
it one of these so I have a file to work
with what I'm working on here today is
just a one shot kind of like a quick
reel I'm trying to get people on a loop
for the next thing I'll do is I will go
back to to music and do the same thing
so there's recommended songs for me
because they already know the kind of
music I work for but they have these
kind of work royalty-free music here
that I can use in my ads so here I'm
going to kind of scroll through all the
different options they have I usually go
into like the hip-hop section or I'll
search instrumental Hip Hop um and that
tends to be where I find the stuff that
works best for for my product I'll grab
a song from there and then I will
usually get a bunch of cutouts I'll have
pgs files of my Logos some of my
products for like the more vintage style
ads and I bring it all over into cap cut
so here you'll see I've put this all
into a layout so I have a shirt cut out
and I have a hat cut out and I locked
him up here uh and then I put a tagline
on here like a racing related tagline so
I've laid it out uh I turned that clip
vertical so this could be 9 by 16 I
think it's tight as it cuts through the
logo and then goes around the shirt and
I've gone through this track that I have
here and I've kind of matched where I
want to be with the Beat of the Music
give you a quick idea of what that looks
like when I play it
[Music]
out but overall that's just a little bit
of my workflow as I put together kind of
like adds stuff for social media that's
where I'll go get my stock footage but
this is a little way you can experiment
with um all the tools and the footage
and stuff that art list has to be able
to make kind of cool ads and assets for
your brand there's more info on artless
in the description here and a big shout
out to them for sponsoring this video
super simple one just I the umbrella
breaking that's what fail to fetch but
you get the idea of just transporting a
speaker like anything they can be
hauling around anything odd and exciting
that downward shy and just killer
wearing the belts if you are getting
someone like working out it's an
interesting angle and shot this is
another there another one I love
especially if you are on a shoot or
doing backgrounds for a shoot is just
get the like the clapboard whatever
references you have to have everyone
fully posed is a really fun one and just
like the AC of being at the beach it
gives you some ideas for action and
things that you could be doing in and
around like what you're working on
obviously examples of like high
production value low production value
but what I would like say is like I
would get I would take maximum Advantage
like don't think about oh I have to do
this exact thing like I need to be in
some crazy place in the Swiss Alps this
concept works just as well in like any
number of places that aren't as
beautiful to be able to like Elevate
something that you're doing and do a
brief stop on location but like what the
little things like I don't have a ton on
this board but just the idea of like
okay can I shoot an artist like in their
Studio what can I do to shoot inside of
a store Etc having a board for that for
locations you're looking at is like an
important thing to think through and
making a specific board for a location
you're going to beforehand to like shoot
a bunch of photos of stuff around it I
think like I cannot State enough like
especially if you are doing regular
shoots in an area like having a list of
like pre-planned things or references
for that like I shoot at the Row in La a
lot a lot of photographers do but like
now I have I shot bunch of references of
like the different types of concrete
they have of like that Garden upstairs
of the things downstairs so we know if
I'm talking to a new photographer hasn't
been there like here's some places we
can go to and here's examples of
lighting so look the way to think about
lighting is that you don't necessarily
need to become a master of lighting I'll
talk about someone who has amazing
lighting tutorials in a minute but you
need to have references to give your
photographer because they're going to
know what to do with they're going to be
like oh that's lit with an external
flash or hey that's a two light setup or
a three light setup like that is their
job but your job is be able to give them
references of what you want even if you
can't explain it to be able to say like
okay hey like this is the actual
lighting style I'm looking for and then
they can go like all this is a hard
light versus a soft light like oh that
have to be shot on film to get that
effect they can give you the
considerations but you want to
understand like like the possibility and
so I just have inside this dock just a
bunch of different examples of different
like lighting Styles like using an
external light this kind of softer light
example or light there figuring out how
you do something like this naturally or
using kind of light as a tool right
where like this is just like kind of
like a cut through or intense like even
where I am right now inside this
environment there's like different light
coming in I could potentially use and
then control what with like the shutters
that we have using the Flash as a
component using an overlay as a
component like the projector here
there's a lot of ways to think about
light I would just be having a bunch of
references you can easily give me like I
like the way that this looks so someone
can help you achieve it and the last
thing we'll talk about I didn't put it
inside the core because I don't want
people to become too obsessed with it
but it's another tool that you have like
inside your entry level art Direction
toolkit and if you have a brief for a
photographer a brief for a shoot or what
you're thinking about with your friends
you can use this it's like the post-
production aspect what can we do after
the shoot to make it stand out and so
all these are examples of that where
it's basically like editing we like all
right cool I can apply this certain type
of effect to it or hey I actually want
to imp I want to take reference from a
particular vintage ad and lay it out
like that and give button options for a
person when they're holding their cell
phone okay how could I replicate a shot
like this like in post can I have
someone floating this is a popular style
now where they'll have like a single
hand become super big and like super
imposed in a wide angle shot something I
do a lot where you basically have like a
large product in there what I like they
do here is actually makes it look like
it could actually be there the same
frame and all these these people like
cop together what you can do with a
white background shoot you have to get
Savvy for stuff like this but this whole
concept of being able to play with scale
like see the size of his shoes there and
just edits and layouts how you could
comp all the finals together like into a
graphic that is kind of the other tool
that you have in addition to all the
things in the shoot is what you can do
after the shoot um to be able to make
things inherently more interesting so
now that we've walked through a bunch of
these references and you can actually
take a look at like okay here's how I
can begin to think about it and again I
encourage you to go make your own boards
for each of these topics and instead of
Doom scrolling whenever you do it on
whatever go and like spend time on your
mood board apps it's a great replacement
for other types of content and just add
things to those boards you like so when
the shoots do come up you have those
references and the use is like if if
your friend goes oh let's take a photo
here or like hey I a fit pick there you
can like whip this up and be like hey
you want to try any of these like all of
a like people are always into how do
they make themselves look better and if
you can take that extra 10 minutes to
begin to put those to use like you are
beginning to a like make better content
and B increase your portfolio and the
way that you think about how that works
because all this adds up to the
intention that helps you get attention
get work get you know like the action
you're looking for on social media so
now once we've walked through that we're
going talk about how do you actually
begin putting all this into practice
besides just putting stuff on boards
let's do it all right so we've talked
through all these references we talked
through your cheat sheet to make a shoot
great what can you actually do to learn
it so the first thing that I highly
recommend is something we doing cut
dirty all the time is called copy workor
copy work is when you try to replicate
an existing thing basically step for
Step by by putting your own putting
yourself or your own twist inside of it
so for instance when we do this with
short form video it comes down to all
right let's actually map out a a shot if
there's a 7-second video and it has six
shots we're going to write them all down
and we'll write down how long they last
for and then we go okay now you in your
location with your model or whatever it
is you go replicate this exact shoot
with those exact amount of times in
those exact angles but with your own
location your own person your own story
but you're basically walking into a
existing format and able to replicate it
successfully and this is a excellent way
to begin to learn how to do something
within a framework that you know already
works works and it's the same thing with
photo so for instance if we take a look
at some of the wide angle composition
references we have one of the copy
workor could be hey I'm actually going
to recreate this shot with whoever I'm
going to go use my iPhone on point. five
I'm going try to see how where do I have
to go how do I have to angle myself to
be able to shoot like that and what does
it look like and what are the variables
and oh I need to actually turn this way
because that'll make the light look
better Etc or I need a bigger lens
whatever it may look like you going and
replicating some of those same looks
will begin to give you the toolkit of
what you can do and so the homework that
you have this week for what I'm doing on
this channel is to go pick a reference
go on to Cosmos or Arena or Pinterest
find a shop that you like and recreate
it with the gear and things that you
have Zone in on one thing whether it's
lighting or composition or two things if
you want to get fancy and be like how do
I replicate this as close as I can and
add that to my toolkit and if you want
to begin adding that skill set all the
time I would say all right every week
what am I going to be doing copy work
for this week so that I can learn and if
you're looking for more comprehensive
stuff this is obviously a Wonderful
World being able to learn things on
YouTube most things I learned about
photography I learned from YouTube and
there's also significant like creators
who can really stand out by making
tutorial content in their Niche we get a
ton of photographers in Cut 30 I had a
bunch of wedding photographers who did
really well because that content is like
super inherently viral because you get
both photographers who want to shoot
weddings and get better and you get like
obsessive people in wedding parties who
want to be able to get references and
send things to the people that are
preparing and so that's actually a great
little niche for making content but I
want to call out Garrett King who's an
excellent photographer h things that are
really interesting to me and you'll have
seen the same motifs in some of my
valuables brand with rodeo and his kind
of iconic American approaches but he has
a uh awesome content strategy he's not a
huge Creator but he's by far one of the
most valuable ones I follow because he
has lighting tutorials like literally
like a dozen plus of like here's how I
lit this thing and one thing I would
encourage your second homework here is
to go do some of those lighting
tutorials and say okay I may not have
the gear he has or the flash or any of
those things but what can I recreate
with the lights in my house or my ring
light or a couple sources of natural
light and a phone light how can I do
some of the things he's doing and bring
them into the things that I'm shooting
and uh you'll find a bunch of other
really exciting tips and things and he's
a high a Creator I highly recommend but
that's a specific homework is go hunt
down lighting and I'd also go look and
you can obviously when you go on
Instagram you hit that little downward
tab you get to see similar people I
would just be tapping into that
Community especially on Tik Tok where
you can kind of search and see you
basically Lally search like Photo tips
or lighting tips or composition tips
whatever it is it's going to to give you
a bunch of content I'd be finding those
creators you can have in your feed and
bookmarking their stuff another one I
really like is Edward Crockett these are
both guys that that went through cut 30
and so I'm very familiar with their
content but get those people like inside
your feed in your life in your bookmarks
create a separate bookmarks folder on IG
specifically for photo tips and
composition tips so you can easily
reference it and then you're really
beginning to work towards integrating
that in your life and then the last
thing I'll say is you don't have to go
in too deep none of this requires the
fanciest cameras you can do a ton just
with iPhone it does doesn't the most
expensive things or lusting after
whatever hard to get Fuji is just about
continually acting on it and every photo
that you take having that intention and
going back to the what I mentioned at
the beginning which is that one concept
rule if you just add one interesting
thing to any photo it will inherently
stand out that one activity that one
composition and change and you begin to
layer things on top of it and complete
the whole kind of brief sheet then
you're beginning to enter like into real
concepting things like an art director
and we will go in further videos into
like this is like art Direction 101
we'll go into like two 1 301 into like
what more interesting and and
comprehensive looks at that work and
campaigns and structure looks like but
for here just start applying that
attention into your life and you'll
begin to think with that mindset that
will set you up for when we learn the
next level so anyway please like
subscribe thank you so much for watching
and I will be back soon with more of
these and if you like them please let me
know I am going to share also the cosmos
boards for this are uh going to be open
so you can go check them out and find
them on there it's or Meets World on
Cosmos I will link them in the
description and thank you all so much
for watching