because guess what when you get to that
dream scenario and you have the Loft you
want and you're wearing the stuff that
you designed you're going to feel
amazing about yourself you're going to
be like this is the life that I wanted
and I went and
[Music]
got in this video we're going to talk
about developing AA and building your
creative dream life when you're in real
creative Fields you're designing you're
in marketing you're in branding you end
up putting a good chunk of your life
into bringing other people's Visions
into the world and that's not a bad
thing because you have to hone your
skills somewhere and you learn a lot
more around other creative people than
you do like purely in your own world but
you only progress in that Journey when
you make these jumps you know you move
to a new place you shift careers you add
something to your skill set you launch a
brand whether it works or it doesn't and
there's no playbook for that and I think
in our lives it's going to keep going I
think you're just as likely if you're
new to your career and you're in your
20s you're going to have a bunch of
these shifts as you are if you're in
your 30s or your 40s because you'll
notice that even when you achieve a
certain level of wealth and success
you're still going to want to keep
creating and you're still going to want
to keep going and the only way to
progress is every few years you have to
take some kind of big jump so this video
is a playbook for that it's a playbook
for developing AA and what that really
means and I use ARA I view as an
important term because you'll notice
that certain creative and
entrepreneurial people are magnetic and
they're magnetic in real life or online
or in the best case is both people are
drawn to their story their energy the
things they put out there and and it's
by Design this is something that is
creatable I have a little guideline for
how I think anyone can think about
bringing that into their life because I
do think you have to be intentional
about do I want to be that kind of
person what does it take and how do I go
about it and be mindful of it and then
we're going to talk a little about
creative life planning because there's
no guide book because if you're not you
know like a creative person and you're
just chasing money there's significant
ways you can go and and do that and it's
a kind of a completely different
Playbook than if you want an interesting
fulfilling life I'm talk a little about
the Mind States it takes to actually
achieve that and I'm going to talk a
little bit about like the core skill
sets and things that are worth knowing
and having in your Arena if you want to
say hey I want to build build into this
perfect creative life how do I get there
so this is going to be an interesting
video and and probably unlike anything
you've seen on YouTube I've made this V
diagram so I've mapped this out and
there's four quadrants here the first is
taste and taste is an interesting one
it's so unquantifiable but at some point
you have to start deciding what do you
think is good and bad not what the elite
online tell you is good or bad not what
capitalism tells you is good or bad or
your design school does what do you
personally think is interesting and not
and why and then what does your Target
customer base think is interesting or
not and why and where is that alignment
right and I think this is a really
interesting conversation and one I'm
pretty deep in because um I grew up in a
place with like essentially no tast I
grew up in Hawaii surf culture super
Asian culture in that era with less
internet I just didn't have access to
much like everything I I learned about
things I learned through magazines I was
obsessed with design learned everything
I could like through magazines from that
and acquired a bunch of my understanding
of everything through Reading and
through school and then moving to New
York and working inside working inside
fashion working inside like a like an
agency with like major clients and stuff
you begin to understand like Discerning
what is good or bad but then I also
learned that you create really tasteful
things like some of the projects I
worked on where people would create
these things that you would think
because they are the perfect item or
whatever would succeed they don't
necessarily right like taste is not an
indicator of success but people will
often CR criticize you or critique you
if you don't make tasteful things if
you're in this design and creative
community and then there's your
barometer what you like and don't and
that actually might be different than
what is tasteful and what consumers like
and don't and you have to kind of
basically find alignment between what do
consumer like what do I like what is
good and tasteful and right and and
decide where you want to live and now it
gets a whole another complicated factor
of what gets attention on the internet
because there's so much of that playing
into this too where people can make
really like there's an epidemic right
now of really nice tasteful Men's Wear
Brands there are so many of them that
make so much good stuff and they simply
don't get a lot of attention because
they don't make the kind of products
that can get attention which means
fiscally they don't get the success
level they should for the things that
are as tasteful and good-looking as they
are and a lot of those businesses are
going to fail whereas I can get people
arguing for hundreds of thousands of
views about whether my t-shirt should be
distressed or not and I sell a grip of
them along the way and then know that
that is part of part of the design
process is understanding the
conversation that's going to come from
it and is that necessarily the most
tasteful thing no it's something that
appeals to me yes it's something that
works inside the bubble that I'm
shooting for yes I say all that to say
you need to understand what your role is
there understand what you like and don't
and have that perspective but until you
start deciding that I'm only going to
put out things of a certain caliber or
I'm only going to appreciate things that
are a certain way or in a certain Niche
or I'm only going to like uplevel my
ability to discern what is good or bad
it's hard to develop that level of Aura
you'll see very few people with AA that
don't have any understanding of like
what is how things go together how
things work and and culture and that
ties directly to experience right
because the easiest way to get that is
experience in life moving to new places
travel spending that time in New York
Paris Italy Milan wherever it is uh you
Tokyo those places are inherently full
of taste they're full of people and
generations of people that take design
and take success seriously and you get
the trappings and the The Fallout of
that is basically spread through
everyone around it so you begin to
understand far more so the more
experience you have in the world the
more learns into like how you can
reflect on things make decisions take
into account different cultures and adds
to this kind of ability to have Aura and
because you'll find very few people that
don't have a bunch of worldly experience
or aren't currently having that worldly
experience who we're able to have that
magnetism and then in this bottom
quadrant we're going to have positivity
this is a super super key one because
you rarely see people that have that
magnetic energy who are negative more
than a little bit of the time they the
ability to be critical and to critique
and to have high expectations but you'll
see they are always looking at what is
that best result how do I excite other
people when I'm around them is it fun as
a huge precursor to whether someone's
going to be successful with their
Creative Vision is if people enjoy being
around them and I learned this like the
hard way in agency work so the past I
think almost s years now we've had this
uh contract engineering agency in Austin
and when we started it I always thought
people would want the best solution who
can provide them the best engineering
team at the best price to solve all the
problems their business has but as you
begin to work and deal with with clients
more and more you start to realize that
actually there's another V diagram there
that is do you enjoy working with these
people and are my problems being solved
and people will basically almost always
choose enjoying working with people over
problems being solved and the perfect
Vin diagram is problems being solved and
enjoying working with the people but
rarely it takes a certain type of
company or person to say I'm not going
to enjoy it but they're going to solve
my problem and they're more often than
not forced into that scenario and it's a
human nature thing and it's interesting
but also should really impact how you
think about providing your services and
your personality because you basically
get a lot more people that are stoked to
be around your energy than you do people
that are like okay they're solving my
problem I really don't like the fact
that every time I walk into this meeting
with them it's just like straight pedal
of metal here's what we're doing wrong
have to fix it like right away even if
that leads to success faster I say all
that to say that that positive energy
that always being excited about everyone
else's projects stoking like egging them
on to do better and like do the right
things being the person in the group
chat gassing stuff up Connecting People
constantly being fun to be out and about
with even the little things like big and
smiling at dogs or whatever it looks
like actually adds up to being the type
of person that other people want to
follow and be around and this is the
thing I personally struggle the most
because I'm inherently critical by
Nature I think most things are whack I
have the ability to self-reflect on that
and note that things that I doing are
whack or not and why and then choose to
do it accordingly which is a useful
skill set but I have to basically always
pull myself back from I don't want to be
critical about this I want to make sure
I have a positive nature about it
because I notice the effect it has on
people when I am overly critical and it
does not make them want to be a part of
what I'm putting together and then up at
the top we have giving and this is one
that I've been really interested in
because I've always fig out the
intangible right like okay if you have
taste you have this worldly experience
you're a positive person people want to
be around you there's something more
there especially when he comes to the
internet you know what separates these
people that are are really like
interested in that that next phase like
I'll give like Daniel dal's a great
example of like you have all that
positivity you have like this you know
this experience of like his kind of
global nature that I think really draws
people to him and uh he's like
relentlessly positive but then he's
giving he's showing you how how he does
this stuff he's like really saying hey
like this is a recipe for a young person
that wants to succeed and that give back
I think is a big part of why people are
attracted to his content I also think
the huge part about why I built the
following I have is I'm constantly
giving value all my YouTube videos my
Instagrams like my goal every time I sit
down and write one of those is am I
making people am I entertaining people
are they are they laughing and finding
it funny in a niche way like some jokes
about marketing or pans or whatever or
are they getting just a ton of value
from it is it helping them shift their
career or work better at their job and
are they going to be able to act on that
like today not like some big intangible
thing but when you continue to
relentlessly give value to people all
the time when you meet them in person
when you see it online that is like The
X Factor that really propels people to
always want to be around you and I never
met Virgil ablo but lots of my friends
have or had relationships with him and
they all would remark on the fact that
he messaged back and messaged people
like all the time he had all these group
chats and and whatsapps and stuff like
that and was super positive with
everybody and would like introduce
people and it was like one of the things
that they mentioned all the time was
that like combination of like positivity
and giving that was just inherent to
what made him so special so now we're
going to talk about the life plan and
and building your creative like I
mentioned before I got to a point um a
while ago where I realized I had hit
some of the financial goals I had for
myself as a business person right CU I
did Focus for about seven or eight years
not on Creative fulfillment but on
accumulating as much money and getting
as high up in my career as I could led
to me being the president of a decently
large company having all these
businesses my hands and all these things
but not being fulfilled and so I did
this exercise it was inspired by my
friend Zach Kravitz who has these um
video he put out about it that went
pretty viral where it was like design
your creative dream and basically go and
list out what your perfect life looks
like and all the things that it costs
like actually go and and map out I
really want to have a G wagon here's
what that cost me every month you know
if that actually matters to you I you
know I want to have this house I want to
be able to live in this place I want be
to go on this many vacations I want to
be able to spend this much on X or Y and
really go down and then ask yourself
that critical question of do I really
want this would this actually make me
happy and it's funny because you'll find
interesting things about what makes you
happy or not some of the things that
make me happy are are things I didn't
expect I lived under my means for a
really long time I drove like
exceedingly normal like Toyotas and
stuff even when I was making like mid
six figures because I really want to
accumulate money and it mattered more to
me I thought than Experience day today
now I drive I have a bunch of nice cars
because I really enjoy those 20 minutes
every day like really make a difference
to me and make me feel good of like
whipping around and like interesting
stuff I've also realized I really enjoy
wearing stuff that I designed makes a
big difference to me I'd rather spend
money on something I design have outfits
that like I was involved with all the
time because you get to walk around and
be like yeah like I'm in my it's
actually really funny those two things
matter to me far more than me buying
anything designer and also me driving
those cars matter more to me than having
some of that money in the bank and
that's very just particular to me that's
not everybody but when you start asking
yourself these questions they make a big
difference so I would ask yourself in
order where do I want to live and that's
both a location and then it's a type of
place that you want which is actually a
really interesting one when you get into
because some people would say hey I
actually want to be able to do all these
other things execute on my Creative
Vision have some big Loft do whatever
but I actually don't care where I am
where some people be like you know what
no matter what I don't care what my
space is like I need to be in New York
and it's good to kind of walk through
that and walk through that with your
your spouse or your partner if you have
one and say what do I want out of my
livings and say what vehicles do I want
to drive do I even need a vehicle right
am I am I actually happy using using my
funds on other things and taking the bus
because it doesn't matter to me at all
because a lot of people will have some
like mid range cards cuz they feel like
they should actually has no bearing on
their life and they're like yeah I don't
know why I have a BMW you know like the
entry level one just cuz and actually I
could just have that $400 a month or
$800 a month back in my bank account
down to like basically down to every
level one of those costs and what most
people find out is their life actually
costs less than they think and what
matters to them is significantly
different and to give you a couple
anecdotes about where that ended for me
personally when I did that exercise is
we realized that we actually don't need
a really expensive home we live on this
street right now that has a no through
traffic has a bunch of other families I
have an 8-year-old son he has a bunch of
friends on the street they're all kids
of SAR ages open the garages on the
weekend they all go out and play
together and that actually M and we're
basically 10 minutes from the beach that
matters more to me than having a
multi-million dollar like like 510
million mansion or living in like the
middle of LA and I actually the perfect
life for me is having enough space to be
able to have my studio to be able to
have my office to have a house that my
family enjoys and then to be able to
live there like in this like more
neighborhoody thing matters way more to
me than having the nicest thing once I
realized that I was like oh that's
actually a fixed cost that's
significantly less than what I can
afford and that means means that that
money can go into other things that are
more interesting to and it would have
never have gone there without having
that conversation and once you map that
life out you say it's going to cost x
amount a month and maybe it's more than
you thought maybe it's less than you
thought this comes into the second phase
of this which I think is really
interesting for creative and
entrepreneurial people because you have
all these options to make money we're
going to walk through that CU like once
you have your cost list out you go okay
how do I actually fulfill this life so
bucket one that everyone has is okay I
have my job you make some amount of
money with whatever you do dayto day for
for most people and then really there's
this question of what do you do after
that and it is extremely American to
have a side hustle right like I live in
orang County almost everyone I meet has
like something either they're
entrepreneurial themselves or it's like
yeah we have a bar cart we run out in
the weekends we have these two rental
properties or you know we own this piece
of this pool company or yeah like I have
an Amazon business like almost everyone
has something else and it's extremely
common like especially in wealthy areas
for people to kind of be engaging in and
I think we have this culture where
people like oh I don't want to do more
after work or whatever but like you
rarely achieve your dreams without that
if you're creative you actually get to
build a massive you get to build the
ability to then have your life where you
work completely for yourself chunk by
Chunk in all these little
entrepreneurial areas those areas are
freelance doing your skill set for other
people for money content there's a
couple buckets of content right one is
content you are uh creating via
affiliate for Tik Tok shop like if you
are creating and you are selling stuff
there is a lot of people I know making a
a to a little to a lot of money but like
some significant amount by basically
making videos for Tik Tok shop products
like so that's content bucket One
content bucket two is making that
content for other people very similar to
freelance like hey I actually make 20
social media videos a month for whoever
bucket three is getting money off of
content like I you getting money from
the Creator funds on YouTube and Tik Tok
and bonuses on Instagram which isn't a
huge amount of money but actually adds
up a lot especially for younger folks
and you're like oh I made $700 this
month or $1,400 this month it starts to
be something legit and then there's like
becoming an actual influencer and having
brand deals and stuff like that so
that's category two freelance category
creation social media category category
three is info product we are taught
inherently that courses and info
products are bad when in reality a lot
of really successful people like spend a
lot of money on them I learned TiK ToK
by buying Jimmy Farley's course I just
bought this um designer Jamie who I
liked online who I use one of her like
this thing she did for this brand portal
or ritual I use as a reference all the
time like when I'm showing people like
uh working in a niche and I was and she
put out like a template about proposals
I was like oh you know I just want to
support it I've used this stuff as a
reference a lot I want to support
whatever she puts out I bought some
template she had around like proposals
and then I looked at it I was like
actually this is a better proposal
template than I use I'm just going to
use it and she's not like some massive
social media following the template was
like 65 bucks but I bet she sells a
decent amount of them even if she sells
10 a month whatever it's like 650 bucks
I would not be afraid to sell info
products like obviously I have a couple
things I do I have the cut 30 program I
have $200 report things I put together
with with Clayton we sawell on hyper
they're not like huge money generators
but it adds up it provides value I put
work in and if you are a creative and
you have a workflow or a template or
something you're proud of or a
significant look and feel even if you
don't have huge social media but you
have like an offering of a thing is a
wayed to generate income and something
to think about doing so you start
getting into those three those those
three buckets freelance content info and
then the last one is brand right I sell
things on the Internet or on retail or
whatever it is and I make money off them
for a lot of people brand is hard
because brand is a money pit but for
most folks I really encourage like
starting a brand by being like a first
order profitable very straightforward
business I sell hats the guy who sells
like creative Department hats is a great
example it's one skew is one visually
good-look skew it's an idea that seems
really familiar because we've seen a lot
of these other brands that say also say
cretive department and have similar
colors and whatnot but he has his own
little spin on it he sells one thing and
is a great business he can probably do
while he's doing 17 other things and
that's an entry level all the way to
like having a full brand or having an
Amazon Project or doing some stuff on
Tik Tok shop or whatever that is
definitely the hardest most timec
consuming of those four things I meant
but that is your toolkit and you have to
pick some of them if you want to live
that dream life you don't achieve it
just by having your job you may achieve
it by having one of these other things
on there and sometimes it's going to be
two but you have to pick them and you
have to actually calendar and work on so
back to anecdotes on my life I
freelanced for basically my entire
executive career I had a overseas
developer I had a friend who was a
designer locally and we would do
websites we did a lot of 10 to 15K
websites Relentless basically one a
month for years and we had that sweet
spot of hey we can do this on nights and
weekends three of us working on this we
don't need to have some big agency or
anything like that we don't even need a
separate LC R everything to mine it's
not going to over you know not going to
overlap into our work it's only like one
project a month but we are all taking
home a couple thousand dollars every
month by doing a really specific thing
and doing it well and I was the funnel
cuz I'm a very social person I Network
very heavily I know a lot of people a
lot of people would see the work I did
at companies and want to work with me on
something and knew that's the thing that
I did and we had a whole little side
freelance thing and honestly that
feeling is like PID my G wagon you know
the uh there there's like I would always
Reserve that money for things that I
wanted um and it adds up over time and
you can look at may maybe we want to
make it a whole business or not but like
that was just one freelance thing that
we did over the course of several years
and I have two friends who have designed
templates and plugins and stuff on like
creative market and stuff who do very
well just by having like very hip stuff
on there that's concurrent with the
times was about deciding which of those
you're going to do and then going after
one of the biggest things I've learned
in the last few months is that you know
for the previous decade I had meetings
all day I had six to eight hours of
blocked out meetings every single day on
my calendar and now I've realized when I
started to not have that that I needed
that same time breakdown be able to get
things done half hour on this hour to
get this thing written hour for this
Consulting project two hours to put this
email plan together this recurring thing
every week I feel like most creatives
need that too you are saying hey I'm
going to pursue making content I'm going
to pursue freelancing I'm going to
whatever you need to calendar out that
time it's like yeah Tuesdays and
Thursdays I got three-hour blocks at
night where this is what I do you stick
to it and you address it same thing with
weekends whatever it is and you got to
realize that your time is not really sac
and you also have to realize if you're
like oh man like I can't figure out how
do I step in LLC if you can't figure
that out like you need to you need
to make the jump and be able to do that
if you can't say $150 to register this
entity is more important than eating out
this weekend you're also you're not
going to get it this is like everyone
who's gone through this this jump has
made those decisions at that point to be
like this stuff is more important to me
than whatever it is I was doing prior
and you need to lock in and do that once
you have your dream life outlined and
you have your outline of what are the
things I can do to add money into my
life to be able to do it you can begin
to actually align that and say I think I
can make this much off this my goal is
to make this much off this and then
begin to start to piece together how you
align to those things and you'll start
to realize that if you're willing to
look at it like it doesn't need to be
done tomorrow that I want to be able to
achieve this in 3 years or four years or
and I'm going to kind of piece by piece
put these goals together for myself that
it all becomes is really attainable but
if you never put that framework down of
what do I actually want and then what am
I going to do to achieve it and then
here's my calendar time to do it it
probably won't happen and so literally
if you don't watch anything else I've
ever do or talk about just go do that
plan out that life plan out where you're
going to get the money to do it put the
time on your calendar and then say this
is a threeyear thing this is a four-year
thing because if you say oh that's too
long or I need to figure out something
else out need to be easier than this
it's not the answer is always going to
be there at the end of the rainbow once
you do the work so just go suffer
through it because guess what when you
get to that dream scenario and you have
the Loft you want and you're wearing the
stuff that you designed and you bring in
x amount of money from from freelance
you're going to feel amazing about
yourself you're going to be like this is
the life that I wanted and I went and
got and there's honestly no better
feeling than that and then once you
realize all these things are achievable
you're just going to keep doing that for
the rest of your life you're going to
start being like why wouldn't I start
this business why wouldn't I attempt to
do X or why because I know I have the
framework to act on it so from there
quick note on mind states that are
really important I'm not like I've never
going to see me doing like mental model
videos or like that but I am going
to talk to you about things I think are
critical to make sure that like are you
know stamped in your mind for all time
and tattooe on your body if you're one
of those kind of people the first was
the classic like if you want to be poor
forever start tomorrow if you watch this
video and you're like yeah I'm going to
get to that next week this is part of
the problem right the answer is like
after this video like start writing this
down do that tonight if you
just act tonight you act right now you
just knock the stuff off the list it is
going to happen you're the person that
makes it happen once you turn into that
person everything change and the second
is live in the present visualize the the
future I do a lot of things now so I can
enjoy what I do da before I was
recording this video I was surfing I'm a
kid at the beach loved every second of
it like I mentioned I love driving
around the cars I am I love making
content I love talking to people I love
designing things every single thing in
my life Stokes me up I am stoked for the
present and even when I was working at a
company like I liked the job I had prior
worked on content worked with retailer
worked on product development we were
doing cool collaborations I was trying
and I was I liked the success I liked
seeing the numbers go up like enjoy the
present but also visualize the future
that planning part is important
especially if you have a spouse too a
plan what matters to yall like what's
important what do you think is
achievable and to like visualize that
and put that on the board cuz right if
you go put the Mansion on the board like
I used to have the Mansion on the dream
board and then when I actually
considered it enough I was like actually
that's not what I want take it off the
board but if you don't V you visualize
like what you visualize ends up being
often like what you get whether you
actually want it or not and so I'm
always visualizing what does that
amazing scenario look like like I'm
about to do complex con uh here in a
couple weeks I'm debuting it for um R do
to booth for valuable and I'm
visualizing that being an amazing
experience and what that going well I'm
not agonizing about what if it all goes
wrong the thir is like every day has
massive incredible value right you can
get so much closer to your dreams every
single day than you think you can if you
just act on that day if like that night
hey guess what instead of Netflix we do
X and Y you he say this 100 times like
if you just do that action like you get
there and you'll see these people like
I'm now surrounded in my life by people
that are all like that where we're all
texting each other at midnight or
whatever being like look what I just
finished or like oh man work shopping
this thing because you just realize that
like it just gives you so much energy
and value and Aura for lack of a better
term because those people attract other
people like that guess what other people
like that are like they're successful
they do things together and it all
starts by being a person that other
people start to know like yeah that
person grms they get after and then
third is pomodoro tasks so if you're fam
with this Pomodoro basically setting a
timer like a 15 minutes to be able to
you know concentrate exactly 30 minutes
concentrate exactly on one thing don't
do anything else no distractions or
anything until that timer is done I'm a
huge fan of this like as a theory
because I think a lot of people get
caught into hairy tasks you're like I
want to sort a freelance business you're
like God it's overwhelming I can't think
about it if you break it down into what
I call Pomodoro tasks things you can
complete in a 15 to 30 minute period all
of a sudden everything becomes easier so
let's take that start a business example
where you start to go like hey I need to
search for names for my business I need
to figure out how to register an LLC
like in inside my state I need to find a
template for articles of organization I
need to get a domain I need to decide
where I want to host my domain I need to
set up a Squarespace account I need to
set up an email account on convertkit
you know like you you begin breaking it
down to those tasks like even email set
up where it's like all right I need to
get the account I need to outline what I
want to do for automation I need to
connect my domain that is way more
achievable to say here's this list of
seven things each one of which takes 15
to 30 minutes then this do here's this
one big hairy thing and then once you
get those 15 to 30 you go back to that
calendar and you go what days can I
actually do that or what times do I have
to do it and you put it in the calendar
and you get it done when you say you're
going to get it done and all of a sudden
your life seems to like Snap into focus
and you are doing everything you've ever
wanted to do as the end of my
motivational speech the last thing we're
going to talk about is a toolkit you
need to basically make anything happen
so I feel like we're exiting the era of
pure specialist like I'm just a designer
I'm just a videographer whatever
entering the era where you have like a
core specialty but you have a bunch of
other things around it that enable you
to be dangerous so first things out the
way the most boring things everyone
should be able to get the basic idea to
understand is one is like Accounting 101
p&l the balance sheet how I make a
business that makes profit what are cost
of goods sold how do I have a basic idea
of taxes this is far easier than most
people think it is but basically people
don't know it unless they have to have a
reason to know it and I would just get
slightly dangerous on that second in a
similar vein is meta ads manager and
understanding how to set up ads how to
set up instant form what's an ASC
campaign how to load in new creative
what is roas a of customer acquisition
how I format creative in different sies
you want to be amazing at understanding
the basics of how it works gives you the
ability to go like testings and expand
things that once you have it and I would
highly recommend putting yourself in
whatever scenario you are at work or
with your own side project be able spend
a little bit of money to figure out and
be somewhat dangerous at that I probably
mentioned before but I'm in like a group
for this called meta ads at scale
because I am having run ads for years on
my own projects and manage teams that
run millions of dollars in ads I still
want to be just like as on it as
possible because it's such a crucial
skill the third is like use of cap cut
and like understanding how to make
quickly edit and make videos and have
them look good and have like
good-looking captions and stuff which is
something you can learn completely off
of of YouTube then we have design and
basic design and like understanding a
little bit about layouts and grids and
typography and being able to make
anything you do like look a little bit
better and just basically getting MVP
together whether it's like a landing
page or an email blast or a promotional
flyer or whatever it is like will
actually end up saving you a ton of Time
Versus whatever whack stuff you do prior
and it's easier than ever with like the
default templates in Cana or anywhere
else but then we have like the
interesting things that are happening
right now where a lot is happening in
technology where basically code is being
commodified through through AI so if you
look at like v0 cursor repet Claude and
you understand like how to prompt a bit
of how to how each of those work you've
experimented with some of those like the
if you uh want to get really deep into
any of those or just trying to find a
way to nerd out now like those are good
places to be because there are people
who are really into that right now like
all the smart people I know who haven't
like hit a win yet are uh spending a lot
of time with those tools which is a a
sign for me that everyone's seeing hey
this is where the ball is going I want
to be really good at it and I would be
recommending doing the same exact things
if I were and all that to say that like
that constant expansion mindset of like
I'm going to get better at this I'm
going to be dangerous enough at this
thing all contributes back to that like
initial Aura and experience concept
right the more of these things you have
the more people are like man like oh
that guy has a complete understanding of
like how shell companies work you know
or uh oh they're able to do like an app
no code and you're able to kind of show
that off or tell that story The more
Universal you are at those things the
more respect you get from other people
the more confidence you have in yourself
the easier it is for you to bring your
ideas into reality which is a a lot of
what having a fulfilling creative life
is about cuz you you start you know as a
little baby with all these ideas you
don't know how to bring them out and
then you'll start to bring them out
it'll be bad you start to get better at
it then then start you start to get good
enough you can actually do the Creative
part of your ideas now you're like oh I
actually need to do the business part of
the ideas and then it's like hey I need
to be able to do the business part of my
ideas and to be able to do the
distribution part of the ideas and you
know it's the content side of it and
then once you understand how all those
work now you can manage now you can be
like I'm going to get a person I know
they're competent to do X and Y because
I know how it works and you begin to
scale out underneath that and that in my
opinion is the creative way and allows
us when you have all those different
skill sets to look at all these faces of
your career and be like you know what I
want to work for the next six years in
Portugal and the only really way I can
do that is if I have something I can
freelance remotely at but guess what I'm
excellent at you know I learned how to
do cap cut edits and I'm so I'm work for
a travel firm that really needs needs
extra y like there are uh like so many
of those skill sets once you get some
applicability of can allow you to move
one way or the other that can allow you
to freelance through this way or that
way or be able to navigate through the
MVP of a product or a creative idea that
is like extremely I know I do a lot of
like super tactical content like you
know how to develop a brand strategy how
do this exercise a little bit more
intangible I think it's really important
just because there is no road map I'll
say this again and again in my videos
there's no road map for Creative success
there's no road map for like creative
careers those are changing in front of
our eyes I happen to be at this midpoint
I've had a bunch of this career
experience but still want to have other
arcs that come out of that and also
where like I enjoy making content and
talking about it where I'm trying to
share as much about that as possible
that hopefully like it has has some
benefit that's there so if you have any
questions about this please let me know
um I am doing a new Tik Tok Series where
I do like extended yaps basically I'm
doing like a Captain's Log where I talk
about what's happening in my day
different kind of challenges really
specifics about like creative work that
I'm doing three or four times a week on
on Tik Tok so um feel free to ask
questions there and I will I will hit
those kind of in that like more candid
format so thanks again and I'll be back