In this video, we are going to talk
about boy internet versus girl internet,
man internet versus woman internet.
Thank you to HubSpot for sponsoring this
video. This is an oddball, relatively
controversial topic, but one that I
think is an important one. So, if you
work in brand like I do, and you do
consumer research, particularly around
the consumption habits of your customer
and the ads that appeal to them, who
they follow, you've probably noticed
something. Your male and your female
customers live on almost completely
different internets, in particular on
social media. First, there's the
networks they interact with. Then
there's the podcasters and YouTubers
that they listen to. And then there's
the algorithmic content they see, which
is more and more tailored towards them
specifically. And I started to look at
this as part of my marketing work,
right? How do I make better ads? How do
I make better content? How I think
better through target audiences who
aren't me, right? That is the hardest
thing for most people to do work in
marketing is take themselves out of the
equation. You need to not care about
you, where you're at in your life and
your background, but care instead about
your customer. Look at things through
their eyes. But then it blossomed into
something bigger as I began to think
about this from a sociology standpoint.
Because the interactions between people
online and in real life are changing
because of these behaviors. How we
interact together as people in different
communities, as members of the opposite
sex, as people in society. And so, in
this video, we're going to dive through
all of this. We're going to look at it
from the marketing perspective, and
we're going to look at it from the
consumer perspective. So, you start to
think about what you view and why, what
you buy and why. And if you are in
business, you begin to think about how
your target consumer sees the world. I'm
going to give an intro, and we're going
to talk through the phases of marketing,
how this is really different than the
last 20 years. We went from big brand
marketing, emotion-based marketing, to
the search era of marketing, to the big
algorithm era, to the tailored algorithm
era now. Then I'm going to talk about
developing a bank of cultural insights,
if you work in brand or creative or make
content, how that works and why you do
it and how I do that. And then I'm going
to break down from what I've been
working on on brand projects, what I
know about the women's algorithm and the
men's algorithms and how they are
different, how these kind of two
internets exist at the same time. And
so, you can get a look into how that
content is different, and what that
actually means for how we consume, and
how we act with each other, especially
as more and more people become, quote
unquote, terminally online. And I'm
going to end with some core thoughts
about why we buy things in the modern
era. They're important to dig through.
So, I think this is an important video,
cuz the world is changing around us.
There are not really people involved in
documenting it. Journalists do not
understand the world that they are
covering. And I am obsessed with it, and
happy to share. it to be a conversation.
You're not going to agree with
everything I say. I don't say anything
in here to be controversial. I say it
because I'm watching it happen, but I
would love for you to comment, share
your opinions, what you see, because
this only gets better as a conversation.
If you want to discuss it live, there'll
be a link to the next community call
down there, where I'll be rolling
through with hundreds of you, like we do
every month. Let's lock in. So, first,
now we're in the time where it seems
almost awkward to talk about the past.
How things were marketed to us, even
when I was younger, like in high school
and college, are just not the same. In
fact, it wouldn't be kosher to market
that way now. And so, I grew up in the
impress the opposite sex era. It was
also the sex sells era. To give some
context to that, I used to work at
Abercrombie & Fitch. They sold to male
and female customers alike. A huge
marketing portion of that brand was they
had hot guys on the bags, and that they
would have good-looking people in the
stores. An entire genre of advertising
that basically would feel really out of
place and antiquated now. And also, a
lot of the purchases you make, if you
were going to go get a new cologne, you
were thinking about, "What does this say
to girls?" Or whoever you want to
attract, obviously. Remember all the
alternative lifestyles out there. But
you were beginning to think of that
inside this kind of human nature ideal
of attracting a partner. And so much of
marketing, from beer ads to fast food,
to clothing, to fragrance, to luxury,
was built around those kind of
traditional social dynamics. And there
was this big monoculture. Like, Nike
wasn't the dumpster fire it is today,
like this weirdly regarded mid brand,
right? It was the brand. Everyone loved
it. You had these big universal brand
experiences that sold to men and women
right next to each other that took over
the culture. And they did this through
all this traditional media, through
television advertising, magazine
campaigns, big sponsorships, celebrity
deals. It was a monoculture era, and the
internet was just starting and beginning
to show more subcultures, but it was
very nascent. This is the late 2000s,
early 2010s. And then we have what I
call the search-based revolution. Amazon
and Google made it so showing up in a
search result, whether you're on Amazon
or whether you're Googling it with a
competitively priced product, meant
brand didn't matter. People just wanted
to buy tissues, shoe inserts, sneakers,
whatever it was. You were searching for
it, and you could position basically in
a math game. You could buy a product at
a certain price, offer it at a certain
price, a handful of features, and you
could basically build a product, a
successful product, without having to
care about brand. And so all these
companies came in. People were ordering
a lot more from China. This was the
early era of Alibaba. And basically
these generic things began to take over
in our lives. And as that began more
competitive, the quality of that dropped
to where you get now you're looking at
all these weird Amazon brand names. You
don't know what you're going to get,
some like off-brand. You don't ever know
if anything's real. It became this like
weird math competition that we're almost
over at this point. You almost want to
see the brand name so you know you're
not getting some like Temu trash. Then
TikTok brought on big monoculture right
around the pandemic. Everyone became
flocking on short-form video, this new
algorithmic content. And you got huge
creators, creators with big mass appeal,
real basically celebrity being born of
influence in that era. And you also had
a new generation of brands that were
taking the market share from basically
the department stores, Sears, the
Macy's, the big like the J. Crew, L.L.
Bean, all that, as well as the Nikes and
the Adidas. People began to chip away at
that market share. Lululemon came out of
nowhere. On, big brands with universal
appeal using a new playbook. And
sometimes they didn't even have to run
the playbook. Lululemon and On weren't
like incredible at social media, but
they were selling to a social
media-savvy customer that did a lot of
the dissemination of their marketing for
them. And so, all of a sudden, by
playing in this new media ecosystem,
whether you did it strategically or
whether your customer base happened to
be involved with it, it basically was
taking market share from these
antiquated brands and building hundreds
of smaller new brands we've seen over
the last 5 years, thousands, tens of
thousands of those brands. But now it is
about algorithm mastery. Brands zone in
on a target demographic, moms in the
Midwest. They'll zone in by race and
gender, something different for Asian
moms versus African-American moms versus
Latin moms. Everything gets boiled down
to the fact that we can be reached with
content meant exactly for us. And then
this plays into societal rewards that
come from being online. You post the
thing that shows you're in the know, you
perpetuate a cycle of what you engage
with giving you more things like that.
That's how YouTube, TikTok, Instagram,
X, Facebook, all social media is
interest-based social media. It's very
good at showing you more of what you
interact with and like and basically
targeting you. So, that's where we were
in the world. Next we're going to talk
about how you develop a bank, how you
start thinking about insights within
that, how you use that to make decisions
about what you consume or what you sell
or how you market or how you create
content. But first, something I'm going
to bring up before we keep going cuz it
directly relates to standout marketing.
Cuz many of you are watching this thing
about how to get your brand or product
discovered. And for years that have been
Google rankings, backlinking, the whole
SEO game. But the way buyers research is
also shifting fast. 60% of searches now
end without a click. They get the answer
displayed to them by the Google Gemini
automatic answer. People are asking
ChatGPT, Perplexity, and Gemini and
getting answers back that skip websites
entirely. The answer engines pick who
they recommend. And most brands have
zero visibility on whether they're even
in that conversation. So, that's what
HubSpot AEO is built to solve. AEO or
answer engine optimization is about how
you show up when someone asks AI for a
brand recommendation in your category.
And HubSpot's AEO tool gives you exact
visibility into just that. It shows you
how your brand appears across those
three platforms, gives you a visibility
score, shows where your competitors are
getting cited, and where you're not. And
it tells you specifically what to write,
what to fix, and what to post to improve
that. You don't need a developer or an
agency, you need a plain English plan,
and HubSpot AEO gives that to you. So,
let me show you how this works. I
actually put in my shoe bags, and that's
something that I sell currently. I've
done no time or prep into AEO. And
HubSpot told me that, so hey, I have 0%
visibility. But then it gave me an exact
plan. I should get a post like this up
on Reddit. I should have posts like
these up on social media to begin
showing up for it. And so, I have that
by ChatGPT, Gemini, Perplexity. Here's
what's being said already, and here's
what to fix to improve it. You can try
HubSpot AEO free for 28 days, and it's
$50 a month after that. If you've never
seen how AI describes your brand or the
brand you work for when someone asks
about your category, it's worth the 28
days just for that. The link is in the
description, and thank you to HubSpot
for sponsoring this video. Let's talk
about cultural insights. How do I even
get to this boy internet girl internet
thing? So, for those of you that don't
know my background, I've been in
marketing for a long time. I started in
marketing in the outdoors industry. I
sold high-end B2C and B2B. I was in
marketing in the surf industry for a
while, working on both high-end, like
actual surf gear, and eFoil electric
surfboards, selling to really
high-net-worth customers. I did
marketing in toys, did marketing in
consumer packaged goods. A lot of this
sold through big retail. So, consumer
electronics and Best Buy, sold in
Walmart, sold in Target, and built out
big D2C programs. And in this last year,
I was really ultra-focused on beauty. I
was a creative director at a private
equity firm that specialized in that.
And so, in all of these, a lot of what
my job would look like as a marketing
leader is, "What are the insights about
our consumer that we are going to take
into our campaigns? We're going to bring
into our ads?" And especially this last
year in beauty, everything is about that
now. In the creative strategy era, it
is, "What are the things that appeal to
our customer we can put in more meta
ads?" We're putting hundreds of meta ads
in the account every month, dozens of
emails, multiple social posts a day. So,
just constant briefs. And every brief,
every great brief, starts with some kind
of insight, something that's popular
right now with your target demographic,
something they're seeing on their feed.
And like I mentioned at the beginning,
your job as a marketer is to be good at
doing that for consumers other than
yourself. So, in beauty, for instance, I
am not that consumer whatsoever. And so,
when I started working on those
projects, I set up burner accounts,
where I would follow the same people
that our customers followed. We'll find
our target customer. We use stuff like
Outer Signal and go through and look at
their personas, find exact people, find
their social media, click their links,
who do they follow, what do they look
at, recreate their feeds, recreate what
their algorithms look like. In another
recent project that sparked this video,
we actually paid for our customers to
let us watch them scroll. And we did
this mainly at my behest. I basically
half funded this. Eventually the company
came in because I wanted to prove a
point because I thought what the
marketing team inside the company
thought our consumer was scrolling what
they were actually scrolling were
completely different. And I was right.
Because look, that's one of the most
secret things we have, right? When we
scroll, it's very personal what's been
served to us and why. And then it
changes. But you need to understand that
in a world where one of the most primary
methods of which we learn about or
consume anything is through what happens
on social media. But I've done this
before the social media era and to now.
How to think about this from magazines
and experiences and retail and how all
of this plays together. So, I am
constantly thinking about cultural
observations and algorithmic
observations for the target users that I
will be working with. So, what does that
mean? It means I'm constantly thinking
up thesis that I want to defend. And
you'll see, this is what a lot of my
short-form content has turned into when
I'm like, "Lonely men buy sneakers.
Lonely women buy water bottles. Blank
isn't a status symbol. People are
ordering in their food more now. In LA,
lunch has replaced dinner." There's a
lot of these I will constantly be kind
of coming up with these ideas I see in
the world around me. And I'll be having
conversations with people to validate
them. Or I'll be putting them in the ad
account with the creative where one of
the brands I work with to validate if
people respond to the idea. And this is
how you become a good marketer. You
think of those ideas, you develop a
platform around why it should work, you
test it, stress test it back and forth
with people. I get the benefit of being
able to do that with millions of people
online who watch my videos. And you put
it into play and you see what actually
brings dollars back to you. And I've
multiplied this by Cut 30, we have a
database called video database, where we
have every Cut 30 person tracked. And
then we have all these people in all
their related niches tracked. So, we can
see what's happening on the internet,
what formats are changing, what
consumption habits, what's getting liked
more or not, are rankings and ratings
videos working, etc. And we can break
that down by category, real estate,
gender. We have all this basically
really comprehensive tool that we built
internally. And so, now we're able to
add these up to these real consumer
insights. And this is brings us to the
women's algo and the men's algo, and how
different they are. And I'm going to
call out both these, I'm going to walk
through both of these. You may not love
some of the things that I mention, and
that's okay. I am sharing observations.
My thoughts on both are relatively
critical. I don't think it's healthy
what's happening inside both of these
algorithms, but it's also what's
happening. It's accurate. So, first, the
women's algorithm, the ads that they are
shown and the content they are served,
one of the biggest trends is that it is
helping women feel seen. What do I mean
by that? I mean, if you have a specific
scenario you're in, a relationship
scenario, a particular skin type, a
background, where you live, a medical
issue you've had, content is being
served that shows you that other people
are going through the same thing. This
is a major part of content that people
see. And this is a good thing in
general, when you come from a background
of women's problems not being as
knowledge as much as men's are, or not
being taken as seriously in the medical
community. There's kind of long storied
history around this that this is a
better solution then. And then we have
what we would refer to at work as the
trad to woke sweet to scandalous cycle
of content, where there are basically
leanings, where you'll have very like
traditional conservative leaning, you'll
have very woke leaning, and then you'll
have very kind of innocent content all
the way to scandalous content on all of
those. It kind of pushes those opinions
one way or the other, and people tend to
fall somewhere in the four square on how
they consume. And then there's an entire
separate algorithm cut out, it's like
the literary art quirky algorithm that's
more like quasi intellectual or actually
fully intellectual that is very
woman-to-woman and kind of operates
outside of that other four square. And
so, you will see this is actually a very
supportive algorithm as when we get to
men later, which is not like this. Where
people can basically find their tribe
and find people like them very easily,
and then develop these parasocial
relationships with creators and with
influencers in a really interesting way.
And this happens on Substack, it happens
with writers, happens with newsletters.
People find a worldview that's similar
to theirs and they latch onto it. And
when you think about how this affects
consumption, the recommendations that
come out of those algorithms feel so
organic and they feel like they make
sense cuz they're speaking to specific
problems. That's a completely different
consumption cycle than basically
anything aspirational, how we've been
marketed to for a decade. And so what
comes with this? What The negative that
comes with this is that when you feel
seen for everything, you get
justification for everything. So one of
the things we found looking at this
content is that any opinion that you
have in the women's algorithm gets very
justified. You're mad at politics,
you're mad at men, you're mad at other
women. You have a generational opinions.
It supports it. Specifically on women's
content, relentlessly, you see your
worldview. And so effective marketing in
there commiserates with that problem and
presents a solution. Classic problem
solution marketing is an amazing time to
say, "Hey, you're not getting enough
greens." Or "Does this makeup not work
with your skin type?" Or "Do you not
like wearing plastic leggings when you
work out?" Or "Are you worried about
your health insurance plan?" Whatever it
is, if you put that content, whether
that's a creator, an influencer, or an
ad, into that algorithm, it works and it
prints money on the other side and it is
a machine. Then we have the men's
algorithm. I am looking at this
objectively from data of working in
marketing in this. But I know everyone's
algorithm experience is different and we
will learn way more about it if we
actually talk about what people see. So
if you have a very different experience
than that, I'd love to hear in the
comments. There's a scenario that I'm
going to talk about a lot called the
quantified man. This is a theory that
men are quantified in a negative way way
more than ever before. Basically,
they're shown their own faults with
numbers every single day as soon as they
log on or open their phone. It starts
with dating apps, right? Men are
rejected on dating apps constantly and
they accept a lot more They put out a
lot more than they get back. Especially
if you fall underneath certain filters,
you're under 6 ft, guess what? Your
rejection is four times as high. Not an
actual stat, but you get the point I'm
trying to make. So hey, just number one,
you are just getting destroyed by dating
apps every single day. And then you're
also you're logging in and you're
seeing, "God, all these guys are richer
than me." Cuz guys are flexing their
wealth online more than ever before. All
their parleys hit. They've They've got
these Mac minis. They're running
automation, AI. I I even understand. So
they're constantly being hit by guys who
are more ripped than them, guys who have
more money than them, who seem to be
luckier than them, who are able to date
better than them, who are running
technology better than them. So, that
algorithm versus the kind of more
commensurate you feel seen algorithm
over here is, "Hey, you suck." algorithm
right there is being pointed towards the
majority of men every single day. And it
may not be direct, it may not be telling
that, but that's a subconscious message
that comes from so much of this being
shown to them. And so then, they are
being sold replacements for that,
supplements. You need creatine. Creatine
is what you've been mistaken. Oh, but
you didn't realize when you click that
create button, you're actually getting a
subscription. Now you're on Klarna. Oh,
you you you don't want a subscription to
creatine? Are you a weak man? That is
what those those gummy companies are
selling in like dark e-commerce cycles.
Peptides will solve all your problems.
That that'll make everything better.
Everyone else is cheating, that's why
they're in shape. Courses. Oh, everyone
else is richer than you because they're
cheating, they took a trading course,
right? That's being thrown at men
constantly. You could be a high-ticket
closer, you could be a trader, you could
be the like everyone else has followed
this method that you're afraid to invest
in. being men are being hit with that.
And they're being hit with that up, you
know, that's like the the college, early
20s level. That's the same thing moving
up. Oh, you don't want to buy and sell a
business in your 30s? You don't know
about this investment? Well, you get
this seven-point checklist. It's
happening all the way up to scale.
You're behind for where you should be at
45. And then AI, AI's the best one. AI
is how you escape the permanent
underclass. This new model is what's
going to get you ahead. You need to make
sure that you're securing your career if
you use this AI tool. You're automating
things with cloud code. You bought these
two Mac minis. And guess what? The
result of 99.9% of that is guys just
wasting time, buying into stuff that has
not actually helped them, but feels like
it's helping. And so this is a
complicated algorithm to to interact
with, right? And you add on top of that,
guys get on a lot on the women's
algorithm. There's a lot of anti-men
content, and look, that's probably
totally justified. I'm not going to get
into that here, marketing channel, not
an interpersonal relationships channel
yet. But then, what happens is they
console themselves with things to
impress other men. Right, if you go all
the way back to the beginning when I
talked about how we used to buy things
to impress the opposite sex, or used to
be marketed to do things to impress them
or potential partner. Again, not trying
to exclude anybody here. But now, women
buy things to impress other women. Men
buy things to impress other men. That's
a markedly different. And in particular,
right now, men are marketed things to
impress other men. Sneakers, almost all
male fashion. Over-lifting is a huge
one. And all the things that come with
that of workout routines to supplements
to the influencers they follow. That
Rimowa suitcase, that Rolex, whatever
that's going to impress another man to
make up for the fact of the quantified
fact you have. Golf, mentorships. And
you'll notice that all these things that
I'm calling out, which are all
categories this is exactly happening in,
are designed to bring a man away from
self-awareness, from participating in
convos that might make them enlightened
enough to appeal to a potential spouse.
And this leads to the factor for both of
these algorithms that the more online
you are, the worse it is. And you're
consuming from mostly same-gendered
voices. Guys have Barstool Sports, they
have How Long Gone, they have all their
like male industrial complex podcasts,
right? Women, it's the same thing.
You'll get well, you'll get Hot Smart
Rich, you'll get all these Look, not all
of it's bad content, plenty of it's good
content. But you're hearing it from
these communities. There's extremely
little crossover. There's extremely
little men and women talking through in
any way that's not ridiculously toxic
viral clickbait. It will be like all in,
right? No person watching the All In
podcast is building any trait that is
going to lead to a conversation that's
positive with the opposite sex, right?
It's slop. And this kind of cuts both
ways, but really cuts when there's not
other perspectives. There is no
monoculture to connect these. And the
more online you are, the worse it is.
And this ties to like other factors,
right? Like I don't know if you've ever
had a phone in your dreams. This is
always an interesting litmus test I've
been talking with my friend group a lot
about. Because now, people are starting
to see they'll have phones in their
dreams. Used to be we would never have
electronics and stuff like inside our
dreams. But when they do show up, there
was a study recently, it was like women
are like 40% more likely to have the
phone in their dreams than men. And
still like not a huge percentage of
people that reported but of the ones
that do, and you look at, okay, where is
phone addiction in terms of and where is
internet addiction in between the
genders. But this is the world we're
operating in. And so I want to end this
out with three key reasons why we buy.
You should be thinking about it. I would
ask yourself, especially if anything
I've said here has made you be like a
little triggered, I want you to think
about why you buy when you buy
something. One of the core goals of my
content, think about why you're
consuming. And then if you're a marketer
and brand, you think about how am I
presenting things when I'm selling them,
then how do I put the most positive spin
on that? So the three key ones I want to
talk about. First is loneliness. These
algorithms facilitate loneliness. Dating
apps facilitate loneliness. Being online
more in general facilitates loneliness.
And we are sold that being lonely and
alone are two different things. But
humans are social creatures. We are
being sold cope by marketing if we want
to think that being alone is something
that makes us happy. Guys will buy
sneakers because it is investment to
immediately be be into a group that will
acknowledge you purely by your purchase,
right? Travis Scott, Jordan, Nike. Nike
put the gas pedal on that, right? The
most money, the most exclusivity, and if
you had it, you were immediately part of
a group of other people that care about
it. Same thing with the minor things
like, okay, I'm going to choose this
water bottle. Why are people buying
Stanley water bottles off the off the
crushing aisles at Target? Not because
it's a great water bottle, because it's
a signaler that you're this type of mom
or this type of person. They had to ban
these at schools near me because the
girls would basically wouldn't sit with
girls who didn't have the same water
bottle and it became a problem. So
loneliness is a huge reason why people
buy and I don't say that to say that's
bad. In fact, an investment that helps
you make friends or help social
interaction become easier or helps you
find your tribe is honestly kind of a
great investment cuz that is harder than
ever in the internet world and friends
matter more than ever. Key to everything
is having a group. And so if it's easy
to signal that or a purchase helps with
that, I don't think that's a bad thing
necessarily. It's just worth calling out
as one of these reasons. The second
issue then the the worst one of these is
signaling and FOMO. Buying something
purely to signal something to a group
that does not necessarily involve you
having their friendship. You're
signaling online or something like that.
And FOMO, fear of missing out, you're
buying cuz the waitlist or it's going to
go or some kind of dark tactic or it's
exclusive or it's hot right now. It's a
little boo-boo. Signaling and FOMO
purchases are a lot of how marketing
works, a lot of kind of dark tactics.
It's worth always thinking about. I
always try to call with people if
they're like, "Oh, I buy all this stuff
or I'm over consuming." It's like, "What
are you buying? Cuz it's a signal or
because it's FOMO, right?" Rimowa, only
a signal. Has no other value. Most
people should never in their lives are
making enough money, unless you are in
the 1% to justify spending that much on
luggage. It's a signal FOMO purchase.
And the difference between that luggage
and luggage that's just as good that is
$1,000 cheaper is $1,000 that you could
be have to improve your life in any
other way. And the last reason we buy is
problem solving, right? Back to that
back to the fundamentals of the women's
algorithm, but this works for everybody.
Is you are now presented, "Hey, do you
have this issue? We built this thing to
solve that." And those issues are more
and more nuanced and more and more
particular. And brands are better and
better at now articulating their value
proposition. It's a huge part of
marketing today is doing that with
creators, influencers, ads for all the
kind of micro problems we damn near
didn't even know we had. And that tends
to be a great reason to buy something if
that's a real problem you exist with and
you want to validate that this is a
solution. I mentioned my shoe bags
earlier in the ADIO section. That's a
product that I sell that has a value
prop. It's a simple prop, but it's like,
"Hey, there's a washable, reusable
canvas shoe bag. If you are a dude and
you just put your shoes in your suitcase
or in your bag, it's kind of gross. Let
me just solve that for you in a
fashionable way you can also carry and
you can easily wash." And our ads are
basically that. Solving a problem for
somebody. And so those three reasons,
those are three of the 90% of sales are
coming through one of those three
reasons for a lot of these consumer
products that are out there. And I'll
get into dopamine and buying things to
buy things in a It'll be another video.
But that's the world that we exist in.
And one of my next videos is going to be
the A to Z of uh the creator economy,
creator marketing, how creators make
money. And I think what's important to
understand in this context is that
brands are responsible for some of this.
Creators are responsible for some of
this. But it's perpetuated by these
conversations we have between people.
And people now play more of a role than
ever inside our own communications. Men
consume way more from men, men that look
like them. Women consume way more from
women, women that they respond to their
look or their vibe or their identity.
There's just a bigger world out there
for anyone to navigate, for people to
feel a kinship to. And you've heard me
talk about this before in my content
videos, where multiplying the area level
of consumption, where if you want to get
your message across, you are if and you
you should have If you look at every
gender and every race should have one
person representing that because people
want to see not just people that look
like them, but people that look like
what they want to see. Some people want
to watch an older person give them
knowledge. Some people want to watch
someone their age. Some people want to
watch someone their their race. Some
people don't, but you want to cover if
you want to hit your full content TAM,
the total available market of content to
get a message across. Then a lot of that
comes down to all these different
appearances and then we multiply that by
content styles. You basically have how
the modern internet works on social
media. So I know I'm throwing a lot of
concepts out there. I know there's some
hot button ideas inside this one more so
than my usual videos. I'm going to
follow up with that creative video where
we're really going to talk about what
that expanse looks like. What how you
make money inside of it and how to
understand what's happening in that
economy and what it means for your
consumption. So anyway, please if you
see things that you agree with here, you
see things that you disagree with, I
would love to know. We'll be talking a
lot about this on the next community
call where I typically talk about
creative strategy for making ads, for
products, for for creators. And so this
is extremely tied to that, right? All my
observations here have basically been in
the name of helping brands sell more
stuff as awkward as that is. And this is
a scenario that we've worth like walking
through and understanding and work
shopping now if you are in those roles
because we have more data and
information than ever. Appreciate you
bearing with me on this one a little
outside the box for our normal content,
but I'm going to continue exploring
these these harder topics because I
frankly just doing tactical playbooks
and stuff gets kind of boring. I hope
you're here for it and thank you so much
for watching.