this is how to create a competitive
analysis whether you're launching a new
brand whether you're working for an
existing brand or have your own you want
to understand the things that are going
on and use the info you have to make
decisions this is how to critically look
at that this is one of the foundations
of brand strategy creative strategy all
comes from exercises like what I'm going
to break down so this is how you do a
competitive brand audit going into 225
and it starts on Tik Tock search I'm I'm
use on- running as an example in a lot
of this but why do I say Tik Tok search
well if you've used Instagram search
Instagram search is inherent useless
Google search is full of SEO optimized
basically uselessness Tik Tok search is
designed to give you the most relevant
stuff for what you're looking for and
it's often a mix of influencers and just
real customers who make content and it
is excellent at doing cuz you're going
to see actual reviews and you can search
review you can search complaint it's
pretty easy to see who's an influencer
or Not by their followers like cool my
honest thoughts wrote she's got 50k so
lightly influential but not too
influential you can see if it has a
sponsor tag orth it we're going to talk
about I purch but you can start going
through and sometimes it takes a minute
to go through like dozens and dozens you
can go through everything from these 2.1
million view videos to 100K to 5K you
can find anything that you want on here
for reviews for specific items you can
look at complaints so many people are
complaining that the and you can hear
what actual people are saying about a
product and describing it directly and
see the feedback for it and I cannot
represent how useful this is so if
you're a brand and you haven't done this
yourself very useful process to go
through to see what people actually
think of your product second for
competitors why I like searching
complaints and reviews is anything they
call out that is bad so for instance if
they're like hey this has this allergy
effect or can you know the ashiness Can
overpower the pigment whatever it is
that is now a development point for your
company if it's a big enough problem
enough people talk about you can focus
your products on solving and this is
huge in any Niche where you're trying to
build something you can also see the
marketing you can think about which of
these is seated which of these is real
what of these videos are viral and why
and then begin to make a strategy from
that so the other thing I like to do
with this is you can make briefs from so
you can see wow there's viral videos
about on-running like there's not a lot
of viral stuff in this top search but if
you start to find outsized results like
okay this is someone who has 60k but you
made a video that has hundreds of
thousands and you know okay with judging
by the engagement this isn't a paid post
necessarily and it's like all right what
about this video is good and what would
I want to do to potentially brief it so
we could try something like that with
our influencers our creators or for an
ad like what is speaking to people here
and you can begin to populate that
content into your content strategy but
Tik Tok is a head of the game all the
trends that come from here come to
Instagram later they come to ads later
and it's worth being the starting point
of any competitive research then we have
social blad social blade is excellent
you just need to create an account uh
it's free but you can go to Instagram
and look at what is actually happening
so the way I look at this I use this all
the time for Creator stuff too is you'll
see this chart it shows you how many
followers are growing a day and it kind
of es and flows and so the last 30 days
79,000 they're growing about 2,000
followers a day and some days are bigger
than others right you you'll start to
get a baseline of how good they're doing
or not and you get this chart and you
say okay my my God they grew you know
they were grow going relatively steadily
20,000 40,000 followers they started to
go up and up massive Spike what could
have possibly led to that massive Spike
and you can go over to the on Instagram
and you say okay what happened round
about those dates and I will cut to the
chase of what happened around those
dates but massive collaboration with one
of the biggest celebrities in the world
and you can start to be like okay well
I'm quantifying what does a big
celebrity partnership look like yeah
well it looks like a uh 100K week 165k
week and then another 100K week and then
we're still going maybe that's worth it
for them right as one can IM but it's
great for brands go back and pinpoint
strategies look at what reals took them
there and why all right so I'm going to
take a quick break to talk to you about
the artless 2025 content Trend report so
they put out this free report I linked
it down here below you can go grab it to
talk about all these Trends it's like
super extensive and I'm going to call
out a few of the ones I think are
particularly important for you to
understand so creativity's emotional
comeback and this idea of human
connection so we are seeing a a bunch of
like shady AI content for lack of a
better term basically people are
throwing out a bunch of video that's
mediocre they're using AI to write
scripts that are bad there's just a lot
of driil that's out there in the content
but the stuff that's standing out is
this like emotional driven contest
things that feel and get access to The
Human Experience you've seen this with
content like maximize where people are
basically making short films make you
feel something incredible and the second
one I want to talk about is influencer
collectives and Creator collectives this
is something obviously you've seen me
working on with the brand Brothers with
Ashman and Jordan and I and then also
the fact I sell cup 30 with Colin
landforce and Alex Garcia these are
people that I do business with and work
with and this is how a lot of creators
are going to function going in the next
year I think almost have to because
there's tons of influencers and people
rising fast that can do the same brand
deal as someone El else but if you have
a group where you can work together to
understand Trend and offer bigger things
to bigger Brands and make newer and
exciting content and build like a
narrative in a world around all of you
acting together this is how influencers
and creators need to be thinking and
this cries to Brands too how can you be
doing this collaboratively with all your
creators to tell a story bigger than
yourself and the last Trend I want to
talk about that's super interesting is
around age inclusivity a lot of us who
are working on content for so long on
Tik Tok on Instagram on YouTube talking
to younger people everything's nuanced
it has all this internet nomenclature
and you're making things for people of a
younger demograph but that is not the
case of who's actually on these
platforms and consuming especially short
form video any is now completely wide
range so a Mass Appeal comes from really
inclusive content right content that
anyone can understand second there's a
room to Zone in on those older
demographics to be like hey we make
content for people in their 50s and 60s
in our specific Niche so anyway this
entire Report with just tons of
information all the things you see here
about 60 pages of great stuff I only
called out three of multiple of things
they call out is available at is
available at the description of this
video and please grab that from artlist
I think you will find a lot of
interesting information then we have the
ads transparency tools if you haven't
used this this is just a massively
useful free thing Facebook has you go to
any Facebook page and know we don't
spend a lot of time on Facebook is the
only thing I use Facebook for besides my
ads account click to about click page
transparency and you click uh see all
scroll down go to ad Library this will
show you for any brand there's running
ads on meta Instagram Facebook Etc what
ads are running and how active they are
there's filters this is I'm my filter
set to active and you can literally see
the creative that they're running reels
they have Etc and so an interesting one
of this like like an interesting one
like I I use to bring up a lot in
conversation is Cole buckton because
they run a a majority of their organic
posts as ads as well something I do on
my page uh on my my brand page not my
personal page you can start to see oh
like there's some brands have a strategy
of just running a ton of ads there's
some that run some ads and they run some
of their reels there's some that do both
and you can begin to look at like how
many creatives are they running and
amount of creative is interesting
they're running 34 ads right now that's
not that many ads and you can then go
back to the oldest ones all right this
has been running since October they
don't have a bunch of like these are all
relatively newer ads means they don't
have any kind of long-term High
performers then let's pop over to
represent for instance 500 results so
this is more typical any brand that's
kind of growing and in the in that like
million million plus a month range is
probably running 500 to 1,000 plus ads
it's a shitload of creative but like a
lot of the brands that are really doing
it are running that many ads and you'll
see tons of reals they have tons of
stuff and if you scroll back they have
old winners in their ad accounts they're
still populated right you can see
they're still running stuff from
September that's working for them but
you can basically go through all of
these click the creative see what
they're doing and get creative ideas for
your brand if you're in the same I'm not
going to wait for that to load you can
say oh man some of these are running
since August and you and stuff that's
running you know way back way back is
probably stuff that has worked for them
and so it's worth working on they can
also see oh cool they're running a bunch
of ads in German and you begin to
understand people's strategy and so I
use this a lot just for creative ideas
what are people running as an ad how is
it different than their social feed
extremely useful tool to have in your
toolkit to understand what people are
doing and the scale they're doing it at
like you may think if you don't have it
like you're not Discerning on what's
Happening be like hey those two Brands I
just looked at are are they relatively
the same size somewhat no represent is
on a tear and a significantly bigger
category similar tool kit this one you
have to pay for the good access but free
access has some of it is M we'll just
keep on our our represent uh angle here
brand I respect for represent CL Mill
lets you look at any emails that people
are sending out so if you're doing
competitive for email first thing you do
is sign up for the list so you can see
what automation they give you are they
sending you automated emails after you
sign up onboarding email additional
sales additional info you'll learn a lot
from that add items to your cart and see
what their abandoned card flow is is it
one email is it multiple emails what
level of discount are they putting out
there if you tally all the stuff up say
you just took all this stuff and you you
you have a boss or you're starting a new
company trying to get investment you're
like hey I did competitive analysis and
I went through and I found here's the 10
pain points people are talking about on
Tik Tok about our brand and about the
you know and for our product I think we
should do okay and then here's the
social content strategy which really
works for these Brands here's their two
peak points where they gain this many
followers and here's the content that
helped jump start that okay and now
here's their top performing ads they've
been running the longest here's four
creative ideas I think that I want to do
based on a successful creative other
people in our nich doing okay then
here's the exact email card abandon
strategy they're doing 20% I think if we
did 30% it would go even better and hey
no one's they're not using automation
but we really should use email
Automation and then start looking at the
campaign you start putting that info
together you're knocking the socks off
anyone that you there people are not
used people working that hard or having
that much info and then you become the
person with all the context right I have
all this context cuz I'm doing this
constantly whenever I go do a like I
have three brand workshops coming up of
some variety I'm going to go research
this beforehand right like I one for
like a major handbag brand I'm like I'm
going to go find out everything they're
doing everything's in their Niche and
I'm going to come fully prepared with
that and also that's just a toolkit I
have to talk about stuff in my videos to
be intelligent in other conversations by
diving in on stuff like for instance
here's all these represent emails and uh
you can access up to 12 months if you
you know you create an account I'm say
I'm just browsing through this here but
look they have a thousand emails that
are in M shows you how frequently and
how often they're emailing and you can
actually go in and click it and see
anything that's happen and then by far
the most useful and this is paid I've
done a bunch of sponsored short form
content for for these guys this is not a
sponsored video at all I use this app
all the time but this is particle if you
am having particle data is an absolute
superpower I cannot describe to you what
life was like before this like if you
want to go look at exactly how much your
competition is selling of something then
you can basically just go look at you
can go look at Ali yoga and be like this
is $247 million sales over time we can
see there's the spike 1028 2024 of just
huge huge amounts of money and guess
what that coincides with their early
Black Friday how much money
they're doing on 42,000 units of this
Accolade net pullover in espresso like
their top selling product is brown you
can tell you a lot just there so anyway
inside this look at product distribution
they have similar stuff to the mil stuff
in here where you can actually I think
actually is MIL inside of this where you
can go look at all the email campaign um
you can see discounts another one I like
to pull up um I use a lot when I talk
about discounting is crafted crafted is
a really interesting one to look at um
look at this crafted top products
interesting for a couple reasons first
is all their products are bundles their
top products are all bundles which is
something that you should be 100% trying
for any brand that's that's selling
stuff especially if you're selling
jewelry or commodity stuff is like make
your own set make your own set silver
set gold set pre-built set pre-built set
pre-built set average discount these are
always selling at an average discount of
20% so there's a price perception thing
they're doing constantly where they're
like hey you can get a deal on this
they're pushing deals whether that's
coupon codes that's live they're running
sales all the time and you can see
that's a strategy like the two core
takeaways from this if I was going to
sell men's jewelries I'd be like I need
be doing sets I need to be offering
discounts like extremely regularly they
don't have to be huge they can average
out whether that's a bunch of 25 and 30%
that I offset with a lot of always
regular pricing or it's like a constant
20% that's the kind of info that you can
pull around this and you can also break
down stuff like color basically it's
like okay silver and gold are basically
at a one to one ratio for these guys
which is super interesting right like
you may think that one might be bigger
than the other and same thing for colors
of different products that you may want
to sell so for instance we look at
represent here you can see the
bestselling products higher price
product I can go down to color and be
like yeah guess what it's there is not a
lot of color variants here if I was
selling to their demographic you know
maybe I do some brown and blue but we
are we are running black for the vast
vast majority of anything you can look
at the male female unisex breakdown you
begin to understand all this about any
brand so this is like the real tool
where you can get an understanding of
social media you can get understanding
of customer complaints you can see what
ads people are running inside the other
tools get some context you can go here
and see what the results are are and
compare it directly like fact I can go
compare lud lemon and aloe and realize
what the difference is in their sales
strategy is like always a really
interesting thing to think about and you
can begin to understand just how
in-depth these things run rate of things
sold I also like to look at this look at
viral products this is the last one I'll
probably do here so cool I want to look
at Brook Lin and they're selling like
viral linen products you can start to be
like all right what is the actual
details of these sales like this is per
day how many units they're selling like
thousands and thousands and thousands of
units where's their revenue trending
compared to their competitors where's
their revenue trending compared to the
overall Market where to thing like all
right they're selling 100 you know you
can basically go analyze by fastest
selling products like okay this tote bag
is actually their bestselling product
would I guess that notar I thought they
were more of a betting company and he
starts to be like look at the rates they
have per day how that the revenue of
some of these products differs from the
rates sold and again I would say this
data is like nothing's ever going to be
perfect let's say it's directionally
correct let's say it's 90% it's probably
better maybe it's maybe it's 85 you at
least get the idea like what is the sale
but it gives you an idea of all the
things you can do to run one of these
competitive analyses understand the
things that are happening so your
homework I'm trying to add this into as
many videos and email stuff as I can is
go do something like this for one of
your Brands um if you have a budget you
want to do things like go purchase
something go look at your whole
demographic inside mil inside particle
and like being to figure that out if
you're just looking at it to get your
own awareness up almost all the things I
I showed uh again you can do a lot mil
without having to have the account I
think free account you can look up to 12
months um almost all the things that I
put out here are free to go look at and
you begin to get an understanding of
what's happening around you and this is
like a super crucial tool to think about
because it's like the foundation of
brand Strat is understanding the
landscape around you and in fact that
today we have the opportunity to get so
data driven on that in a way that just
was not possible for decades is amazing
so I know it was a very technical
tactical video like getting into stuff
but this is a crucial part of your
strategy toolkit and I really hope you
enjoyed it