This is the new playbook for brands to
win on social media in 2025. And if you
are creating on social media at all, if
you advise or work for brands or work in
marketing, if you have your own brand,
it's kind of crucial to understand this.
This is a version of a talk I give all
the time at corporate off sites and in
presentations and workshops I do with
brands. So, I've refined this pretty
regularly over time. And it goes through
three things. the foundational content,
what every brand should be doing like
table stakes for modern brands on social
and then it goes through growth social
strategies that brands who are growing
and executing well on social media are
doing basically all of and then I'm
going to go into the leading edge the
2025 modern strategies that brands who
are on the fringe are executing on. Now,
if you have a complete picture of this
toolkit of all these things that brands
are operating and doing and how they
structure, you will know way more about
social media than 99% of marketers. And
that is my goal by the end of this video
is for you to have a comprehensive
understanding where you can shock people
with how deep you are in terms of
exactly what the strategies are that are
working. So anyway, it's going to be an
interesting ride. We'll have plenty of
video and visual examples along the way
and I am excited to lock in. First, I
want to talk about the foundation. What
should every brand have before they
start thinking about doing more on
social media? And so the first thing is
owned social network presence on
Instagram and Tik Tok. Instagram and Tik
Tok have the highest leverage for any
brand out there. Don't talk about
LinkedIn, YouTube, X, any of these
things until you have Tik Tok and
Instagram. Why is this? Because of this
amazing generational opportunity that is
anytime you post a video on these
networks, even if you're brand new,
you're going to get 200 to 400 views
automatically. It is going to give you a
shot to roll the dice into virality.
From video one on those accounts, you
can get 10,000 views to a million views.
And we see it again and again. And being
able to leverage that opportunity which
just did not exist like purely did not
exist a decade ago is a immense thing
that every brand should focus on. And so
the foundational point is having the
accounts on there but now it is
basically table stakes to be approaching
those networks differently to say we do
not post the same content on Instagram
as we do on Tik Tok. We know that they
are different. The algorithms are
rewarded differently. We may use similar
things or similar cuts but we actually
treat those two differently. And the
third part of the foundation is
consistent use of influence inside
content where personalities whether they
have 10,000 followers or a million
followers are contributing to your story
on the internet and helping tell that
through collaborative posts being a part
of your actual on your profile or just
calling out your brand. But that is what
any brand who takes social media
seriously starts with that as the
foundation and everything else is extra.
But that was the simple part. Let's dive
into actual growth social. What does
that mean? So when I define growth
social and I update this presentation
pretty frequently as like time goes on.
I'm really looking at what were people
doing really well last year that now
everyone who's smart is adopting. So
this is really the 2024 playbook now
that we've had some time to actually
look at it review it and see what has
stayed consistent. So the first thing is
creators as the face of brands putting a
face to your social media content. This
can be done in several ways. You'll see
brands like Dar Shoots who have a
handful of creators basically doing
skits and you see the same recurring
faces all the way to brands that have a
creator making content relatively
regularly inside their feed as the
primary creator to people who have
secondary accounts with other creators
on them in addition to their main
accounts. But you will notice that
personalities have come into social
media content. And basically every good
account that is growing through that
likely has a strategy where there is a
creator involved. And this ties really
well into this idea of founder
personalities. And not every brand does
this, but a lot have realized how
critical it is. And you'll see they
don't have to have the biggest
personalities. To use that dare shoots
example again, their founder is often
present in the skits and the voice in
his own videos. One fashion brand I love
to call out with this is Perl. Perival
will have the founder inside their
videos like every 10 or so. He'll give
an update on the business or he has like
a cheeky perspective or he'll do one of
the traditional and it's not the core of
the content but it's part of it. And
you'll see brands like Kosis where the
founder is in collabs. She's building
her own presence. It's not huge 30
40,000 but is a central character to a
certain part of the brand marketing. And
it doesn't always have to be a founder.
It can just be a CTO or someone who's
extra present. But there tends to be an
employee who's helping drive a different
focus on social media like tangential to
the world that is driven by the core
accounts. And with that, influence has
graduated from hiring an influencer to
do a single post into influencers in
long-term relationships with brands
where they have sponsorships where
they're the faces where they do
different content. You may have noticed
I debut art list reports all the time. I
have a long-standing relationship with
them where I debut those reports. Same
thing with Particle. I do videos with
Particle every month. I'm a voice and a
part of the Particle community. I've
announced the last two Shopify editions.
They have a relationship with me as a
creator in a recurring capacity where
it's interesting for my audience to hear
about that, where people grow to expect
it, where you are a character inside
their story. Those long-term
relationships are better for everyone.
It's not just a sporadic one-off where
you talk to your audience about it and
forget it. It feels like it's developing
real rapport. It makes you think and
spend more time with the brand and be
more conscious of it and actually be
able to storytell about it better. And
then everyone can look at consistency
and realistic natures when it comes to
kind of rates and relationships. And so
that is the big personality drivers
there is integrating creators and
recruiting those creators into the core
brand accounts having founder or team
presences that are on there. And we'll
talk about employee generated content in
the like leading edge stuff later. And
beginning to build influencers that are
more like a team way we look at like a
sponsored skate team back in the day.
And this is something I've always been a
huge fan of. When I was doing a lot of
work with Lift Foils, it is a a surf
foil and e- foil brand. They always had
a team, a bunch of sponsored people. We
always had them in the same content.
They were had other relationships like
Brian Grub, who's one of those people
who did that, had all these big deals
with Red Bull. He's doing all these
tricks. He's doing these things, but he
also will be coming and doing tutorials
inside our Lyft content. You could go
explore that team. We highlighted them.
It was part of our content planning was
we know we could get X videos from this
person, X videos from that person, and
they're using our gear inside of the
other content opportunities they're
exploring. That's a really realistic and
good way to think about growing
influencer inside your social versus
just paying for more and more one-off
posts. But perhaps the biggest
development in growth social last year
was how big seeding has become like
extensive product seating to
influencers. Not just like sending a
handful of products, sending a boat ton.
I work with a brand sending up to 3,000
mailers out a month of products that
aren't cheap. Inside one of my brands,
we are sending dozens. And brands are
realizing that just sending stuff out
with no expectations and beginning to
have those relationships and watching
people post and knowing that creators
need things to talk about as well
becomes useful. And big brands are
adopting as well. I got an ESOP package
the other day which is something I never
expect a brand of that caliber to be
starting to seed especially to creators
that are relatively fringe like myself.
But that is where we've gotten on this
is that they are thinking in terms of
scale of that as well. And to do this
I'm going to break down some management
of this and how to do this well. We'll
get briefly into tactics here before I
go back high level. So usually how this
works to do this well is there's a
research portion of this. A lot of this
research happens on Tik Tok or happens
on tags on Instagram. Look at who tags
the brand on Instagram. You can find it
there. You search Tik Tok and you search
review. You search the brand name. You
will find hundreds typically for a
brand. You do that throughout your
category. You make a list. You do
outreach to those people. And you're
literally DMing them from a brand
account or using an email. If you find
an email to get an address to send them
stuff. You are monitoring all this in a
spreadsheet because there is no software
that is actually good for this. There
are some that try and then you are kind
of noting, okay, did they receive the
product? you're following up and they
did receive it to see how it went and
all that needs to follow a cadence. Did
they actually post? You have to monitor
because stories and stuff like that
sometimes it can slip through. So
matters to actually check in on these
creators. You see if they actually
engage, if they did engage, you're
actually notating that so you know if
they engage and you're beginning to
build a list of people that actually
post when you send them stuff. Then
you're noting who has results because if
you got a bunch of followers from
something, this is why I encourage
influencers to do feed posts a lot
instead of stories is people can see
more result from that and be like, "Hey,
that got 10,000 views or 100,000 views."
They're beginning to be interested in
introducing those people into campaigns.
And it's a graduation from I just hit
them up and I gave them something, they
didn't respond, all the way to, hey,
this is now a person that we pay that's
integrated in our workflow. And there is
in this economy we have of creators,
that's a whole different video, there is
no shortage of people in whatever niche
you are to do that. And the lift that
comes from this in terms of, oh, that
content did really well. Let me now run
this in the Spark ad or white label this
and pay them all the way to just seeing
the natural sales lift is significant.
And if it is not or you're not seeing
content, there's probably things related
to the unboxing experience or to the
product itself that make it not warrant
to have that jump. Now, the fifth of the
six tactics in this growth social
segment is the multi-account presence.
You will see lots and lots of brands
doing this is a smart way because you do
one social account is not enough to take
advantage of what's happening. So, you
will see brands will have accounts by
region. So for instance, one thing we
had done at gelb blaster I talked about
a few times is we had accounts for
Mexico accounts for Canada for Germany
for UK specifically supporting those
retailers and their initiatives when we
were distributed globally and actual
creators who make content in different
languages or different accents around
that. So regional is an approach a lot
of brands do and you will get a creator
in that region posting from that region
with that account in that language or in
that dialect doing things that are
particular to that culture and it works
really well. The second multi- account
item is by style. So you will notice,
hey, we actually have a more candid
account or we have people that look
different on different accounts. We have
like in cosmetics, it's like, hey, we
have girls with different complexion or
different racial backgrounds or facial
structure or eye types. That's important
because people follow people that look
like them and have similar problems and
similar encounters in their life to
them. Same thing in fashion. You will
notice, I actually did a study for a
major retailer for this where we were
interviewing Gen Z people where they
follow people that look like them and
check what outfits they have from
fashion influencers to then decide what
they were going to wear. not necessarily
to buy the product, but to say, "Oh, how
am I going to style these like denim
jeans or whatever it looks like?" And
it's because they find people with their
body type to see what looks good on
them. And that is a whole subculture.
So, styles of content and then types and
looks of people. You will start to see
brands will have 10 accounts, 15
accounts because the ripple effects of
the internet are basically as big as you
can possibly scale to. And the last
piece, especially for physical products,
is Tik Tok shop with affiliates. not
just putting a Tik Tok shop up, seeding
affiliates and beginning to run hundreds
of people, getting to 40 videos a day,
100 videos a day, coming from affiliates
to drive revenue in there. And this is a
really important one to think about
because of the lift of it. If you are
not super familiar with Tik Tok shop,
the basics of it are there are creators
that run affiliate. That basically means
that they can make money when they post
and link a a product. You've already
seen that. Now, they are in high demand.
There are lots of those people out
there, especially if you can actually
drive some revenue. So, they are
constantly gifted products. You have to
have a program to reach out to them and
get them to gift their products. Rarely
are you going to have good creators
actually request it. Now, none of these
creators also get on retainers who
actually paid a monthly basis to do x
amount of videos for brands. And so,
brands are constantly hunting those
down. But what happens is with that
commission, the Tik Tok shop sales
coming in, you are still beating most
retail margins. And there's a lot of
scale to it. So, you'll notice the
bigger brands that are operating at this
who are doing a million a month or even
hundreds of thousands a month,
multi-million a month, are running so
many affiliates and creators. There's so
many videos about their products hitting
at various degrees that it has a lift on
Amazon has a lift for brand recognition.
Can you imagine if by purely off
commission you could incentivize
commission and grit to be fair. You
could have have hundreds of people every
month posting about your brand on the
internet that aren't influencers you
pay. It is a majestic opportunity for
brands and one that everyone is taking
serious in this growth social lens. So
now we get to the fun part, the leading
edge. What are brands that are on the
tip doing right now? What are the people
that are standing out happening like as
we speak, as I make this video in June
20 and 25? So, first, this idea of video
series and brand TV. This is one of my
favorite conversations cuz this is where
you get all the people being like, "Oh,
the budget. They need tens of thousands
of dollars an episode." One dude or girl
with a mirrorless camera or a fullframe
or whatever it is can work absolute
[ __ ] miracles. And if you are denying
that, you do not know what you are
talking about and you are going to get
left behind by this era. I have seen
shoots now that look like they're full
production shoots just literally a
person shooting someone one way in a
conversation then turning around and
shooting it the other way with the same
camera and like moving two lights and
getting the same results you normally
have a crew for. And this is where we're
at with technology with the savvy of
this younger generation of videographers
and with the run and gun nature of
brands making great content. But you'll
see all these brands who are doing brand
TV. Alexis Betar, probably the most
prolific, who created the series that
got so popular that like they have Lar
Ro kind of crossing over into it and
like minor celebrities inside of it all
the way down to the lower production
where you have Mohawk Chevrolet remaking
the office inside of their car
dealership. But basically, this is
brands who are saying, "Hey, in addition
to our normal social on those channels,
we're going to have a recurring series
every week or whatever it is where we
are treating it like we're making TV."
That is something a fringe groups are
doing. Ritz Carlton did it recently.
It's going from small brand to big brand
and is a super savvy way to approach
content because the reason this works is
because we are in this consumption shift
where people are just moving from TV and
streaming to social increasingly and if
they are doing streaming or watching TV
they also have social on at the same
time and by replicating formats that
people know inside that social it works
and it helps brands be more
entertainment and less purely selling.
The second thing probably the most
talked about this year is clipping and
distribution and services like [ __ ] So,
what this means is you are hiring
people, whether oneoff or are putting it
out there to a community to clip videos,
basically take your existing content
archive and put them out on other
accounts to gain additional
distribution. This happens in two ways.
One, you'd employ someone to actually
make those clips and put them out there
and play them a fat fee, maybe an
incentive to say, "Hey, you're going to
make these clips a month. You're going
to post them on these accounts." Second
is you do a bounty inside programs like
Wap. We're like, "Here's a training.
Here's our archive. We will pay you
$2.50 per thousand views." I think
that's what Goalie is paying right now.
I can confirm it. I have it on here.
That's exactly what they're paying right
now. It's easier to do this for personal
brands, right? That's why you see people
like Bred Scales has a has a great
channel. People you've seen do this and
help them blow up. Druski has a channel.
They're offering much less, but it's
easier for you to be able to blow up
doing that. And those bounties will rise
over time. You can basically pay for
views being circulated by people
clipping content. The power of this is
massive as well, cuz someone can feel
like they're everywhere. And the
algorithms are smart. And if you start
to watch a Bre video, you see 14 other
Bre accounts suddenly conquer over your
timeline. It is a genius way to get
faces out there that started with
personal brand. This dates all the way
back to the Tate era was the original
playbook for this. It's now been kind of
commodified and now is in the brand era
where goalie's on the fringe. Goalie is
one of the if you aren't familiar with
them. They're a Tik Tok shop like hero
story and they're leaning into more
fringe stuff. We worked for them for Tik
Tok shop and it was also like helped
turn their company around from near
bankruptcy and more brands are to follow
if they have the right catalog and they
fit the right mold. Then we're entering
into long form on YouTube. YouTube is
one of the hardest content types to
break as a brand. You'll see brands that
do it really well either have
personalities to lead it. I'll call out
Represent or I'll call out Minted New
York because they're basically just
documenting their founders working out
and doing stuff around running a brand
which is just compelling content for
male consumers to just have on on the TV
and has a great angle for it. But if you
don't have those kind of personalities
in your brands a little bit harder or
you have basically just YouTubers who
are starting brands or you have brands
are treating YouTube like YouTube. [ __ ]
being another good example of that where
they're going and doing YouTube style
long form videos about people with an
aspirational lifestyle who are on who
are doing clipping etc. and kind of in
that culture and telling amazing dynamic
well-edited stories. But to do that on
YouTube, you have to have a concept. You
have to treat it like a show. It's not
just making videos. You have to either
act like a YouTuber or act like a show
of content. And that is something that
is really hard for brands to do. It's
why you see so few on here with any
level of resonance. But that is a huge
opportunity for the ones that do. And
one of the reasons I'm so focused on
YouTube, you see these videos every week
is there's still just a massive delta.
It's so much harder than the other
networks. And if you are the ones to
succeed on it, you're owning a line
share of the attention. Like not to cut
y'all in on a secret out here, but like
there's not many other marketing
creators out there. There's not many
other marketing creators getting these
views. Most of the videos about
marketing that get views are kind of
older videos and sitting in the
algorithm. I'm one of the only ones
putting up those numbers, if not the
only one doing like real B2B like that.
And that has a monopoly over people's
mind share that is like unassalable. And
the longer you keep doing that and the
farther ahead you are, the better it
goes. And it's actually shocking to me
how far ahead this is and how few people
are competing to keep up. That's a
separate video. Then we go into EGC.
There's three more left in this leading
edge category. So EGC is employee
generated content. So we're in this era
where Gen Z is deeper and deeper in the
workforce. Gen Alpha is about to start
coming in the workforce. And if it feels
like half of Gen Z are creators, it's
cuz it's probably true. There are so
many people who are native to making
content. It's natural for them to make
content at their jobs. It's also natural
for them to be on screen or want to be
on screen or see where that takes them.
So you'll have brands, Remy by Riley is
a great example, where their employees
are part of the content. The Remy by
Rally account is funny because literally
it's just employees doing trends and not
even talking about the the product, but
they're just like running content for
fun basically. And this is a good model
for brands to begin to inundate
themselves into the culture to gain
exposure to leverage the fact a lot of
their employees want to be creators.
Complicated in other ways in terms of
how do you actually incentivize this or
reward this or pay for this and what are
people's work responsibilities but more
and more brands are putting just
separate employee channels or employees
on Maine more and more frequently and
then we enter into niche social for
instance Snapchat still big for brands.
NYX Cosmetics is a big Snapchat. If you
are targeting Gen Alpha, Gen Z and you
are not on there and you're a brand that
is more consumer focused, like you need
to hire some younger people to help you
navigate that. And even Substack, so
Rare Beauty just launched on Substack. A
friend of Hyper, Casey Lewis, Hyperlet I
had with Clayton. We've interviewed her
a few times. An amazing Substacker is
helping American Eagle do a Substack
where they're looking at, hey, let's
find some of these niche communities,
smaller things. may not be worth our
full social time, but if we're already
good at all this other stuff, this is
something we can lean into at a
reasonable budget to find a more niche
focus. Again, you only get to once
you're at the leading edge. The way I
like to break this down is you have to
do the foundation, master everything in
growth social, then get into things that
are on the leading edge. And you will
see there are teams once you start
getting in the flow of this, it becomes
much easier than than what it looks like
here. And the last piece is the mass
seeding affiliate and training. That's
when you start talking about they're
seating thousands of affiliates,
thousands of influencers every week with
new product. You're adding tons of
affiliates on a Tik Tok shop, as many as
you can. And then you are training. The
step that goes beyond that is you're
starting to recruit from your community.
You're starting to find people who are
trying to be influencers in your
audience and coach them up to find
people who aren't affiliates yet on Tik
Tok, but make good videos about your
product and making them into affiliates.
This is the real edge is like you're
basically being we have to drag those
people along with you. You can't wait
for people to do it. You're better off
recruiting them, bringing them into the
light and having them stick with you is
like the very very very leading edge of
what's happening right now. That's the
social landscape. That's what brands are
doing. like every tier in capability.
That's every one of those tactics, at
least a brief summary. You will never
find content as comprehensive about this
this on the internet. Frankly, I charge
a lot of money to do this in person.
Basically, I don't think anyone who's
actually done this in person will ever
see this YouTube video cuz my audience
here is much younger. But if they do,
actually, the value goes into let's
actually workshop this through
everything your company's doing today.
What's the status of each one of those?
Which one of these is actually a
priority? What are the steps to act on
that? And even just the hour you spend
on that has a massive value. And that's
where I come in. But if you've ever
wanted that comprehensive look at this,
this is a great video for it. I will
probably update this if this does well
next year because these things naturally
change. If you have any questions about
these different content types and styles
and things going on here, let me know.
I'll either tackle in the comments or
try to hit on another form of media. I
appreciate y'all watching so much. I
will link some other brand social
content here, marketing content that's
relevant. Thank you'all so much for
watching.
[Music]