I do an exercise in inperson workshops
with Brands small and large it's called
a brand narrative exercise this video
I'm going to walk through the complete
process I used to run this all the
different stages of the exercise and a
bunch of real life examples good brands
now who create compelling content often
view their content in their world like a
TV show plots sets characters and even
if you don't think your brand is set up
to be structured like that almost all
are and in this exercise we actually
hash through that we identify all those
different plot points you can use to
form your brand narrative and then we
make a Content plan from there of how
that actually feeds into the marketing
that you create and today we're going to
go through that whole thing we'll go
through stage byst stage then I'll break
down examples in fashion from represent
and in consumer package goods from poppy
if you ever really want to understand
how a brand narrative and a brand story
shapes and how you can do that in a
really modern way this is the video for
you so why would you want to treat your
brand like a TV show how does that even
make sense why is your brand even need a
narrative to start short form media
short form video Instagram Tik Tok
YouTube they dominate the way consumers
create content they also dominate as the
places where we advertise Our Brands for
online sales or for online awareness for
retail sales whether we're doing that
directly through our organic media
whether we're using influencers whether
we're running it as advertisements
that's where media consumption lives and
people treat engagement with this
content the way we used to treat
traditional entertainment watching TV
the way you go on and see sitcoms or
watch sports people now scroll their
feeds or they do both at once there's a
new generation of entertainment in the
same formats that we saw on traditional
television that's taking over feeds as
well so one of my favorite examples
there two and a few of these are from
the same production company um gymnasium
is is boy room or boy room so this has a
comedian where it actually goes to
basically insane houses that single
dudes have in you know uh Philadelphia
or New York and you get these tours of
these kind of basically a look into a
wild world someone might have and
they're presented in a short episodic
format that's not unlike what you would
see on TV but instead it's built for Tik
Tok and Instagram like almost everyone
has seen Kareem's amazing show um as
many of you guys may have known for a
campaign for a different brand Kareem
and I had had some uh fake beef earlier
this year but we had some fun with it
super interesting guy with an
interesting way of doing things on the
internet and he has this amazing Subway
takes show where he basically gets quick
informational stuff on the subway and
everyone gives a take it's an episodic
series you can go scroll through a 100
of them or one comes across your feed
you know exactly what you're looking at
but it's not just interview style
formats as well Liam run into this
Bodega get me toilet paper you and P so
for instance Bodega run and I think all
three of these are by that same
gymnasium production company they're
basically timing people going into a
store to be able to get a certain number
of things and find it in a certain
amount of time without the bodega owners
necessarily knowing and they're just
kind of creating a more fun visceral
entertainment series I encourage all
creators in an excellent strategy but
that's entertainment companies treating
short form as entertainment what about
Brands so this concept I think the first
time I made this video January 2023 this
is something I've been harping on for a
minute I've actually seen a lot of
brands do and a lot of Brands reach out
that this video was impactful in how
they've looked at their content is brand
should be doing the same exact thing
because now we're at the time where
people consume value content and
entertainment content side by side it's
not like I just watch TV and I only
watch sitcoms and dramas and sports on
TV and then when I want to learn
something I go read books right which is
a very generalized way of what is looked
like 10 years ago but now someone might
consume a piece of my content about
marketing right next to Bodega run and
that's just part of their day right
they're consuming multiple things at a
time right next to a promo piece from a
brand all this is in one feed and so you
are competing against that and so I did
this video and then a series of of ones
that came after about thinking of your
brand story as a TV show and actually
setting up like this and got an amazing
response for it and now 18 months later
it's a concept that's that's everywhere
I'm not saying I created the concept
necessarily but definitely was one of
the first people really pushing it out
there like that and have been stoked at
how many Brands responded to that and
have built with that in mind and I've
talked in similar ways about how
creators and Brands can look at making
sets Etc but the reason you dive into
these existing plot devices is because
they work because people are used to
them because if entertainment has used
them for so long there's probably
something in human psychology that gets
you to actually resonate with it so
let's look at brands that are actually
doing this an interesting way so midday
squares is an amazing one and one of the
founders guessed it on Cut 30 a few
weeks ago and really a really
interesting breakdown of when they
wanted to actually start on their brand
there this had this idea that from the
start they want to in their identity
have this kind of reality show and they
said that they came up with they used a
really interesting idea where they came
up with with basically three spirit
animals for their brand and how they
were going to make their content and I
think the first was um one was Shark
Tank it's like Shark Tank the
Kardashians and Elon Musk or something
similar an apologies to their team if I
butchered that but they basically from
the beginning were like we want this
combination of you know business content
with a dramatic feel like are they going
to make it and they're pitching along
with this like overall celebrity feel
almost documented as reality TV and you
can see that in their content they've
built these personalities around the
different people in the brand every that
you see in one of these content pieces
is like kind of dramatic but in a really
interesting way where they're talking
through how they built a chocolate
factory or some big thing that came up
for their brand or walking through their
story and they've definitely embraced
this kind of approach by a very
different lens we have Alexis patar so
and this is a brand that's been around
for a minute and changed their content
strategy and shifted it to these
vignettes so they basically came up with
a number of not real characters they
presented a fictional world with hazel
formerly Jules a bunch of these other
folks basically like stylists and
characters and Personalities in New York
they set them in certain stages and had
drama come up between the characters
when they showed up at parties and
attempted murder like they have
basically created this little vignette
Series where they all get you know they
all get a bunch of views they're able to
go back and forth and like have this
interplay between characters there's
drama and people really got into this
world they created because it's a world
where it's very natural for them to wear
the jewelry of the brand and people
really wanted to follow this like fun
little scripted series and got in touch
with the characters and they consume it
in little 30 to 90 second vignettes and
those are two far-reaching approaches is
right you can approach the brand
documenting it completely like a reality
show creating a fictional show and then
there's just kind of like a more normal
approach to it which is what I'll talk
about when I actually give my examples
of a represent or or poppy let's kick
into the exercise so this is the Brand
Story when I do this in person we sit
down and we Workshop this out in a
whiteboard and we start with the plot
what is happening with our brand so if
you're a new brand or an old brand what
would actually be going on so the plot
for instance you have events underneath
plots so that is are we launching a
product that's an event are we going to
a trade show that's an event do we have
like a yearly offsite that's an event
are we doing a big influencer house or
meet up that can be an event you list
all those out you end up having kind of
quite a lot of them and you can decide
basically with a little check mark is
this event worthy of content or is it
not you want a big old list on one side
then you have devices so plot devices
are things like is there drama involved
with this is there something that we
want to be able to come up with to lead
into it is there a narrative connection
between these two things do we have kind
of fiction or do we have recurring ideas
or items they almost feel like events we
want to make sure hey every month we do
something like this like it's basically
where you get to get creative underneath
events and then how you're able to kind
of connect those together with the
emotions of an existing like you would
see in television or in movie where it's
a cliffhanger something like that like
how do you begin to build into the plot
how those devices you how those events
actually connect and then we have sets
where do we film where do we make
content what do we have say we have an
office space and a factory space and
midday square is just great there you'll
see like the Chocolate Factory where
they make it you'll see the office where
they do their things we're doing some
demos and things in Costco where Costco
basically became a set piece for them
and there's oneoff sets okay are we
doing a thing are we going to a trade
show are we at a hotel does this
influencer have a house whatever it is
what are oneoff places that we might
shoot and characters and characters was
where it gets interesting so we'll start
with the team who on the actual team of
the brand makes content if you're the
founder are you making content is your
designer making content are there other
people in the company that make content
this is interesting the something when I
was working at jail Blaser there was
like the head of sales is a very active
LinkedIn presence his LinkedIn is part
of the overall content strategy from a
like in a significant way and he wasn't
like if you had said and sat down you
know okay well we have the CEO he's
involved in content um we have a social
media Creator she's involved in content
we have other kind of social media team
members they're involved a bit but then
you have someone who actually makes
content professionally as part of you
know similar way like I do around
marketing content and you're like okay
we actually want to integrate that in
the story and his content was a very big
piece of that for certain networks and
you actually make the list of team
members you want to create content that
can create content and in bigger
companies this becomes interesting
Workshop like who actually wants to and
who do we want to and do they fit the
brand who else is there but having that
combo and getting it out there and
knowing what tools you have is important
to be able to structure that narrative
and then we have Community are our
people making content do our customers
make content how can we involve them in
the plot and the devices I'll talk about
represent a little bit later they're a
great example of the community because
people are going on these run clubs and
events with them that they host and are
actively creating content to participate
in that and they also engage with George
who the CEO a lot and like comment to
him and and there's people who kind of
join in that conversation in a really
interesting way and then we have your
kind of traditional devices so allies I
look at this as like other companies you
work with or collaborate with that's an
an ally other influencers that you
either pay or work with or represent
your product whatever it is those are
also allies they're people that aren't
really in your company but they're in
this big list of people that you can
work with to help gain benefit and who
are generally on your side in how they
present things then you have opponents
and the opponent idea is really
important because every brand is kind of
taking a stand for something and it can
be a conceptual opponent or a literal
opponent so if you're Pepsi and Coke or
Poppy and alipop or all four of those
together there's kind of like a bit of a
bit of that enemy naturally and all that
right one big soda company versus the
other big soda company whether it's
mentioned directly or whether it's not
or this idea of the smaller soda
companies okay there's two of them but
then there's also them positioning
themselves against big soda big soda is
really the enemy the Prebiotic sodas May
compete against each other but really
they're taking market share and saying
we are better than the Pepsis and cokes
of the world and that's how we want to
present this and so they have this big
conceptual enemy and a lot of Brands
will have that they'll have some
incumbent they're going against or some
new companies they're trying to kind of
shut down that maybe they don't make
content directly saying it but there's
this idea aide that if we kind of create
plot devices around how we want to
position ourselves against this
traditional concept of drama that is the
line of every TV show it's interesting
and then conceptually it can be the same
way if a software brand is fighting the
idea of being unorganized right like
that can be a conceptual enemy so how
this Exercise Works is we just roll
through the list big whiteboard we start
to go through the events and the devices
the sets the characters and if if
someone can't think of events another
thing we do is we actually go down the
list of like when were you founded what
did you launch what did you put together
what trade shows you attended what were
big moments in company history what
changed the trajectory of what you've
worked on so far and if you haven't
launched yet you begin to think that
through so I did this exercise a bit for
what I'm working on with my valuables
brand where I'm like okay what can I
base my content around the next few
months it's like cool we have launched
July 30th it's a bunch of launch content
we have like a secondary launch I'm
basically preparing for pushing some
more product we got a lot to start I'm
like all right we're have like a
secondary launch it's one there I'm
going to China and so I'm going to visit
my factories which is like a set and
that's going to be a whole event that
happens right there we're talking about
doing complex con this year and having
the brand at complexcon so that would be
a big thing that happens in November I'm
looking at doing a Meetup in New York
and a meet up in LA and it's like all
right cool let's incorporate that even
though it's kind of my Meetup but me as
a main character of The Brand I'm
putting that out in there I want to do
this next photo shoot I want to be more
of a community photo shoot invite out a
bunch of like my influencer friends and
stuff and do um do like a race it's one
of the ideas we're working on and I'm
like all right cool that would be an
event and that would also involve a
bunch of these other folks and you could
start to see like even with me as a
smaller brand that isn't spending much
of money doesn't have a huge team like
the team is me I can basically start
building out here's the things that are
happening here's things that I want to
happen here's where they fall on the
calendar okay shoot I need to make this
content or that content and that brings
us to the second part of this once
you've mapped all that out you can make
a narrative content plan this is like
what is happening that pushes your
Brand's agenda throughout this next year
I like to map out a year and so what I
walk through with companies is this
strategy of year anchors your seasonal
plan and your weekly plan so the year
anchors what we call Fame Builders and
fame Builders is pulled from um another
like a like another like like cinematic
writing exercise it's not my original
term but basically that's this idea that
things are going to happen once or twice
a year they're going try to get you the
most attention you possibly can huge
product release big debut of something
big media Sprint holiday ad spend
whatever it is but you want to basically
say we have these one or two things
happening every year that are super
important to us for Apple that could be
the keynote they give where they
released all their new products right
and you want to kind of identify what
those are and then make sure you have a
specific content plan for that then you
have your seasonal plan I break this
down to Seasons and stories it's like
all right what are we doing and what's
happening for us that are you know what
what are our key things in spring summer
fall Etc and then within that like what
are the various stories that we're
trying to get across we need to get
across inside that so we map out in our
seasonal plan so okay in the fall we've
got these two product releases where we
have to move some of this other
inventory we have or we have these four
app updates we're announcing our new
influencer team or whatever that is like
that's the you handling that inside your
seasonal plan you map that out and then
you get cand and break it down to a week
plan there's two sides of this you have
series and so if you if you've been in
Cut 30 you've seen some my cont videos
talk a lot about series what's recurring
thing you can do way I have like a
series called brand battle I have a
series called products brand I have a
status series these are all series I
have as a Creator and that's something
that every week I want to consider do I
do those every week or every two weeks
um you know what's the right Cadence but
I want to continually release those
series much like a TV show this YouTube
I do every Sunday at the same time is a
series I do in your week plan you want
to prepare for that and have that be
something You' thought there then you
have specials what's the thing that we
should do that's outside of the norm
where we're trying something new but
we're putting some atttention and time
into it and that's like a special the
way you might see like on you know 2our
special on TNT right all this is pulled
right from TV plot devices and then we
have our ongoing content just regular
stuff which is pillars and Trends and so
pillars is if you are a brand coming up
with a couple Core Concepts things you
repeat all the time so we have a product
showcase where we do a man on the street
or green screen feature walkthroughs or
news or whatever it is you have this
kind of recurring content that does well
for you that you sub it now as a pillar
and that's stuff you put in your weekly
content what are those actually identify
those what the content does good for us
we do storytelling carousels we you know
like going back to the midday squares
example they're going to basically say
any challenges they have in the week
they're probably going to look at it and
be like let's make a video about that
challenge and how we overcame it and
then there's trends for a lot of Brands
you should be looking at right cool
there's these visual Trends going around
where people compile all their footage
or put together or people are dropping
their wallets and showing off their fits
or whatever it is this audio is doing
well like it's worth kind of thinking
through and trying some of those ideas
out for a lot of product teams and for
everything on this from the fame
Builders to the stories that are
happening inside your season to your
Trend videos to your series to your
specials you ask these five questions
this gets to be a huge document which is
a good thing because you have you can
begin to build a thorough content plan
just doing this exercise okay what's the
plot where does this tie in how can I
build up the drama or the intention
around it and who are the characters so
for instance if I'm doing a Fame Builder
we're debuting a huge product Who's
involved the CEO do we want to get our
influencer team involved how can we get
our community involved and then having
that lens of like from the opponent
perspective what's our competition going
to think how are they going to respond
how can we predict that how can we get
ahead of that in our messaging like it's
that stuff that's really begins to be an
edge and then what's set where are we
going to do this content right like like
I'm looking at my seasonal plan for this
fall for my brand personally and I'm
going cool I have my typical Studio set
I have the sets where we're going to be
doing our photo shoots I'm going to
China and I'm there for that for a week
that's a set you know and what can I
take advantage of filming there make
sure that's interesting then what assets
do we need might is you creating long
form assets short form assets written
carousels videos series videos begin to
actually look at granularly as we go
through these things in these and like
inside this narrative line like what do
we actually want to get out of it and
then what networks they going to go on
right oh we're not spending enough time
on LinkedIn we want to have a different
approach on LinkedIn so we should create
assets specific to that but you begin to
work this out into a spreadsheet you
have a you know you have a significant
amount of content that's built out
within it and a significant amount of
ideas for people to go flesh out and
you'll find if you're doing this
exercise whether it's just you with like
a pen and paper or a big notion dock or
it's a team with a whiteboard and an
offsite tons comes of it and tons of
rabbit holes come to it you can begin to
really look at okay let's find our
pillars let's find our series you can
see like the workshops I did for this
for like a day sometimes two days and uh
I really try try to give it to a day but
because you actually get into this like
all right once we've actually mapped out
all those people are now we start going
into this narrative plan you can spend
90 minutes just on what your content
pillars are or how we should find
Identify some specific Trends right now
to make our content better immediately
or hey let's actually map out our series
plan our specials plan for the next 12
months based on our release calendar you
start to get really granular with this
so I want to give some actual examples
you can see how I think about it and
these examples I'm not saying people
have sat down and done this exercise
necessarily some Brands it's very
natural just to be like this like I
don't think represent has planned to
have basically what I just explained as
a big part of their marketing narrative
is natural to them it's just happened
it's why part of why they're successful
they are ingrained in it a lot of Brands
is not natural and in fact it's good to
think through with intention even if you
are natural to see how you can do it
better represents an amazing example for
this for a few reasons first is
characters George Heaton CEO is a
character and he is a as important to
the brand as the brand itself in my
opinion but he's not the only character
for the brand you have his brother
Michael heon telling a different type of
Brand Story a More Design focused Brand
Story more introverted brand story but
also important and presenting in a
similar way equally on brand and content
kind of rolls out and is shown between
the two of their accounts but then they
also have influencers and whether it's
paid for whether they're sponsored or
not doesn't quite matter like Pier Lon I
don't know if he's like a rep sponsored
person but he wears a lot of rep and he
gets a lot of people considering wearing
represent his content functions as a
promotional piece for the brand he wears
other brands and stuff too so again I'm
not sure what the relationship looks
like but he is someone that is a
character of their brand more more
secondary they also sponsor athletes for
instance this guy is like a high rocks
represent athlete so anyone that's a pro
team and characters a great way to think
about characters is like surf you know
sponsored Surfers sponsored skaters
sponsored athletes for a brand those are
all characters in The Brand Story I of
think they're very underutilized in
terms of brand stories but that's a
great way to think about this is like
any of those people are also involved
with the
brand a brand I worked with for a really
long time where we made this the pro
team a huge part of the Brand Story is
lift foils and so U both the Florence
brothers are are John and Nathan are
both sponsored by LIF foils they also
have a like a kind of a massive Rider
lineup of people small and large from
the Florence Brothers to you know to
Annie to uh this guyy just absolutely
rips andah heiti um to to to smaller
kind of up and comers like Brady to like
Brian to Super established and Brian's
in a ton of the content including much
of the viral content that we did while I
was there but they're building up kind
of this this like wide team of people
that of all different backgrounds right
like like Mal is a younger a younger
Rider right um Yago is like an
environmentalist who also happens to be
like like a foiler Zayn represents like
the Australia but basically those
characters are all people that are
telling the brand narrative and they
were really really involved in how we
put this together like like with the
brand and that's a traditional like you
know Sports surf angle but like is super
relevant today in social media and
you'll see those people are all like in
the content and sharing content on their
pages and brand should look at that like
very closely that's a good example like
represent is doing that exact same thing
they have people sponsored like that so
they have their characters that are
doing the brand they have all these kind
of models and influencers related to it
they have people that work at the brand
have their social media they have George
and Michael themselves so a lot of
character and you look at sets in the
same way where their office is a set
their office is a huge gy it comes up a
ton inside their content they open their
La store they're always filming content
inside their La store George has some
kind of like Los Angeles Mansion or
something like that that they're always
shooting at like they're always at
airwan like they have set up a bunch of
these different places that they can
shoot at at any point in time whether
it's their YouTube series Etc where
they're actually able to Leverage The
Brand and leverage the fact they have
characters and they have sets and
they're releasing things relatively
constantly to basically move the plot
forward but then let's look at that plot
and the things that are happening with
them right opening that La store was a
huge event every time the George goes
back and forth from the UK to California
if you're watch it following your social
media it feels like an event they
release product constantly that that's
an event they have collaborations they
just have like a a Duke and Dexter
collab and that's event they the other
Founders and stuff are tied into that
they're releasing an airwan smoothie
that's an event that you know you can go
tap into you they're doing a boxing
capsule or a collaboration again all
those things get to list out in the
calendar of like we have all these
things happening we need to make content
from them how are our key people
representing that are we putting it on
YouTube we're putting it on Instagram
what are we running for ads they are an
excellent example of just fluid brand
narrative happening constantly we got a
Metallica collection we have a boxing
collection and then you look at content
types you're like all right cool
sometimes we're just doing 3D you know
like they're able to add in layers of
stuff obviously they have like all the
resources in the world to be doing this
as a brand that's like really
skyrocketing but it's a really
interesting way to Think Through how any
brand should function and this whole
idea of character and TV show that's not
contrived at all it's naturally what's
happening with the brand the
personalities around it and they're
playing into it really well and the last
we'll talk about is Poppy cuz I want
always be using fashion examples right
so poppy is really interesting because
they have a couple devices right they
were on the founder was on Shark Tank
and got invested on on Shark Tank and
that kind of plays out in their content
that's a big event and because of that
the founder being on TV the founder was
a part of the brand narrative they were
also one of the early accounts actually
get Creator working on their account my
friend JT Barnett you've probably heard
talk about um sourcing creators for
Brands a lot I think actually helped
them get creators involved in their
account and nail that strategy before
but they have a combo now of like the
CEO is a character the different
creators they have as a character their
employees as characters inside the poppy
brand and then what they're doing as far
as plot is they're releasing new flavors
all the time they're getting into new
retailers or doing big things like
running a Super Bowl campaign they
always have the ability to fall back on
like the Shark Tank narrative they used
to have and they're positioning themsel
in in really interesting ways like I
think they're uh they're not like
dunking on ollipop or anything all the
time but they're definitely like having
an enemy and there's another brand going
like toe for toe for them and like
ollipop is definitely much more cheeky
in their social media like throwing some
shots at poppy which is interesting and
but again like part of that like enemy
Ally structure but then both of them are
positioned against big soda right but
they have to dance with that lightly
they want to get acquired by a Coca-Cola
or a Pepsi group right and so they can't
go at them hard hard hard because that
might then dissuade someone in the
boardroom but at the same time you have
to be like reminding people this is a
much more healthier alternative to the
soda you grew up with that's a message
that comes across inside everything and
even the little things like having their
you know street team members walk around
with the little poppy backpacks they are
creating tons of different narratives
characters have the same through lines
through this um and all the ways that
we've talked about it right and this is
and what I like about this is this is
the kind of thing you could come up with
with a plan like the represent stuff a
lot of it's natural they have really
charismatic people involved in the brand
they're doing a lot of these releases
they're doing interesting things they
built interesting places it takes a
while to get that infrastructure
together if you can even get there at
all but someone like poppy if you have
any company that's selling in cpg you
can begin to think of that structure
like what is our origin story how do we
replay it what stores are we going into
what are we positioned against
categorically in the world what creators
do we use what team members do we use
how do we get our street team of members
involved how are we constantly releasing
new flavors getting feedback and then
having a plot around that we tease it
people guess and then we release it once
we release it we actually go on like a
tour like they're able to kind of really
put that out there in an interesting way
I think they done a great job with it
and I'll leave you with how I'm thinking
about this as a new brand right so I'm
getting ready to have my first launch in
a few weeks I don't have the resources
or the size of some of the other brands
that are out there I'm talking about
here like how do you have characters
right so I'm a character obviously this
is a brand that is largely based on the
fact that I am an influencer with a
large following but I also wanted to go
beyond that so I'm looking at okay I
have people I'm seating with the product
I want to be involved I like to tell the
story like um toga who designed some of
the stuff his he's tagged in some of the
things people know that he's like a part
of it design some things inside of it my
Factory in uh crease group I talk about
a lot inside of this are WF like
character and a set and there's some
interplay in there because I'm very open
about the brand one of the main Concepts
is like it's like an open source brand
I'm going to tell you all my suppliers
I'm going to show you a bunch of how
it's done it's a brand that helps build
Brands the concept I love and really
resonates with how I make my content so
I'm bringing into the brand so that also
means that cool I'm not afraid to show
you my supplier go work with my supplier
I'm working with them all the time going
to China with them or talking back and
forth I want them to thrive and succeed
and that as a character and the people
in there like yah who's the art director
there I worked with on on the on the
shoot here he makes cont he is like
there's probably some interplay there
same thing with all my boys right so
landforce or Zack Kravitz or Ashwin or
you know or Brandon from blank like
these are all friends of mine right
there's going to be some interplay the
way I post about blank stuff that like
you know maybe some of my stuff's in his
videos he's wearing a shirt or whatever
it is or you know like Zach's worn
valuable content Alex Garcia's worn you
know shirts and valuable content like
how do I make that into a bigger play
right that's begin what you think about
it's like who are my people and that's
why there's a huge benefit to being to
having some kind of web following not
just because of the followers but
because of the network right the ability
to say all right I want people to be a
part of my brain Story how do iiz them
to do that how do we get people excited
how do we actually execute that all
right so thank you for watching I hope
you got some value out of this just a
reminder that like I want you out to run
this like go run it for your brand use
it for freelance clients use it if
you're at an agency uh it doesn't belong
to me it belongs to the Internet it's an
amalgamation of like exercises I've been
in things I've found online things that
I've come up with myself like all all
put into one thing that I think is super
valuable for Brands and if you change it
or you update it or you find things to
add to it please share it with me um as
I do a lot less exercises and consults
and stuff as I go to launch my own brand
I'm just trying to push all those tools
out there for other people to use and
and run with I'm out here in Miami it's
by last week before my brand has its
final launch and then I head out to
China so lot going on we'll be
documenting all of it and appreciate
yall coming along for the ride thank you
very much