today we're going to talk about three of
the most interesting Concepts in Brands
marketing and creativity Brands is a
vehicle for artistic Vision oral
building and product as marketing I've
touched on the topic of Brands as art
before with gentle monster who are the
true art as marketing brand but this
video focuses on Monclair where the art
is marketing they use incredible
curation collaboration and experience as
a vehicle to sell jackets that are
probably warmer than we need but sold at
the highest level as many of you know
I've served as a marketing leader and
CMO at retail Brands and now I advise
large brands on social and World
building like this so I'm blessed to be
able to spend my time researching these
and get to actually try and validate how
it works and as always I'm going to
share as much as I can with all of you
so today we will start with my 45 second
version of the insane Monclair near
bankruptcy to multi-billion story we'll
touch on Oreo and their Trend setting
retail strategy and how this plays into
montclair's collapse we'll actually walk
through my favorite Monera
collaborations and campaigns across Auto
Sports cult Brands and luxury discuss
their event campaign and gen Z
strategies and take a last look at what
does this actually mean for newer brands
or people that want to learn from what
they've created let's lock in so
Monclair has an insane story like any
good luxury brand it was founded in the
Alps making actually high quality
products used by cold weather workers
and skiers around them but that wasn't
enough of a market and by 2003 they were
in near bankruptcy so they were bought
and moved to Milan by someone who had a
significant vision for what the brand
could become and then was able to act on
and execute it and take this idea of
luxury and really well fleshed out
products and then add on the other
layers of marketing and bigger
applications than just servicing the
people with whom craftsmanship mattered
fast forward into the 2020s and they've
done three billion in revenue and they
actually own Stone Island who they
bought for a billion dollars who's
another brand who has come from Pure
product of performance but built a
really interesting story and culture
around it but I'll save that for another
video this Monclair story was actually
one of the first Tik toks I ever did
about two and a half years ago that
actually did really well and part of it
is this story is anchored in some of the
most interesting marketing of our time
it's wild collaborations its Unique
Designs it's building a world that goes
far beyond a cold weather jacket and
ties into something that no matter what
you think of it is intrinsically
interesting and it goes through a wide
range of appeal by going from not just a
sporadic clab here and there but many
stories being told simultaneously so
let's break down how this works it
starts with the core product at the end
of the day Monclair sells puffer jackets
as the vast majority of their sales come
from this Bas level skew that helps keep
people warm in the winter months there's
some offshoots whether it's vests or
more Pro gear and they've branched out
into a lot of the lifestyle accessories
and clothing and general things that a
brand will do but it's all complemented
around this one core hero product the
puffer but but then they've also dove
into this idea of product as marketing
they've released a wild amount of
collaborations and products that many of
which are almost unwearable you'll see
them be viewed more as art more as
something that's experimental than
something that's being bought not just
saying hey we're going to go buy big
advertising campaigns and put up more
billboards with Monclair on them instead
it's we're going to create things that
are helping bring creativ Visions into
the world that help garnish attention
that are going to serve as marketing for
our core line because while only a
handful of people might buy some wild
cra green or Rick Owens piece it
continues to bring more attention and
ideas back to the core Monclair line
let's look at a tactical example of the
same strategy in a different category
with the Oreo approach so you may have
seen all kinds of weird Oreo flavors
over time peeps Swedish Fish the cursed
candy corn flavor apple pie at one point
in The Last 5 Years Oreo decided we are
going to radically expand the amount of
products we have and we are going to do
it for a few reasons the first is
obviously gain more retail shelf space
at the peak of this strategy when you
walked in it was no longer Oreos and
Golden Oreos and double stuff and thins
now there was a whole lineup of just
like 10 more intense flavors occupying a
significantly larger amount of space on
the grocery store shelf that leads to
sales more sales of these products but
also the attention driven by just the
insanity of this concept of people being
interested in people picking up one of
these crazy flavors on the shelf and not
even buying it but again considering
Oreo further led to a 20% % increase in
the mainline sales of Oreo just their
standard products so not only did they
get this benefit of the new lines they
Rose the main one as well so when we
talk about product as marketing and we
seal these out there products from
Brands like this they're still getting a
sales benefit some people are buying it
and even if that sales benefit is a lot
smaller than what happens if they
introduce a new cor skew they're also
raising the mainline as well now at
retail with Oreo what happens is that
the product that people pick up first
from the Shelf is the product they most
often buy so packaging and basically
consumer psychology and Retail a lot
revolves around getting someone to pick
up your product and then there's the
craziness of hey I'm picking up my
Dunkin Donuts native body wash and
picking up my Sour Patch Kids Oreo if
they choose not to purchase that product
they're most likely to grab the thing
that is most next to it or similar to it
which will be the traditional version of
the Oreo maybe I'm not in for Sour Patch
Kids or candy corn Oreos but I'll go
grab the standard one so at retail this
makes sense in terms of psychology now
with a luxury product it's a bit of a
different scenario because now you're
talking about awareness that lasts over
a length of time someone makes a
decision to purchase a $900 jacket
winter jacket they do that once every 3
years not even a seasonal purchase
there's a a lot of continual touch
points for the brand that have to go
into what actually makes that final
decision and so what Monclair sees with
the sheer amount of campaigns they do
and we're going to get into my favorites
of these campaigns in a minute is they
know that they have to keep up a
constant Cadence of being front and
center in people's minds as a brand of
interest and so they have what's called
their genius campaign which is their
collaboration structure which has about
let's say a dozen collaborators at any
given time all of whom are releasing
continual collections underneath the
brand to be able to just have a constant
cultural approach to being able to be
present inside top of mind so when
people do finally go make that one
decision they may like a product along
the way and get into it but when they
actually go to say hey I want that
winter jacket Monclair has been in the
back of their minds continually over
time and this decision is also
generational when you look at it from a
brand of this size because you'll get
younger consumers who at some point are
going to make their first big purchase
like this you know if you are under 25
you're probably not thinking about ever
buying a $900 jacket unless you
absolutely have to but some point you're
going to make that transition you're
going to have the resources to do it
it's going to matter enough and then the
years of inundation that you've had to
basically make that first purchase be
you know what I have to have a Monclair
is a really important foundation that
Brands who are playing the long game
think about so we've talked a bit about
the strategy here let's actually dive
into some some of these collaborations
and what makes them special and after
that we'll go into events campaigns and
talk a little bit more about the genzi
and younger strategy that they've done
before we talk about what brands can
learn so I'm going to start with the
Craig green campaigns that they've done
so Craig green is a high fashioned
designer and he's created five
collections with Monclair 2018 to 2022
all of whom are sculptural they are
essentially art pieces these are not
things you would seen worn on the slopes
they're even complicated to see on the
runway but you if you look at the art of
presentation back to this idea Brands as
art each one of these products as seen
in the photography that we display here
is an art piece this is not a clothing
necessarily designed to be worn and
functional this is clothing designed to
be an expression of Craig Green's
artistic vision and he's doing it with
the Monclair canvas of winter Garb and
has created what is a truly unique slate
that makes people rethink sculpturally
like what a garment could be and what
design literally looks like and also
what its display is like because these
garments are designed for these photos
they're not even necessarily designed
for wear they're designed for wear in
the one application of when it is
perfectly outlined does it create a
photo like this whose symmetry whose
look is immediately scroll stopping and
look stopping and I think this is of all
the Monclair collabs one of the purest
brand as art product as art applications
of it and we've seen a lot of Brands get
inspiration from this whether
subconsciously or consciously in what
we've seen released now or so many
Browns will look at let's make an
Instagram perfect piece where its art
display is almost more important than
its wearability it owes a lot back to
these five Montclair collections with
Craig grain but one of the biggest
things I like about this and and
montclair's approach in general is that
they've spayed out from Pure clothing
and done things that go into Automotive
so let's talk about their partnership
with Mercedes-Benz so this Monclair
Voyage campaign the first like really
impactful Mercedes campaign involved
this concept vehicle launched right
before the kind of overtaking of AI
imagery I actually think it'd be a
little less impactful in this new era
because we see so many things like it
now but they created this massive puff
piece G wagon this whole campaign where
it's being dropped from the sky created
the real version of it and anchored an
event around it and one of the most kind
of Staggering looks and feels of
anything and also a real stretch for
Mercedes who we' never seen Go full
science fiction in the same way with
such cultural resonance creating a
vehicle like a future art vehicle for
the snow and I want to do a whole video
at some point on Art vehicles in in
general and people that take art
Vehicles seriously but this is some
perfect application of a campaign that
really brought both Brands out of their
comfort zone but they didn't do that on
just this campaign they kept it going as
well so I want to talk about the nego
collaboration here I'll do my brief nego
rant where you've seen now with Fel at
Louis Vuitton a influx of some of these
2000's hip-hop personalities whether
it's the clips being on the runway or
nego being part of the creative process
process but this presence of the people
that like that era the fragment design
era the Bape era comes to a Nostalgia of
people of a class of people who now have
resources and money of that 45 to 55y
old person who worked at an agency or in
whatever job who grew up in this hip-hop
era who now has the resources with which
to make luxury purchases that is what
that whole demographic appeals to Neo is
like the embodiment of this even better
because he goes crosscultural he's just
as impactful to us hipop as he is more
Japanese as he is in Europe he's able to
kind of transcend a purely American
ideal of what that demographic looks
like so the Mercedes that he did with
Monclair is a much more streamlined
approachable you may even drive it take
some of the ideas of that first Monclair
Mercedes but then strips it down to
something that is actually very much a
vehicle that you would drive and use and
I like this combination of this kind of
hypermodernism that you saw in that
first application to this kind of ' 80s
9s driven design that we see here that
is actually very drivable but carries on
this like extension of the Brand Story
and like the puffer iconography and
feels kind of very uniquely M CLA going
back to the brand is Art concept cars
are a vehicle for this kind of thing you
see brands do concept cars a lot you see
Brands collaborate or do vehicles with
people a lot because it is a great
canvas to be able to put expression on
and it's a better canvas than purely an
item of clothing or a retail store
because vehicles have that same
aspirational and sharable quality cuz
people are so into them but their
Partnerships also Branch into sports so
Monclair sponsors the football club
Inter Milan which makes sense as a Milan
based brand for those who are not in the
football World this is a pretty Prestige
application to be a sponsor on and they
basically do the kind of nonactive wear
off-pitch kind of clothing for this with
a kind of like a nice refined approach
for that but this is that continual
branch of how do we as a company again
selling that core puffer Branch into
these different parts of culture we've
got this High fashion approach with
Craig G green we're getting into the
auto Enthusiast into the hip-hop culture
with what we're doing with Mercedes with
Neo and then we have we're actually
applying to the kind of the the football
fan a more refined approach you see
everything that's done here is is pretty
straightforward and when they do try to
break this out of the mold of bit this
kind of Aram collab that they have here
again is very like stripped back for any
of the Monclair campaigns not my
favorite of the work here although it's
it's totally fine but they are again
they're able to keep it very streamlined
and normal quote unquote in what they're
doing with inter while pairing that
right with like this hyper modernist
approach that they're doing with
Mercedes all because they have a brand
world that can live within both and then
we'll talk about the cult design aspect
of it with what they've done with Rick
Owens my favorite designer where they've
actually taken both a fashion and
interior approach here which is
something that I'm I'm really interested
in so the Rick collections that they've
done are a perfect encapsulation of like
what any good Rick application is where
Rick will have these viral items right
someone's wearing a body as a backpack
someone has some kind of crazy look he's
only using models that look like they
aren't from this world but at the same
time we'll also have some just like
extremely wearable black items that can
become a wardrobe and a staple for
anyone who understands kind of the Rick
Cannon this is the same thing they do
inside the Monclair Universe where there
are these kind of insane puffers also
than this very wearable applications of
the exact Monclair Styles where they're
bridging that really good gap of
attention and cability and this is of
all those kind of collaborations has
morphed into one where I feel like they
probably sell the most of inside that
kind of straightforward application what
also they've touched on here is
futuristic living so now we see Monclair
move from Auto move from sport into
interiors and spaces as well using kind
of Rick's love for that his kind of
existing template of how he's
continually working spaces into how he's
marketing and now put that into how
these collections come together and
you'll see the core of it is where
fashion meets architecture and they're
designing atmospheric environments you
know the Rick Owens Mountain Refuge a
weather steel Sanctuary tying it back to
that brand World building of everything
has to be in snow everything has to be
related to the warmth of the core
product that is the through line that
you see in all this as a core of
montclair's World building that ties
back to their value proposition and it's
executed so well across every single
thing that we've seen here and I love
how they do that both in the clothing
and in the actual physical interior and
exterior design environment they've done
here with Rick and really what they're
doing is they're giving him a toolkit to
say hey guess what we're going to pay
you to design a weather proof building
to your artistic vision and standard and
we're going to use that to Market puffer
jackets and those are going to be your
puffer jackets and it's going to be our
main line and it's a really interesting
and thought through experience that feel
is executed at the highest level and the
last collab I'm going to call out is
Palm Angels so Palm Angels is an
interesting brand it's funny I rarely
see Palm angels in the wild but when I
do I'm usually like whenever I'm staying
at like a festar resort like I was just
at nou Barcelona I was at like the
Montage and um the Waldorf in lagona a
couple months ago I will see like kids
in Palm Angels like the kids of rich
people wearing pal wearing $400 Palm
Angels shirts it's my main like in real
life experience which which I find funny
what I almost look at as like Rich Kid
Clothing as a like a a very Flex like a
club Flex garment for a certain
demographic and make that distinctly
Monclair so if you look at these light
up jackets here are like the perfect
extension of what these brands are
together of taking this weatherproofed
item and then making it into a kind of
wild club kids statement piece or this
collaboration where they're going like
full retro racing and they actually made
a working cart track to go with which
will TI to experiential stuff we'll get
here in a second but the risky trying to
tap into these different elements of
culture this is one of my least favorite
is the mon racing side of it with with
palm Angels but just to show you the the
Gambit but this is not even the full
extent of the collaborations happening
and this is what I want to imp part on
everyone is the scale when you're
operating a brand at a certain level and
I know a lot of people that follow this
channel are at marketing or in marketing
at companies that are pretty significant
when you look at the the fact that we've
barely touched on let's say a third of
the collaborations that are ongoing like
at any given time with Monclair gives
you an idea of the scale with which you
need to operate to be generating
cultural capital like this this is not
just an internet thing Monclair has done
a good job of bringing this into the
real world as well so for instance they
had a London Fashion Show really based
around the debut of these collabs one of
the interesting things they did is get
very Community involved in it and
they've done this both in the in Europe
and they've done it in China so for this
event for instance it wasn't just a
runway show that was purely for like the
fashionistas there it was a like
interactive experience that they invited
a huge amount of their Community to
where there ended up being I think like
10,000 fan invites that were included in
this like massive world that they
created instead of a traditional fashion
presentation I'm going to take a brief
step over into what they've doing in
China because this is another
interesting thought when you look at
building a generational brand at this
level and really pursuing a brand as art
is that it's not it's about all these
markets when you're really operating in
that multi-billion dollar territory
you're thinking through all these
potentials and so they have been going
after the luxury gen Z Market in China
and they've done that by launch ing
collab specific to them they have three
gen Z Chinese talent and who were like
when they launched this program got like
5 million views on webo which it's a
little bit of a different platform
that's a pretty significant but they
basically have launched a specific
campaign tapping into that market and
they did that before launching this very
prolific city of Genius campaign they
did in Shanghai where they debuted this
kind of Next Level collaboration
platform that they're doing with a
somewhat Festival somewhat art
installation that's also kind of a way
show but was a major cultural item that
they were able to put together in
Shanghai as an anchor for what they're
doing to really showcase themselves as a
global brand and be able to put their
collaborations forward to a market that
is beginning to understand it one of the
last things I want to mention to tie
into this before we talk about what
smaller Brands and up and cominging
Brands kind of learn from what they've
put together here is all of this still
comes with that core of luxury which is
service one of the most interesting
things I like to call out often about
the Monclair website is not just this
like amazing city of Genius section they
have where they're kind of you can go
and explore all the collabs and this
interactive environment but the fact
that they have virtual appointments and
inore appointments with stylists to be
able to help people wear these things
that they're creating and decide what's
right for them and that idea that you
can have that same personalized luxury
experience to be able to go engage with
them is something I feel a lot more
brands at this level should be
considering because when you have so
many products and so many skews like
they do so many collaborations you
understand how you to wear them how to
use them how they fit you what you look
like and that is a something a brand can
come in and solve and then establish a
relationship that allows you to kind of
form a real connection with the brand
that's going to be long lasting and I
love that that is something that they
offer and is available but obviously
most of us aren't running $3 billion
Brands aren't thinking like this in that
same way but I would encourage you to
look at the the foundations of what's
put together here basically the saying
that instead of running all these
traditional advertising venues instead
of this TV budget Etc like how can we
engineer cultural capital and can we do
that while also generating sales of
product and so at any level I do feel
that Brands who have Vision if you have
if you are an artist at the end of the
day or you have artists on your team
enabling them has the exponential
potential to do better than just purely
buying eyeballs for dollars and becomes
a question of are you willing to take
the risk to invest in that and to carry
it through to where it needs to be and I
would highly encourage in this era of
Brands where things are less measurable
than than ever when people want return
on ad spend to fit in a really specific
bucket that actually doesn't work and
attribution doesn't work that way if you
have have the ability to take the risk
and push for it that you do it but then
to get more tactical a few things we can
learn from them that I love and think
can apply to smaller Brands is first is
in is in sports with what mon Clair did
with inter I think Niche Sports is a
great opportunity for Brands whether
that's local like you know small leagues
whether it's you know uh Rodeo or
go-karts or bowling or women's soccer or
like local college teams was opened up
with n Partnerships with sports are as
much about the content as the exposure
but when you do get exposure even to a
small audience there's an audience that
really cares at that small level who are
there's fandoms in those Sports who
support the brands and support their
athletes but there's also the ability to
create content around those niches as
well really I feel like as an
underutilized tool by small and medium
Brands and with nil the name image
likeness kind of opening up college
sports to be able to kind of spend money
like this I actually feel like we are
having more of a monetary conversation
than ever around Sports and there's more
opportunities to get in at lower price
points than ever and back to my point
before look at your top of funnel as art
one of the biggest conversations we're
going to have in 2025 for medium and
larger Brands is we need to do more on
top of funnel right everyone's kind of
identified uh if you are a mediumsized
brand or a large brand you are digitally
Savvy you have kind of figured out how
you're hitting the top of your meta app
Loven Tik Tok YouTube and Google
scalability in terms of your spending
dollars to getting dollars back and what
a lot of people realize now is we need
more to of funnel we need more brand
marketing it's going to be the hot
conversation of all year and how can
that make a bigger audience for us to
then spend our new kind of direct
generation engine under underneath and
having that top of funnel be art or
product as art and collaboration as art
is one of the most redeeming ways to do
it your team will be most excited about
your fans will be most excited about and
I would lean into that and then last I
will call out that initiatives have
power both internally and externally so
when you see you hear Monclair genius or
Monclair city of Genius or young icon
when you actually name your projects
brand your projects it gives it power it
gives something to be proud of it gives
something that's resonant and when it's
put out there publicly and externally
and people kind of hear about it and
know about it it's the same power as
having a good brand on your actual
company it can apply to the individual
things you're doing that's something I
think should be considered more by
smaller Brands as well if you do have an
ambassador program or an influencer
program or whatever it is brand it call
it something give it some life and some
personality is something that this that
Monclair does extremely well I think
smaller Brands will be able to learn a
lot from as well so that is the Brand's
art Monclair case study video I
appreciate y'all watching and diving in
if you have questions on this let me
know obviously it's a passionate topic
for me to talk about we'll be back with
some more case studies I'm going be
going a little more in depth on these if
uh if these do well been thinking about
doing a video about Rick Owens thinking
about doing a video about the world of
Travis Scott which is actually a really
interesting one uh and about off-white
few others are kind of floating around
the back of my head so if you do like
these please comment let me know and we
will keep them Comming thank you so much
[Music]