So, in this video, we're going to walk
through creating a brand aesthetic. And
I'm going to go entirely through a
capsule that I just creative directed.
We made some really nice items. Things
like this Togo leather duffel bag, these
wax cotton hoodies. We've gotten tons of
appreciation for on the short form
videos I've worn it in. Custom
envelopes, custom packaging, cashmere
hats, silk scarves, the whole gambit.
I'm going to walk through how something
all this comes together from mood board
to reality and how you have the
aesthetics that actually tie it into
something special. How you design
collections overall. We'll start with
the graphics and inspiration. We'll move
into the actual collection design and
the product design. I'll unbox the
entire collection so you can actually
see all the details, the things we put
together. And then we'll go into the
content and photos we made and some
strategies for when you're approaching
collections and putting these things
together yourself. So, Hyper, which is
my newsletter I run with another
creator. If you're not familiar with me
at all, I'm Orura Mates World. I'm a
designer, creative director, former kind
of marketing head who makes a lot of
content and does a lot of design in the
luxury products and fashion space. And
my partner inside of Hyper is Clayton
who runs which is like a men's fashion
newsletter. He previously worked at
Barney's and his has a very different
but equally as intense vision as I do
about what makes things interesting and
luxury and stand out in branding and
design. So we write our brand strategy
newsletter every week um on hyper and
talk about all kinds of things and then
we do projects like this where we offer
creative direction design etc for brands
that are trying to do interesting
things. So we got approached by Fermont
who are a landing page company and
basically funnels and similar things for
e-commerce. They do software where they
want to make a luxury merch collection
to be able to give to their best clients
to be able to offer for sale and be able
to showcase their technology which
allows people to create like custom
pages and full funnel flows for their
e-commerce brands. So from there it
starts with a mood board. So Clayton uh
put together this mood board of what
we're looking at for the collect gift
all the designers and the people that
are going to be involved to give them a
sense of where we're going. This is a
this first image is kind of a perfect
image as you see where where things
align of like where we have this kind of
elevated men's wear feel but it still
has like some level of casual street
wear to it. Things that are more
subdued. You see the overall palette
elevation in kind of materials texture.
You'll see some of these recurring
themes we end up with the palette really
similar to the two items this guy is
wearing here. Some similarities in that.
These mood boards help drive how we
think about the collection and what we
can do. So it starts there just to get
everyone on the same visual page to put
this together. This is in arena. And
then we put together a director. So for
this we worked with a neighbor of mine
lives right down the street where I'm
filming this video. Uh Ben Beondo who
has does some really nice graphic work.
He's the creative director for a brand
called Lonely Ghost, an influencer brand
that you may may have heard of who also
does some really nice work was
definitely on the same page thus as far
as visual aesthetic. And we wanted to
get a whole set of iconography done for
this brand from scratch that helped
transform it from the software brand
that it is today into something that
makes sense as a recurring whether it's
just a capsule where we do a bunch of
these kind of merchandise line that that
has the right vibe. So we put together a
brief for him on the actual logo
direction something I just put together
in slides on what we liked and some
angles we wanted to approach. So it
started with the existing branding
that's there which we did not want to
include at all. We wanted to have maybe
some light inspiration some of the
existing colors they work with. We did
say, "Hey, let's pull some from that."
So, it makes sense, but not necessarily
like leading into the kind of yellow and
black that they have so frequently. And
so, you'll see we actually pulled the
green and the off-white kind of cream as
the core things for the collection based
on what they already have based a little
bit on their existing design. So, I put
together this brief for him of some
things we liked and styles we liked, all
things we pull from where I really like
these kind of logos that are more like
marks, more traditional high design.
Same thing with like treated word marks.
How can we make a word mark be
particularly unique? this idea of luxury
type, like how do you give typography
like a standout approach? And then
potentially this idea of like a double
word, like a letter incorporating that.
I don't like to give too much direction
when I'm working with designers that I I
know are going to crush it, but I like
to have some visual ideas of like here's
three or four things. Here's three or
four examples of each of those that they
can potentially pull from inspiration
from. So, they're not starting from zero
with what do you want? I find instead of
just some big mood board, actually
saying, hey, here's four kind of
concepts to play with. Obviously, come
with your own is a good way to approach
it. So, you'll see what we actually
ended up with. You know, this was the
first round of logos here. We really
liked what was going on with this kind
of four-letter treated type. We also
really liked this F. You could see that
was incorporated into type similar to
that double word mark we had inside the
inspiration and some kind of options and
how they could potentially be applied.
And then a bunch of other styles he kind
of exploring and colors and so was not
feeling as much of these backsides, but
again, that's why we get a bunch of
options. Same thing with kind of what we
putting together here, but really liked
this first direction that was put
together. This thing goes into round
two, which is refinement of that
direction where we're saying, okay,
let's think about, okay, how would this
apply to a t-shirt? We want to actually
put on things like I'm very much about
how do you actually put graphics into
use and kind of what makes the most
sense? And we were close here, but far
different from where we ended up. We
were just kind of exploring some
exploration. The one thing I did
absolutely love was this kind of scarf
treatment here. And we had some
adjustments there. We took off the text,
a few things that ended up making it
into production from this round two all
the way into round three where we're
almost we're very refined. This is this
one on the right is like exactly what we
went with. So some of these patterns
changed. We implemented some of these
little items like the FM RMT that you
saw. We took that logo originally. This
was kind of underneath the globe etc.
Like how moved it around. We begin
thinking about application. So this is
where I get really hands-on. I like to
let someone really cook on graphics.
We'll go back and forth really think
about where can we apply things
correctly. So our next step here was
kind of collection design and structure
overall. So, how I typically look at
collection design is that you need your
standout item, your your viral items for
lack of a better term. What are the
things that are going to get people's
attention? That's category one. And for
us, it was this waxed hoodie where I
knew as soon as you put it on like
social media video or you see it in real
life, you go, "Wow, it's going to be
crazy." I knew I wanted to do it. I knew
the factory and the places that would
have the treatment. We'll unbox it a bit
later, but I was like, "This is going to
be our our standout." And so, how do we
want to apply iconography there? We did
an embroidery hit in the front,
embroidery hit in the side, and then we
decided to do a silicone tag on
everything. As far as the apparel items
to help like tie it together, you know,
in the collection, category one is those
standout items, the things that make
everyone want that they're going to be
that are going to sell out quick that
people are going to be asking about. How
do I get my hands on? The second one was
this leather bag, which we will unbox
here in a bit. I knew we wanted to do a
duffel. I've been working on some duffel
tech packs with the team. And so was
like, hey, let's do something that's
really high-end for that, too. Then you
have your core items when it comes down
to structure. So like a shirt is a core
item. For us, we also wanted to balance
affordability because some of this was
being given away and some was being
sold. You also got scarves which are a
lower price item. And then these Kashmir
hats, another one where like we felt the
shirt and the hats are the core items
and those should be kind of what's going
to be most consumed.
I think that breakdown is how most
people should look at collection
designs. So, if you're starting small,
for most people, I'd recommend starting
small and you have about five items. I'd
be really shooting for two to be like
extremely stand out to have two that are
more normal and easy to get and have one
that's like cheaper or an easy access
point where you can buy in or get into
the brand with an accessory or similar.
So you have a small collection kind of
to ratio like we put two standout items,
two normals items, one accessible.
That's a pretty decent way to start. But
as you get bigger, you expand the middle
and the bottom like for those
collections getting those real standout
items especially if they're more
expensive or you want people to be like
hunting after them. I will kind of keep
it in that ratio until you're looking at
like two to eight to two if you're
looking at like a 12piece collection
where you have like two standout to like
eight solid across a range to two more
accessible. Uh and then that's where you
can start being like all right maybe
let's add a third standout item. But
that's kind of the ratio I like to look
at is even when you're small you still
need those standouts and then as you
grow growing the middle of the things
actually people use and wear and then
keeping those like outsides a little bit
small and this is corporate merchandise
so a bit different than a full fashion
line and full fashion collection.
There's a whole bunch of thoughts into
that. But if you are just looking for a
framework or a guide work to get started
when I do a lot of these projects,
that's the way that I look at it. All
right, so I talk a lot in my videos
about how creatives should be putting
dedicated time aside every week and
every day to uplevel their skill set.
The biggest question I get is, how do I
actually learn these things if I want to
go a level deeper than YouTube? So, I
partnered with Skillshare to actually go
and pick out a number of courses that
you can use on their platform that has a
monthly membership covering all kinds of
categories from photography to design to
music, business, marketing, and more.
So, you can have some specifics that you
can do that will help get you on your
journey. So, first, in my videos are
more fashion focused. People ask a lot
about tech hacks and getting good at
that. There's a whole class on Adobe
Illustrator for fashion that teaches you
how to work with these flats like you
see here with CADs. What I think is
important about this is this will help
you get a grasp of Illustrator and then
it has everything from like creating
shapes and actually creating some
deliverables and using the pen tool that
will help you not only learn how to use
the files but actually modify and create
your own design. If you want to get into
Photoshop and the basics of design, say
you've only used like Adobe Express
before and you want to take it a level
deeper, they have a whole path which is
like when they put multiple courses
together to get you like a learning
journey dedicated to Photoshop basics.
And this one is great. I will link all
of these specifically uh inside the
description of this video. I also really
like this new course, Mindful
Photography, that is about creating a
daily habit for photo. I talk a lot
about daily habits inside some of these
videos, and I think if you do want to
become good at art direction, come good
at natural content creation, creating a
daily habit like this, um, is excellent,
and this is a great course to do it. So,
the first 500 people to use this link
will get a one month free trial of
Skillshare, so you can do this yourself.
My number one pro tip is that set
dedicated time, whether it's twice a
week or every day, whatever it is,
schedule the time that you're going to
use to pursue this. It will help take
you a long way. All the links will be in
the description.
All right, so now we've recapped a bit
of the design that's gone into the
collection. Let's actually take a look
at everything that we created.
So, first we'll start off with these
branded boxes. These are from Arca. All
right. So, then we have these envelopes
are super nice touch. Wax seal. You'll
see in this thing I've done on some of
the valuable items as well. I have a wax
seal of the logo that I have from You'll
notice I've done this on valuable items
as well. wax seal that's on an envelope.
A shout out to Alexa from Vermont who
actually worked on and found this one,
but that same kind of like textured
green that you'll see matches some of
the other items we have. All right, so
some some packaging.
This is done from a hat supplier where I
do the vast majority of my hats. So,
this is actually a valuable silhouette.
So, I have these valuable cashmere hats.
It's something I love whenever I do
unique items like this. It's something I
want to be able to offer and use on
projects. I don't have a brand color
that's like a dark color uh like this.
So, love like jumped to the opportunity
to do this which is dark green. If we
get up super close to it, you'll see
that there's a logo color on color which
is when I do more luxury stuff like
this. This is actually a black on green
and you want to be more subtle. I think
this is more fun as a super rich
cashmere and a leather band in like a
green leather to match engraved brand
logo on the clasp. And whenever I do
these, um, it's still just a normal hat
shell underneath. So even though it's a
hot fabric on the outside, doesn't mean
that your dome's going to be sweating
when you when you do wear it. And then
custom garment tag with it. So whenever
we're doing hats like this, I always
have the list of like what's going to be
custom band, what's going to be custom
on the actual connection point if there
is one. Are we going to do a custom
shell? We have a custom care tag, what
we're doing for the logo, and the shape
and size. So then we have the shirts.
You know, I will never go for any
standard tea. This is a heavy weight,
not as heavy as the valuable ones is
about a 320. Um, but it's it's a a style
and silhouette that I absolutely love.
It feels super luxury. It's really
tight. The fabric is perfect. One of the
fabrics I was finding when I was in
China was this one. Screen print on
here. This also has a silicone tag on
the back. Secondary print, custom tag on
the inside here that's stitched in all
the way around. The only downside of a
stitch in like that is that you can see
some of the outline on the back, but I
think that's part of it. uh and enjoy it
either way. When we go back to
collection structure and how we put this
together and we were talking about it
having a core item like the shirt that's
affordable that anyone can buy into
that's still super elevated is the kind
of stuff that actually gets most used
and worn for the brand or items like
this shirt and that hat that are kind of
casual every day versus not everyone's
going to be able to go for that hoodie
or some of these other items I'm about
to break down. Little branded bag for
this scarf. This is a cashmere scarf.
This was done by Crease Group. You see
those are guys I went to China with. We
do higherend luxury items like this. I
often do it with them. So you can see
the scarf here. So we looked at the the
designs before that Ben did. So then we
applied one of them to here with this
pattern that incorporates the the F logo
which I absolutely love. Is silk. It has
the rolled edge. Um we were going as
close as we can to a Hermes scarf.
Obviously this is kind of an an item
that you've seen people wearing and you
can use as an accessory. We did want
something that was more female leaning
as well. Little branded care tag 100%.
So, but again, this is one where not
everyone's going to wear or have a use
for these. So, this is more of a
standout item, like a flex item versus
the things like the shirts, which ends
up being what's most consumed. But to
me, this is my favorite item just
because I love uh what we did with the
iconography and then what Ben did with
the pattern on this and then being able
to apply that to something where like if
you know and you bought things of that
quality before, you're like this is just
as good as any luxury product that you
can get with the exception of like the
truly the best of the best. And now the
crown jewel.
Now the crown jewel
from upbranding on the bag. bag. We
figured people could reuse these as a
laundry bag. We didn't want to do like a
disposable dust bag uh because it just
says more as a premium brand. When you
get a premium item, that's something
that maybe you could use. And so, love
the idea this be like a luggage bag or a
laundry bag in addition. All right. So,
then we have this actual bag, which is
definitely the most exciting item of the
ones that we've done. Uh you can see
we've got the metal tag here. I actually
have the original. So, I was in the
factory when they were making these. I
was in the factory when they were
cutting the pattern. Uh just because
this is a project I care about. I'm
using this duffel pattern that we did on
a number of of like upcoming projects. I
want to make sure it was perfect and
just, you know, if we're going to go
over something, we want to call it
luxury, like I want to make sure I'm
present for it. So, they actually gave
me this uh like like the first iteration
metal brand logo tag color on color.
This is Togo leather that we we picked
out directly matching leather to the
actual colors here. You can see kind of
how close we are. It's impossible to get
like exactly precise when you're going
like between materials, but super close.
There a couple things that make this
stand out. I even like the little
highlights. If you'll notice, like
whenever there is an option, we did that
in a contrast color. This piping in the
contrast color, but it's a really
gorgeous leather.
And you'll see now that I have the
interior out, it gets supple. Some of
the details I really want to call out is
these oversized zippers. This is
something I love to do whenever you're
kind of making something stand out is
what do we do with a zip and the
oversized is a really fun way to do it.
When we go in here, you'll also see
the branded luggage tag attachment in
there in the same matching leather, but
they're on another garment. And then
this interior. So, the interior is in a
branded pattern. We have all these
separate pockets in the exact style that
I like, including the zip side over
here. There's a zip side,
same liner. And then also we have two
other additional pockets over here with
a nozzle
strap that you can use as well.
Little things like what these connection
points look like here. Everything about
it designed to just be really stand out.
Definitely my favorite item of what we
put together. So this bag was also done
by Crease Group. Um, and I will shout
out I don't want to reveal too much
about the clients that they have in case
people get mad, but there's multiple
luxury houses are being produced on the
same lot as the factory that I was in
there with uh accessories that I like
like leather goods. And so it's cool to
see everything handmade, hand cut,
handstitched, like really well uh like
just impeccably wellcraftrafted and it's
just awesome to see that level of
quality and obviously be able to get it
for a brand. And Crease Group did that
like interior packaging and branding as
well. And the shirt, I don't think I
mentioned before with that. It was done
by a vendor on Patra called Custom
Creations that I use a lot for shirts,
etc. because I just already have all
these default weights picked out.
They're also someone I have good
communications with, so I can tell them
to get a specific fabric or something I
get from China, they're able to execute
on it. But particularly when things are
under some level of timing stress,
they're a great one I go with. But
anything on like the full luxury end,
especially if we're going in like to
larger production, I try to do as much
with Crease Group as possible. It's cool
to see a bunch of this in the flesh
after we've kind of gone through all the
work of putting that together. And now
excited to kind of use that inside daily
life. And like I mentioned, when I
create these, like the whole idea is
like creating reusable things. So for
instance, like you'll see this hat in
across many projects in the future and
started on a project that never went
into production. And I adjusted some of
the style, moved it into another. Same
thing with that duffel bag. I have
multiple duffel bags that I'm using for
my own brand for client projects. So
like nailing that in, knowing all the
options, it's useful to be able to have
that to kind of work through the future.
And every time you add something that
canon, as long as you create a tech
pack, it's really worth it. like that's
something that becomes part of like your
designer profile that you're able to use
and grow with and then offer to to other
people and those things are going to be
able to move considerably faster. You're
going to already know like what the
results going to look like. You have
less sampling time and so the more of
that you have is one of the reasons why
people will come to people with
expertise versus trying to attempt to do
those things on their own and like
adding a bunch to their timeline to make
sure it's done right. So a quick
breakdown on some of the technical
details of like how we put these things
together. This is the tech pack for the
duffel bag. You'll note this is not like
some immensely complicated tech pack,
right? Simple, straightforward things
like this work a lot. We started with
this. We did not know where colors we
wanted to go. We knew what the
silhouette is. And then you can see to
the final version we end up using where
we have the colors of the different
handles. We have this liner that matches
the scarf that we're doing. We've been
selecting some more specific leathers,
etc. And then to ensure that everything
is going the way where I was actually
there at present at the factory when
they were cutting the pattern and when
they were choosing the leather leathers
and when they were choosing the linings
to save time with the back and forth and
I didn't like fly out there specifically
for that. I tried to time everything as
much as I could with multiple projects I
had to be most impactful when I was on
that visit in China. You'll see we got a
bunch of photos done. We had two kind of
spectacular models we worked with on
this. I'll shut everybody out in the
links and we used and Caleb Shane was
the photographer. So number we sent a
brief. We knew we weren't doing
something like super high production,
high budget, but we wanted to have like
an interesting feel. He did a great job.
He shot a mix of digital and film so we
could pick from it. Picked from a kind
of like a full options list of models.
And you'll see we have this things for
standard product shots. We didn't want
to have any like white background. Ecom
is not really the vibe that we're going
for. We put a separate brief together
for him as well. But he shot gave us
tons of options for this. And we had
like a bunch of different approaches to
how we want to put this together and
then the image options that we were
going to be able to use. You'll see um
as you've seen in my art direction
video, I always like to have at least
one concept when we're doing a shoot,
even like a quick kind of running gun
like what we're doing here. So for this
one, we kind of duped. So it's this
trend that was uh going viral in China
for a while, people showing off their
their wealth by spilling out of their
vehicle. Uh it was also that was then
that trend was then based on a like 90s
not times 2000's Tumblr trend where
there was a photo of this done by like a
luxury brand. So we kind of duped it for
this and then caught some video behind
the scenes of that as well. So we had
something more conceptual that we could
use for social content as well. Uh shout
out my Gwagon. This is part of why it's
a business expense. Overall being able
to capture all those details. We had a
full kind of mood board and list for
this shoot as well and just getting kind
of awesome work from Caleb who just does
a great job even with these very like
subtle photos of like showing off and
like putting product into a a wonderful
and amazing light. So for for a big part
of the premise was to show off the
landing page technology that they used
for everyone that was getting the box
their influencers their customer people
that are buying it. So you can see some
of the BTS I shot that they kind of did
some treatments and stuff on. This is
kind one of their landing pages where
you're able to view this bundle. They
are able to put like custom galleries
options for products. Google can select
sizes and things of like five together,
add to a custom cart and a custom
checkout as part of what they enable for
brands. That's a bit of the like front
end how this all works. Uh the only
thing I really didn't talk about here
was like shipping and logistics and
warehousing. We used Micro Merch as the
3PL for this. So they handle all the
fulfillment and stuff. Um they're great
for projects like this. We coordinated
shipment. This had to be done over the
course of like four months because it
takes 30 days just to get all the
designs and stuff right. uh took 30 days
to lock everything in and orders and
pricing and back and forth and files and
samples, 30 days of production, and then
we shipped a bunch of it by sea. We
aired a few things like at the at the
end just to make sure we hit the
timelines we were on, but it is about
120 days to do something like this
effectively. And some people will tell
you that that's really fast because you
could obviously be planning collections
like a year in advance. Uh then some
people will tell you that's slow because
if you did everything at the highest
price point possible and aired
everything, you could probably do the
same thing in like 60 days if you were
running a little bit more risk. I think
120 days is the perfect amount of it. I
hope you enjoyed walking through this
and everything about, you know, the mood
boards, the actual designs and graphics,
the thought processes behind putting so
much of it together, and then kind of
the end result of what everything looks
like. You have any questions about the
process or things I should hit in future
versions of this video for other things
I work on, please drop them in the
comments, and we'll do what we can.
Thank you so much for watching.