today we're going to talk about Brands
as a vehicle to get a creative or
artistic Vision into the world many
creatives have the misconception that
art can't be commercial or shouldn't be
commercial or that needs to be done
specifically on the artist terms and now
with social media there's also this
concept that the artists almost owed
exposure via these channels we have this
amazing reality today of the internet
social media and an appreciation of
independent Aesthetics that's
commercially rewarding in a level that's
absolutely unprecedented if you were a
designer or creative or you have a
Creative Vision you want to bring into
the world in some way getting exposure
for it and getting paid for it is easier
than ever and I'm here to talk through
the route of embracing it embracing
Brands is a vehicle for art and for
vision I'm going to show off how brands
of different types and scales Embrace
art and talk about types of businesses
and types of creatives and finding your
space I'm going to run through examples
of brands of different sizes and that
includes everyone from gentle monster
making sunglasses at the highest level
of fashion to a local chain specializing
in food who put art as their kind of
primary vehicle for promoting their
brand and we've been able to integrate
this into one really interesting concept
and also artists at different stages of
Social and how they've kind of embrac
that to make the algorithms work for
them the real goal of this video is to
develop a blueprint for how to start
looking at art as a vision inside of
Commerce so I'm going to start by
talking about Korean sunglass brand
gentle monster so you look at this brand
for the first time or with an objective
lens you notice something unique about
it right away and that's that the art
and the art direction is at the absolute
Forefront of everything the brand does
in fact everything else is almost
secondary to the overall creative ideas
that it's expressing as you browse
through their website look at their
imagery you look at their campaigns
there is obviously someone with if not
multiple people with just an intense
aesthetic and creative and artistic
Vision that they are bringing to life I
like to use them as an example because I
feel like this isn't a sunglass company
they make beautiful sunglasses but
really this is a vehicle a vehicle for
someone or some group who have such like
burning creat of intention inside of
them to use this brand and the vehicle
of selling sunglasses to bring their
Vision into reality and to me this is a
really important concept for creatives
to think about and they in particular
are a really interesting Showcase of
this because you see everything from
these physical spaces that are
essentially art installations to product
that they are treating as art like this
margel collab where they up with like
leather wrapped frames there's a
seriousness level to the creativity in
this that drives the brand forward as
its kind of number one thing it's not
like some unique product Market fit it
is creativity and art as what makes it
stand out one of the things I like most
about the brand their presentation is
the story section A little bit of a pun
on Instagram stories with the layout uh
inside their website but you can go
through and you can look at all these
surrounding creative that goes into
their campaigns and releases you know
dating back sign this 24 Optical
collection and this gentle High School
concept is one of my personal favorites
where they're playing into the
iconography and movie references of an
entire genre they created a really
Unique Eyewear collection and then this
whole world that goes around and this
concept of World building specifically
for a campaign where you know they have
a principal of a fictional school they
have this amazing art direction for the
actual assets themselves super intensive
video is built to perform in our kind of
modern social media era and that's just
the first layer cuz on top of all these
social media friendly assets on top of
how they've art directed this shoot like
this all being a vehicle to sell
sunglasses they also like have this kind
of AI art project as well where you can
generate an ID this links into their
pop-up stores and there was the ability
to have this community art interaction
element built on top of their General
Campaign which is a lot more than you
can say that your average fashion or
sunglass brand or even your un aage and
higher end version would actually do an
ex and they have tons of these campaigns
I've called out before in some of my
packaging videos when they released
these uh 2024 collection they did this
gentle jelly and they actually sent
people these oversized gummy bags with
the sunglasses inside of them which is
like a perfect influencer play um but
also has this you know obviously like a
basis in pop art that was really
interesting and then they don't just
Express that within campaign assets and
within visuals they create to promote
but it's also within the retail as well
their retail presences are functional
art installations you go to them not
necessarily to go to a store and shop
for sunglasses but because this is an
experience that you want to see with
your own eyes and put together and they
have these experiences spread throughout
the world and so this concept of the
core brand function being art is then
played through all the visual assets you
see the design of the product itself and
the stores with which they actually use
to Showcase it and this brings me to an
important point that I actually discuss
with creatives a lot whenever I'm on the
I'm on the phone with Brands who um want
to have this type of vision I had a few
of these conversations now because I did
a short form video about this concept
and a lot of Brands asked well how can
they be so successful but I'm trying to
do the same and I'm not and I think
that's where I want to bridge the gap
inside this video how do you actually
get to this what are the different
levels and how do you become a gentle
monster cuz I'll tell you that that
brand has been around for a minute
they've invested a ton of time and money
into cultivating that they have a
understanding of high fashion and a fit
in the market there that not everyone
can achieve but you can start small and
work your way up you have to understand
some of the parameters of what makes
these things successful and so the
biggest part of the conversation I end
up having when people kind of ask this
especially if they are putting time and
value into production at this level but
doesn't succeed is that often people
aren't making their assets to perform on
social media so this first big
misconception that people have we'll get
to this point to actually talk about
actual artists later is they're like
well if I make my art I make the thing
that I want if I put it out there it you
know why doesn't it get 1.5 million
views 4.9 million views Etc the way that
it does for gedle Monsters and then you
get this other subsection um which I'll
talk about when I break down different
types of creatives of people that are
like but I make my art should get that
like I have 100,000 followers on
Instagram I'm owed the ability to access
them to Showcase my art and I want to
basically put out there right now that
we're not owed anything by the
algorithms they're doing what makes them
money and they're showing people what
they want to watch in a vend diagram
with what makes them money that people
watch and so to succeed in getting your
vision out there you have to play that
game and you need to accept that and as
soon as you accept it you cross the
threshold from I don't want to play that
game I shouldn't have to play that game
to I'm going to play the game then you
have now entered an arena with which you
can win because gentle monster is making
assets at an artistic level that are
designed to perform and will actually
perform on these algorithms and yes
they're high production they cost a lot
of money they are collaborating with the
right people and creating the right
things that look and feel right for
social media you'll notice one thing
right this is a 9x6 video this isn't
like I had to make a square thing or a
short film or whatever like that's one
of the biggest things is put that is the
content format right now that works 9
x16 video no black bars at the top or
the bottom you don't want to you don't
try to be the exception to the rule make
full screen stuff that is what people
watch in the algorithm not a single
image not carousels this is what gets
the most traction and you can use those
other things it could all be pieces of
the stuff that you do but go out there
and say I want to put my vision as
concretely as I can inside the
Frameworks that I'm provided and when
you get to a certain level where you can
even use a 4x5 video like you see here
and have it perform you're going to know
because you're going to have your social
performance be so already out there that
you've crossed that threshold and you
have begun to understand how things move
on your media but to get to be a point
of a brand at this level to get to the
point where you can break the rules a
bit you have to play by the rules to get
there and the rules are literally
formats the rules are this type of
15-second video this compelling thing
that someone will watch on Instagram and
share and if I can make something that
is so cool that people share it
thousands of times you will get the
views that come from that and it will
build the brand that you are trying to
build which ties me into a sub
conversation because gentle monster also
owns a cafe brand in Soul which I'm not
going to butcher the pronunciation of
this is a physical location that you can
go to is presented with the same level
of intention and art direction that you
see inside the gentle monster brand but
their primary goal is to sell viral
looking croissants they're putting the
same level of production value and
intention into this to sell Bakery items
now they have the resources to do this
but I'm going to go in a second and show
the scales of how we get here and what
working up to that looks like and I
think that this is an approach that if
you have a vision within you or you an
artistic person you can take kind of
throughout so probably the most
well-known item is this kind of black
croissant that they have they also have
these Burger cakes but they are crafting
the menu for this Cafe and the
promotions around it based on an innate
virality but it's not just virality for
the sake of getting views is virality
that is paired with an artistic vision
and that's the core thing to remember if
you have one takeaway of okay I want to
go apply something interesting to any
other type of business right not to
fashion right fashion is its own Beast
that requires understanding and capital
it's complicated if you want to go make
a cafe that is an extension of your art
and we'll talk about this brand cops
it's a doughnut shop doing this in a
minute then you need to think about the
product and the art hand inand and how
do you make one beautiful enough to be
able to inform the other and this is a
great example of of someone doing so
this is a good opportunity to talk about
businesses and creatives as and the
different types of them and where they
stand so you can understand where you
playing this is also important so
there's three different categories I'll
put businesses in from a artistic and V
Creative Vision standpoint the first is
commercial businesses commercial
businesses that don't care whatsoever
about art direction or creative
Direction They core strategy when
they're selling their products is to say
here's what our product does if you want
to buy our product based on that then
you buy it and however artfully we put
this out there either it doesn't matter
or we don't care and that's probably the
majority of projects that are out there
if you are working on a business like
that you need to recognize it because
often trying to shift it into a more art
directed business either may not
actually help them or they're not going
to do and if you are a creative working
inside a commercial business like this
you may have to realize that that's
going to be something that you choose
but isn't going to actually lead to a
creative fulfillment in what you do and
the second type of business is an art
directed business there's a light art
directed business which is you have a
commercial business a drink company
whatever it is that cares and has
intention in what they do campaigns
they're interested in their brand and
their themes and they utilize some level
of intention of design to help achieve
their goals and then there's a heavy art
Directed company which is saying hey you
know our primary thing is still selling
this product right our product is still
the core thing that stands out for our
brand and we do a lot of intention into
our brand our Direction Etc but it is
it's still a an add-on to this other
vehicle that is the product that we sell
and that's more kind of art and commerce
living hand in hand um but in their own
like separate Kingdom and then we have
art and content first brand there's two
types of these I think that's really
important and I love art and content
into one because there is this this
whole idea that you can create something
in the universe whether you're creating
video content you're an influencer or
you're an artist I kind of lump them all
in the bucket now of people that are
doing a creative thing but then how do
you attach Commerce onto that so there's
attachment which is hey if you are an
influencer or you are an artist and then
you try to sell something you sell
merchandise you sell other stuff
strapped on top of it that isn't you
know is related to what you do and sync
to it but isn't like a perfect fit it's
just a it's a monetization vehicle for
attention and interest that you have
have you live in this first bucket and
the second is a synced art and content
first brand which I would look at like
gentle monster where you are saying our
Creative Vision and the things that we
sell are one and in fact the art and the
Creative Vision is the most important
thing selling what we do and that's the
chain of businesses we have and I think
it's important to note where you are and
then where you want to be not everyone
necessarily wants to have a complete art
and vision brand but it's worth
understanding what they are and the
difference between that and the lightly
art directed brand and I think you have
the ability to basically move in between
these categories right you can move from
a commercial to an art directed brand
light you can move from light to to
heavy art Direction you can move from
attached potentially to sync now none of
these moves are easy but it begins to
show you the scale of how Brands can
kind of switch around look at their
landscape what I don't think you can do
is move like two steps in the chain I
think it's a one step with a something
else would be an entirely New Vision
this is a good opportunity to talk about
types of creatives and artists as well
because I think about where do you fall
in this bucket when we talk about the
careers and what you want to do and
where you want your future Vision to be
it's worth understanding like where
you're actually at in that cycle so I'll
first I'll talk about inactive creative
so this is somebody who you've made art
you have a passion for art but you don't
do it at all anymore for whatever reason
and there's probably plenty of good ones
you're too busy whatever it looks like
just doesn't validating kind of sits
behind the door but you still have that
inside of you it's an inactive Creator
right one above that is the stubborn
artist that someone who makes the art
but only wants to have it on their terms
right they're like I make horizontal art
I don't want to put it on Instagram real
I want people to embrace the things that
I have the way I have them and you may
have a vehicle with which allows you to
do that and allows you to get some
success from but most of the time you
don't and until you graduate into one of
these other categories of artists you're
you're stuck there and stubborn artist
is often a mind State and you have to
ask yourself is this a mind state that
is helping me or is it a mind state that
is hurting my goals and you have an
employed artist and I'll cut those into
unfulfilled and fulfilled this means you
have a creative job you are working in
videography or illustration or whatever
it is for and companies employ you
whether freelance or not and you don't
pursue your own Vision necessarily as a
primary thing but you help fulfill other
people's Vision there's the unfulfilled
version of that a good example I like to
use is if you are a a a writer but
you're how you're actually making money
is you're writing sponsored content for
brands for Forbes or whatever that looks
like where you're like okay I'm really
just doing purely commercial work to get
this done and it does not get any give
me any creative fulfillment or I'm a
videographer and a filmmaker but you
know really I do like I do editing
support for you know news shows I have
no passion and there's a fulfilled
artist where you're working on a team
helping fulfill somebody else's Vision
but you really enjoy it it lets you get
that out be like hey I do work for a
brand I'm not making art every day but I
am doing something I love and I get to
have my level of input I get to get some
of my vision in the world as part of
this bigger thing and there's a lot of
people that find F F in Creative roles
as an employeed artist like got imagine
if you were a designer and you're
working on the kids super team or
whatever you may not be putting your
vision out there in the world but you're
working on a vision that you think is
super compelling and you're excited
about it then we have what I call an
artist and flow this is some where
you've married art how Commerce is
consumed whether that's on social media
or physically in real life whatever it
is you have figured out the pattern and
the Flyway with which you can create
things in ways that people like to
consume them and you are able to use it
to get more attention and more money and
the last is an artist behind a brand so
in the version above you're an artist
who's basically promoting yourself and
the things that you do but you take that
one step further and you say okay now I
am putting that Vision behind a bigger
commercial vehicle I look at creative
directors for major fashion houses right
like alesandro was the artist behind a
brand at Gucci for X time now he's doing
that at Valentino you can argue kind
someone like Rick Owens is an artist
behind a brand that is also his name but
that could live on to be bigger and be
outside of him at some point there's
other designers and contributors and
Muses and things like that you know
ruigi behind rude in a more exet Weare
sense but you're basically saying hey
I'm going to create a thing that is a
related to me or a namesake to me or I'm
going to be employed to come work in a
thing and I putting my vision behind
that commercial vehicle because is meant
to have fiscal success more primarily
than be tied specifically just to the
art now I'm going to talk about a few of
these artists and the types and how you
get here right so Daniel Aram has his
own signature style whether you like it
or not has achieved achieved immense
Commercial Success from that signature
Style by leaning into the things that
work on the internet today so first
having that signature style is huge
having something is visually
recognizable you could go that is Daniel
Aram I know if it is eroded I know if it
is a statue I know if it uses this color
palette is likely him when you have that
signature visual style in the social
media world this applies to a brand as
much as it does to an art to art it
allows you to succeed there's a
recognition and repetition that social
media rewards now he's taken this very
far not necessarily in a great way like
there's a coin he has a coinbase nft
that came out one day ago in this year
of Our Lord 2024 which is a crazy
concept right but like he's doing
whatever he can to get the back has
married this idea of his art and
commerce so intrinsically that is
basically almost every project is is
somewhat related that's at least half
the posts in this feed are like brand
related I think there's a lot of artists
that necessarily wouldn't necessarily
want to take it that far there's a lot
of people that are critical of the kind
of thing that he does but at the same
time he obviously has a concrete visual
vision of where he wants to go and has
used social media and used collaboration
and used his own visual style to achieve
it now let's take a step back let's look
at car so I'm social media mutuals with
her and she has done this at a smaller
level right she is a creative that makes
her own art and she has used social
media as a vehicle to be able to reach
her target audience extremely well on a
smaller scale she has some Commerce
relation a bunch of sponsored posts with
like Adobe and people like that but for
the majority of the time she is making
her art whether you like her art or it
resonates with you or not it has found
its audience with her Target and with
the people that look up to her and what
she's able to do and how she's done this
well is document the process of what she
creates and how and she's built out a
studio space that is an excellent
vehicle for social media and then she
does things like say she's moving to
Berlin currently or something like that
where the where the journey is something
that people want to follow along with
and this is an amazing example of her
artistic vision is information right
when you are at a certain age and you're
beginning to and you're putting these
things together in your life you are
working through what what my what is my
Grand Vision going to look like over
time but the ability to then share and
document that experience do it in an
aesthetic way do it in a way that you're
target audience you know feels some some
kinship to allows you to build at the
same time and doing that in 9x6 reels
and Vlogs and picking her colors super
intentionally and picking the way
everything is presented well and being
like you know what like having a studio
space you obviously it's great for any
artist to have and work through but
actually it's going to get you a lot
more value because I can document it on
social media that is a framework with
which you can use to be able to be a
full-time Artist as she is based on on
social media I think that's a really
interesting concept people need to think
about and you can think about am I doing
this for myself as a creative versus I'm
doing it for a brand you kind of have a
choice there this where I'm going to hit
this point in a second time about the
social media friendliness of this this
is my friend Oliver Oliver Prime uh
We've made friends online you DM talked
on the talked on the phone and talked a
lot about social media success right CU
I was like hey you have really cool
projects but you're documenting them in
this kind of like almost like abstract
ways again that didn't necessarily work
on social media and like really what you
need to do is is find a format and
repeat it online to be able to show your
art to the world because his art is very
visually compelling and uses magnets and
the process of it is is very interesting
like he has a great look personally uh
the art has a really interesting look I
was like hey you need to put it out
there in a way that will be resonate
with social and that often just comes
down to process videos and you can see
he's now taking shots on goal constantly
with 20,000 plus views and then some of
them hit 220,000 views 633 th000 views
and they're all about showing his
process right and this format that
you'll see here where you basically see
a amazing looking final product you see
the process with which to create the
product and then you see a more thorough
reveal of the product at the end is like
the ultimate current format for uh for
being on reals right now to be able to
like have something succeed and it's
like GL Glimpse the final thing run
through the process of making that thing
and visually compelling way especially
works you have a visually compelling
product and then show like a payoff of
what that actual thing looks like do it
in 15 seconds repeat and not all art is
made for that but the majority can find
a way to incorporate into it but when
you find that format you repeat it you
repeat it and you repeat it until it
finds resonance and you've improved
enough or you see which of your pieces
move in a certain way and you develop
your visual style and with his like
magnet driven style he has an aesthetic
that you could say all right in the same
way that I see Daniel aram's work I can
see his work I know immediately it's him
and if you can identify something like
that at a small scale like I have no
doubt like he's did a project with
Spotify I have no doubt he can go as far
as he wants to take this and it's cool
to see that at these various scales as
an artist now let's look at these
various scales as Brands so I did this
video last week about destination so
about people going to airan to get a
smoothie about the Starbucks hidden Tik
Tok menu and really this is a precursor
for me to be able to talk about like
these overall concepts of how creating
something that is social media friendly
or creating an experience is really what
separates like can transform any
business on social media and I like to
look at drinks and food as one because
of the innate viral there so if you're
looking at a business you can do as art
I don't want everyone to be like I have
to make some Sunglass or high fashion
brand I want to look at how I can
translate any normal brand into that cuz
a lot of us can't jump into go doing
something High fashion and so food is an
amazing one because when I look at one
of the things that are have a large Tam
or total available Market in a large Tam
enables virality so you're putting
content on social media the more people
that will like it or want it or want to
save it or share it the better that
content can do and the biggest
categories that everyone loves hard to
resist amazing food and amazing food
content Fitness tons of people want to
be fit and have some level of that
integrated into the content they consume
Interiors the reason you see so many big
interior design creators people see
people blow up on there is everyone
cares what their spaces look like and I
say everyone it's a big generic like
let's assume 70% of the population cares
inspiration people look for motivation
they look for reasons to go on forward
in their lives category 4 and the last
is entertainment something funny or
beautiful like a movie or a film that
eats up time makes you feel good about
yourself or makes you feel emotional
those are the things with the biggest
available Market there are other huge
markets out there and there obviously
Niche markets but when you look at you
know okay how can I apply virality to
something huge when you apply to food it
is a whole cge industry of things that
come with that when you apply to Fitness
same thing and so when I would if I were
you looking at how do I get my Creative
Vision out there what brand could I
choose to do that I would not be afraid
to choose one of these more common
things because you can lean into how do
I take an Artful approach to doing that
and so I note inside here this brand
right here Revival coffee in Austin so
they have viral drinks they're in a tier
three city right at best right uh so
Austin you want to wait in line to get a
beverage looks great on social media
Revival coffee by Gabriel I think an
influencer has taken the first step
towards we are creating a thing that
looks good on social media that gives
people a reason to go to our business
now this is still a step away from art
and vision corresponding into the
business but it's the beginning of it
and if you go apply that same attention
to any coffee shop any Bakery any pizza
shop whatever it is if that is the right
Vibe and the customer you want to
attract and you want to tell that story
correctly you can begin to execute that
vision and if you want to start from the
start and do that that's where
interesting businesses come in like this
business cops so cops is a doughnut shop
that is Art and I it's really
interesting to me because when you go
look at the pictures you're like what am
I even looking at here before you even
decipher that there's a dut involved
they have a you know photography and art
Direction kind of team in house that
shooting a bunch of these things and
you're going like all right someone with
intense Creative Vision is cooking here
for like a local Canadian dnut shop and
they're executing all kinds of
conceptual campaigns visually uh they
have interesting presentation on the
actual products themselves they present
the the recipes and everything in a
really art Artful way like every single
thing that you see on here is
intentioned uh built for social media
and you can actually go like hey when
I'm actually going to engage they're
they're tying in a narrative here from a
previous campaign something that's
available like at the actual store but
this is like an art first donut shop and
that's a really interesting concept to
me because not only is it something that
you want to visit but you can see like
they're just doing something that's more
interesting than what any other brand in
their space is doing and when you are
doing something with artistic Vision
that's the goal right make something so
interesting that it is just immediately
more compelling than anyone you're
competing against and I love this as a
concept for food and I really use this
example to get you to think outside the
box of a brand you want to do since so
many people want to have brand Vision in
Fashion but if you look at the same
thing in a gym and if you think of the
same thing in any sort of Professional
Service whatever it is there's some
Industries where you can succeed some
not it depends on the sinking of the
vision and the target consumer but for a
lot of things especially things where
Aesthetics play well into why a consumer
would go engage with it which is
obviously anything you would wear on
your body anything that you would
consume you might take a picture of for
social media any place that you may go
that you engage and spend time in like a
gym whatever it is you have this ability
to approach it with this artistic way
and overall I think this is an important
concept to think about where are you on
the Chain some light art Direction
campaigns that art is Artistic first
what kind of vision do you have do you
have a vision that you're burning to get
out of your body that you want make sure
is translated into the real world or are
you want to contribute to someone else's
Vision or do you want to learn along the
way and those are like really important
things but understanding this concept
that Brands can be art you can lean all
the way in is something that I think
will bring more interesting visual
Creations into the world and enable
creatives to see the Commerce potential
in what's inside their heads so now I
challenge you to think about where do
you live inside the structures that I've
outlined and then where do you want to
go inside your creative Journey do you
have the vision inside your head to
build something as compelling as a
gentle monster and how do you begin to
put yourself in the situation and do
that or do you really want to look at
yourself at the point of the career
where you want to be working on other
people's Visions to gain that skill set
think it's about identifying where
you're at now then also where you want
to go and begin to build that Ro map for
your career to really think through
these ideas and decide where you best
live in that chart both here and in your
near future and I'm going to follow up
to this video later this week with a
video on brand narrative so brand
narrative and World building are two of
the concepts I'm going to explore a lot
over the next kind of coming weeks and
it's really about this idea of how do
you shape the actual environments around
you about the stories that come in and
out the things that are happening and
the things that you want to create to
form a cohesive Vision whether it's for
your personal brand a brand that you
work on or a brand that you are founding
and running so you can do the most
interesting and creative things with it
and help Propel that Vision forward to
make something unique any questions on
anything I've talked about here or any
other examples or interesting things we
should touch on please let me know in
the comments uh this obviously a topic
I'm stoked to talk about and thank you
for watching