In this video, we're going to talk about
a secret weapon for brand social media,
archetypes. Archetypes are about
deciding the role that a brand plays in
a consumer's world and how they come
across on social media. It becomes
basically a template for the kind of
content you create to get a strategy
that works. In a previous video, I
talked about how to start brand social
media from scratch if you have nothing.
But for this archetypes workshop, we're
going to ask the question about what do
you do if you've already started on
social, you have something going, but it
just doesn't do good enough. [music] As
someone who has worked through this now
with hundreds and hundreds of brands in
Cut 30, and then brands from startups to
Fortune 500s in the work and workshops I
do, I've built methods for this and I'm
going to teach them all here. We're
going to walk through how to do this
exercise. We're going to walk through
five archetypes that apply to the
majority of brands. Now, I have examples
in here for software, fashion,
interiors, resale, food and beverage,
and services. You have a wide swath. No
matter what kind of business you have,
there's no excuse not to tap in. So,
after we go through the exercise itself,
we're going to walk through each of
those archetypes, what brand they're
good for, the question to ask yourself,
the type of content they make, and
examples of brands that are doing the
strategy. No fluff, all tactics. And as
you can tell, I love to talk about this
and I'm happy to workshop live in the
next community call we have, which I
will link down below for any projects
you have. Let's lock in. So, first off,
if you haven't done one of these with me
before, haven't been to a tour date,
this is a good time to let you know that
I love exercises. I love a series of
questions, filling out a document, and
making a plan. And a few reasons this is
useful. If you are a freelancer, going
into a conversation with a client and
actually having something you can run, a
process, not only makes you look more
professional, but also helps establish
buy-in with the client on what you're
going to do. It's the same thing in the
conundrum of if you work on social media
at a brand. For a lot of people, you're
often a younger employee and you're
usually faced with the challenge of how
do you convince leadership to act on
these ideas. So, archetypes is a concept
that goes back into marketing overall,
in overall brand strategy. Brands often
look at what is the archetype our brand
has. And there's a number of strategies
around actually putting together the
brand persona and the brand voice. So,
we're going to distill that concept that
a lot of CMOs and executives are
familiar with down to social media. So,
how this exercise would work if you want
to run it for your brand, a brand you
work at, or for a client, is you would
run through the archetypes below. I have
five here. There's definitely more. You
can make up your own. You can cut it
down to just the two or three that are
relevant. But basically, you start by
going through the options. And then a
key step here, and what I want to call
out right at the beginning, is a lot of
brands have an idea for some amazing
thing they want to do on social, but
rarely does anyone actually ever do the
big idea. Why not? It's because they're
constrained. They only have so many
resources. They only have so many teams.
Even though they have this vision, they
don't have the reality. And so, the
second step in this process is to
actually map out what resources you have
to execute the content, or what
resources do you think you can get?
Because this is really important as we
dive into these. You'll find with the
Oracle archetype I'll talk about first,
that's about having an expert in your
organization or on staff. So, if your
org has that, it becomes a really a
no-brainer to center your content around
it. But if it doesn't, you may have to
look at picking another archetype. And
so, in that process you go through who
can be on camera for the brand? Who can
design for the brand? You know, whether
that's internal graphic designers,
whether that's an agency you already
have, whether you have a budget to
retain someone, and then where do you
get them? And then what can you actually
showcase? What's going on at the company
that you can make content about? So,
once you cross-reference those, you pick
an archetype, and then you go through
the different content ideas you have
there, and you start to build out a
brainstorm list. So, when you end the
exercise, you've picked an archetype,
you've listed the resources you have or
don't have, or what the company's
willing to do or pay for or try to find,
and you actually have a list of ideas
people are excited about based on the
archetype. So, you have a content
roadmap that people are already bullish
on. And you can bring that to a system
like content pillars that I talk about
in other videos that you run an ongoing
social process. And if you have this
skill set, if you can do this, if you
can get by and help execute this, this
is one of the rarest skill sets, right?
A lot of people work in social media,
not a lot of people make social media
actually bang. And I love nothing more
than watching this process work. Every
time someone cracks out of Cut 30, and
we'll walk through a few of those in the
examples here, it just gets me stoked.
So, without further ado, let's tap into
some archetypes. So, first is the
Oracle. This is best for brands who can
teach people about the brand space, the
world they inhabit with deep expertise.
So, relies on a core expert or a team of
several experts who can storytell. And
so, if you ask the question, "What does
our customer need to understand or want
to understand about the world that we
inhabit that nobody else is explaining
properly?" And so, then they do
historical explainer content. So, for
instance, if you sold chess sets like I
have in front of me, you are able to
break down the history of chess in
general and major competitions or
outliers or certain moves being adopted
or the design of chess sets. You have
this whole history around that. You want
to expand that world? You can go into
all the tabletop gaming. You can go to
chess's connection to strategy and war,
to the psychology of competition. You
have a world of history to talk about as
a content pillar. And category
comparisons. Use that expertise to talk
about things that are better or not. An
excellent example of this is a dentist
we had in Cut 30 who would talk about if
certain products were actually worth the
money or if new processes or ideas were
actually valuable for customers with
different teeth problems. And the
formula is, is X or Y better for Z? So,
if your expertise is helping explain
that, whether that's what type of
dermatological treatment, does this
shade of makeup look better with this
skin type, that comparison for a certain
end person is excellent tactical
content. And then third is why things
are the way they are. We have all these
assumptions in life, why we do our taxes
a certain way to why suits are formal
wear to why cameras have aperture.
People are way more interested than
you'd think in the little things that
are consistently surprising about life
in all ways. And this is one of the ones
I love to lean into cuz I don't think
anything is too boring. There's a brand
that I work with that does industrial
parts manufacturing, and you may think
at the outset that that sounds kind of
dull, but then you look at it, a story
behind every screw, every bolt, every
welding piece, the machines, three-axis
CNC, supply chain, why these things are
made in that country versus the other.
You'll be surprised how deep people nerd
out about them. And the best part is,
maybe there's not 100,000 people a video
to watch it, but say there's 2,000.
They're nerding out about welded parts,
you're probably adjacent to an industry
that's going to be procuring them. And
the last content type for the Oracle is
predictions for the future, thus the
name that we have. So, based on all this
expertise, what do you think is going to
happen next? So, historical explainers,
category comparisons, why things are the
way they are, and predictions for the
future. Let's walk through some
examples. So, one of my absolute
favorites, and probably the easy to
point to, is Ken Sekiguchi. You've heard
me talk about his videos before, cuz
I've bought products because of this.
So, he will go into the background
behind a workwear pant, why it was
designed, what their history was.
Selvedge denim, we've all heard the term
about selvedge, he's able to talk about
that accurately. And what you will see
him do is he will set up some of the
topics. So, for instance, the background
of a pilot's jacket, and it will
eventually lead to him releasing his own
version under his brand, Front Office.
And it doesn't happen every time, he may
talk about other tangential topics, help
build the world and his expertise, but
when he cares enough about a jacket, and
he's dove deep into it, and he then
releases it a couple months later,
you're like, "Yeah, this guy's really
studied the art." And so, one expert, he
is the social media for the brand. They
don't even have a separate content and
their separate page, where he talks
about a whole world of things, and you
trust his expertise when he then
actually releases product. And how that
comes out is you'll see historical
videos at the top of funnel with big
wide reach. You'll see details of the
things that he is developing, and then
you will see carousels of the actual
releases, like uh these fingerprint
pants, which you have seen me wear in
content that I love and bought with my
own money. This is the women's wear
example, but I have the men's, and
that's a basically exact example of a
content funnel. And then a local one to
me that I know, cuz they are a a local
business here in the Orange County area,
is Blam Motor Works. I love their
content, they film in their garage. And
look, this Dave This is a good example
of, if you do have someone with a
professional film background who has a
nice camera, knows how to set and frame
these. These aren't the craziest highest
production videos, but they do spend
time making them look good. And they
talk about the restoration and
conservation of Porsches, which is what
they're experts in. And it's amazing,
obviously, having a business where you
can show really cool-looking cars to
help anchor it. Not everyone has it, but
if you do have it, and you have a
manufacturing facility, or you have
access to those, you've got to be
telling those stories. And so, they have
an expert on camera explaining the work
they do. How the rear steering wheel
operates on a 911R. So, this is just an
explainer of how that works. All the way
to actually walk-throughs of the
projects they are doing. An excellent
example of the Oracle in that brand. And
you will see guys in the comments either
arguing about the Porsche world, or
asking questions, establishing the brand
as expertise. Another one of my faves is
Kreiss furniture. And we're going to
talk about two Kreiss's here, k r e i s
s, and then actual c r e a s e that I've
worked with later on. Can get a little
confusing, but uh this brand has their
standard social media. But then they
also do a lot of having the founder on
their feed, and the founder has an own
account where he is talking about
underrated plants for your landscaping,
trends that are in and out. They're
doing stuff that's in their showroom.
They're doing all the typical brand
interior content with an occasional
appearance by him. But then his social
media is the real driver. So, in this
two-account method, you're able to post
your typical content on main that you
want. You're able to use your larger
expert that's building up as an
influencer to help grow that account,
but you don't need to rely on it too
deeply. And then he has his own presence
as well. And he is talking about trends.
Is boucle played out? What's the best
paint color for an entire home?
Landscape hacks. Latest trends. Very top
of funnel expertise-driven focused, but
then funnels into what they sell at the
brand. And if you want to look at a
formula to do this, there's pretty much
no better place to look. So, he can
highlight, okay, here's a viral kitchen.
Here's Yeah, here's all like 10 items
you could have, the state of a trend.
And he is just sitting down doing these
edited yaps. And the last one I'll talk
about here, because I don't want to be
too founder-focused, cuz you'll notice
there's a lot of founders in those other
videos. I like what Rarify has done, cuz
they just have someone on camera. So,
Rarify is resale rare and collectible
furniture. And any brand that's a retail
store or reseller should be making
content about the products they sell
explaining why it's good and useful is
the biggest no-brainer you have. And
they just have someone from the team on
camera talking about the different
things that they sell, why they became
famous. It's collab with a an influencer
I follow, it's funny. And it's different
members of the team. That's what I like
about this, too. It doesn't always have
to be one person. I actually like the
idea of having a team showing different
expertises. And they'd be able to walk
through the things that they sell. Now,
you'll notice all these are very visual
brand. have to be like that. There's a
great example is a YouTube account, it's
like Infinity or Instantly or one of
these email marketing firms. But they're
just answering common email marketing
questions or talking about outreach
techniques. This works just as well for
an agency. Anything with a topic to talk
about can work for the Oracle. Let's
talk about a fun one, the performer. And
then we're going to get to my favorite
after that. So, with the performer, the
content is a show. It's entertainment
driven, it's personality first. It's
built to be binged and shared rather
than focus on selling. The product
barely needs to be mentioned, it's often
omnipresent throughout the entire
content. Now, I'll tell you what that
means. So, there's shoots is a great
example of this. They do skits, fashion
skits. You hear a lot of people talk
about them. They will have a couple
creators, they will go to interesting
places. You'll see their budgets
expanded over time to include travel.
They will have skits, they will have
compilations. Basically extremely
relatable entertaining content where the
clothes are always on. That's what I
mean by omnipresent. They may not
necessarily be talking about the
clothes, though sometimes they do, but
their presence is what anchors it. And
the question to ask is, if our brand had
a show, what would it be? What would it
be about? Would people watch it without
knowing if it was ours? And a I saw an
example of this is Mohawk Chevrolet, who
for a long time basically did a spin-off
of The Office on their TikTok with some
characters. This is great. A place
that's offices that have a lot of
downtime or they have a couple funny
personalities in there. Like leaning
into that and doing a bit of a scripted
series and doing skits with those people
in and out becomes a fun way to do it.
And again, them being in Mohawk
Chevrolet or dealing with the things
around running a car dealership makes
the business itself omnipresent. And
this also ties in the really viral
examples, people like LC Sign, where
basically everything is a skit that
leads into promotion of their signs
which is extremely entertainment driven
so it's an entertainment hook on all of
them. And before we get into my favorite
one I want to talk for a second about
Framer. If you want to elevate the look
and feel of a website experience one of
the easiest ways to do that is with
shaders in Framer. If you want to do
this on your canvas go up here to the
plus sign that is your insert panel and
you go down to shaders. Now let's walk
through some of our options that we
have. So each shader has a default and
you have options. So for instance this
gradient section I can choose the colors
I can choose the speed I can choose the
scale. Then these are image shaders I
can use to manipulate a picture. So you
see here I can select the image so that
I put one of my backgrounds here for
example. There's different types of
cells can adjust their thickness can
invert it have some of these more more
mosaic styles and go high pixel low
pixel play with the aberration. And they
have several effects that I really like
great to spice up something like a tech
website. These particles that kind of
drift and you can set them in a super
slow speed or scale for a background.
You can control the speed and
interaction. I think it has like a cool
ambient effect. All these backgrounds
are responsive and fit into any part of
your site. So for instance you see I
brought it in here and it added it to
all of the different segments and I
could begin to layer text over it. If I
delete it it removes it from all. If I
want to have a style that matches a
little more like what we did with that
pixel I can bring it in here and begin
to work around it. And actually continue
to manipulate the shader inside my web
builder. They're great to swap out
existing backgrounds or just put an
interesting idea together. Make a simple
landing page that much cooler. You can
check these out and learn more about
Framer at the link in the description.
If you have any questions about the web
experience or want me to cover it in any
future tutorials let me know below. Now
for my favorite of the social media
archetypes and don't worry there's the
the ones that are remaining after this
are the ones that are way more like
tactical and straightforward I'm just
doing the fun ones first. This is the
world builder. Building a massive
content that's interesting far reaching
and surprising far beyond the world that
the brand inhabits. This is if you
really have the ability to go outside
the box. Can we make something creative
that people will love so much they love
the brand right next to it. So, for
example, that our brands making short
films, doing a fictional character
series, immersive intellectual content
and curation. So, this is best for teams
and founders that are willing to take a
risk. It's not for everyone. But, when
people start to ask, "How can my
software brand make content that's
really cool? How can my boring business
do something outside the box?" This is
the one I point to. You have to take
some risks, but there's an awesome world
to build here. My favorite example of
this is Death to Stock. Death to Stock
is a is a stock photo website, right up.
They do shoots for stock photos that are
a little out of the ordinary.
>> [snorts]
>> Their content, they do a immersive
intellectual world where they have their
own in-house creator and they partner
with other creators to talk about what
is happening in the world around them.
Something really strange is happening in
packaging. Hottest girl you know just
got into electronics and they're
detailing like the cyber deck trend. So,
they are talking about all the things
that are trending in the visual world.
And then when it ties to the brand is,
yeah, we we do stock photos that are
also on trend versus the average ones
you get. So, it takes an intellectual
concept tied to the value proposition
and then executes it relentlessly at a
super high level. And people build a
real affinity with the brand. They
immediately go, "Oh, we we get it. These
people understand us, understand the
artistic community, the visual
community. They provide value and they
tell really dynamic, interesting
stories." Is this an easy strategy? No.
Is it one that makes them by far the
best content of anyone that they're
competing with? Yes. The ultimate tech
example and then one of my favorite
examples for this um because their
product objectively is bad, right? No
one knows what Cluey does. Few people
are buying from Cluey, but their social
media is amazing. If you were to marry
those two things, if someone was taking
the same strategy they're doing but
applying it to a business that actually
has some legs, could do a lot. So, they
basically have office skits about a fake
fictional story of what's happening in
the business that are really well
produced and done with a recurring cast
of characters, all this narrative-driven
content, but it is all iPhone. It is all
base captions. It is just scripted and
put together really well. And then a
more esoteric example is Fern, who are
basically doing really beautiful short
films. Talk about the essence of things
that their fragrance represents. Or if
you did have a really artistic team or
access to an amazing creative director,
they have built a truly like
unbelievable series around this. And I
do think that they're at the point where
say you have been investing in social
media and you have a brand that just
can't make anything interesting. And
you're working with a few agencies,
you're tapped into this stuff, you have
some kind of budget, it may be worth
thinking about taking the moonshot. This
is the time, right? Or if you keep
trudging along in the same stuff and
spending money on it that goes nowhere,
use that same budget to do something
interesting. This is the time to act on
it. So now getting more tactical, the
catalyst. The catalyst uses content to
push people towards a better version of
themselves. Your content is the bridge
between who they are and who they want
to be. So it's educational, but it
doesn't require a big expert all the
time. It can have multiple staff or team
on there. But it's like how do we in
different ways, whether that's with
carousels, whether it's inspirational
motivational content, whether it's just
simple explainer videos, how can we make
our content proofing guidance of how to
help our demographic achieve what they
want? So that's training and process
documentation, inspirational stuff like
text overlay, like simple one-shot
content, and then community highlights
and and challenges. And when people say
what I mean by community, I feel like
accounts like big accounts like Artifact
C, they're a great example of a
community-based content, right? Where
they are curating stuff their community
sends them all the time cuz they've
built up an audience that wants to have
a dynamic multi-way conversation with
them. When you look at a lifestyle of
you know, Base Living is like a curation
account, but you could just as easily do
this as a brand. They have a couple
catchphrases that I must live a certain
way. Like they're basically creating
almost almost meme account stuff around
the demographic that they're trying to
serve, people that are looking for that
more back to the earth lifestyle, and
they are curating the world around that
in a way that doesn't require anyone on
camera. But but I think my favorite
example of this is someone who I worked
with closely on their social strategy,
which is Chris Cruise, so a
manufacturing group. So you'll notice in
a lot of their content, they're doing
things like, okay, what's a brief that
gets a result when you are giving
something to a manufacturer? What does a
simple product really mean? How does
this process that is used in a fashion
process actually work? Like this laser
manufacturing. Let's recap this
interesting sustainable fabric. So
they're building a world around being a
manufacturer. That's always from people
always point to me they're like, "Oh,
how do I make this boring business
content?" Like I think in your world
it's not as boring as you think. There's
a million people who do import export
stuff from China or they're a
manufacturer who would think that their
stuff intrinsically is uninteresting.
And really you just have to look at the
branch of where can we go visit around
us that does something interesting and
how deep people will get into it. So
they go through all the choice where
there's label choice for your brand.
They're going to the trade shows their
demographic is interested in to show
them the highlights if they can't afford
to go. They're basically helping be that
catalyst from where their audience wants
to be to where they are. And if they
become clients along the way, great.
Then the last one we're going to note
out here is called the helper. Brands
that don't have a deep expert to put on
camera, who want to lean on value
content, but it's not like motivational
in the way the catalyst was. That's the
biggest difference between the two
because they are pretty similar. Is that
the catalyst is like is aspiring. Like
there's a better life for a better brand
out there. It's going to be shared
because it's motivational. Whereas the
helper is more practical. So often
relies on a core person like a creator,
but they don't have to be a deep expert.
have to be a founder. They can be
sharing it along the way. It's someone
who's more like on the journey with you
or who's really relatable. And so the
question asked is what are the little
helpful things that we can do that our
customer will appreciate? And what are
little anecdotes that they'll find that
they can relate to? So this demographic
does visual tutorials in this archetype,
carousel stories and like light tips,
story vlogs, and then interviews and
curation. So one I like for this that I
actually met um the woman at ShopTalk is
Kyoko Beauty. So this is an excellent
choice for a beauty brand, right? Where
they're using a handful of creators to
basically kind of break down, "Okay,
what is Korean skin care?" They're a
retailer that aggregates different
Korean skin care brands. And basic help,
like don't buy this serum, get this
instead. But again, not presented by
like some super established makeup
artist, etc. They're just talking
through realistically, "What are all
these different things you may want to
make along your buying journey?" If I'm
interested in beauty, I'm interested in
Korean beauty. I want to choose a
cleanser. They are at a level like
again, not that far above their
consumer. Not presenting it like, "Hey,
I'm a chemist." They're doing those
comparisons and answering the consumer's
questions for them. That is the role of
the helper. And this is an excellent
account to look to for that, for using
multiple creators, for using multiple
styles. I think they're a great example.
Um another example, Cut 30 Grad, Hashi
Home, where they're doing relatable
stuff about being a host. So they have a
lot of skits in there, and they're kind
of presenting that life of someone who's
a host with kind of relatable notes
about them. So it's less about being
super useful to that person, and more
about being relatable to them. Everyone
who's actually a host relates to the
kind of content they make. And of
course, her ceramics are at the heart of
all of them. This is a secondary
approach from, okay, this is very info
help focused, this is just relatable
helper focused. And then another
software one that I want to call out. Um
I know they've sent their creator
Miranda, who's amazing, through Cut 30 a
few times, is Marpipe. So Marpipe does
one of the dullest things you can do
from a software. They do catalog ads for
Meta. If you don't know what that is,
it's like a just a dense part of like
the Meta advertising experience. The
auto-generated ads of your products that
show up. They help make them beau-
beautiful. And so they have a creator
that they have who's also has her own
account, who makes a lot of
informational content about marketing.
What are the trends, what's happening in
the world. And what they notice is even
though a lot of these aren't directly
related to the brand, and even though
they take a lot of shots on goal, and
it's not like constant hits all the
time, what it's done is providing this
stream of informational content has made
it so the brand is much more recognized
and their ads perform better. And that's
a perfect example of organic and paid
going hand in hand is if you have just
any degree of brand, right? And any
degree of informational content that's
actually helping their user, it's like,
oh yeah, I heard of that brand. I
remember the video they did about
marriage marketing, or sneaker fatigue,
or whatever it is. Oh, here's what they
actually do. For a more dense, complex
product, just being that entry point,
helping get that click, helping reduce
the money or the barrier to entry it
requires when you're advertising, is a
massive value add that putting a creator
on main, having them do helpful content
can help execute, no matter how
technical the niche is. If you have
questions about this, want to workshop
this for your brand, the community call
info is below. We are doing that in just
a few days. If you missed that one,
there's one every month and I'll update
this to the most recent link if you're
watching this later. All of these
archetypes I will have the cheat sheet
for down below as well. So, you can grab
all these links. Try to make it as easy
as possible. But, I cannot encourage you
enough to do the exercise, right?
Actually go through, think about what
does your brand have as far as talent?
Do you have a full expert? Can you get
just a creator? Can you be more helpful
versus more aspirational? Do you want to
take a real shot on goal and then do
some world building? Now, you have some
examples. You're armed with some people
to use and have conversations about with
your team. And you can stop kind of
floundering around, stop trying to be
everything to everybody, and lock in on
one archetype. Hope you found this
helpful. As always, thank you so much
for watching.