in this video we're going to cover
creative Direction 101 we're going to
talk about building creative briefs and
how to do those so that they work we're
going to talk a bit about the creative
process if you're generating a lot of
assets and we're going to talk about how
creative Direction applies to things
like making products interesting and
creating ads and this is a good topic
because the term creative directors has
become very widely used but really in
theory it's about how do you make things
interesting and how do you tie all the
pieces of the cultural conversation that
are happening into decisions that you
make inside product marketing and
branding all with the through line of
design so I've got a bunch of
interesting examples and things to talk
through everything from some products
some standout product direction from
things like this dreze fragrance set
we'll talk about I'm going to be
unboxing some new product samples and
talking about the creative Direction
there I have a products I just got I was
super stoked on it's an awesome example
of applying some creative strategy to
product and I'm actually going to walk
through a bunch of the creative I've
been making with the design team dark
room I work with for my own brand you
can see the briefing process you can see
the creative that comes out of it and
you can see how designers and creative
directors of Brands can work together in
a rhythm but most importantly we're
actually going to Zone in on a couple
key creative Direction strategies so you
begin to build a toolkit that you can
use for Creative Direction no matter
what your field is if you're a designer
videographer a marketer an entrepreneur
you can begin to look at these options
and say Here's how I make things stand
out so without further Ado let's do it
so I'm going to dive right into the
value first and I'm going to talk about
creative Direction strategies so I like
to think of almost every creative as
someone who needs a toolkit I made a
previous video about this about
organizing and strategizing on your
creative toolkit but really it's about
including techniques things you can do
on any given campaign or product to make
your stuff hit and as a creative
director I built out my toolkit over
time I've used it as a CMO as a VP of
marketing as a product designer as a
consultant in all kinds of different
roles I have a number of things that I
go to recurringly to look at is this how
I can make this thing or that thing
stand out we're going to walk through
them exactly so one of the easiest ones
is the idea of scale you can make almost
anything inherently more interesting by
making it really big or really small and
all these I'm going to talk about are
Concepts you can apply to your reference
cuz we have all these videos about mood
boarding or building up references
people build all these big boards but
what do you do with it how do you make
it original you take your reference and
you go through your toolkit and look at
what you can apply to make it different
so for scale and I've talked about this
one I believe before and I've done some
short form videos on it this is
something that Brands like Jacamo use
all the time you see them use scale
inside their social media content they
make really big objects and that is just
a technique that is attention grabbing
on camera but then something really
small by virtue is almost the same can
you make the really cute version of
something that exists already and after
scale comes aesthetic so for instance if
your brand is a really strong aesthetic
and if you have a creative Direction
angle to your brand you probably want to
develop that aesthetic ahead of time and
by aesthetic I mean Western Gothic a
commonly known visual theme that ties
all your things together you can apply
that aesthetic lens to any referencer
idea you can take a photo from a famous
campaign and be like hey let's do take
the Western angle let's take our
aesthetic approach to this can we do the
same setup but within our world of being
built can we do it if it's Gothic brand
like it's in all black has these fonts
and these treatments but it's this
concept we put on our mood board so
applying your aesthetic can become the
toolkit and this is different from the
idea of beauty which I'll get to now
where you take any existing idea and you
drive it up a notch by saying how do we
make it as aesthetically pleasing as
humanly possible this is an angle I'm
going to unbox some luggage here in a
minute that a brand I really enjoy took
with one of their products and use it as
an example and then we have the idea of
Transportation it's not the best word
for it but you'll understand the concept
when I break it down how can you take a
reference or take an idea and put it in
a completely foreign place this idea of
having a runway show in the Mojave
Desert or showing off a car on a glacier
these are things you see commonly in
advertised things will be almost in a
completely surreal environment and by
moving what's expected into somewhere
unexpected you immediately Engage The
viewers mind they know something's not
quite right and they're intrigued and
then one of my favorite is is this idea
of clashing how do you take two ideas
and hit them together as hard even if
they don't quite work there's something
happening and this works great if you
have a bunch of references on your mood
board and you say I'm going to combine
two things to make something completely
new where you can take an angle or a
composition of something you love from
one photo or one video set but then
combine it with a specific look or feel
or setting or setup that you have
somewhere else that brings it into this
new thing this is one of the easiest
ones for people to digest when you do
build these big mood boards you can go
here's all the things we like how do we
not just copy them okay let's take X
from this one let's take y from this one
and then really ask yourself does that
stand out and we'll talk a bit about
that line in some of the examples I'm
going to walk through and then we have
tension how can you apply an emotion
that makes people feel a little bit odd
to any anything that you're Crea shame
fear anger ego and I'm not saying this
is the most moral way to go about them
if someone looks at something and they
feel bad about themselves then you are
creating a feeling if someone looks at
it and they feel great they feel
supported in their beliefs even if they
may feel weird about their beliefs
something that they've had tucked away
it's applying their ego that's an idea
fear obviously a big component in
marketing and any home security system
how can you make them feel that inside
any campaign or anything that you do all
these are tools that you have to take
the ordinary and make them extraordinary
and the more them you understand and
list out and begin to experiment with
and try the farther you go inside
whatever you're putting together so on
that note I'm actually talk through a
few products and just give a few
examples and I'm going to dive into some
figma boards and show some work so first
I want to talk about this semi viral Dre
van noton fragrance set the card that
they have inside they these gorgeous
luxury per and it is somewhat viral
because I ripped this one up so I'm
holding it patched together a bit they
have this fragrance kit that just looks
extremely be it's a set it has that
unique social friendly looking feel and
you see all these color patterns running
behind it what I want to call out here
is that this is a pretty pretty much a
normal perfume sampler to seen a
thousand like it maybe a slight
alternative of Capper variety and when I
rip open this packaging you see that the
only thing that's behind it is a literal
gloss print card and it's getting this
effective presentation so this is one I
love to call out as an example because
they're using the beauty angle they said
Hey how do you take a normal fragrance
sampler how do you make it something
aesthetically pleasing but also everyone
talks about what is the cost and
obviously there's a ton of cost involved
in any ornate perfume packaging a huge
part of that industry this is a literal
paper box die cut to fit these in there
with a another piece of printed paper
like literally printed behind it with a
color pattern on it this is not an
expensive piece of packaging for this
set especially for what they charge with
it and then all this set just basically
being a down sell to get you to then go
buy the $230 bottle this is just created
with intention someone said how do we
take this and apply Beauty to it and
then found a way to do that all right so
next up we are going to be unboxing some
luggage this is from July they are an
Australian luggage brand they sell in
the US their claim to fame is
truck they sell all kinds of regular
luggage for people like the TRS but I
don't know if y'all have seen that uh
there's the meme of what's his name the
guy from 30 Seconds to Mars Jared Le and
he's at a Gucci runway show and he sees
someone walk by in the outfit and his
like Jaw is dropped down and then he's
wearing the outfit like 3 months later
that was me with this suitcase because
I've begun to look at things like all
right I can have any standard thing I
can have a raoa I can have things that
look a certain way but when you're
making content you begin to think about
what's going to help a video Hit what
are all those little things that could
even just the ownership of it could
potentially make anyone hang on for an
extra half a second in a video what can
make a photo pop and then when you're in
a category that's as old as luggage and
as competitive where there's a 100
brands if you follow me on Instagram you
know I do a series called Product versus
brand where I talk about luggage Brands
and break them down and there's a 100
luggage Brands many of which are
mediocre and so July had a standout form
factor but they also then applied a
standout aesthetic so this is a gloss
trunk trunk in a normal carry-on size
but the gloss impact of this and when I
saw in the ad I had that same effect of
like ooh like what about that in
multiple colors it's just an aesthetic
choice that no one else is doing
everything you see out there is Matt is
subtle this is decidedly unsettle really
stand out has a number of colors if you
don't want to go full Supreme red I got
the green one as well that's like an
emerald green but they're saying hey
we're going to take the beauty angle in
product with a simple technique that
just stands out in the market it
positions against everyone's subtle base
colors and goes that is super bright
while still incorporating their
trademark trunk Style so it already has
an aesthetic difference that the brand
has with this beauty angle applied on
top and even if you they offer this in
your regular matte colors too if this is
too much which will be for a ton of
people then the downsell is it's getting
people to look at the mat options they
present them side by side in the
advertisement with they kind of natural
contrast and a little an option based
for your personality type so then next
up you may have seen I've been wearing
these online a bit this is a sample for
my valuables brand for 2025 it's a set
of baggy cargo pants that we are doing
in this super unique textured fa that
you've probably seen in my videos so
I've been thinking about content I'm
going to do for that I'll bring this up
inside the the figma that we're going to
show in a minute but it's like all right
how do I make content around samples for
my brand because I've noticed as I've
been running this brand that I need to
be building more hype for the products
before they come out I've never been a
big like hype up the drop person I like
to put things out and then sell them but
as a social media Creator and thinking
more from that angle as thinking from a
brand perspective I need to story tell
better and so part of what I wanted to
do for all the new things I'm creating
is document the sample Journey more so
then my thought is how do I cretive
direct that cuz I can sit here here and
be like I'm or this is the sample I made
it's this and it's this and it's this
how do I apply an interesting angle to
that and so you'll see we came up with
this idea uh two ideas really where
we're going to make like almost like a
carousel that documents the process of
it that's presented in our in a very
aesthetic way and then a video that goes
with that in a complimentary aesthetic
where it builds like an archive
basically where I am instead of just
talking through the sample I'm talking
through an archive I'm going valuable
sample 2025 003 the blank blank blank
it's doing to this it's in this status
and then we're you know these are the
changes that are going to be made before
it goes like live and like kind of and
then having as a record and then having
a directory of all these things as they
come alive and then doing that in a
carousel format in a video format and
seeing what works but that's me taking a
common idea and then applying just a
visual concept on top of it that matches
the aesthetic of my brand and then the
the last thing I'm going to talk about
before we get into some screen sharing
is this sample which I haven't even
opened which is from shift Global who
are producing a back FR and this is
going to be a conversation about
creative Direction technique this is
where just showing the frame of mind
that goes into so there's two types of
products right you can make a product
just that looks One Way Or you make a
product that has some sort of
interesting function and then obviously
in the best world you do both so far in
the products I've created I've just done
a lot of things t-shirts with cool
designs on them they're elevated in
various ways but I also want to make
things I think have the potential to be
more important more interesting in
someone's workflow so this is a vintage
duffel bag that that shift has sampled
they did the design with me they did all
the technicals and stuff they're
excellent at it we worked on Concepts
together you'll notice the important
thing about this product is this right
here the zipper angle so this
idea is that we are able to use this to
put a full pair of shoes in and not
touch anything else in the bag that's
what we're going to test out in the
sample said hey if you want to carry
shoes in your bag we now have a whole
section of this and you have a really
nice luxury carry all you can carry
around with this unique vintage feel you
can see what we did with this leather
here which is excellent like in these
straps custom zippers a valuable tag to
make something really interesting
obviously these on the bottom but that's
making a user choice plus the visual
aesthetic we have of the brand so
whenever I go to create anything you
really want to think through like what
is that user journey of it how can we
make this really applicable I know that
the majority of dudes are just throwing
shoes in their bag and that's probably
not the best decision let's give them an
easy way to do that let's also make
something so super social media friendly
where anyone that owns this they want to
make a video and unzip this and pull
their shoes out they have something
unique and then I'll tease this in a
minute to we're looking at like over the
shoulder bag that fits a full laptop
inside there as well that's our quick
product unbox pop onto the computer all
right CH let's actually dive into some
workflow here so for my brand I do a lot
of graphics with an agency called dark
room they have a service called Dark Art
that I have a designer through it's a
couple thousand bucks a month but the
biggest thing they have and the reason I
use them is their designers have taste
and are like trained appropriately to
their standards and they do ads for like
all these brands that that you would
know we'll dive a bit into the actual
workflow here so here you'll see this is
a notion where we actually create the
stuff that we so there's an in progress
folder these are stuff we're working on
now there's a completed an archive
folder every time I want to make
something new inside of this in notion
make a new page populate a potential due
date what style request it is what the
number of assets that I need are Etc and
I fill in a brief so for instance this
is a brief type this one I just put in
for these sample videos a brief title
the add type the purpose number of
assets the ratios links to the content
they're going to use and any other info
and then a bunch of the reference so
then that gets put into the pipeline for
people to work on and so I'll call out
that this is basically the format that
you need if you're communicating with
somebody you need a way to give them a
brief has all the things that they need
to know that you can then add lines to
based on your workflow this is the one I
have with these guys through notion the
last uh brand I was at was I was the
svpm marketing I had about an eight
person team doing this kind of stuff we
did it in clickup there was an intake
form there's a form that would go in and
we get ided to designers cues and we had
a view of where everything was everyone
could look at and people from other
departments could request those assets I
could approve whether it would be done
or not and we could work through things
like that and we could put our own in
there and everyone put their tasks in
there as well so we could see one
holistic system you can do that notion
you can do that in Click up you can do
that in the day I prefer notion for a
number of reasons I have a lot of other
workflow in here Etc but I would
basically include the title of the brief
the creative type what the ask is number
of assets you need where it's going the
ratios the exact content people people
make sure they put the links and stuff
in any references they have this is
creative brief 101 and so there's a more
nuanced like you know interesting stuff
you can do when you really get into it
but like that's the core that but with
that comes references and how you do
refer I'm going to pop over here to
Pinterest so I have a shared Pinterest
board with the designers on the proess
we're looking at references of things
that we want to try we think are
interesting it's like okay how could we
pull something like this together like
all these different ads like for
instance you'll see when I open up the
emails we actually did something like
this but a magazine I have a lot of
white background assets this is just
looking at different ways you could use
them and deploy them we have a bunch of
these in here for conversation at all
times if you saw my video the other week
um where I was showing how I use artless
stuff um this is kind of example
reference I've used for video but it's
important to keep these and use them
both ways because I brief the designers
to work on specific design but I also
brief photographers whenever we're doing
a shoot so this reference is something
the designer put in there he wants to do
something like this when I go to make
the brief for the next photo shoot for
shoes I'm going to put this in there and
be like hey please capture every angle I
would need to get this kind of photo or
to do this kind of design he's going to
get their angles they may put their own
twist on it may have a conversation
about it but then that will go over the
designer and they'll have the assets
they need this kind of flow is really
important to keep the conversation going
and then if you get in a real workflow
where your designer and your photo folks
Etc and you are all on the same board
and you can really start to cook but
it's also totally fine to keep it like I
have my photo team and I have the design
team kind of separate and you can see we
do a lot of print ads and print ad
Styles and so we have a lot of those
kind of variants in here different
things we look at you'll see we have
something based on this is a piece of
creative we're working on now you need
to have a place that you can go to
whenever you want something new and you
don't have an idea let's actually go
through and talk to some of those
references and you can look at at and
you can say all right how do we make
this kind of unique to us right how do
we apply our brand kit to it how do we
apply those principles I mentioned
before about tension or scale how do we
just use those visuals in our own so
after briefs are in after references are
pulled then we're going over into the
actual design so for instance this is a
email segment in here we have our email
kit so this what I mean by a basis or a
kit is this is all the things we use for
emails the fonts we use this is the
sizes this is the buttons this is the
styles that we use all easily
referenceable so if we decide to change
them we can change them in one place and
update and you'll see like that book I
just mentioned we're using like a m
Magazine version of that here this is
more interesting than like a default
product photo like this to have it be
like a magazine shot with some of the
sketches I have so this is how we kind
of take that idea and apply it into our
own brand and what we're creating and
the designer will be able to look at and
say hey I pulled this from this
reference like sometimes I'll include a
reference in the brief sometimes I'll
just be like whatever ideas you have and
they'll go back to those shared boards
and pull things with their own
inspiration that they know we've agreed
on and you'll see how those emails will
come alive you similar you saw this
other graphic treatments in there we've
applied our own styles to this so let's
talk about stuff that's in process so
for instance I want to make those sample
character cells I mentioned before I
dropped in a bunch of kind of options
and variants and Graphics was like Hey I
want to think about this and we we
jumped into a process for it where I
said hey I want to instead of just
having a picture of a sample I throw on
some concrete let's make something let's
so we took some of these sticker
Graphics something that we kind of
worked on prior something we created for
the brands we have some elements we
could use on different things okay like
hey how can we throw that in let's list
out some key items for it let's design a
timeline of where the product is at in
like the design and creation stage we
can then call do a call out for on where
it is potential graphic treatments these
like kind of C pieces here we're pulling
something together live from this idea
of like how do we make a more
interesting sample Carousel another one
you'll see this complex con invite that
we did pull up that brief so this was
one where I saw this graphic which I'm
pretty sure is like AI or whatever I was
like cool this would be actually
interesting back to like that
Transportation idea like let's put a
real person inside because I have a
model shot in a very similar pose and
let's actually put the clothing items in
there so I listed out he let's put the
cap let's put the sneakers let's put the
bag we actually have all of our stickers
like I mentioned before and so we
created this as the invite and it's like
boom the person's in there so it's
immediately like different kind of
intriguing and people like oh you're
making an action figure and then I have
all these items that are in there we
have the stickers and that became the
invite for the event but then taking it
a step further into like the scale
concept I mentioned earlier is like one
of these comments here is me being like
how big could this go because I'm
thinking hey maybe we put this as a 10t
print out like on the booth let's apply
scale to this idea cuz people really
liked it or maybe I could get like a
plastic blister pack thing like this and
it could actually be a photo opportunity
like that's where you begin to get that
process going where you have that
toolkit and say oh could I make a really
big version of this for future events or
hey people like this what else can we do
and incorporate from it and you begin to
see everything from hey those sticker
designs make it into everything to hey
maybe we use this action figure concept
you place it somewhere else in there you
begin to build a bit of a world and
another kind of thing to think about
here is ADS like if you are running ads
you need ton of them I'm putting new
stuff into ASC uh all the time on meta
and one of the things I saw another
YouTuber you may know um Dar or Dara I'm
not sure I've met her in person but um
she makes YouTube about about ads and
Facebook ads and she had a a real like
hey you be try and call out ads and so I
was like cool I put that reel as the
brief and was like and I put the call
outs for a bunch of my products in there
and they tried it out with some
different styles like this color range
that we have that we've had before we
did these kind of like almost like
vintage ad like oversized style as well
um again with our our kind of background
in these different sizes you can see how
this ties to some of the other similar
stuff that we have and then this kind of
newer looking feel here for these and
that's stuff that I'm immedately going
to test and I'm going to drop into the
Facebook campaigns but you have to have
that flow of like we need new ads we
need new Concepts so if I see a video
I'm popping it in as a brief if I see
something on Pinterest or Arena or
whatever I'm saving it in the shared
folder and I'm using that for a brief
whenever we have it but build up your
references put a ton of stuff into
briefs you get it you test it based on
what works you do more these call out
ads work then we'll try new visual
Styles we'll try new products we'll
build this out as you can see it's
already got a bunch of options but we'll
add more into what you know we can
actually put together but this is the
idea of briefing in workflow and
revisions and application that is the
basics of applying intention and
direction to what you're creating and
the same exact thing works with when
you're creating content you're creating
reals or whatever when you're in product
devel when you're in design development
when you in UI it's just a good example
that I have that I'm allowed to show so
anyway hope you found that interesting
this is kind of the 101 version of
creative Direction and how to do briefs
I'm going to do a more advanced version
of this I'm thinking of doing that with
a guest and someone who like lives and
breathes inside briefing um that
probably doing the new year and I'm
definitely have more creative Direction
videos one of the ones I'm working on
putting together is actually pulling a
bunch of like different creative
directors their portfolios and their
work to like just show through a big
archive the way I did that like 100 Art
Direction references video um I did just
do an art Direction 101 video like the
other week it's easy to hunt down it's
very similar probably link it here at
the end um that just thinks about that
perspective but I'm trying to make sure
as many of y'all as possible just get
that basics of like there's no schools
that teach this right uh you basically
learn on the job or you don't like all
right how does the briefing process work
how do I use references what are
techniques I can do what is a real life
workflow um and to show as much of that
as possible so I appreciate youall
watching um my hyper newsletter mail.
hyper studios. us talks about brand
strategy and creative direction if you
want to sign up for that I have a bunch
of products for sale valuable
studios.com um as always like And
subscribe and appreciate appreciate
y'all so much