There's an entire cultural conversation
now around the idea of having taste.
Tech firms are desperate to integrate
people into their creative departments
who are tasteful. A new generation is
exposed to more and more online and
learning how to decipher it. And
contrary to popular belief, developing
taste is easy. And in this video, we're
going to talk about how to find your
taste. Because while it is easy, it is
not innate. It is completely learned and
it is a lifelong journey, but one you
can really enjoy. All it takes to
improve, find it for yourself, is just
the start. In this video, we're going to
talk about the foundations of taste,
frameworks for finding your own,
learning how to critique and decide if
things are good and bad in the society
that's taught us not to. We're going to
talk about how your taste is reflected
in your decisions, how to really find
your taste in the real world, and the
progression of establishing taste over
time. I'm excited for it. Hope you all
enjoy the ride. [ __ ] it. But we're in
this time where tech in particular has
discovered taste and finally has some
value in it. Before it was almost a
counter signaler to have any care about
anything in the world except a
technological goal. But now in a world
that's more visual than ever, where
people have more standards than ever and
where content is educating them more
than ever, taste is ultra important. We
see everything from claw positioning its
entire brand in the AI space based on
taste doing their pop-ups to large
acclaim. Now, exposing a tech world to
marketing the rest of us have seen for
decades to financial brands like what
Quarter has done where they've applied
interesting visuals and the basics of
creative direction to create something
tasteful and unique that better reflects
their product and helps differentiate it
from the old guard. But how do you
actually learn it? I want to talk about
the foundation. There are two levels to
the foundation. One is the concepts of
human perception and then second is the
foundational knowledge of what's been
established through history. And these
both play a role with each other. But
we're going to break all the
fundamentals of taste into a couple core
categories. Visual, audio, and
experience in particular. And then in
categories like books, fashion, and
music. But it's important to talk about
the visual nature of things because this
is a framework from which taste starts.
So if you have ever been into
photography, you've heard of the rule of
thirds. I'm going to use this as an
example as there are a number of
basically immutable laws that are around
us that help determine if we like
something whether we know it or not. The
composition of a photo, the grid system
which controls typography and the
layouts of how anything visual we see,
whether we find it appealing or not,
whether it just feels wrong or feels
unprofessional or just resonates without
even knowing. And these have been
quantified over time. You look at books
like Cheeko's The New Typography. You
look at Swiss poster design. If you look
at all the best photos, they're
award-winning over time. They follow a
set of loose rules where things that
abide by them naturally look good. The
same thing goes for color. There are
certain colors that are more appealing
to the human eye. They make us feel
certain ways. It's ingrained into our
nature. And there will always be
outliers or disagreement. But the
fundamentals of whether something is
good or not often come from how it is
enjoyed. And if you want a foundation to
begin to understand what is tasteful and
not develop your own opinions about
this, you need to get a layer of this
from which you can engage basically an
educational layer. We'll call it the
foundations. So if you take books, you
take fashion and you take music.
Throughout history, there are a number
of popular objectively tasteful things
in all of those categories. And
developing a foundational knowledge of
it, of knowing what they are, knowing
why it was popular, you begin to build
out a framework and a groundwork for
yourself. Starting with design, if we
put the four categories up there,
design, literature, music, fashion.
Design is fundamental for understanding
taste because a lot of this has been
covered. A lot of people have spent a
lot of time achieving different looks
and feels that help us decipher the
world around us that almost all visual
patterns and styles we see fall into. My
first real introduction to this was when
I was in college and I took graphic
design and I had intro to graphic design
class and the textbook that we had was
Meg's history of graphic design which
you can just buy. But why this was
important is that over the course of a
year of doing this 101 class, we're
exposed to all the different periods of
design. And so if you go to that book
and you can skip the Sumerian texts and
the history of the first of the
Gutenberg press and all that, you can
start with the key periods. You can look
at defining visuals. Look at RCOO and
Baroque, the styles of the ornate
medieval era. Look at art noo and the
illustration that came from it. And then
really look at in the 20th century the
visuals that defined the world we're in
now. art deco, bow house, experimental
things like the Memphis movement, Swiss
design, Fruter arrow. If you look in a
book like this and you go through these
different design periods, you're gonna
have a fundamental understanding of what
looks good and doesn't. And you're going
to have a vernacular with which you can
understand the visuals that you're
presented with. And same thing in
classic literature, classic music,
classic fashion, if you want to have a
foundation, once a week, I want you to
do one thing from one of those
categories. Understand a new period of
design. have a new classic album,
whether it's from classical music or the
Beatles or Jimmyi Hendris or whatever it
is you've heard of or you can find or a
top thing, a prolific book, and engage
with it. And what we're going to do is
we're going to enter in our second
category, the framework. And as you're
looking to uplevel your taste, one thing
that is definitely worth focusing on is
upleveling your writing. If you've ever
wanted to improve your writing for
content of all kinds, from newsletters
to LinkedIn to videos, then I recommend
you check out this free resource called
20 ways to craft irresistible content
from HubSpot and my guy Samar. This
guide has 20 battle tested writing tips
you can apply to hook readers and make
better content. It covers everything
from finding ideas and writing headlines
to editing techniques and the copy work
exercise that the pros use to sharpen
their skills. My favorite part is the
storytelling techniques section. They
break down proven patterns for writing
and how to hook people and keep them
engaged throughout your content, whether
written or video. Whether you're writing
a newsletter, LinkedIn post, or a video
script like I do, these techniques help
you structure your content so people
actually hang around to finish it. If
you want to rise above the written AI
sludge that we're seeing on all
platforms and sharpen your writing
skills, you can get this free guide at
the link in the description. And thanks
so much to HubSpot for sponsoring this
video. When you engage with these
things, the objectively tasteful, the
things that exist in the world that we
as a as humanity have decided were
interesting and good, you need to begin
to think about how you feel about it.
What is your opinion of it? So, first
ask yourself, why was this appreciated?
Why do people like it? Why do they think
it's a classic? Be able to articulate
that? And then think about, do you
appreciate it? Do you like it? And do
you agree? And why? Or do you not like
it and why? And you'll find that your
discovery becomes interesting. Instead
of going and listening to whatever the
latest album is that comes up on your
Spotify, you're diving into some of the
classics that exist, the originations of
whatever genre you like, the earliest of
house music. Begin to put into context
all the things around you. And when you
start to ask those questions, why do
people like this and appreciate it? Why
do I like it and appreciate it? You open
yourself up to the world of taste. And
it's easy for the rest of your life when
you're making those decisions. You're
picking picking what you do before
sleep. Are you going to scroll your
phone or you going to read a book? Are
you going to pick the same music you
always listen to and it's on auto or you
going to choose a classic album? When
you go to buy a new item of clothing,
are you going to look at what McQueen
did in that category and do some
research about it and watch a YouTube
video first or just get the same thing
from Zara? But if you start making those
decisions and thinking about it, you're
building the foundation of taste. And
this framework leads you into the
ability to have critique to see anything
and based on the body of knowledge you
have of what is people consider good and
what you think about it, is it good or
bad? And a matrix with which to look at
this is composition, effectivity, and
vibes. Anything that you engage with any
whether it's choosing, do you like this
couch? Do you like this song? Do you
like this thing? You think of it from
your perspective. How is it put
together? When you begin to objectively
think about, is this quarterzip better
than that quarterzip? What is its
composition? Is it wellmade? Does the
material feel good? Does it feel cheap
or expensive? Was it handmade or
machine-made? beginning to get in these
questions around the composition of a
thing just as much as if you hear a
piece of music that sounds well produced
or has layers to it or makes you feel in
a certain way. Everything starts with
this composition. Even when you read
literature, does its pros resonate with
you? Does it have that level of quality?
And it's not the end all, but it's a
thing to think about inside your
critique. And then the effectivity. Does
it actually work? Does the quarter zip
look good on me? Does it keep me warm?
Do I like the music? Does it make people
want to dance? Do they enjoy it? Do they
feel emotion from it? And then we have
the vibes meter, the intangible. Do you
just like it? Does it have something
special to it? Is it unique? Because
things can be well composed, can make
you feel something, but they're just
missing that last segment. And the three
of those things together form the basis
of how you can critique something.
Whether it's excellent, whether it needs
work, and in which area it needs work
in. Hey, everything's right, but the
vibes are off. Hey, the vibes are
amazing, but it's not actually well done
in any way, shape, or form. These are
all levels that exist. You can describe
almost any piece of writing, music, or
design underneath and begin to
understand why you like it or not. And
being able to do that critique is really
important so you can actually articulate
what's good and bad. But then the
difference between someone who's
beginning to understand taste and
understand the world around them and
someone who is tasteful comes into your
decisions. Do you live your taste? And
really every single decision you make
from the goods that are in your house to
the clothes that you wear to what you
choose to eat to the topics you choose
to discuss with other people is all a
basically game of give and take of are
you letting this decision be driven by
your sense of taste or are you giving in
in some regard? And this is where you
begin to really think critically about
everything you engage in. You start to
realize that, hey, you know, I'm
sacrificing a certain level of quality
in the clothes that I buy because I've
always wanted to have an outfit where I
could have or a closet where I could
have all these outfits. But really in
reality, if I want to make the tasteful
choice, if I want to make objective,
it's the right choice. I would be
getting longerlasting, more classic
things and less of them. And there's a
big difference between knowing you
should do it and acting on it. and you
begin to be considered a tasteful
person. Begin to live that taste and
better understand those items when you
make that decision. When you say it's
actually worth it for me to not get the
dopamine from all the little purchases
I'm going to save for the one good thing
or I'm going to think really critically
about my decisions. People ask a lot
about the product versus brand series
that I do and why we know so much about
blenders or leather or knives or
whatever it is. And it's because I
intimately am interested in making the
best choice and knowing about it and
caring about it. And I rather spend
hours asking friends and looking at what
best knife I'm going to do if I'm going
to spend $200 on it than not. I'm
consumed with that idea and consumed
with the understanding of things are
good or bad. And it's gone into my
career as someone who's done product
development, who does marketing, who
makes content about things. It's worth
it for me to understand it. And I want
to have as large of a framework about as
many things as I humanly can. And I want
to be able to argue about it and
critique it and give an opinion on it.
It's become really important inside my
life. also led me over time to get
hundreds of millions of views for people
looking to me for my opinion. And the
best exercise for this is spending more
time in thrift. If you were able to go
into a thrift store and put a complete
outfit together that looked good and
would be completely relevant, you're
doing that through taste, not through
buying the answer. Anyone can go spend
top dollar to buy something that will
look amazing. Can you based on only the
things that you know in your mind about
how fashion should be your feel of
composition effectivity like we talked
about before go into an environment
that's essentially chaos where
everything is been devalued and put
something together for cheap and once
you start doing that same thing with how
you compose your home you're able to
save yourself a significant amount of
money and then you're also able to have
that exercise of remove the labels from
it remove the designer names remove
who's recommending it and let me put
something together based on my style.
It's a great exercise to do. Go actually
put that outfit together for the
weekend. go furnish the new apartment,
whatever it is. And then that's the end
of the foundation. Then there's a next
layer to this. Once it's absorbed in
your life, you begin thinking about it.
You begin trying things on it. You will
begin to notice you think critically
about everything around you. You become
more valuable at work. You understand
more of the world. You have a better eye
for things. Will respect you more
naturally. But to get really good at it,
you have to defend it. Real taste has
stakes. Between work content, if you
make it, and your friends, you begin to
know when you have taste and it's
defendable cuz people are going to ask
you. They're going to be like, "That guy
has great outfits. That person's always
had an interesting thing to say. What do
they think about X?" You'll begin to
know you have it when people come to you
for it. But if you want to get really
good at it, you want to actually feel
comfortable in it. You can't just have
that innately. You need to put your
opinions out there for others to judge.
And then to have those conversations.
And I have those conversations a lot
with friends. I have opinions on things
and I want their opinions on them. And I
want to go back and forth on them.
Whether that's what coffee machine they
chose to get or how they feel about
whatever album or a piece of content on
social media or an idea. It's an
important part of discourse and how you
can engage and have real conversations
with a lot of people that aren't just
about current events. But I would
encourage you if you really want to get
those opinions formed to put them out
there in some way. Whe that's the
written word, whether that's making
content, whether that's a lot of
aggressive conversations with real
people, you have to be able to defend
those things until you're able to
articulate that matrix we had before
about something's composition, how
effective it is and its vibes and be
able to go back and forth with someone
and help convince them into your point
of view or be able to accept that, hey,
actually, I need to change my framework
that elevates you to another level of
understanding. That's why people who
work in certain industries where
everything is one of those decisions and
there's conversation around it. If you
work deep inside fashion, you're going
to have a different regard for what
fashion is than if you're just a
consumer. You begin to get into these
frameworks. And then there comes
experience. You can only get so far from
the world that you're in. A lot comes
from traveling all around. I learned an
awful lot in the time I've spent in
China about how things are made and put
together and the quality of them and
what to respect and not. That's changed
my opinions a lot on everything from
electronics to material. The more you
experience in the world and the more you
engage in, look at it from that level.
Like whenever I go to a country when we
were in Italy over the summer, I want to
only listen to the music that was
popular then in Italy and popular the
last few years and immerse myself in
what's considered good there and what
people like and how it's made. And I
learned a lot and got engaged in a lot
of interesting things in the process.
Same thing when you go look at what are
the coffee shops to attend to, what are
the clothing brands people are wearing.
You can begin to actually learn a lot
about what that looks like globally and
it will shape your opinion. You can only
get that through experience and that
comes in time. And then to end, this is
a progression. This is a lifelong
experience. Like the title of this video
says, having taste is actually easy. To
begin to look at things from this lens
and decide what you like or not and
build a foundation around it, any person
can do. Now, becoming amazing at it is a
lifelong journey. Is a thing that's
going to change constantly. But it's
about having that curious mind state
about talking about ideas instead of
other people or about other events.
About thinking about every decision you
make critically and acting on it in your
life. It's going to be something that
carries with you forever. And it can you
can start whether you start when you're
50 or you start when you're 12. It
doesn't matter. It just matters if it
keeps going and progressing over time
and that you learn and you'll find where
you want your lines to be. It's going to
be different for every person. The
important part is you think about it
critically and can articulate it and
that you care. As I mentioned before, I
will be on tour in the new year. You can
check out the dates of where we're going
to be live. Down below in the
description, I have a webinar coming up.
It is around January 13th on creative
strategy in the new year. If you want to
apply principles of taste to work for
organic and paid content, we're going to
talk a lot about that. Just have a big
community call where we have discussions
about what happens in this space. I am
gearing up to release another video
about the new year and working your plan
for the new year looks like. So, you
expect [music] that coming soon. And I
appreciate y'all so much for watching.