Don't start a personal brand. Do this
instead. This idea that personal brand
as we know it to where say, "Hey, I'm
just going to start posting online and
like telling my story." We've been told
that for months, years by every
conceivable personality online that this
has an advantage, and it does, but is
more and more saturated by the day. And
I'm going to talk to you about how to
stand out. In this video, I'm going to
break down the secrets that every
creator should be thinking about that
takes their content from normal to
something special. I'm going to talk
about the new format I think everyone
should be looking at instead of just
kicking into personal brand content. and
then how to think about and act on this
for yourself. Let's lock in. So, as many
of you know, I've teach creators and
brands how to make content. 1,200 plus
people through our cut 30 program at
this point. I've learned a lot from
that. What makes good personal brand
content and what doesn't. And we also
see shifts from a year ago when we
started doing it. Content is very
different than where it was. And one
thing that has stood out is that just
talking about something now, just
saying, "Hey, I'm going to talk about
what's cool in my niche or I'm going to
break down things that happened or I'm
going to talk about what I'm working
on." It can still work, but it's harder
than ever. But when you start to break
down the big creators, who breaks out,
what do they do? There is something that
they all share in common. It's what we
refer to in Cut 30 as a format. A format
has a few parts that are ultra crucial,
and I'm going to break them all down.
So, when you think of a format, think of
a repeatable thing. When it shows up on
your feed, it looks the same, feels the
same, compelling, and draws you in. Now,
I'm going to start with an example from
some of the biggest creators out there
because there's a through line as to why
they work. So, first we'll look at Nara
Smith. You've probably seen her on your
feed. She's likely making a zen from
scratch. In her videos, there's a couple
through lines that are super important
and crucial to this idea of a format.
One, she's doing a thing in every single
one of these videos. So, she's actually
making something from scratch. I made a
joke about it being a zen, but she's
making a pineapple upside down cake or a
whatever for her children from nothing
through the video. So, you watch from
start to completion an action happen.
And this is really crucial because a lot
of good creators stand out because you
watch something happen completely. And
there's smaller examples of this, too,
but food is often a through line. or
someone like date night kitchen who's
kind of walking through what you can
make for a date each time, but you are
watching something completed front to
end. This gives people an incentive and
a reason to stay and an expectation
they're watching something completely.
That's an important thing to think
about. That's not where it ends. Also,
she is presenting herself in a certain
way each time. She wears couture while
she's doing this. It stands out on
camera. You've probably seen hundreds of
videos of me in strange hoodies on my
short form, right? I actually don't wear
a lot of hoodies dayto-day, but I wear
them all my videos because I know it is
a repeatable thing. I knew I could get
my hands on a lot of them that helped my
videos stand out. People recognize me on
the feed. People stop, maybe leave a
comment. She can now afford to be doing
this in Jean Paulier. I cannot, but that
is a big core of how her videos stand
out. Is this thing is being completed
while you see her presented in a certain
way. Also, the framing is unique, well
lit, and also the same each time. You'll
notice she's a little set back.
Nothing's too big on cam, but is
repeated and basically the same each
way. This is the fundamentals of a
format. And where I think most people
fall flat is you can frame your thing a
certain way, wear something a certain
way, but you also need this idea of a
completed action. Let me rock another
example. So, a creator I know, Thorne
Bradley, you may have seen him. He's a
guy who chops wood online. If you look
at this in a certain way, you see the
same basically principles in action.
He's chopping wood in most videos.
You're going to see him with an axe
physically taking down a tree or
attempting to do that. So, you realize
that at some point in the video, an axe
is going to be swung and people will
stick around for it. Same thing with
presentation. He is a good-looking guy.
He presents himself in some relatively
thoughty ways to appeal to a certain
demographic and that works really well
for him, right? He's singing about that
same presentation, but he's using this
as a vehicle to talk about anything. His
content, he talks about politics, he
talks about interpersonal relationships,
he reviews axes, he can hit anything
that he wants to within his zone. And
really, he's looking at topics that he
wants to talk about through this lens of
I'm completing this action in this same
setting, like with this really specific
look. One of my favorite creators, Ken
from Front Office, he does this
similarly as well. He's always sitting
at his desk. He's a little bit back.
There's a book you can kind of barely
see in front of him. And he's breaking
down fashion, but he does it again in a
specific way. He will say, "One jacket,
three ways, one track pant, three ways,
and then he walks through three
different examples, different people
executing an item with a different
vision." So, you know, I'm going to see
three examples. I'm going to walk
through all three of these and they're
going to be different. And it gives you
a reason and a format to stay to the
end. This brings us back to the
beginning and my clickbait title of this
video. Don't start a personal brand. Do
this instead. And you need to think
about creating a series. Whenever I talk
to anybody now is creating a personal
brand, wants to make a video online,
wants to look at how they're going to
present themselves, creating a series
and treating it like television is the
way to do it. I'm going to walk through
how that works. So, first you need your
core skill set, right? I wouldn't be
saying, "Hey, this is the first thing
you should ever think about. You need to
learn how to make your carousels, learn
how to cut videos, learn how to talk on
camera. You may make some content
beforehand, do your normal stuff." But
your real goal is to get to your format,
get to a series. And some of my favorite
creators, like I think Ken posts like
once a week. Caro creates another great
like vlogger. she posts once a week,
maybe twice with a carousel. It does not
have to be a daily task when you treat
it like this. It needs to be a slightly
better, more thought out, higher
production thing done less frequently.
That gives people the reason that is to
tune in. It's basically, hey, every
Thursday, I know I'm going to see a
clothing broken down three ways, I'm
going to see a vlog about this woman
putting her studio together, or I'm
going to see someone make their
gluten-free cupcakes in this really
particular way, but with this through
line, a very similar set, a very similar
graphics package. package. Another one I
like to call for this is shift fashion
group where they they tear open clothes
their kind of main marketing for their
production firm and they'll talk about
how it's made. Same graphics package,
same setup, same format every time. It
is a TV series as social media. So now
you're looking at, okay, who who am I?
I'm a I'm a realtor. I own a coffee
shop. I'm a marketer. I'm a designer.
Whatever your kind of job or role is,
and this could be services, this can be
software, whatever it is. What is my TV
show format? There's a couple ways to
look at this. You know, find your
industry and your skill focus. And then
just go look at old television. This is
the number one, two, and three way to do
this. What were MTV shows that were
running in the 1990s and 2000s? Redo it.
TRL, redo it. Pawn Stars, whatever that
is. Look at these formats. Someone
behind a counter talking about
something's worth and something new
comes in all the time and they bring in
an expert. That's a format. Speed dating
where you work through a couple people
and people get evaluated really fast.
That's a format. And how do you then
apply that? It's like, hey, can I do
next, but it's coffee shops in Seattle
where I'm a realtor. Can I do pawn
stars, but people are bringing me
properties to evaluate if it's worth the
price or not? Find those same formats
and apply it to your niche. And I think
that's where people overthink it. Like,
how can I make cool content? I have a
I'm a chiropractor. What are these
techniques? What are the other how do I
find the same thing where I'm gonna
actually show it and do it and make it
as a series. And if you look at it like
that and you say, "My goal as a personal
brand is I'm I'm not going to launch a
personal brand. I'm going to launch a
series where I am the main character. I
do it once a week. Publishes at the same
exact time. I create something
interesting there." You are now standing
out from the noise of all these people
talking all around you. And if you've
already established yourself talking,
it's something you can add into it. But
like that establishing time where it was
extremely easy to establish is is gone.
It's competitive to establish but still
possible. Now the standout is doing
this. I liken this to YouTube as well.
So for instance, one of my favorite new
channels is Fashion Neurosis. Very
similar to other channels we've seen
where people are interviewing other
people, right? You can put an interview
series out. It's extremely common
YouTube series. But honestly, people are
kind of tired of just seeing someone
sitting right here getting interviewed
and we're still talking at the same
table and they're watching the
conversation. There's so much of that.
But by adding this thematic format where
they said, "Hey, we're going to get
high-profile guests." But they are
treating it like a therapy session.
They're lying down on this intricate
couch. there's this very specific angle
and point of view where they're looking
down on them. There's this couple little
set pieces that is an immediate
standout. They're taking the same
interview series but presenting it more
thematically like an actual show. And
that is why I will tune in to fashion
neurosis versus not watching yet another
Rick Owens interview. And so I think
that's an important differentiation of
things that can work this way. A podcast
that does this really well is a
technology brother. There's a million
tech podcasts, but they have a format
where they are sitting, they're dressed
really nicely, they have a thematic
setup, they print out and read and
interact with things that are happening
online. So, for instance, they'll print
out tweets and respond to them, post
those clips as responses, post the main
podcast. They have a Chyron, like a uh
like a news show running beneath them.
They've taken this exact format, just
been like, "Hey, we're going to make
this look more like something I would
expect to see on CNN money." Same thing
you've seen with celebrities where uh
they're all sitting in a cold plunge,
Kevin Hart did this, Hot Ones,
obviously, but pulling examples from all
these things you see around it and
applying that to your content. So
instance, instead of telling me here's
five marketing campaigns that happened
this week, five marketing campaigns
happened this week while I'm doing hot
ones is again a way more solvable,
watchable thing, adding that extra
variant. So if you are looking to build
a personal brand this year or improve
it, it wouldn't be about, hey, don't
posting more content, doing more X or Y.
Find your series, find your format. If
you zone in on what I just said,
dedicate to it, do 10 of those episodes
weekly. I guarantee you, you will be way
farther along than doing something with
less intention. So I appreciate y'all
watching. Thank you so much for tuning
in.
[Music]