this is your guide to mastering email
marketing whether you're a marketer
trying to improve your skill sets a
designer trying to learn about
implementation or you want to own and
operate your own brand or you have a
brand and want to expand the toolkit in
this video we're going to walk through
all the key Concepts and how to do them
well we're going to talk about actually
getting subscribers from your web
traffic and social media we're going to
talk about Automation and flows and
emails that send automatically and we're
going to talk about campaigns that
you're sending out ongoing as promotions
we'll talk about software ideas for each
and just give you a complete Playbook
that you can always come back to
whenever you want to make sure that
you're running through all the best
practices of sending great email this
video is very focused on e-commerce
Brands and wanting to sell I will likely
do a separate video if you're
establishing yourself as a personality
or starting a newsletter but that's
coming later for now let's get into it
so the reason email subscribers are so
important is they're with you for the
life of your brand social media traffic
is not owned algorithms can change at
any time ads aren't reliable and if you
do email well it should be a double
digigit percentage increase inside the
revenue you're doing for your e-commerce
business and even if you don't run just
an Ecom and you sell into stores you
sell other things it's extremely useful
to be able to continually touch those
people and educate them on your releases
your products and your brand so first
we're going to talk about getting
subscribers I'm going to hit the loow
hanging fruit if you are a brand you
have to have the Subscribe available on
your website I would highly recommend
having a dedicated section on every page
at the bottom above your footer that
encourages people to subscribe but you
also have to have a why one of the
things that people Miss is giving anyone
a reason to actually subscribe there are
a few most websites or most brands will
just say hey keep in touch with our
recent releases Etc if your brand
doesn't have a lot of desire for those
and people aren't kind of foaming at the
mouth to get the new things that you
have that's probably not going to be
enough to get people to sign up so
there's a few techniques you can use the
first and most common is a discount and
if you're the kind of brand that's okay
with doing a discount account 10% 15%
20% whatever it is it's definitely worth
calling that out on your subscribe the
second is actually giving people some
level of value saying hey you can get
this free guide you can get this
Playbook you're going to get a freebie
when you place your order free shipping
whatever it is but just remember you're
probably going to have to give something
to get something and I'll talk more
about guides and content as a tool for
this in a moment because in addition to
having that place on your site you're
also going to want to have that same
option available in a popup no one likes
popups but the truth is that they
convert and a good popup will get you a
single- digit percent and sometimes even
higher on pages that people land on and
when you're running ads and when you're
generating traffic this really helps you
make the most of it there's two types of
popups that most people use one is a
popup that fires almost automatically
upon Landing which tends to have a bit
higher of a conversion rate but be a
little bit more annoying in user
experience the second is what's called
an exit popup which is when someone goes
to click out of the page it shows them
the ability to subscribe and really it
comes down to whatever you want to test
but I'd recommend imp implementing one
of the two and then having it so it only
shows up for every so often before
someone subscribed and isn't showing
constantly we'll talk about some options
for this when we get into platforms the
third option you have is your social
media many people see things like many
chat which allows someone to comment on
a post and get sent a link as a common
tool that creators use for email signups
but brands should make use of this too
and the second thing is your link in BIO
whenever you have a social media profile
it doesn't have to just take people to
your store giving them an email sign up
option is a nice soft call action to
incorporate as well but real quick let's
go back to guid and content what most
people don't realize is that digital
content is a way better way to get
someone to sign up for your brand
especially if you don't want to give a
discount than almost anything else and
you can give them all kinds of content
around that in fact you can say things
like hey get a link to our 10 most
popular YouTube videos if you have a
fashion brand give a guide to styling
your product a beauty brand it could be
tips or a video in almost any brand
there's some way to give information for
that value whether it's a PDF or just a
video but you'll see it will work
wonders if that's in your offer to both
increase your average order value versus
discounting it and to get people to
convert for a different reason versus
purely money so next up we have flows so
flows and automation are words that are
used interchangeably but what it means
is these are emails that are
automatically triggered when someone
signs up for your list or completes an
action on your site there's a few that
we're going to talk through the first is
an onboarding flow so when someone
subscribes to your email they either get
an email directly sent right to them or
they'll get a set of many emails that
educate them on the process they're sent
over time and I highly recommend this if
you're looking for a framework for this
one that I use very frequently is
there'll be an email that comes right
away on subscription that introduces the
brand and some of the popular products
of the brand an email that comes a day
or two later that then shows some of the
best content of the brand and things you
really want to show off a few days later
let's say two or three you send an email
that's about the brand and showcasing
the history maybe a week later you begin
to introduce all your best Sellers and
you can follow up a month or two later
with more of your common products now
based on your brand and the content you
have you can decide Your Own Adventure
but I would recommend having that
onboarding Series be four or five emails
over the course of 30 or 60 days so make
sure to set up an onboarding flow so
that when people sign up they get
educated on your brand and in all of
these emails I would say your number one
objective does not have to be just to
sell if you are selling every time
someone opens an email then they're
probably going to open them a little
less if you encourage and add some other
things in for personality whether it's
great social media videos beginning
curation or just telling more of your
story introducing personality it's going
to go better next there's new customer
flows when someone actually buys you
have a new opportunity to basically
offer them a discount on their next
order thank them for their purchase from
the founder recommend similar products
that might go well with it ask for a
review ask for a referral or a
recommendation even ask for Content
those are all email types that can come
a day a week a month after a purchase
same thing for people that purchase many
times one things I love to call out for
Brands who are looking to build real
brand value and loyalty is take your top
1% 5% of customers identify how many
orders that is and set up a specific
flow for them that lets them know with a
direct email from the founder or some
special gift or code or acknowledgement
that they're one of your top people and
that you value them another common flow
type that I really like is high volume
subscribers your super fans people that
open every email how can you give them
even more content something to think
about especially as you begin to build a
larger list and really get into email
marketing but something you may not have
to do off the Jump for a newer brand but
with all these inside your email
platform you can go design several
emails set triggers for timing a day or
24 hours from an action and put it
together in these very simple widgets
that guide you along this I think this
is a pretty good time to talk about
email platforms and what email platform
to choose and some of the tools for them
and then we'll get into campaigns and
some final best practices so one of the
most popular platforms for email
marketing is called clavo they're almost
almost every Shopify brand of some size
uses they have a big competitor called
sendlane those are two of the really
popular platforms for big large email
lists that have all these features that
we mentioned but the side of these
brands that I want to make sure we
understand is that they're expensive and
they cost a lot more so when I started
my new valuables brand I went for a more
affordable alternative that has a bunch
of the same tools which was omnisend and
I also reached out to omnisend when I
was doing this video to partner with
them to explain a bit of how omnisend
works so the first thing I like most
about it is they just have a much
discounted approach especially as you're
building out your first followers you're
not paying hundreds of dollars to get
your email subscribers you're paying
much less and they have dedicated forms
popups automation email deliverability
all the things you need templates that
you can actually act on everything I say
in this video directly within omniscent
and you can check the link in the
description below for a special offer
from omnisend and it's your choice when
you start whether you're optimizing for
Value you're optimizing for as many
features as you can or you want
something you already understand but I
do think there's no reason to overpay
for one of the larger platforms when
there's now a lot of smaller platforms
that do the same thing like I mentioned
many chat is a software that allows
people to comment on your Instagram
posts and you can then DM them a link
this is a great way to DM them a landing
page to get some signups I highly
encourage especially if you're giving
away content like a free PDF or videos
in fact many of you may have come to
this video from me doing that exact same
thing on short form and then there are
tools that specifically help with high
popup rates one of them that was really
popular that is now being deprecated CU
they were required is called ampt they
actually got really high signups by
triggering pop-ups at the right time
there's a cottage econom of options have
now popped up to help replace where they
were in the market but next we're going
to talk about campaigns and campaign
ideas campaigns are the emails that you
send out regularly to people that are on
your list to get them to purchase and
educate them on your brand and if you
are a marketer or on a marketing team or
have your own brand you're always
looking for ideas for this I'm going to
walk through a bunch of my favorites and
first if you want to get inspiration for
this then you can use mild.com as a
great place to see any Brands emails to
see what they send and also if you have
a subscription to a service like
particle they actually include in their
event section emails uh from m in there
so you can look in one place so the
first type of campaign we're going to
talk about is an announcement campaign
when you're just releasing a product or
putting something new out another great
option is behind the scenes so for
instance with a fashion brand I work
with we'll have our announcement email
with a lookbook and then we'll actually
have a behind the scenes with a bunch of
the sketches and designs and process
behind it that we'll send out afterwards
there's also a written email basically a
plain text email from a founder or a key
team member that is a great great way to
get some engagement in a campaign with
something completely different and I
would recommend sending out a key
moments in a company's timeline there's
content driven emails and I encourage
highly you to put content put social
media content in all your emails don't
have it just be selling show people how
customers are engaging with it or you're
engaging with it throw in Tik toks
Instagrams YouTubes ugc reviews let
people actually experience media as they
want to but you can also have emails
that are just about content your new
YouTube series your common support
questions things that are coming up are
happening in the world you can be a
source and a guide as a brand to be able
to help people navigate your world and
products then we have collections and
themes so if you have products you can
theme them by color you can theme them
by looks you can put some of them
together and style them no matter what
we're talking about and any kind of
industry and then help share people
experiences you can use with your
products same thing goes for the world
outside of your products if you have a
beverage for instance or you have
something that can be used in cooking
and you want to curate a bunch of things
in and around it or other ingredients or
other products that go with it you can
begin to give that guided experience to
the people that subscribe and then we
have collaboration working with other
brands or working with creators to get
their picks or their selects or an
interview or some kind of collaboration
product or even just a collaboration
content that will help stand out you can
take curation even farther than what I
mentioned before where it's surrounding
your product and actually make that a
theme of your account even developing a
sub newsletter at a company I worked at
previously in consumer electronics that
was in the the Drone category the camera
drone category we had a sublist that
people could opt into it was
specifically about industry news because
we found so many people were just
excited about the category that we could
be a vehicle to educate them there they
helped build brand resonance and we sent
those emails out less frequently it
helped us build a cultivated passionate
fan base and then last there's Guidance
the ability to help people navigate
through the things that are interesting
in your world if your brand is based in
a place or doing certain things you can
actually talk people through it and
share some of those experiences and this
leads me to the last section where we're
going to talk about best practices so I
will say most brands are more successful
when they send emails from a person when
instead of coming from info it comes
from Carl at or juliad or whoever it is
especially if it's a founder or someone
with a presence online that also makes
those plain Tech emails and that
guidance or that curation be more
personable when it's from a person and
you will notice over time those open
rates will go higher and it helps
connect to your brand story and your
world building one thing I'm not going
to dive into here because I'm a good
email marketer I'm not a great technical
email person is deliverability things
like spam and bounce rates and whatnot
you will want to go dive into that on
your own and dig a bit into it as you
grow it's going to be a big thing that
comes up same thing with things like
domain verification tying in your
domains dkim SPF there's all these
records and things that will happen that
are worth communicating a with it that I
just want to call out so as something
you can dive deeper into in other
content outside of here and then lastly
to make this easy on yourself because
this is a lot of emails you're going to
be sending a lot of emails I would
recommend sending at least once a week
if not twice a week and for some Brands
it's even more especially as your list
gets larger you're going to need a way
to keep things fresh I imagine having a
several different styles of emails like
your campaign announcements your
collections your curation a Written
Letter behind the scenes you can
alternate as useful but having a kit
whether you're doing that in Adobe or
you you have a brand kit in Adobe
Express or whatever software you use
actually having easy elements buttons
Styles fonts pictures that your team can
work from to easily swap things in and
out of the email templates you have is
going to make your life way easier so
anyway that's the guide to getting
started with email marketing a bunch of
campaign ideas and flow ideas for you to
run for your Brands and I appreciate you
watching you can sign up to learn more
about omnison and use them to kick off
your email at the link in the
description thanks
[Music]