Today we are going to talk about
mastering mood boards. Whether for you
as a creative or if you're actually
working on projects as a designer or a
marketer for a brand. I'm going to go
through all the tools from Arena to
Pinterest to Cosmos to Millote and
foreplay and what exactly you do in each
of them, why you might want to use them
for what kind of work. I'm going show
you some examples from my boards and
other boards. And I'm going to walk
through the creative toolkit. What are
some of the apps that are outside of
these boards you can use to populate
what you're working on with ideas. This
is one of my favorite topics. I'm
working in boards all the time. I both
love making them and effectively using
them on projects. So, I'm stoked to walk
through it with y'all. Let's lock in.
So, first let's talk about tools. And
I'm going to start with the one that's
least covered first, and that is Arena.
That is a
r.na. And so, Arena is interesting
because it is the least functional of
the mood board platforms. The UI is a
little bit brutalist. Everything is a
little bit harder to configure and share
than any other network, but it has the
best references. All may be a stretch,
but majority of creative professionals
are using this as where they're actually
putting the real work that they use. And
there's lots of references here that
aren't caught in the same algorithm as
the other Pinterest board, like
Pinterest and Cosmos and whatnot,
showing you the same stuff. So, how does
this work? When you get to a block on
Arena, like this IKEA 1984 catalog, and
you go down the side here, these are all
the other boards that link to this. And
what's nice about Arena is you can pick
something completely random, like I'm
just going to pick 258 and go into this
board here. And it's just going to be
filled with I mean, this is like an
amazing set of like interior content,
right? So you can connect to your
boards. There's source links for a lot
of it, but there's just much better
inspiration actually working through
here, but really you're exploring.
You're finding starting points. You're
following some boards and seeing where
it can go. What's nice is you can find
art directors who are really doing work
and putting together super comprehensive
boards for their projects like you see
here and actually find like pretty
amazing inspiration and shoots really
regularly. And so what it lacks in
search functionality and some of these
other things to source is really truly
greatly a discovery platform for finding
awesome stuff. And I can't recommend
highly enough using this as part of your
image sourcing workflow. So what do you
actually do in here? So one of my
favorite recommendations for creatives
of all time, if you watch a lot of my
older videos where I talked a lot about
creativity and life more, I emphasize
swapping your scrolling from like
consuming Tik Tok and like god forbid
like x Instagram reels into mood
boarding. And so I use the app one sec.
I also use the the hardware piece brick.
And I basically limit access to social
media except for times I have set on my
calendar to do work on social media
where I will browse specifically to be
like I need to find stuff for these
projects or I just want to check in and
see what's happening to kind of prevent
the scrolling that eats your time. But
instead I let that scrolling time that
downtime live in the mood board apps
live in Cosmos live in Pinterest and
live in Arena. And to use that
effectively you need a framework of
boards you can add stuff to. And I'm
going to get to that at the end of the
video. I'm going to walk through like
brand board frameworks and I'm going to
walk through individual board frameworks
that are helpful for that. But in case
you're wondering like, okay, what do I
do? How do I get this? I would be
spending time weekly like inside these
platforms just finding interesting
things and attaching them to a little
framework of boards that you have for
your various creative work. And you will
continually be shocked as you go through
arena at the quality and intensity level
of what is out there. So next up we have
Cosmos. I love Cosmos 2 for a few
reasons. So, first they have a for you
page on there that is very accurate. So,
if you were to look at the boards that
I'm working on right now, what they are
showing me is extremely accurate to it.
And so, it's nice to have a feed that's
actually good, that's relevant to the
stuff that I'm putting on boards is a
great feature of Cosmos. Same thing with
the feed of who I'm following. They also
have discover functions where they have
a curated algorithm that is excellent.
Their curation team is incredible and
they're always putting really
interesting stuff on the feed. Albeit
noting that it is always like super
artistic and tasteful. I know not
everyone works in those kind of worlds.
But one of the other best functions of
Cosmos is the ability to search by
color. So I can go in here and say this
particular shade of green and then I can
do packaging or whatever it is that I am
looking for. Apply this color search.
All right. They didn't find anything
that's in there. I'm just going to start
with this color overall. So the ability
to find anything that has a similar
color. Same thing when I switch over to
this red. being able to just find things
that work in there and then narrow the
search down. So again, I pop into
packaging here. They didn't have any
results when I was showing that green,
but there's plenty here that work under
that red kind in similar color schemes.
You can go actually dial down a notch
into what you're searching for is a nice
touch. And you will see I actually do
lots of boards. We'll talk about this
later when I get to board structure in
my Cosmos boards here. 90% of these are
public so you can go hack around in
them. And I am building color stories
for brands based on these functions.
Like this board was built by putting
like three color codes in one at a time.
And we were kind of going through trying
to figure out if these colors went well
with each other. And what that kind of
journey of those working together would
look like is like a board like this for
example. And they also have in this
function trending stuff, recent
categories, etc. So the downside of
Cosmos is that there just isn't as much
stuff on there. But it's a great way to
hunt through a lot of really tasteful
and artful stuff of what they do have.
And since it's a newer network, more and
more stuff I assume is going to get
added over time. And then we have
Pinterest. So Pinterest is still
excellent. They actually got rid of a
lot of the AI stuff I was complaining
about a while back where it used to be
like a lot of AI on the feed. The only
downside is it's just ads all over. It's
just sponsored content. Like literally
every single row is showing you
sponsored content. So you're constantly
having your eyes drawn to another
priority that's not your search. And
that's the hardest problem I have with
this is I just don't know why they have
to show so many impressions like inside
these scrolls. It completely ruins the
scrolling experience. but they still
have great sharing, collaboration, and
an amazing image library that lives on
Pinterest. And brands also do a good job
of of actually positioning themselves on
there. Quick note on that, one of my
favorite brands on there like Cusette,
50,000 followers, they have a bunch of
different whether it's their actual
individual products and they will
actually go into color and they launch a
new color, they put color stories and
combinations that work with that color
inside Pinterest. So, it's a great
navigation to find if people are like
working on their kitchen. I think
there's a lot of brands, whether you
sell interior objects or anything, that
could use this kind of treatment that
could take a similar approach. That's
not the point of the video. We'll talk
about Pinterest marketing a different
time. Now, we're going to talk about
Millanote. You've probably seen
Millanote. They sponsored a number of my
videos, but they are like a big note
board. You can't source images on there,
but it's a great way to organize them.
So, for instance, if I have a bunch of
different mood boards, that actually is
not helpful for the way that I think.
So, I think in like seeing things next
to each other. I want to see my mood
boards, like this is my brand mood
board. This is what I was doing in 2024.
This is where I'm moving by the end of
2025. I want to be able to have those
stories in these big old boards. Embed
things, play things, leave notes. And so
a good workflow, what I'll do all the
time is I will build a Cosmos board. I
will download everything from the Cosmos
board. They also have a one-click board
download as a zip, which is amazing. And
I will literally whip it into Millanote
to be able to actually move that around,
add notes, combine with some of my tech
packs, like make it make sense as a
brand workflow. I do the same thing for
art direction. I have a running list of
art direction concepts I want to try on
upcoming shoots where I keep these like
basically a bunch of little mini boards
with my notes and my little references
and stuff down here and ideas and embeds
all together. So that's more of a way of
organizing your mood boards. But since
you do get like I think the the first
board is like free unlimited if you just
have like a big brand board. It's a
great way or big personal boards a great
way to actually visually think of the
stuff you grab from mood boards. And
then we have foreplay. What a lot of
those other platforms don't contain is
like actual ads and content. And so like
this is my foreplay swipe files. This is
all things I'm saving for ads to create
ads. And so I actually have having saved
like this is a like a represent comp. I
believe it's a couple represent comps in
there. Skiims ads where I'm able to
actually save and create boards and
swipe files of different like
advertising types and styles which is
useful in its own way. And I can easily
import those links into other mood board
software. But it's also useful from a
discovery perspective as well. So, if I
do want to add things to it, you can
actually have the ability to go inside
and I can literally go search sneakers
or I can search a brand and I can
actually find advertisements for this.
If you are doing tactical level work or
say, "Hey, I want to go look at
everything Reformation has in their ad
library. I want to use some of those for
examples." You can actually find all of
that within foreplay and scroll back
through it and monitor those things,
which just gives you access to a whole
different way more practical ad set if
you're just purely looking at visuals.
as you break down kind of the difference
between these different apps. That's a
good one. And I do think that's
important because like for instance,
you're never going to find these ads
inside Pinterest, but there's a lot of
these like looks or text placement like
man, they are running a lot of creative
that looks a certain way or has a
certain feel that you want to make sure
you're able to add and save. So that's
where software like this comes in handy.
But that was the mood boarding guys.
What else is in the creative toolkit?
What else helps you like get
inspiration, actually use it, like add
to these apps and begin to tell your
stories? I have a massive list of
different like resources that I use. I'm
going to share a few of my favorites
here. I think you're going to find
usefuls. This is Cover Junkie. This is a
collection of magazine covers. I love
this because magazine covers are like
the OG hooks, right? You need to be able
to pick up the cover based on who's on
it or how crazy the images to actually
buy it. And so, I find a lot of hook
inspiration and visual hook inspiration
from covers. And you can go and actually
pair down. They have uh all these
different categories and best of. You
can go by every magazine title. You can
go by keywords. You can just find
absolute tons and tons and tons of
images in here. And so, let me go find
an example. Look how many. This is so
many. So, I'm going to go down to I say
cool. I want to look at all the
interview mag covers. This actually show
me every interview mag that they have
inside the database. That's a great look
as well. Start getting into like weird
foreign titles or whatever it is. You
can find a lot of interesting
inspiration in what they do there.
Another one is the art of the title.
This is another one where this is
basically title sequences from movies.
You can look at how they did text
placement and things like that that
again as you begin to look at short form
you can get a lot of creative ideas
especially as everything gets
increasingly cinematic. They have these
great little collections of how they do
it. Nice related ones and it's fun to
actually go through especially to things
like you know like more be movie style
and kind of see what those graphic
treatments are like is more good
inspiration for you. And then one of the
most useful is I candy. So, I candy has
all these different shot types you can
use for videos and different ideas, you
know. So, projections, they have a bunch
of examples of the shot type, a little
bit of how they did it, technique, and
where it's used and all these different
filters to go through it. And you can be
like, "All right, what do you mean by
match cut? All right, let's show some
examples." And they'll actually just run
you through and you can go through these
galleries of shot type examples. So if
you are filming something, whether it's
an ad or a music video or a short form
video, you have this world that you can
live in of just awesome visual
inspiration and shot types with actual
names you can use to describe to a
videographer or build out your creative
toolkit. So let's talk about what you do
with all this stuff. And so I recommend
we'll talk about brand workflow and
creative workflow. And I recommend
having like a workflow for each of what
you do with boards and inspiration to
organize it. So for brands, having a
mood board just for campaign ideas.
Number one, campaign and lookbook ideas.
Number two, for product and product
inspo. Now, you can have just these big
master boards with everything or you can
start to break it down seasonally or
yearly depending how robust it is, but
at least having those and having one
that's more brand focused. Now, a lot of
designers will have like a type one and
a color or type and graphic or they just
have one overall graphic board. But if
you have at least those three boards of
like here's what we're doing
graphically, type and fonts and color,
here's what we're doing with product,
here's we're doing with campaigns. It
gives you the ability to save a whole
number of things like at any time and
like literally so like this is a board
for valuable shoots. This is just shoot
ideas, things for me that I'm like, hey,
I want to try this like I recreated this
shot in a shoot recently or think about
doing a filter like this. I'm shooting
some vehicles in the future. Like, okay,
how can we put our own spin on making
like a compilation of something like
that? Like I have these these big boards
of things I want to try for shoots.
while at the same time when you're
working on a brand identity in another
project. I was saving a bunch of things
for that pitch just in this one simple
font board. But if you have those, it
gives you a framework to consistently be
adding to. If you are creative and
you're working creative, I would have a
couple different buckets there. So, I
would have a board for every brand and
every project that you're working on,
you can add stuff to. I have a couple
overall boards. Typography, no matter
what your life is going to interact with
type, I would be saving some typography
boards. Same thing with ads or
inspiration by industry if you work in
multiple industries. And then just a
personal board of just things you like.
Having some big setups. I have a few of
these. We can just save stuff that is
special to you for whatever reason so
you don't lose it in your head later on
is a great way to set up. And what I
usually end up doing is every Sunday
night, one of the things I used to do to
combat like Sunday anxiety is I would
organize all my bookmarks for the week.
So Sunday nights I would go through my
Twitter, Instagram, Tik Tok, whatever it
was, and I would put my bookmarks into
my boards or into action items in my
to-do list. It was a calming thing for
me that made me feel like I'm getting
ahead. got some value and also man I
didn't lose all those references you
just save in your bookmarks in
perpetuity. That's always an exercise I
do and if you are doing those things
where every week you're adding your
references somewhere and in free time
instead of scrolling you're like mood
boarding and adding stuff to these
important boards you'll find when you
show up into creative conversations or
go to do a project you have this massive
base that you've built that allows you
to really be able to crush things out
and even when you're building pitches
for clients I recommend think about the
same way. You don't want to be one big
mood board. Build a smaller board for
type doesn't take a ton of items to get
your point across. You can have five 10
things on a mood board. Like even three
to seven things that are perfectly
positioned is like super useful. The
clarity of thought by a mood board for
type, a mood board for color, a mood
board for packaging allows you to remove
that like indecipherable like oh I kind
of like this with a little bit of that
like feedback. It's like okay well let's
get feedback on the type like which of
these three images matter the most. Like
there's the ability to kind of get more
concrete. You'll see um you're working
with big web firms, you're working with
folks that are going to be dialing into
lots of smaller mood boards like inside
what they ask for feedback for. That's
one of the best tools you have is like
send somebody a mood board, allow them
to remove the items that they don't like
or get feedback on it and they can come
up with boards that allow you to
navigate through what people like and
don't and how you actually bring that
creative vision to life. So anyway, if
you want to explore more, this ties
really well into the art direction
videos I do. I've got one on road that I
think is underrated. Also got one on
Stuy that I imagine most of you all have
seen. You can dive in more into art
direction in those videos there. You
have any questions on this, you have any
other tools other people should know
they may want to see in the comments,
please drop below. And I appreciate
y'all so much. Uh, please drop a like,
subscribe, all those things. And thank
you so much for watching.
[Music]