all right in this video we are going to
do brand planning for the entire year
and we're doing this on January 1 but it
is useful at any point if you want to
dive in and map out 12 months or just
the future of your business small or
large so last year as many of you know I
launched a luxury product studio with a
corresponding brand and designed and
released over a 100 products myself and
on projects and right now I'm here in
Barcelona we're at the noou hotel I'm
doing what I do best which is brand
planning I'm running a workshop for a
global company and in this video I'm
going to share the five-part brand
planning strategy that I run when I do
these workshops with companies small and
large that just works let's lock in and
explore a bit of Spain while we do
[Music]
it first we're going to go through the
five part one and two go hand inand this
is your product and the calendar I'll
talk through these one by one and then
show how they overlap next so first
think about your product releases for
the year and this is going to be a
combination of what do you have ready
for product so for instance if you
already have things designed or in
production Etc as most people do it's
reviewing that and then there's a
question of what do we actually need we
have these things here we have these
things ready then the conversation
shifts to where are we in the market and
what do we need to do to stand out and
this is an important differentiation
point because we have to put things into
production early for most companies
things are landing but the world doesn't
wait for you to finished production
right taste change things change
positioning changes I talk a lot about
positioning because a lot of the brands
I work with are in retail my background
is in retail marketing and positioning
is important because when you walk into
a retail store you are positioned
against multiple other companies on the
Shelf I come from a consumer electronics
background and so a lot of positioning
there if you walk into a store like Best
Buy or a finac in Europe media Mar and
Germany that kind of thing you will see
three products in most categories
headphones phone cases drones certain
toys Electronics whatever it is there
will be at least three items in almost
every category and those three items are
positioned by good better and best and
the good option tends to be the lowest
price point it's offering a deal to the
customer an easy pickup at a low price
this usually isn't the first mover in
that product category wasn't the first
person along and you have better which
is your standard product this is
basically the product that everyone is
going for your most average sale and you
have best someone who's positioning by
saying hey we're going to charge a
higher price point but we give a better
experience
that tends to be an easy way to look at
positioning for Brands but more
importantly you need to look at what
other brands road maps are what your
road mapap is what consumer problem
you're solving and this goes for
clothing fashion consumer goods software
as much as anything so when we talk
about what do we actually need for
instance if you are a hoodie or a
t-shirt brand you obviously see that
there are now thousands and thousands of
hoodie and t-shirt Brands out there so
if you are not differentiating in some
different way that's going to elevate
you you are probably going to have a
rough year as your consumer base
continues to get sapped by the widening
market so you need to think about what
are those products that would help us
stand out so that's what we map out in
this part of the exercise what do we
have what do we need and let's focus on
need because need is different than want
need is if our business wants to survive
and grow and meet our goals what do our
products need to be and so for me giving
an example of my valuables brand I
released a lot of products last year to
test the market because I realized with
a big following and my skill set I have
the ability to sell a lot of things I
need to find out I rather validate in
the market by actually trying to sell
what things are versus like leaking that
out I want to find out fast I released
things in apparel I released things in
kind of more uh fashion-driven apparel
as well as more kind of classic apparel
I did Footwear I did shoe bags I did
client projects that were a little more
public that like luxury goods I did
unisex products versus just men's
products and I did belts and accessories
I did car accessories for me to validate
so one of my big needs is I need a
product Market fit I need something that
I know is going to scale is doing better
than the other products and so right now
I have two candidates for that and
that's what I'm working through my
version of this exercise is how are
these going to move and the last part of
product is your dream road map this is a
really important part of the exercise
and things a lot of companies ignore is
they're not thinking about what would
our perfect year look like from a
product perspective so I take some time
and map that out I think through what
are all the ideal collaborations that
we're actually ready for I wouldn't go
pie in the sky like if you're a smaller
brand you're like hey I want to do a
Louis Vuitton collab let's look at what
would be your perfect collab this year
for where you're at because if you are a
smaller brand you're probably not ready
for that collab collaborations additions
licensing say you want to run like
Metallica you know Hello Kitty whatever
it is your goal with this is to create a
constant working document of things to
add to for the ideal products in your
road map so for instance I have have a
lot of car accessories as part of my
brand I want to work up to be able to do
large car accessory collapse I would
love to be able to do the merchandise
for Dodge Challenger Ford Raptor I'm
positioned obviously a little more
towards American companies I'm not going
to achieve that this year but what are
the collaborations on my dream road map
that I can achieve is hey I could easily
do something like that with car clubs
with shops with accessories Brands
that's the kind of thing I'm prepared
for now so I'm putting that on my list
of dream things I want to get this year
so now we have what do we have ready we
have what do we need to survive and grow
and hit our goals and then we have our
Dream Road mapap and I would just list
those out create a working doc this is
best in a spreadsheet where you can
literally have like a list going down
and begin to think about is this a dream
product is something we can do what's
its status Etc and now we're going to
put it in context of the calendar this
is a really important conversation to
have because timing is everything in
brand planning when I go do workshops
for big Brands it almost always is
around timing because they have
constraints goals to hit High periods
and low periods attention that needs to
be gotten content is all based around
timing so a lot of it comes down to
calendaring and this is how we walk
through it and after that we'll actually
get into things like content sales
channels and more so the first thing to
do if you have an existing brand is pull
up your calendar by week from last year
on Shopify I used to have like a B+
version of this exercise and then I saw
uh this breakdown from Taylor holiday
who runs this agency called Common
Thread I have a lot of respect for about
how he does it now I do it exactly like
he does with this weekly breakdown
because you can pull up your Shopify if
you're D Toc you'll probably have a
report like this that encompasses retail
if you are if you have sell through data
if you are a retail supplier but the
goal of the 52 week when you actually
look at it you're going to begin to see
your Peak weeks and weeks are important
because we're starting with product and
then we're going to go into content and
you're going to start to see that a
release or a Content Blitz can shift the
nature of whether a week is up or down
you're going to go through that calendar
and you look at all your main Peaks all
of the weeks that you're going to see
usually it's like a week and a couple
around it that are a peak you want to
identify all of those to identify all
the main areas you already do good sales
I would literally list them out the best
way to do this is to print a big
calendar like this out obviously put it
up on a screen then Mark your big Peaks
and write out what product release
holiday you don't know which is good to
then dig into and figure out then look
at your alternative Peaks other things
that happened that weren't quite as big
may have some potential you usually find
for most brands they'll have three or
four big Peaks and they'll have another
two to five smaller peaks of things that
kind of happened that went pretty well
the bubbled and now once you list them
out you're going to start to see hey do
we want to replicate these and are these
going to be replicable or not so for
instance if you went viral for some
reason some influencer posted you you
may not be able to replicate that that
Peak may not come back this year you're
going have to account for that if it
happened on Valentine's Day for instance
if Valentine's Day is big for you you
got be all right how are we going to go
super hard on Valentine's Day we'll talk
about how we tie all these together well
you're going to see when you have this
sketched out I do my workshops mainly on
whiteboards and so we will actually go
map this out month by month you're going
to look at across those 52 weeks and
you're going to go like all right I have
my Peak and I have the few weeks around
those Peaks I have my alternative Peaks
a bunch of areas there then you're going
to see LOLs for a lot of Brands who
aren't supplement brands or brands that
are gifted for Valentine's Day January
February becomes a l we late in the
planning process to to release products
for that time now in January but you
might want to think about this for the
next year is how do you solve that right
how do you make a giftable product like
Valentine's Day can solve your whole
January February LW if you're able to
create a product that works for that and
a lot of Brands think they can't create
a product that works for that but
they're wrong even if you have like a
hardcore goth brand oriented towards men
think about what your customer base is
doing on Valentine's Day do they likely
have a goth girlfriend is there a kit
that you can begin to provide for them
that makes their life easy begin to
think about that user experience and
user Journey brainstorm some of that
during the process because you're now
your job is to identify these LOLs and
you're going to see them there's going
to be five or six points where you don't
make sales you're not making the sales
you want it may have happened to you for
years you may have seasonal products
many of you know I worked with this
company LIF oils for a long time they're
a hydrofoil electric surfboard company
we would absolutely dominate in the
Summers people aren't trying to invest
in hydrofoils in the winter so we would
have to do programming or at least plan
our year around the fact that things
aren't going to be as big in the winter
people don't buy those kind of products
or focus on regions that do where
Australia summer is actually Western
winter and so now that you have those
gaps we're going to talk about what
you're going to do inside of it there's
a list of options so the first is a
release one thing I do constantly inside
brand workshops especially with medium
like small to medium Brands let's say
you're in the seven to uh like under 50
mil8 figures is you shift your release
calendar people that are doing big drops
for seasonal clothing collections we
actually break it out it's like hey if
you're releasing 20 garments inside your
spring collection we're actually going
to release 14 and then we're going to do
three two product drops like on on low
weeks for things that we think are
really interesting or we can make good
content around or we have an influencer
plan for so all of a sudden we can get
some smaller spikes that's a really easy
one if you have like a wide range so you
have releases that's tool number one to
fill Gap is product releases you go back
to your dream state additions licensing
collaborations if you don't have a good
idea is this a time to launch a collab
is this a time to go pay a percentage
for licensing I think licensing is
probably deserves a whole video it's one
of the most underrated tools for Brands
I can think of um you may have seen me
or heard me talk about the licensing
Expo in Las veg when I was doing
licensing when I worked at gel Blaster
we did a Halo edition blaster for
instance that I worked on where we would
go to the licensing show meet with the
people that are licensing and figure it
out there's a there's a booth there
you've seen a lot of these big Brands
like licens heavy metal uh or have done
heavy metal collabs they're just paying
10% 12% royalty and a flat fee to be
able to use that iconography and there's
a booth at the licensing Expo that
literally you can go through and you can
get Metallica mly crew Slayer roll
through there's a No Limit Records Booth
right down the way too it covers like
the Gambit interesting trade show to go
to to look at this kind of stuff and
also if your brand has IP that's
licensable it's interesting too the
pudgy penguins are there pushing their
IP which I thought was a smart move as
well but I won't dive too deep into that
rabbit hole and there's releases there's
licensing Etc there's cultural events is
there something happening on those weeks
you can tap into again go back through
Valentine's day back to school summer
break that kind of stuff what is there
that you might be able to tap into
culturally they might be able to have an
event or a promotion or content around
it that's their second way to fill the
Gap then the third way is to create an
event I'll use tarte Cosmetics as an
example they go launch tarte Island
where they invite a bunch of influencers
out basically have a reality show
playing out on Tik Tok they created an
event to give them hype to sell products
in a downtime for them you'll see tech
companies will go launch their product
road map keynote or whatever it is but
this is a great opportunity to have an
influencer house or a three-day
challenge or we're going to go live or
we're going to create our you know our
annual our 10y year anniversary whatever
it is is there an event you can create
and again it can be just online doesn't
have to be big budget but how do you
create a concept pull something out of
thin air that you can then promote and
make content around that can help fill
that Sales Gap because your goal overall
is to maintain or increase your peaks in
and bring up all the areas and time
around it because we're now on a 247
promotions calendar for most brands and
if you're doing that if you're tying in
your product releases and you're tying
in that calendar then you are already
just winning it life for your brand
planning for the next year so usually I
will end this section we will have
whiteboard it out all the gaps and we'll
have identified hey can we do a release
in this Gap is there a cultural event we
can hit in this Gap so we'll just pull
it up and Google it right there or are
we going to create our own moment in
this Gap and that will be the end of the
product and calendar section of this
exercise and then it gets to the phone
bar cuz content has to be layered on top
of all this so I'm going to show you a
little more of the city and then we will
lock in on content and on channels
before we get to the fun part which is
threats and mitigation
[Music]
all right so content right now what we
have is we have all the products that we
are going to release we have planned all
the ones we want to release or tentative
to plan we have a calendar of the year
of what we did last year and what we the
goals we need to fill areas we have now
we need to assign content to that before
we do that we start with where we're at
as a brand where are you at with content
postmortem last year what content worked
what was our best performing content not
just view I don't care about how many
views I care about what content drove
sales interest followers influencers
fans it may not be your highest viewed
content and go summarize that what are
we doing well what are we doing bad who
are the influencers that are working for
us who are the creators or ugc that's
working well for us what are the posts
that working out for us and then break
it down by Network well usually is a
sign repeat improve ignore it's the
three statuses so repeat hey we did
these things we did it well can we
repeat it that's the question you have
to ask yourself we think the social
network is going to be the same do we
think this will still work you have to
ask yourself that question and if it
will you can just run it back repeat
keep doing it improve is hey we've been
doing this thing it's not very good we
have to change it this is your moment
now to be like we can't just keep doing
the same and prove it item two
item three is ignore ignore is important
because so many Brands try to do
everything at some point like just don't
do it like I don't do a lot currently
for my brand on Tik Tok I will at some
point but I don't have the bandwidth
right now so ignore and be okay with
ignoring things the Big Brand exercise
even with huge Brands it's like okay is
something working like lean in and start
to think about do we really need to
start focusing on one of these then what
are they and what do we think is the
best Roi of all the ignores that we
should actually start to move on we'll
get to that later so next up is pillars
if you've been through cut 30 you heard
me talk about cut 30 which is like my
content training program you know I
focus on pillars for Brands and for
creators all the time pillars means
repeatable content that you do all the
time so for instance a pillar of my
content if you've watched my short form
videos is packaging content I make
packaging content roughly every two
weeks is a pillar of my content always
does pretty well but pillars are either
coming or going packaging content for me
used to be on the up and up now it's
kind of on the down so it's still a
pillar but it's not a huge performer for
me it may no longer be a pillar for me
in like six months we start to think
about as a brand okay a pillar for us
could be hey we do content with this
Creator we do unboxing videos we do
whatever the things you recurringly do
that work well what are they and if you
don't have a bunch of things that work
well what are they going to be what are
you going to try your goal is to have
four pillars for your content four
recurring repeatable topics formats vide
types that you're able to do like
literally every I'd say about every two
weeks say one week to a month is given
Fair every Brand's different you are
repeating this stuff and ask yourself
all right how often am I repeating it do
we think it is coming or going this is a
question I ask all the time for about
Trends about content do we think we're
improving this is going to go up think
we're it's dying and we're going to lose
it it's worth just having that in your
head so you know I need to replace this
whatever and have that conversation okay
we need to replace some of these pillars
we're going to need new ones what are
our ideas Etc now you have your
postmortem of last year and you have
your pillars of your content what are
your most important rocks to the content
that you want to do let me go through
release support you pull back up your
calendar and you go through all this you
go like all right what do we have to do
to support these releases what we need
from photo shoots video shoots social
media content influencer seating ugc
categorize those out then go across all
your releases what we need to do for
each of those plans for some Brands to
do like weekly release es big releases
this becomes a really comprehensive
planning moment for some Brands you're
just dropping a handful of things we can
be a little bit less but you need to
really map that out so for me and my
brand personally I'm trying to do way
more content shoots next week when I do
a shoot and I do behind the scenes in
the shoot I sell a lot of product when I
don't do a shoot or I try to milk a
shoot as long as I can it doesn't work
the more shoots I am doing it feels like
the better my stuff is going to go so I
very focused on mapping every single
thing out around shoots I'm trying to do
like a shoot a month maybe more and then
around that comes I need to be seating
around that I'm doing behind the scenes
content there's content coming out about
it what are we trying to try what
network are they on I'm not going to get
extremely deep into the Nuance of this
but map out for every release you have
listed that could be five it could be 50
what content are we doing to support it
sometimes this one when you see me do
multi-day workshops this will be an
entire day is just release content plan
so don't be afraid if it takes time you
need to come back to it and if we have
recurring meeting for your business
around it even if that meeting is just
with yourself and next up is tests what
are we not doing from a Content
perspective we want to try and have the
ability to actually test i' be listing
those things out hey we want to try
YouTube we want to try more influencer
work we need to get ugc creators we
doing Tik Tok shop like list out what
your tests are and then again get to an
actionable framework are we going to
test it yes maybe and then I would
Define the maybe we'll test it if we're
doing this much revenue we hire this
person like what is the gate to identify
the gate it's a lot of what we get to in
these exercises get down to what will
Define yes or no we're going to do it or
it's unlikely we're actually going to
test us even though we want to be honest
with yourself and then last we're going
to hit success metrics what does success
look like to us and this is an
interesting combo because usually a lot
of people will say oh success is what we
need to post every day is the time to
dispel those kind of myths we need to
get a million views we need 50,000
followers
doesn't matter none of this matters all
vanity metrics those are not metrics
that matter I will literally get paid
egregious sums by teams to come in and
be able to tell their leadership team it
does not matter how many social media
followers you have your only metric that
really matters is are you making the
sales and then you have to put that back
on the social team as well and be like
all right well great we only need 50,000
followers but are we making the sales
are we getting the interest are we
getting the email signups like what are
the metrics that we want to identify and
lock those down and it's worth noting
one of the things that comes up a lot
with retail we end up using is like hey
are we having visibility if you is a
view Bas metric because a lot of Brands
sell in retail you can't really measure
the sell through of that is like hey are
we getting visibility in key regions and
that ends up being a conversation a lot
of like Hey we're actually we're
expanding into Canada we need more
Canada views we need toble to show
retailers we're getting Canada views how
do we prove to retailers our content our
social is working we need a deck we need
be to show them these okay if we walk in
with these kind of posts all right we're
doing 1 million views a month in Canada
that's something that we can show to
London drugs or somewhere in Canada that
we're selling in and be stoked about it
and have them be stoked about it and so
that you begin to actually develop
useful strategy that brings us to
channels nice transition there so your
channels for your business are selling
via ads online Tik Tok meta App 11
spending a lot of money just ignore that
last phrase like you didn't hear it
organic what are we selling just by
doing our email our social posts
existing website traffic SEO wholesale
what do we sell at retail what do we
sell in our own stores which is pure
retail what do we sell with partners and
in Partnerships and literally just map
those out Advertising based D Toc sales
organic D Toc sales wholesale sales to
other stores sales to our own own retail
sales through Partners or other
providers value resellers whatever
identify which of those are we doing and
focused on now are we going to try any
new ones and then back to when when are
we going to try it what are the gates to
unlock it hey we want to open our own
retail store okay we want to do that
this year we want to do that next year
what Revenue do we need to be at or what
parameters or things need to happen for
us to do it list those out so you have
an actual checklist to do it this is the
biggest thing you'll learn from this
video or takeaway is if you want to do
something you literally M about what are
the things that has to happen to do it
and what is the yes no for me to do it
or not okay I'll do that when I'm at
100K in Revenue great we decided it
we're going to do it when we're at 100K
in Revenue once you actually have that
commitment again it can just be to
yourself if you're a one person business
where you have that consensus among a
group you have to lock that in sometimes
I'll rabbit hole for an hour getting to
a consensus on some specific thing but
that means you're walking away with
Clarity the teams know the executives
know you can make a decision based on it
it's a really important thing to think
about and then last is Success metrics
for these so for instance you go into
advertising what's our success metric oh
we need a 2.1 row ass actually we don't
really want a 2.1 row ass because this
you know this this or that we need to
have a higher row ass or actually we
don't need a higher row ass hack these
conversations out row ass is return on
ad spend if you're new to that it's like
okay what is our make money level are we
judging it based on our customer
acquisition cost or their lifetime value
or we basing on you know first sale
profitable we actually want to be
there's a whole number of things that
come in here of like what is what do we
view like success what do success look
like at retail how many units per store
per week levels of POS new new engaged
you like there are a whole number of
things to think through here but I would
just try to go through all the channels
you are in and Define what does success
look like to you and now we're going to
talk through threats and mitigation like
one more Peak around Barcelona now I'm
going to talk about probably the most
important thing here which is
accountability charts
threats and mitigation this is a good
oldfashioned brainstorm exercise
whiteboard big column what are threats
to our business column one column two
what can we do about it now when it
happens often these things will happen
threats there's a whole number of them
so for instance I am an influencer I
sell all my products based on the fact
that I'm an influencer what would happen
if I was canceled or I The Social
Network changed I could no longer
influence what can I prepare to do now
one is get more voices talking about my
product than just me that could be
something I can work on now second is
make sure the Facebook ads model to new
customers have nothing to do with my
business is like locked in and scaling
that's number two then what would happen
if it actually went down say I would no
longer able to do this it's like all
right find another personality to take
it over focus on Facebook ad scaling to
people who have no idea that I am be
able to move this budget here or
whatever God forbid but again you're
playing through threats retailer come
you know someone comes in at the
competitive price a quality issue get
kicked off the shelf at retail someone
comes out with a better product cheaper
whatever you need to map through all
those threats and again just go through
those columns and lock down those two
things last thing here the secret sauce
of this entire video we've now gone
through all this right we've gone
through what are products we want to
release what products are we releasing
what's the calendar where releases are
what are all the holes in that calendar
how are we going to patch those holes G
through the content we have to create
around those releases what do we want to
test we going through the channels where
are we selling how do we better support
them what new channels we want to go
through then we got went through all our
worries what is it that's going to stop
now it's who's going to do it this is
the biggest one because uh you can talk
through as many ideas as you want I me
with all these companies have a big
slack Channel where they share videos
like we share your videos all the time
or we want to do this or that and then
so few of them actually do it basically
there a 50-50 type of companies there's
companies that like oh we're doing all
these things now we want to do more of
them and get better at it there's
companies that like we share them all we
can't figure out how to actually act the
accountability chart is a big one so
basically every single thing on this
list that doesn't already have someone
in charge we're going to put on the
accountability chart I will go through
basically every release that you're
doing every release that you want to do
every piece of content that you want to
make type of content bucket whatever it
is every launch every event every sales
Channel listed out big list on and
you're going to have a little uh set of
tabs here do we have to do this we need
to do it company has to do it to grow
and survive do we want to do it we're
doing it because we want to at the end
of the day it's it's a nice to have we
didn't do it we're not going to third is
it's too much we went through it we're
probably not going to be able to do this
this year too much column it's good to
just admit it sometimes too and the last
column is who is accountable who would
be in charge because then it begins to
really impact these other colums you go
all right we have to do this all right
well who's going to do it is it me is it
a new hire is it this person in the
company is it that person in the company
who is in charge of Tik Tok shop who is
in charge of our influencer strategy for
this release who is in charge of making
sure this new product comes to life
who's in charge of this licensing
project and assign that accountability
and everyone's going to be like all
these compan oh too busy everyone's
mapped out no one's ever too busy no
one's ever too mapped out every company
I talked to basically everyone is
underutilized and if you are a Founder
then you probably spending way too much
time on Twitter or doing whatever it is
you're doing online and focusing on your
business you also can be more utilized
the other thing is I was meeting with a
friend of mine this morning who had just
clawed back his business from all the
agencies he's outsourced too and he was
just like I realized I I've been in the
same scenario before in my life where
hey you you I want more time as a
Founder I'm going to go these agencies
they're going to take these things off
my plate oh what do I do with all this
time oh I could be doing everything
better what the agencies are doing okay
now I take everything back so that
happens a lot so if you're a Founder you
probably have time to don't always be
thinking about taking everything off
your plate it's a fou but Lally have to
go through that chart chart again if
you're one person business it's going to
be you all right and then that's you
might put more stuff in the too much
column you might say hey I need to hire
somebody part-time or full-time or up
work or whatever it looks like you're
going to break this all down and the
last piece is you're going to assign
dates when do we need this stuff to
happen by and if things are hairy or
complicated like Tik Tok shop or we're
just going to get it done by May one it
maybe too unrealistic break it down One
More Level okay to do that we need to
make sure we have SKU and compliance
info on every one of our products and we
need to you know set this thing up or do
that thing break it down to more steps
and assign dates to those steps will
always make any date more understandable
just keep it down to simpler tasks
assign the dates to all these things on
this list it's another one where you're
start going to move more stuff into the
too much column because the dates you
look at you're like oh we can't
actually do all this or you're going to
look at be like man okay we got to get
to it then you look at your check-in
Cadence this is the last one who needs
to meet about it and ruthlessly cut
people off meetings so they don't need
to be a part again can be a meeting with
yourself whatever it is but how are we
checking in on where the progress is we
have to have some kind of cadence we're
doing this monthly we're doing this
weekly we have a review we're putting
this all into clickup notion whatever it
is but build that CAD that's it this is
the structure I use I'm talking through
this kind of stuff with companies all
the time thought you would find it
valuable to apply to your own business
as you're planning for the year I'm
doing a bun of that planning myself
while I'm here in Spain and if you
actually go and map through this and act
on this I guarantee it will be an
improvement for your business drop any
comments or any questions you have and
thank you'all so much for watching