all right and today we are going to talk
about making money as a Creator which is
a relatively taboo topic because
basically you get people talking about
how you can scale agencies and make all
these dollars you have very little
people talking about concretely how to
freelance vehicles for your creative
expression and things that aren't purely
around like the fiscal nature of how do
I make something that generates X cash
flow mon so I'm going to give a very
realistic walkthrough of setting
yourself up for freelancing what to do
if you have soft skills and you don't
have like the really specific
freelancing skill and how you can still
get side money forming collectives with
other creatives and the ideas about
creative Studios building an agency if
you do want to build an a having a
creative vehicle or basically something
that moves your vision forward that is a
commercial Enterprise but doesn't really
fit in traditional ideas of business
this is one I like a lot and the ideas
of scaling and exiting any of those
things like as the time is right and a
little bit on how you generate business
for so first as always who am I to talk
to you about any so I've been through
basically every single thing that I'm
going to talk about here I was a
freelancer for many years years because
as many of you know if you are a
creative professional most jobs just pay
trash and it's really hard to get the
life you want do things that help build
your skill set and only do one thing and
it's a sad reality but it is a reality
but also what's nice about being a
creative is you do have a skill set that
you can place a premium on above the
hours that you work and so throughout my
life I've done freelance graphic design
I did freelance website development even
now I still do free uh freelance
creative strategy and product
development in addition to all the
businesses and things that I run and
operate but in addition to that I didn't
always just freelance solo and I'll talk
about this a bit in the collectives and
Studio section I've brought in other
people too cuz I recognize one of my key
skill sets is being charismatic and
having a network of people in
relationships I'm able to rely on but in
addition to that I've had an agency for
going on seven or eight years now um I
used to say six and then realize about 2
years have gone by but it started as a
marketing and product development agency
and then shifted purely into product
development but it's about 40 people I
am fully out of the business uh now at
this point I'm just a a stakeholder in
it but we went through all everything
from starting from zero with no clients
through scaling it up to five people 10
people to eventually having it be large
to me having not to not have to be in
the business and then continuing it on
thinking about what the future looks
like today but most importantly I think
really critically about this because I
lead a very creative life that is not
doesn't follow your traditional career
path I thought a lot about how to make
money and I talk to a lot of other
creatives about that and we often work
together refer business and this is the
kind of thing that isn't available to
creatives everywhere which just part of
why I make this videos so that even if
you don't have that same kind of network
you can still benefit from some of the
things that we all so first I'm going to
talk about freelancing and setting
yourself up for Success there so if you
have a hard skill set you're a graphic
designer you're a web designer you're a
video editor and you're good at it you
always going to be able to get freelance
work there is demand for that kind of
work and I highly recommend once you're
at a certain point in your career where
you're kind at least relatively proud of
the work you do you put yourself out
there to do it because the reason this
is important I've talked about this in
previous video so I won't go into it too
in depth begins to get you into the
relationships that you understand like
what client expectations are how to
communicate you've set up software to be
able to run invoices out of you have the
basic infrastructure propos proposals
things like that actually make this work
so quick tactical notes on
infrastructure so Zoho books Zoho is a
software suite that has like they have
all kinds of stuff basically I look at
them as like they're the B tier of
almost all software they have something
that does everything it's like a B
versus like there's a tiers but their
books feature which is an accounting
software is free you just sign up for
that and keep it relatively minimum
means you have to pay for QuickBooks or
any of that and I highly recommend it
it's very simple you can create and send
invoices out of there second thing is
you're going to need some proposal
templates I'll link um this woman Jamie
template who I referenced in the
previous video like in the notes here
she has a great template I think it's 15
or 45 bucks or whatever if you're
sending proposals out for how to
structure creative work and the other
thing on L for freelance I think is
really important uh to consider then
we're going to dive into collectives of
Studios because it's it's much more
interesting is communication on this
with whoever you're working with is
really the differentiator in in how
people work together right you may be
the most skilled person of any kind in
your field and some people will hire you
for that most people hire people because
they like them and because they
communicate what's going on they feel in
the know and they know when things are
going to happen and they don't get
surprised so when if you're freelancing
the top tips I have out there is you set
up set up your invoicing software and
you can do a free one like there I would
get your LLC set up do it as one person
at least you establish some level of
like tax set up for yourself get a firm
proposal template that actually walks
through what you're going to do and
steps and timelines and then every week
force yourself to update your clients
everyone you work on with what you did
the statuses of what you're what you're
working on any hurdles or challenges or
things that they have that you're
waiting on them for and communicate
regularly every week for all your
clients like in perpetuity whether they
read it or not but get in that habit of
being accountable for yourself and your
timelines for communicating where you're
at and for identifying blockers that
might sound like simple advice but it is
extremely useful and the second thing
I'll note here is to publish your work
put it on social media put it on SIMPLE
website portfolio if you don't want to
pay for much it's probably worth
learning getting a basic WordPress
template the the cheapest best template
that most people can use like a visual
Builder is the Salient template if
you're going to use something on
WordPress the reason I recommend
WordPress is because you can literally
buy a website self-install WordPress and
you paid your $10 a year for your domain
or whatever and you don't have any
recurring costs if you're comfortable
paying 10 bucks or 20 bucks a month or
100 bucks a year or whatever it is then
you can 100% use a bunch of the other
ones I'll do a whole portfolios video at
some point to talk about but you know
can use Squarespace Etc it's probably
but put your work in a centralized place
you can easily point to it and just
regularly upd update it whenever you
complete something usually what I like
to do is whenever I send the invoice I
put the work on the website or in my
portfolio it's just a great way to like
trigger it in your step and in your
process but now for the more interesting
part so from freelancing you'll notice a
few things come up if you have a job
they might not want you freeler you
might not want it to be known that you
freelancing I've dealt with this my
entire life especially before social
media and that became a way to attract
clients it was always a bit of a like
all right like how do I how do I get
clients to get this work how do I
present myself without everyone knowing
about it there's a lot of kind of nuance
to it and also you'll notice that if you
don't have a hard skill I called out
Freelancers for hard skills if you're a
project man creative strategist a brand
strategist if you're more of like a
brand owner you know you're someone who
has more of a t like a like a tactical
project management skill set you'll
notice it's a lot harder to freelance
people don't just hire a freelance
person for all of those sometimes they
do some of that work is out there but
way less frequently than like a designer
a developer and so I'd like to just
identify right now you are best as a
conduit and I will be putting together
this idea of basically like a collective
creative Studio or an offer so what does
this mean this means that you are best
to use yourself your communication your
organization standpoint to bring a
couple creatives together to work on
specific projects like hey we do web
design for 10K 10K project we do some
type of recurring work but by bundling a
small group of people together is is an
excellent way to be able to gain value
out of your soft skill set but also this
idea of collectives is really important
because I'm going to talk about agencies
in a moment and not everyone wants to
have an agency for a few reasons so I
will inherently Define maybe we'll talk
about agencies and Studios side by side
I'll inherently Define an agency as
people that are providing services with
the idea that they want to scale those
Services up you want to be able to
provide more of those Services whether
you want that to be 40 people 100 people
a th000 people you want to continue
providing those and make more money also
with an agency you kind of want to be at
least some people's full-time thing and
you're going to Define it as you're kind
of purely doing Services there are some
ways you can develop your agencies to
use your internal hours to spin off
projects and things but the core of that
business is going to be getting money
from services and when you're small
doing multiple things in an agency while
you're trying to scale it can be more of
a distraction than it is good but for a
collective the idea is different this is
you working with people you like or have
a relationship with to offer a set of
things and not necessarily trying to
scale at large basically saying hey we
just want to be able to get some side
work but get it as a group or we want to
be able to work on some creative
projects together to help generate
interest put something out in the world
make make some money and also get get
interest in our work and this like
Collective or Studio idea is is really
important I feel like in this time
because what we're seeing is uh you know
this this world where creatives are
really afraid of AI and all these things
that can potentially like take the jobs
that they do right like if you are a
freelance illustrator your work options
are a lot more limited now due to AI
right it can do a lot of that job so
creatives are forced to become more
multi-disciplinary you're you're more
useful if you are an art director who is
also a video editor you know a social
media manager who is also a designer and
you are in any of those single roles and
that's only going to continue and as
technology gets smarter as overseas
Talent gets better that's the other
thing most people are competing with
overseas talent that will do a similar
job cheaper especially if you're not
really Best in Class then you need to be
able to kind of put your solution
together and the answer to that solution
is working with others because if you
come in a package you're saving
whoever's hiring you out time you're
probably doing it cheaper than a larger
agency would be able to do and you can
kind of do more interesting work but
also you're able to then execute
projects and try things out on your own
you guys can do for fun and for interest
and I like to define a creative Studio
as a group of people that is making a
project usually there's one person or
two people that are kind of central to
it that that kind of drive it who are
saying we provide services to some
extent but it's not our full-time thing
like that's that's the kind of the core
that like we do not purely just provide
services the anchor we also do just pure
creative projects like we do some things
together without money being a variable
and we are interested in developing
products and selling things like you
know branded things Etc like underneath
the studio name as well whether that's
info products software or physical
products and it's not like it's a
different business type or anything it's
more of an idea to get in your your mind
and a concept when you work yourself
with other people to start out so that's
how I run my business valuable student
so I was making a lot of content so as
you know my background of a really large
short form social media presence I was
getting a lot of work for that
Consulting agency style work making
websites doing email marketing brand
strategy Etc I decided I do not want to
do that work and that just clearly came
down to I've done that my whole life I'm
generating a lot of value for other
people at the stage I've at in my career
I'm more interested in things I have
equity and ownership in that I can sell
down the road or that provide me a
vehicle for Creative expression for the
things I really enjoy and the things I
want to enjoy making money on is a high
value ratio of the money I make to the
time and energy I put in and how much I
enjoy so I took all the freelance work
that I was doing and I passed it to
another creative and this was a decent
amount of work 20 25k month and like yes
fre you get shock like that's just like
the side work like not even the main
like if you are really an optimized
carea if you can actually make a lot of
money but I'm not a channel telling you
that you can go make millions of dollars
or trying to set you up to do that
there's like other channels for that
it's just but just for context but when
people talk about hey I want to develop
a studio I want to do things with other
people I want to set up a you know like
a small creative firm I don't want to
scale it the common questions you get
are oh that's not sell or what happens
if you want to step out of that business
right and I think the key thing you note
about like smaller creative collectives
is there about relationships so if you
do have someone that has a similar skill
set You're Building bringing someone up
underneath you and like I have a lot of
people who are one level down from where
I'm at who I either give mentorship
advice to or who I work on projects with
or who have come along with me through
things I've worked on that I'm happy to
like continually give work to right it's
a perfect scenario like this where some
of them are looking for more work
actively because they're not at the
point in their career where they can
just generate work on demand whereas I'm
looking to shed that work I still want
to get fiscal value and so I'm able to
say hey here's this amount of work can I
get you x% back on that for x amount of
time or whatever it looks like to be
able to make that transition and like
that's the kind of things you can have
when you have a open conversation about
money between creators that's the last
note I'll make around um around
collectives is this the idea there is
about creatives that trust each other
right it's not about hey I just hire
this freelancer or grab this random
person the creative business is a much
more relationship driven business and a
lot of other more transactional
businesses because you not only have to
work with someone well in a creative way
and a lot of nuance to how creatives
work that other Industries don't
understand but also there's a huge trust
level right like if you don't get paid
or if you don't come through with the
project on time like it's a problem and
I I basically have a a one strike it's a
one strike like unless like some major
life event came up or like someone
someone passed away like it's really
hard to rely on anyone especially when
you begin to have a reputation that you
need to be able to trust other folks and
a big part of that is having open
conversations too right if you're
selling a 10K website package and you're
paying a developer 2500 to that 10K and
at some point they might see that 10K
invoice you need to be able to
tactically explain and break it down
just so they know and eliminate the
conversation being like hey I'm paying
you 2500 bucks paying the desire 2500
bucks I'm taking 5K because I brought in
the business I'm project managing it and
I'm going to do the copyrighting like
and that that's the breakdown so
everyone's clear but having that
communication and people all knowing
what happened and no one getting feeling
some type of way down the line or having
the opportunity to express that stuff
early is really important and builds
that creative Rapport where people will
feel like they're being traded fairly
they know the wiggle room or
conversation they have within it and you
can actually break down numbers so I
would highly encourage when you are
creative to work together and share
money and the reason I'm sharing you
know some money Insight in this too is I
just feel like we don't talk about it
enough like as a creative
entrepreneurial Community um versus the
people that are you know purely about
money they talk about it all the time so
anyway back to where what I was doing so
with valuable Studios I was like hey I I
talk a lot my short form content a lot
is about designing things about creating
products about fashion and apparel and
whatnot but I'm mainly talking about
other people's stuff and so much like I
was doing work where I was talking about
where I was for other people I'm now
making content talking about other
people and some of the projects I have
my core projects are kind of weird for
me to make content about one of the
brands I've worked on forever is a
women's wear brand it's just not quite
like the right fit to make content about
our agency like I mentioned is like a
hardware software engineering agency
also like I I well no well enough to
differentiate the content that works
like or or not like one of my big
clients at that same time was a like a
surf company or a again there's not the
overlap with like the market I'm trying
to reach but I said all right one of the
things that will be most useful to me is
be able to show people through products
that I sell the things that I'm capable
of doing from a creative Direction
standpoint and from a product
development standpoint and also to be
able to fiscally choose something and
say hey I don't want something that's
purely representative of me but it's
also representative of things I think
can sell that have an identity that I
think is missing in the market so I
started this valuable Studios brand I
released clothing and and accessories
underneath it and I released a pretty
wide range of that and it's not because
I thought I could sell that out
immediately based on my following I knew
it would take some time to move through
a number of these things because I want
to show people the breadth of what's
what's possible and then at the same
time like almost immediately as soon as
people started getting the actual items
I was getting inquiries about work to
develop those products for other people
I have a bunch of that that work
happening now that's way more
interesting than the work I was getting
inquiries for prior and similar to what
I want to do and then now that I'm
putting out a bunch of the ads and the
assets I'm getting a bunch of creative
Direction ask about hey we want things
that look like that what does that look
like and that puts me in a position
where people know that I offer that kind
of work they know I have this brand they
can see the example of it where I'm able
to position myself where I can they know
exactly what they can expect when they
work with it I have a framework with
which I can apply it I'm developing all
these things and using it and I can be
more Discerning in what I accept or not
because I can I I have a a commercial
vehicle that is um like making money on
its own right I can say hey is this the
right fit for the brand or fit for that
versus having to take that work and so
that's really important to me I feel
like it's important for a lot of
creatives to have a vehicle I'll talk
about agencies first and then we'll get
into Vehicles so the agency business is
a great business I actually highly
encourage most people especially with a
creative skill set to start an agency
instead of starting a brand or to start
them in Tandem and this is for a couple
of reasons right cash flow being one of
the biggest ones I often get asked like
how do I fund the number of things that
like I do and I work on and a lot of it
came from like living a really lean life
earlier in life which I'll I'll talk
about in a minute cuz I thought I would
be like a retire early type but ended up
not wanting that and the other is like
now especially I have income coming in
as a Creator and income coming in from
freelance I can then use to like fund
The Ordering of inventory or fund
initial shooter or creative Direction I
can come into projects with some of my
own money to put into that which is not
something everyone can do but Services
enable the ability to do that we'll talk
about that again in the vehical section
because agencies are actually a great
enabler of of spinning off projects but
you can start an agency without having
to have a bunch of cash flow right you
just you need the people that are
invested in it and working on it we
started our agency was three of us in a
Wei workor and we booked our first few
clients we hired pretty quickly you know
we got got to 10 relatively fast but we
didn't have to have a bunch of money to
put in no one was expecting a salary to
start you but we were all paying
ourselves within like 60 days the key
things the differentia an agency wanting
to start and scale that and why it's
interesting and I'm not going to talk to
you like any like like that make 10K a
month gurus like this is p like if you
genuinely want to start a creative thing
is you build that knowing that you want
to scale it up to a certain level and
have that conversation early do I want
to have a 20 person thing that makes me
a good lifestyle business that makes a
bunch of money do I want to have a 100
person thing that's like noted and and
creative and like competes and people
regard really well it's pretty decent
size do I want to build a major agency
and I have some aspirations of something
big I would think about that at the
beginning of what you set out to do I'd
also be thinking about that regularly
every year or so at least about what you
think that future looks like it
determines your path but no matter what
whether you want to be 20 people in a
good lifestyle business I think that's
about the right size to actually get
agencies to make decent money or you
want to end up being like large and
really competing for for major work you
have to build with scale in mind now
what does that mean that means that you
have process this is a hard part for a
lot of different creatives but what
makes people stand out or not is does
everything you do with the agent spelled
out and documents somewhere that
everyone is forced to learn and operate
under the principles of so so for
instance how we onboard a client the
emails they get when they're
communicated what are proposals what the
updates that we send every week look
like how we track our hours how we
present our deliverables what they're
you know what all the way down to like
do we send out Christmas gifts do we
send out new client gifts to how does a
team member on board how do they report
their hours what is their one-on-one
scenarios with their manager like how do
we hire what do we look for when we hire
all this needs to be documented I would
say not necessarily the first time you
do it but like the third time you do it
the 10th time you do do it once you've
refined it a bit turn it into a process
and have a process with which you are
pushing process out to your team and
stick with it because this enables you
to a step out of the business something
you can't really do in a collective
right that's a kind of thing where
you're just in it it's a natural vehicle
for you to make money versus an agency
need to establish that and scale it and
secondly be looking for that scale be
understanding that you need to always
have more work there's always more stuff
that has to come in and that is a focus
of the of the company where some people
need to really just focus on new
business and not everyone's going to be
able to just be creative and you're
never going to be able to hire some
silver bullet like sales guy it's going
to fix your problems it's going to end
up being you and whoever you kind of
started this thing with are going to be
the people that are responsible for that
and the earlier you take responsibility
for that the better I would not
recommend starting that no matter what
gurus will tell you what until you have
had experience working in one already
you've seen how building and client
relationships and management go for that
and the ups and downs and hurdles of
that life before you decide to want to
sign up for it and this is why my
general career advice for most younger
creatives is to spend 2 years four years
in a at a brand brand that is a say a 15
person to 4 person brand like on the
smaller sides you can wear multiple hats
but see what it actually takes to like
sell a thing and like build a brand and
have it operate if you're at a Big Brand
you're not going to learn any of that
and you're going to be siloed and a lot
of what you learn is not applicable to
the real world and then an agency at
that similar size range like 20 to Max
100 where you're going to wear multiple
hats you're going to be super busy it's
going to be rough you're going to see it
scaling you'll see the seasonality and
you're going to have work through what
it's like to manage and juggle multiple
clients and people if you have both of
those experiences you're going to be
really prepared for do I want to have a
brand now or in the future do I want to
have an agency now we in the future and
like what it actually takes to do it and
I would I think as a crucial basically
five to to 8year road map in the
beginning of any creative career that
people should really follow if they want
to be big best set up for where they go
from the future and a lot of people want
to have that answer too quick but I
don't think you're going to really have
the toolkit especially as a creative to
be entrepreneurial the way you want
until you're in that 26 27 range anyway
unless you're like a very particularly
driven type of person who's like set to
be an entrepreneur from the start but a
lot of creative people are better off
refining the skill sets and then
applying it than they are just jumping
in so I've used this word vehicle a lot
this whole time so the reason I like
this idea of collectives or Studios a
lot of people need a they need a reason
to put out their own work and they need
permission to put out their own because
you feel weird about like okay I can
post my my illustrations on Instagram or
whatever it is but like how do I
actually commercialize the thing that I
do and every artist inside dies a little
bit when they hear commercialization of
what they do but most of us are going to
end up wanting to or having to do that
at some point so a vehicle gives you the
opportunity to do that and a vehicle is
basically like an entity whether that's
like an LLC or a Corp or business you
have with friends or business you have
yourself where it is has a mission for
which you are going to make money you
are able to put stuff out you have a
website you have a social media
following you have an email newsletter
you have all the things that enable you
on Dem on command to be able to push out
stuff that you want to be able to say
hey I want to release this thing or I
have this idea and I can put it out
there in the universe like that's a
vehicle so for me like for valuable
Studios for instance like I have this
Americana and like car Focus stuff I put
out now I may be interested in that
forever and run that brand looking like
that in that particular way to that
demographic forever or in 6 months I
might be like you know what like I want
to go in a brutalist t for the next 9
months and I'm going to make like
brutalist desk ornaments and I just go
and I hammer that I can and and it will
be people know that since it is related
to me is an extension of of my social
media if I go change the nature of it
and put something out that fits my
Creative Vision that won't be unexpected
and I encourage most people to create
that vehicle for them and agencies are a
vehicle in their own way too because you
have resources and those resources
sometimes are fully allocated and they
sometimes so something when we were
building our engineering agencies we
dedicated the certain number of our
hours towards internal projects things
we wanted to develop and some of those
actually ended up going really well
there was a major retail brand that
actually spun out have an idea that went
for that and then now we actually have a
major really interesting software um
software that connects to Hardware
basically just to dive deep into a
second but it is a a Diagnostics and
analytics service that goes can go into
any hardware with a smart battery
whether that's a smart bike whether
that's a GoPro camera a drone even a
vehicle with a smart battery we can read
all the things that are coming out of it
locations where things are the trouble
that any of those have had and we can
put it into a a dashboard that enables
people to actually make decisions based
on another thing that we developed
internally that we have are looking to
commercialize outside of it but either
one of those things like a lot of people
create agencies they don't have any
vehicle within it they never have the
bandwidth for it they're always
overworked and they can't devote any
hours for it or they don't have the
proclivity to let that be part of their
DNA from the beginning we were all very
entrepreneurial who started this so we
always wanted it to be like a core of it
like having that whether it's from a
studio whether it's having your own
personal brand whatever it is having
that vehicle where you know okay if I
have an idea I have resources and other
people to help get it out and I have a
framework with an existing audience an
existing infrastructure and building or
whatever to push that out there is
really big thing and going back to the
collective or Studio idea this is always
interesting to me too because if you
have something that works you can spin
it out like so for instance if uh if my
valuables bring the car accessories
portion of this takes off and I really
started like okay this is a vehicle
focused brand I may either keep that
brand and just say cool this just as car
accessories now and then I develop
something else personally for me or I
may say actually you know what that
actually served better with a better
name spun out with a separate business
with someone else operating it and to be
really focused on this product Market
fit that we found and going and doing
that like that's a way I think you have
to think as a creative as you expand
your ways to make money is like all
right how do I put operators in place
inside businesses Which business is
related how do I have multiple and
people always uh I did a Tik Tok where I
broke down like all my various like
businesses and streams of income which I
think a lot of people found relatively
shocking is because there's a lot and uh
and I say that to say that you always
hear about someone like you know like
Trump got sued right at some point like
and someone they were talking about hey
how how many businesses he has he has
like hundreds of businesses right and
there's these big business people that
have like hundreds of hundreds of
businesses I can see how people can get
there because and it's it's hard for the
average creative person to see CU they
get overwhelmed thinking about one
business bu nonetheless like two then
you start to realize a business is just
a game of like okay something's working
can you put it on somewhat autopilot can
you set up a team with a process that
runs it and you just check in on it or
can you then pay someone to come in as
an operator to then run that business
because you built a playbook for it so
you can step out and do something else
as a creative with a studio there's also
this idea of passing the vuon so just
like I pushed all my consultancy work
over to a friend when I no longer want
to do that work better that that gets
saved than abandoned right it's the same
thing with say valuable studios in seven
years is a you know a a midsized
creative brand that does clothing and
HomeGoods and whatever and I no longer
want to do that but it's not scaled to
the point where I can sell it it would
be interesting for me to say hey here's
a younger creative who has a vision
don't you why you walk into this brand
that has a legacy that has a customer
base that has X and Y and you be the new
face and vision of it similar to how a
creative director passes passes the
Baton and you know you're you get some
ownership you get paid underneath that
you do the things that I would have done
prior but you get to go take it in your
own Direction like that is a an
opportunity with some of these more
Boutique brands that again aren't
thought about in traditional business in
the same ways right because there isn't
that same creative element always but as
you go on your career you're going to
end up thinking through a lot of this
you're going to be freelancing at some
points you may be freelancing with a few
others and forming like these loose-knit
Collective versions in the meantime you
may have a studio as your create a
vehicle you may want to sced an agency
you may end up doing a brand by thinking
through all this and kind of how to
approach it and and knowing the options
that exist I feel like it's really
useful to begin to like develop the full
toolkit you have as like a creative
entrepreneur and I find that there's
like two creative types right there's
obsessive creatives actually say
probably not in the right word there's
ADHD creatives and then there's type
creatives right the type creatives are
like every single space of every single
current is completely perfect and they
are obsessed with the execution of their
one thing and there's creatives who like
have a bunch of ideas and who work
really well on any number of things but
need to be bouncing back and forth
between a bunch of stuff or they go
insane I am definitely the latter and
for all these businesses the biggest
differentiator as much as no one wants
to hear it is having amazing social
media and I say this because it's also a
massive competitive advantage against
incumbents just like how traditional
Brands can get disrupted by smaller
Brands they're more Nimble on Tik Tok
shop who or who can do more better
organic content the same is also true
for agencies and trust me I get this all
the time I have massive agencies to
reach out relatively frequently to try
to figure out how to get their content
right and when you actually tell them
what they need to do they really don't
want to hear it few actually act on it
and just go look at the content even
like the agencies that do good work
right now and that is a opportunity
because small Freelancers and small
groups are who are good at social media
are getting outsized work and a couple
things that are worth kind of framing
around I also have a lot of in the
program I have cut 30 we do like 30 days
of content workshopping learning how to
make content like this obviously get a
lot of creatives a lot of creatives in
the audience and a few anecdotes from
that that I think are are really useful
are one was we had an existing creator
with a decent following you know good
conceptual content it didn't necessarily
drive him like a ton of business or like
the views that the quality of what he
was putting out would so he would do
like film appreciation he'd be like
here's what I like about the
cinematography of the bear and we
reposition that like so in the program
we do a lot like strategy and
workshopping like why do content's bad
how do you make it good and we were
saying hey instead of being like let's
talk about why we like the
cinematography the bear here's the bear
cinematography Playbook like the six
Tech techniques you can use to replicate
so it immediately become bookmarkable
and sharable people working on something
like this say hey let's use these
techniques let's do this thing here's a
specific stuff to do you're still
appreciating it but then also you become
if you're able to show it off and show
your work and show your work in context
with this like great work like he's
doing as someone hey if I want to get
that style of stuff I should go to this
guy and like that is a key positioning
thing is the kind of stuff we Workshop
in there all the time that people just
don't realize it's like how do you take
an idea from hey let me just present my
work let me present this thing I like to
let me develop something that is useful
and savable and sharable and something
that also positions me as the kind of
person that could execute this is why
like I make a lot of videos about
creative Direction and collaboration and
those kind of techniques and I get hit
up for all of work about it because
you'll know a key thing I do in 90% of
those videos is I don't just go here's
what happened I go here's what happened
and here's what I would do if I was in
this position or what I would do if I
was going to make this better and just
by adding that point on it I immediately
and putting myself the people are
putting themselves in the shoes of oh if
this person was doing that for me what
could I get out of and then another one
we had in in this in the same last
session was a um a creative where she
was you had an intersection basically of
like marketing advertising design and
then Fitness and Wellness this is
something that I encourage people really
heavily to lay into when they're making
content and I think most agencies have
an opportunity to is if you like
specialize whether you're an agency or a
collective and you say we're really into
you know the intersection of Art and
technology or uh the the intersection of
fitness and you know social media
whatever that you find those two items
is you should be really on top of the
things that are happening so you know
this I put out content before wasn't
telling the stories that were like
relevant and virally exciting hit really
quick with stuff about the Olympics and
then continue to make more content
specifically about that like and the
things that that spread out around it
and if you have a unique Viewpoint like
for instance if you are doing like you
know Sports and then marketing and you
talk about the things that are happening
there all the time you become synonymous
with that expertise and it's just
something that I feel like is is
completely worth doing another example
I'll give this is um there's this agency
called dark room one of the guys in had
done uh C 30 a while back I'm actually
about to do some content with them
because I'm using their services for
design stuff I work on but he does great
content a combination of video and
written where they'll be like here's
just trending and interesting things
happening in our Niche so their agency
is immediately associated with like
people who know what's going on like
they know the hot stuff that's happening
and then they'll do longer content like
Hey we're actually going to do like spec
ad we're going to go you know redo a
bunch of ads for like X brand I'm going
to post the whole thing from how I
concept it to how we design it to like
some of the auto layouts and things that
we have that we use for our clients and
like so you can actually see the tactics
of it but uh by having that combination
of like okay now you begin to people
think of okay who knows trending Brands
and stuff okay well I know this guy
posts about it he has a big agency okay
well like what kind of work should they
do oh I can actually watch them work and
see how they think about it like through
through the content it's not even their
client work it's like spec work for like
a existing brand and so I think that if
you begin to put those Frameworks out
there where you're documenting the
things that you do where you're
presenting your knowledge of the space
in the particular intersection that
you're into where you're presenting your
Viewpoint playbooks to execute on it and
you're actually showing some of the work
and behind the scenes you do even if
again you can email once a month you can
make a video once a week whatever it is
establishing that Canon of that over the
course of that business doing it from
that perspective you are going to be
just a million times better than even
like the biggest agencies right now
which is a unique opportunity to like
basically get that work so I will link
the video here I have like a get started
making creative content video that like
breaks down like here's the exact
software and equipment and stuff like
that so if you want to do that and then
we run cut 30 every six weeks the next
one's Tuesday September 24th and we have
another one uh before the end of the
year so if you do want to run that
you're welcome to join I do encourage
you to hit with the free resources and
things first and kind of see where your
head's at and then if you want to come
Workshop and really get after it then
it's cup 3.co but anyway I'm working on
two additional videos should be out here
the next week one I'm going to do
another Vlog I haven't done one in a
while uh breaking down some of the
things are happening in my life that I'm
working on right now and another thing
is I I'm launching a project that kind
of cre directed all the products um and
then worked with Clayton from from hyper
who I have my newsletter with to to kind
creative direct some of the release
around uh and so I'm going to document a
bunch of that so you can actually see
some you know product development
creative Direction stuff stuff in action
uh be a little bit different than the
type of content I normally do I'm still
working on a uh another where I'm like
basically responding to content that
Brands and and uh creators do like
breaking it down really tactically for
people so I have a few different types
of videos that are coming out um they'll
be having here in a few weeks last week
I had had too much travel so so
definitely miss one of these but also
drop any questions you have in the
comments I am still doing these like six
minute yaps on Tik Tok they're actually
going pretty well um so I'm starting to
get some pretty serious views and I'm
responding to questions on there so if
you do want to get like more direct
quicker feedback or feedback in the form
of a video then pop on over to Tik Tok
also or Meets World and thank you for
watching