Today we are going to talk about
building an email newsletter. So whether
you are considering it for the first
time and you want to actually grow it,
get to a certain velocity, make some
money off it, or you have an existing
newsletter and it's not where you want
to be, you want to take it to the next
level, we're going to break it down. So
why are we talking about this? I looked
around recently and realized most of my
good friends have an email newsletter
that's like a critical part of their
life and their business. Having to write
and put something out there even to a
small amount of subscribers forces you
to establish a cohesive narrative of
thought which brain rot internet has
taken away from us. It also gives people
who make content or who are doing things
in the world a easy call to action to
offer people where you don't have to buy
something or dive in but you can
subscribe to the newsletter which lets
you retain people off of a network. Then
obviously there's monetization. We'll
get to my newsletter business in a
minute but I know a lot of people that
make good money casually off of their
newsletter. But most importantly, it is
interest on demand for the rest of your
life. Even if there's a 100 people all
the way up to 100,000, whatever idea or
offer or thing that you want to put out
there for the rest of your life, you
have an email list that will activate to
validate. So, in this video, we're going
to cover my experience building a
six-figure newsletter business with
Hyper and how we got there. I'm talk
about several of my friends businesses.
For instance, I do Hyper with another
creator, Clayton, who has his own
newsletter called Spreza that also
generates good income for him. It's
really interesting. I'm going to walk
through some of my favorite examples in
the space of different types of
newsletters. We're going to go through
the various email platforms in which you
should choose and why. We're going to
talk about making a standout newsletter
because a good newsletter isn't just
about you, but there's several direct
paths you can take to actually make
people care about what you're doing.
We're going to go through a section on
growing your newsletter and actual
tactics to get subscribers. And then
last, we're going to hit how you
actually make some money off this. But
overall, I pretty firmly believe that
anyone who puts some intention in for
about 24 months can get a newsletter
that makes them, if not six figures,
pretty close to it. Now, I don't put a
lot of dollar figures in any of my
videos or say, "Hey, is this how you
make money online or anything?" But
newsletters is actually one of the best,
most monetizable things that people can
have, and I'm always consistently
surprised by how many people I know that
make money doing. If you've ever wanted
to send your ideas to thousands and
thousands of people and see how they
respond, let's lock in. So, first, let's
talk about my experience building email
newsletters. I actually got my start as
a marketer, diving really deep into
email. This was on the brand side. We're
focused mainly on newsletters here. But
I worked for a director of marketing. I
think actually VP of marketing at the
time who was encouraging me to build my
skill set. I had been a designer. I was
getting into marketing and he was like,
"Hey, if you want to have longevity in
your career, you need to learn more
things." So he uh encouraged me to do
training with the email system we had at
that company, which was Eloqua at the
time, if you remember that. And when I
moved into different industries, I kind
of took that expertise with me. So, in
one of my next businesses, I had a
agency, a product development agency,
all contract engineering, with a friend
of mine who had worked for prior, who
had a pretty big personality and a known
presence on the internet. He was like a
minor celebrity for lack of a better
term. And I helped build his email
newsletter. The brand we worked at
together, I had the emails coming from
his name. We started out a separate news
from him. We then used his name and
likeness and his LinkedIn, a number of
other things to build that newsletter to
be a lead funnel for our agency. And it
was one of the most critical generators
of business for us was we had this all
in ConvertKit at the time. I'll talk
about software in a minute, but we built
up a 20 25,000 person email list off of
very niche downloads. Our agency was
extremely focused on robotics and
aerospace. Basically, anything with an
autopilot or a sensor. Like this is
pretty niche stuff. And we built up one
of the biggest lists like in that
category that then drove work for the
agency. And that formed the impetus for
me to say, why am I not doing this
myself? So, I started a newsletter
before I became a video creator. I was
building it mostly on X. I grew it to
several thousand people. Didn't make any
money off of it. Started to use it to
work with my creator items as I became a
video creator and then it became an
extension of my creator business and I
partnered with Clayton who I run the
newsletter on now and said, "Hey, it
shouldn't be my newsletter. It should be
a a bigger thing than that. We worked
really hard to grow it. It's 35,000 subs
now." And it's a six-figure newsletter
business where we sell mostly
advertisements and then also other
packages and things that go with that.
We built that all on Beehive. I'm
familiar with all these various
platforms. And this is a good segue into
what platform should you choose to build
your email newsletter. So, as many of
you know, I run my brand email off of
Omnisend. Now, I ran off Claio for many
years. Claio raised their prices
recently, which is a good impetus to
switch over to Omnisend because the
pricing got kind of crazy. But that's
good for brand email. You're choosing
basically between Claio and Omnisend and
a few others for brand email. We're
talking about email blast and
newsletters here. So, that it really
comes down to Beehive, Substack, Convert
Kit. Anything else you're choosing for
this, I would not recommend. You are
choosing between those three. And
really, you're choosing between Beehive
and Substack. I built my first
newsletter on ConvertKit. I built that
former gurus newsletter on ConvertKit.
I've used it a lot. They're they are
behind now in terms of the opportunity
they allow for writers and creators. And
so, I'm going to push that back and just
focus on Beehive and Substack because
those are your kind of two core choices
and why and how to do it. So, there's a
huge moment happening right now on
Substack because Substack is a email
platform that is also basically a social
network. Your posts show up into a feed.
You can post on a feed. There is a
built-in recommendation system and
people who are on Substack, who are any
level of social, have other
relationships with Substack people and
who post frequently on there or post
elsewhere, want to make content around
their Substack category can grow very
organically on there. You will get an
organic boost, which basically means
more email subscribers by going into the
Substack ecosystem. This is something we
talk about extensively at our
hypernewsletter because we say, "Hey,
we're 35,000 now. If we've been on
Substack the last year, we'd probably be
50." And there's some reasons why and
why not to choose that network. I'll get
into. But if you are focused primarily
on growth from your email, then Substack
is the choice to work on. But with a
caveat, you need to be social. You need
to be able to work with other creators
to say, "Hey, I'll feature your email
newsletter and you feature mine. You
need to be posting on the Substack
algorithm. Have relationships. Push
subscribers over there." It may be hard
to do all that from zero. You may not
know anyone. This is whole new for you.
In which case, this may not be the
thing. The other core thing about this
is if you are selling subscriptions,
they take a pretty hefty percent. It's
like 10% of all subscription revenue on
there. adds up is an expensive
proposition if you are really selling
through that to do all that through
there. And so there's some
considerations to have before you get
into it. But if your main focus is I
want to get as many subs as possible,
you're going to have any level of
relationships with other people that do,
Substack is the place to go. Then next
up we have Beehive, which we currently
run our newsletter on. So Beehive is an
excellent place to monetize your
newsletter. Has all the same growth
tools. They have a website builder
within there that's really solid, all
the same kind of email tools. They have
a great system for referral which we'll
talk about inside the growth program of
this where you can have your subscribers
bring more people to you. They also have
recommendations but doesn't have the
same power of substacks but they give
you business. Every time I log into
behive there is a list of people that
want to fill slots inside our
newsletter. And it's lower price than if
we sold those ads ourselves but
basically any newsletter we want to send
we can get somewhere between $150 and
$500 from a beehive placed newsletter
segment. We had a Nike feature for Nike
Air Max inside of our Beehive newsletter
the other week. They basically work with
companies to fill inventory at certain
prices and they'll basically on click or
on opens and you have a endless option
to insert ads into your newsletter which
means if you are not someone who wants
to do sales or feels like you have a
flow to be able to get newsletter in
there, they will get you money inside
this especially if you have topics that
brands like to talk about. So, it's a
real huge consideration and one of the
reasons I recommend the network most is
I know a lot of people especially
writers are not salespeople and beehive
will do some of that job for you and you
start to get to a decent sized
newsletter that money is going to kind
of be built in for whenever you need it.
So, when it really comes down to your
core choice, behive gives you a little
more individuality, a better of a
website experience, and gives you better
monetization opportunities for for
basically ad placement. And Subsack
gives you more of a network to grow and
get you more subscribers. Don't
overthink it. Start with either one,
whichever name you like better,
whatever. The core of starting an email
newsletter is just to start it. If
you're starting a brand, run a business,
or have multiple businesses, I found an
excellent business banking platform
setup you should check out called Relay.
Whenever anyone asks what I wish I'd
done differently in my earliest
businesses, it would be having a
relentless focus on cash flow
visibility. Now that I have all these
projects going on, it's about ease of
management and visibility for multiple
things in one place. If you're starting
a new business, Relay has no minimum
balances and no hidden charges or fees.
It's an excellent starter option from a
business banking platform that
understands the entrepreneurship
experience and is built around it. And
when you get more advanced, you can
actually manage multiple entities from
one login, so you don't have to keep
jumping around accounts just to keep
track of everything. If you're paying
contractors, Relay lets you request
their payment info securely. Plus, you
can ask for a W9 upfront, so you have
less headache at tax time. Another thing
I love is you can create multiple
checking and savings accounts inside
Relay to better organize your cash flow.
You can even set up automatic transfer
rules so money moves the way you want it
to without having to manually do it
every time. If you're growing a business
and want a banking setup that actually
feels like it's designed for you, Relay
is a really strong option. Check out the
link in my description to learn more.
And thank you so much to Relay for
sponsoring this video. So, now we're
going to talk what makes a standout
newsletter. I'm going to run through
some examples cuz I have so many friends
who have newsletters I absolutely love.
And then we'll get into how do you
actually drive demand for those. But the
thing that most matters most is not
driving demand. That is the concept. The
concept is what matters in a newsletter.
There are so many newsletters out there.
If you want to start one today, you are
in an endlessly competitive world. And
one thing I want to call is don't just
make it about you. When I started my
newsletter, it was called product
people. It was really based on
factories. I want to send people factory
links and help them find and build
products. And so that was saying, hey,
there's a niche there. Someone isn't
doing it. I'm going to do it. But
eventually turned into Orin's newsletter
talking about the content I made, etc.
But also that inherently is cool. People
want to hear about that. doesn't have
that same like virality or growth that
comes from some of the tactics I'm about
to talk through. And this is why we
transitioned it to Hyper and the brand
now is it is a brand strategy
newsletter. We are the number one place
you can go for brand strategy. If you
care about that as an entrepreneur, a
marketer, a designer, you will get ideas
and functions from that and that's where
we've zoned in. But there's three core
categories to establish a standout
newsletter. One is finding a new zone, a
new angle, something other people
haven't done, a unique lens. We'll talk
about that in a second. The second is a
topical deep dive. Similar to what I
talked about with factories, but with
things that work. Then we have media
replacement. Things that people used to
read traditional media for, but since
traditional media isn't consumed
anymore, people who are replacing that
via email. So, let's talk these through
one by one. So, I want to talk about a
new zone. What do I mean? A new idea.
So, there's two newsletters that come to
mind for me. The first is my friend
Andrea who has a newsletter called
Snackshot. The other is my friend Casey
Lewis who has a newsletter called After
School. Let's focus on Snackshot first.
Andrea's newsletter which is amazing. I
remember when it came out because there
was nothing else like it. That was what
was inspiring. She took this idea of
snacks. Her entire newsletter is about
snacks. She would put out these
intricately thought out filled with
amazing graphics that she designed
herself deep dives into, you know, the
the sexualization of of food or like in
and how that's going into packaging or
its overlap with religion or this this
new deep dive in all these different
packages that came out. She had a
serious thing called Iracular
Spectacular based like off the MGMT name
where she break down all these different
categories and items. But she said, "I'm
going to take a niche that is not
written about considerably or only
written about by these legacy
publications and I'm going to put a
twist on it. I'm going to go really
cultural. I'm going to identify all the
new emerging things. I'm going to find
trends from that deepest person in this
niche that exists." And she was and she
thought about it critically and there's
nothing else like it. And so if you want
to be in the mix, you are even
tangentially related to the food
industry. She became like a must readad.
Now the next I want to talk about Casey
Lewis. She has a newsletter called After
School. It's my favorite newsletter that
I read because it has a complete unique
lens I would never get anywhere else.
She writes about Gen Z culture. Bo
basically be like, "What is Gen Z
thinking and talking and walking about
and she made a newsletter that only
talks about that." So, for instance,
when Thanksgiving or Christmas, she'll
be like, "Here's I watched 500 Gen Z Tik
Tok haul videos so you don't have to."
And then broke down what Gen Z is
buying. She's doing work that research
firms wouldn't do, right? That isn't
necessarily happening anywhere else, but
is absolutely fascinating if you work
selling anything. And so, those are
examples of unique ideas. If you want to
make a standout newsletter, what lens
can you look at? You're finding a unique
presented lens with which no one else
talks. That is number one, the best
item, the hardest item because you need
an original idea, an original focus.
Most people aren't going to be able to
do that, and that's okay, but that is
like the way to stand out. And the
second category, which is most likely
for a lot of people, is what's called a
topical deep dive. And a lot of people
do newsletters like this, newsletters
about a subject. I'm going to tell you
how to make them good. So this is you
take one topic, marketing, computers,
electronics, whatever it is, and you
just talk about in their newsletter. And
a good example of this is uh Rachel
Carton. She has a newsletter called
Lincoln Bio for social media managers.
Her entire purpose of this is news for
social media managers. Now, there's many
websites that focus on social media,
right? Hers is good because she has made
a an effort to be a tactical responsive
platform about this subject. And this
would be the same thing for you.
Whatever niche you're in, you're
competing against a ton of newsletters
out there. Look at Rachel as a model is
a great one where in her newsletters,
she basically has a list of things to
try every week. So basically every week
a social media manager can open that
newsletter and be like, "Here's the
things I I can I have ideas this week.
It's saving me some time in my job."
Critical component. What can you do
inside your newsletter that if someone
opens it up in your target demo, they
can use it immediately. And she also
does timely interviews. It's not just an
interview series around her niche, which
there's plenty of, but hey, a new
campaign will come out that's everyone's
talking about. She'll have the social
media manager on. She's quick to be
like, I'm going to find what's
happening. And then give people info on
what's happening so it's relevant. And I
want to talk about my friend Jacob. He
ran through Cut 30 a while back and he
makes content just about Salem, Oregon.
So Jacob turned his local Instagram
account, which began to do very well,
into a local newsletter. And that's
exactly what Jacob has, right? Where
he's saying, "Hey, cool. I'm going to
present all the things that, you know,
if I'm in a region where it doesn't have
the right local news, local news doesn't
cover what people actually want. We're
going to talk about everything from
restaurant openings to important
political things to what's actually
happening to spotlighting local people."
And there is a niche for that, right?
And you cover that niche with care and
attention and you stand out. So we had
this like new zone category. We had
these topical deep dive categories. And
the third category is what we call media
replacement. So right now you go to try
to to read an article on anything you
may have read three years ago. You go
even Apple News or Business Insider or
whatever you you notice a trend, right?
Everything is paywalt. There's ads and
stuff all over it to make it hard to
actually read and consume. And the
articles suck. Like people writing it
are worse than ever. And it's like not
the info you wanted. They're not
thorough. Like traditional media is at
the worst state it's ever been. It's
only going to get worse. And if you work
in that industry, you need to get out.
Now what is happening is media
replacement is happening by single
writers right it doesn't take a writer's
room to execute a lot of what's
happening how does that work so two
examples a woman I know Emily Sunberg
has a newsletter called feed me and for
me that's actually replaced a
significant amount of things I used to
read if I was browsing Apple news and
looking at the economist or looking at
like articles from the New York Times or
whatever that she's basically taking my
interest level of those similar things
and she's just been like I am making my
version of it and it's good it's well
written it's funny and it was replacing
traditional media and is worth her her
her substacks like four or five bucks
completely worth it every month for me.
Same thing with my friend Nate. So Nate
has a newsletter called Express Checkout
where he does the same thing. He
aggregates CPG, so consumer package
goods and all he does is he just writes
the news the way similar you'd expect
like an ad age or someone would have
done prior. If you are in this industry,
he's doing like basically must-read info
for you. And guess what? That saves me a
ton of time. I'm invested in a bunch of
CPG brands. I work with a bunch of CPG
brands. If I want to learn what's going
on, I look at his newsletter. I don't
need to do anything else. And he knows
he has a captive audience even with a
couple thousand people that anyone who
wants to advertise in that niche can get
to. So, those are your real three
categories. Now, choose one of those.
Are you replacing a traditional media
scenario? Are you doing a topical deep
dive and making it good? Are you
entering into a new zone or a new lens?
And then we're going to talk about
publishing cadence. Once you've decided
this, how often do I have to write a
newsletter? And my main thing is is I
encourage people to just stay on a
cadence. A lot of these newsletters are
like Emily's is daily or close to daily.
I publish mine weekly. Some people
publish monthly. I think it doesn't
matter. Just stick to it. And I would
highly recommend weekly or monthly to
start. And you just need to do it. needs
to happen like there's it's more about
not missing it ever you're you're
assigning your cadence and how much your
cadence is. So now how do I actually
grow demand for my newsletter and then
how do I monetize my newsletter? Let's
dive in. So one of the most effective
ways to grow a newsletter is X formerly
Twitter. Terrible social network filled
with some of the worst people but you
will find there is active engaged word
cells for lack of a better term that are
on there that are engaging in those
things. If you post tweets and you reply
to people and you grow on there
attaching a call to action to all of
your tweets that perform to sign up for
your newsletter works. I know this
because I've done it. And I find a lot
of people I meet who are trying to go to
their newsletters. I'm like, "Hey, are
you on Twitter? Are you on X?" And
they're like, "Yeah, you're doing pretty
good." Yeah. Do you attach a call to
action to every time you have a banger
tweet? They're like, "No." Well, guess
what? All my friends who have banger
newsletters, we talked about these. This
goes for this was Landforce. This was
James Camp. This is a bunch of these
folks you may know if you're on X. We
hit the plug on almost like at least our
top 20% of tweets because you're already
spending time in this network anyway.
Begin to grow and add your following.
And most people just don't want to ask.
And you have to ask if you're going to
start a newsletter and you want to grow,
just do it and be proud of it. and push
it out there and let people to sign up.
And so X is that's one of those. Find 10
people in your niche, reply to all their
tweets with something smart and
insightful while also posting highv
value content yourself like on a daily
cadence, something people can save or
share about with words in there around
topics that people engage with and like
you're headed in the right direction.
Second thing around growth is emp it's
basically taking advantage of your
existing list. So Behive has a great
referral setup where you can basically
set metrics with which someone will
receive a reward for referring people to
you. Leveraging your existing audience
to push your newsletter for you. And
this is really important because like
you can do that from an incentive
standpoint, which is always great. You
It's just something to have and you can
think about existing. But really what
you want to do is from a content
standpoint, is your newsletter sharable
enough that people are sending it to
other people, which will then increase
your subscriptions organically, right?
When I look at Casey's newsletter, I
forwarded her newsletter to, I don't
know, 75 people probably. And I'm sure a
good chunk of those signed up. I am one
of thousands of people probably
forwarding her newsletter to lots of
people because it is that good and that
relevant, has that much info related to
a job that is nowhere else. If you
create good enough sharable content and
I'd have that lens is what I'm writing
about good enough and if you can't do
that weekly now you have a monthly
newsletter because you better be able to
do something that's that useful monthly
and say this is I'm focused on getting
the people that read this to push it
out. You have to have that lens when
you're attacking this. Then we get to
Instagram and Tik Tok with a call to
action. Right? My newsletter would be
nowhere near where it is today if I
wasn't banging out videos on LinkedIn
and saying uh or banging out videos on
Instagram and Tik Tok and being like
get more the full download or get
all the links in my newsletter this
week. And if you are a creator of any
size, I'd be doing that at least once a
week. Shouting out your newsletter in a
call to action and linked in your bio.
We have so many people who are casual
creators now. I'm sure a lot of people
watching this video are. It is the best
easy call to action. If you don't have
it, you are losing the plot. Now, you
just have to find ways to shout it out.
One of the easiest ones is if you are
talking about six things, just say, "I'm
going to link these in my newsletter."
People are lazy. They're not going to
hunt this stuff down, but they will sign
up for a newsletter to get sent directly
to them. Think in terms of lead magnets.
The idea of you give someone an email,
they get something from you in return.
Can you give them a one-page playbook or
a template or your compilation? Like I
have a lead magnet that's a packaging
directory. You may have seen this. It's
all my favorite packaging in like a
little notion database with links and a
picture. Took me a few hours to put
together. I get emails all the time
because whenever I make a packaging
video, I get and you can see my whole
packaging directory if you sign up for
the email list. It's like I recurringly
use it. So it took one time a lot of
time and now I'm going to use it for
literally years to get email
subscribers. But if you are posting
content on these other networks, you
need to ask for it. You need to have it
in your bio and kind of tie those dots
together. But that is the number one
growth, right? That drove probably
25,000 of the subs that we have
currently are like literally just from
that. And that is for anyone who's
creating that video content that is
worth doing. And then we have just
Substack in general. If you are on
Substack and you are getting recommended
by other people or you are recommending
or you are posting on there, there's a
lot of organic traffic that comes from
it. Clayton, my partner in hyper has a
men'sware newsletter called Spreza. He
has recommended by a lot of other
Substacks in that same niche. He
recommends other people. He grows
considerably every day. he wakes up and
has new subscribers from the fact that
he's just on Substack and in that
ecosystem. And this ties into this idea
that social media is social and email is
the same way. Work with other email
creators, cross collaborate, push each
other's newsletter. Like that is a thing
that works inside this industry. And the
last piece of this we'll talk about is
paid recommendations. Behive has a whole
built-in thing for this where they'll
actually promote your newsletter to
other newsletters and you pay per
subscriber which a lot of people use.
And then people run Facebook and meta
ads, that same lead magnet we just
talked about where, hey, if I could run
a packaging directory ad that says, hey,
join my email list to get access to this
directory, I can probably get emails at
like less than a few dollars each. And
you begin to look at the economics of
this, getting the money next, and say,
hey, it's actually worth it for me to do
that because I make X amount over time,
you can begin to grow your list
monetarily. And there is so many of
these big newsletters you see, they've
grown this way, and it's somewhat
frowned upon in terms of like, oh, well,
is this an organic? They really like me,
they really not. That's something you
have to test your way into finding out.
But if you're like, hey, I'm doing all
these other things. I'm growing but not
as fast as I want. Then the two things
you can do is say hey make the best
content ever that is going to go
basically sharable viral which is option
one or start working on paid stuff. We
haven't done any paid in the newsletter
we have existing but if I was ever like
hey I I need to get this to 100k that's
the first lever I'd pull. So lastly
let's talk about making money on your
newsletter. So the first option is just
paid subscribers. So Clayton who runs
Presza he has paid subscribers hundreds
if not more of will pay every month for
access to his newsletter. Usually how
that happens you'll do some amount for
free and then some amount paid. So
there's like a free newsletter every
month and then some other ones that are
paid. I would not recommend that from
the start. I would build up a following
and then add paid onto it in a layer
that's like, "Hey, now there's two
newsletters a month for paid subscribers
and kind of filter that in." And you can
do very well on it. So when I was in New
York, I was interviewing a woman on who
has a a newsletter called the Sociology
of Business. She has a $50 a month
Substack, which I would not be surprised
if it has like thousands and thousands
of subscribers. And that is a good
business as you can imagine just from
doing back of the napkin math because
she's providing genuine real value as
someone like noted with a super
impactful like deep dive article. So you
can work your way up from a couple
dollars to you know someone like feed me
who has way more subscribers but is
doing like you four or five dollars a
month to a more niche but doing like 50.
You have this variance in between. So
paid subs is number one. Again once you
have a newsletter if you're driving that
amount of value people like it that's an
easy way to turn on and and get a
baseline there. The second thing is your
actual offers. So, my friend James, who
has a newsletter called Nano Flips, he
talks about buying and selling
businesses. That's his entire thing,
buying online businesses, growing them,
selling them. He provides examples. He
shows listings of businesses you could
buy and what he would do with them. And
he has like tactics within his
newsletter. But he has a a program he
sells like that is about that same thing
that is promoted in the newsletter,
which probably would make way more money
than anyone running an ad in a
newsletter or anyone running a paid sub.
He also has the same thing where if he
has other offers he's done like, "Oh, I
want to get x hours of consulting. You
can hit me here." He pushes himself and
his offers through his newsletter, which
is going to be way better money than
paid subs, but you need to actually have
things that are worth selling and using
for this, right? This is an example like
on our hyper newsletter. We don't like
push a bunch of things, but I do have we
put out reports every so often. Like we
have a report on how to make great
merchandise for your brand. It's like
$200. You know, we don't push it really
hard. It's at the bottom of the footer
every time and people buy regularly,
right? And so you be able you can have
some of those low offers that are in
there that help you take advantage of
that list without having to go add paid
subs. And then last, you have ads. So,
Hyper runs a lot of ads. We have ads in
basically every newsletter. Some
newsletters can charge more than others,
but if you're getting into the, you
know, if you're over 10,000, you should
be able to get a couple hundred bucks
per. If you're in your niche, you may be
able to get more, and you start to get
up to the 30, 50,000, you should be
getting at least a couple thousand bucks
per. And so now, they actually have to
go and people people are not going to go
hunt down your newsletter for those type
of ads. You will get beehive style ads
if you're using them, which are in there
for 300 bucks, 200 bucks, 100 bucks,
like like cheaper ads. If you want to go
find perfect people for your vertical,
maybe they'll hunt you down, but you
have to go outbound, right? And so every
month, Clayton goes and hits up new
people for us to work on inside this
newsletter. And he sends out x amount of
DMs and it has a media kit in it. This
is what you need. Hey, we have Hyper has
30,000 whatever subs. We have a 52% open
rate. We have a blank percent click
rate. We've worked with these brands and
they saw these types of clickthrough and
followthrough and you can get one email
blast for this amount. You can get a
package for this amount. And we have
some other offers that you you can do
like related to it. And this is the type
of people we reach. They're this and we
survey our audience regularly. we kind
of know hey they're in this jobs
positions they're in these industries is
where the value is and we try to find
people that that has the most value for
it's not about going and blanketing this
advertiser that advertiser it's about
like who would actually gain value from
this right you see I do a lot of content
with air sponsored our newsletter before
air has done like reports with us
because people that are creatives or
work in brand strategy who want to have
an asset management system for that same
thing who say hey like I need a a better
way to serve and deliver files and work
through that like that is a complete
alignment between my demographic and who
air is trying to sell to and that's not
every company there's not 100 companies
that are like that. Maybe there's 50
like but that is that is now your demo.
Go reach out to them. Have that
conversation and then go back to it,
right? Like keeping that list of those.
One of the easiest things to do is if
there's similar topics, go look at every
newsletter they've ever done. Go back to
their archives and find who all their
advertisers are is one easy way to
start. I'd also be critically thinking
about who you have value for. Find those
people on LinkedIn on X. Sending them
DMs. Again, the more of a social media
presence you have, the easier this
becomes. Why I recommend everyone become
a creator even at a small level. That's
a separate video. And you basically have
to go into that salesunnel. Now, people
get overwhelmed by sales, but I would
make it dead easy. Once a week, you got
a 2-hour block. In that 2-hour block,
you are selling. You go through, you
update your media kit, you find some
contacts, you send some DMs, you follow
up on previous done end of your two
hours, you've now sold your stuff for
your newsletter. Probably more time than
you need in most cases, but your job is
to basically put that together to
actually put ads inside the newsletter.
And between those three things, you have
plenty of ability to monetize. There's a
newsletter I signed up for when I'm 19,
Bob Leftets. It's like a music
newsletter. He's still writing it. That
guy's like 68. He sends newsletters
every day. his newsletter is a key
business driver for him and will be for
the rest of his life. And I would be
looking at that for you if you are a
writer or want to do this. Your time
horizon is forever. Your time horizon is
until I want to stop making money off of
this thing I'm passionate about or
having community around this thing I'm
passionate about. Both are equally
important. And so I would be building
this for the long term because guess
what? You may get 100 subs your first
year, 200 subs your first year, but if
you get to 20,000 by the time you're 65,
that's a life changer. It allows you to
do all types of things you couldn't do
before. And I look at this like, hey,
this our hyper list will be hundreds of
thousands of people by the time I
retire. it will be a force inside how
brands do strategy and since I'm looking
at it on that time horizon you look at
decisions really differently and you
make different money or do different
things in between but this is one of the
things like social media has always
shifted you move away or I can't access
these fans email stays for a long time
so I wouldn't say that you'd ever want
this to be your entire business but is
an excellent compliment as a side
project if if you if you're working
full-time if you are a creator or if
you're just really passionate about any
subject so I appreciate you all watching
I'm sure you have any questions on this
maybe we'll do like a level two deep
dive. Please drop any of those questions
on there of what I didn't cover and I'll
link them up for a future video. But
hopefully we gave you plenty of a
blueprint to get started and act on a
newsletter that will actually work.
Thanks for watching.