all right today we're going to talk
about making brand social media content
in particular short form video that
doesn't suck and that will actually
perform for your brand we're going to
talk about how you need to think about
it we're going to talk about funnels for
Content I'm going to give a bunch of
examples of specific video types that
basically anyone can make some of them
require some production a lot of them
are basic very simple and it's a
blueprint you're going to be able to go
through in this video at any point in
time and find social media ideas you're
going to be able to execute for your
brand and so why do I have any
credibility to be able to talk to you
about this so first of all I'm pretty
decent short form creator of my own
right about half a million followers on
platforms but I've also worked with a
number of Brands I've worked with ones
that have a million plus followers lots
that have hundreds of thousands of
followers I'll show some examples of
specific content and things I've worked
on inside this so I'm going to kick off
with this video and I'm going to show a
lot of videos you're going be able to
watch while I do this this is a great
example of content that shows a product
but does it in an entertaining way every
single clip you've seen so far has
teased the product and then it finally
shows it and shows it in a beautiful way
and by the time it's actually shown it
it gets back to the beginning where it
teases again this to me underlies the
Simplicity of what you need to do if you
are have a brand and you're trying to
show it and that is create things that
people want to watch so plenty of Brands
think that the algorithm has it out for
them what they do can't succeed and it
doesn't really come down to that unless
we're in a prohibited category I'm not
going to name the names of prohibited
products because I'm not tring to get
YouTube flagged but for the most part
for Brands to sell any normal thing and
they don't have some crazy political
stance or trying to sell something
really controversial you do not have a
problem with the algorithm instead you
are simply making things that consumers
don't want to watch let's put this in a
broader perspective you as a brand on a
social media platform are competing with
creators these are people whose lives
are designed to be able to entertain
they're making things that are humorous
funny educational entertaining and these
creators and the networks that they're
on are competing with the larger world
of entertainment they're competing with
Netflix Disney Plus Peacock for
consumers time when they are on their
phones or lounging and in turn those are
competing with traditional television
sports ESPN network news this is all war
for attention and so you as a brand need
to be able to compete on the same scale
as all of those people and so if you're
out there just being like I'm going to
make content and just about my products
or my product Sal you to be the focal
point of every single one of my videos
you're going to fail unless you do it in
a really intuitive way where you have
some principles along the way but if
you're content can't compete in any
other way the algorithms don't owe you
anything they are not going to just
Propel it out there for no reason so
what can you do two types of content all
content the internet boils down to one
of these two types you have a value
content value content is what I make in
all of my videos even if I'm selling
something I explain to people something
valuable to them that will help them as
a person as a creative or in their
business people will tune into to my
content because you want to learn things
and because I provide more value than
your average person just telling stuff I
try to go a level deeper and give actual
tactics that are useful and that people
don't often talk about that
differentiates my content from another
Creator Brands can offer value content
as well one of my favorite examples of
this is food companies that do a lot of
recipe content recipe content is the
ultimate value content because everyone
wants to cook good food everyone loves
to look at aesthetic food it's natural
to our senses and we bookmark stuff like
that all the time I don't particularly
live in a food algorithm If Ever I see
something where I'm like oh wow that is
a amazing you know keto Fried Chicken
I'm bookmarket it and Brands who are
contributing to that or making their
ingredients a focal P of that have a
really easy way to naturally create
value content basically think how can we
in our role as a brand educate and I'll
dive into some steps of that later then
we have option b entertain there are a
lot of ways for content to entertain
there's obviously humor you can have
series you can do cinematic things but
even if you are going back to that video
that I I've shown right before if you
can just take your brand and show it in
an entertaining way beautifully or
aesthetically that's the beauty of
Instagram reals right now on Tik Tok you
can't just do things off aesthetic now
you can't entertain by being funny you
can't entertain by telling a good story
by following Trends there's lots of ways
to create entertainment cont content on
Tik Tok that will help promote your
brand but on Reals in particular you can
just do it off the beauty and format of
the content because that's a lot of the
content that's rewarded there and so if
you show your product in a beautiful
away that is a form of entertainment
those are the two buckets value or
entertainment someone is consuming it
just for fun and people consume a mix of
both and Brands can create a mix of both
there's a third type of content the
third type of content is content that
fails content that is doing neither of
these things it's not particularly
educating you or something you want to
SA or you learn from or content that's
entertaining you and making people feel
good about themselves or want to share
it or laugh or have a moment or be like
wow that was cool and that is where the
majority of Brands I have conversations
with where like my social isn't going
anywhere how do I improve my social they
live there there's a certain tier of
Brands who make pretty good content and
they're trying to improve and take it to
the next level you'll find some value in
this too then you're getting down to the
Nuance of I how do I make Exceptional
videos video after video so for Brands
having a toolkit I'm going to go back
and forth between videos and and talking
about how content works and inside this
um there's all these different styles
I'm going to talk about and the
Beautiful unveil is a style and that's
this first velour garments video that I
showed off is a perfect example this is
another one where if you have an
interesting looking product or you can
take it out in an interesting way all
you simply have to do is unveil it and
show off its details by basically be
like I'm going to unpack this someone
wants to see what the full extent of it
is from what they're teased then they're
going to see all the different bits in
context and then repeat both of those
videos are like what 8 seconds like this
is not have to be like overthought and I
think for anyone that has an interesting
visual product this beautiful unveiling
is a great concept um this last one I
believe was likely shot on iPhone the
one before that was shot on a DSLR but
whatever your product is if it has a
good-looking bag if it has a good-
looking box even if it doesn't it's just
okay go and carefully capture that in a
similar format and this is one of the
things I love to talk about for people
that're like well how do I make content
like this literally map this out shot
for shot just write it down I'll do it
with you like on this exact format that
we have right here first shot someone's
picking up a bag in a pile second shot
they're unzipping the bag macro shot
third shot pulling the product out of
the bag still macro fourth showing a
detail but not the whole product fifth
showing another detail six they're
actually smoothing out the full image of
the product they're letting that one sit
that's an outline of a video you
literally go step by step like that and
then write down the lengths of the shots
and this is key cuz if you're first
doing this you don't really know how
social media content Works you're going
to make those shots too long and so you
literally could be like. 5 Seconds 8
seconds 1 second and you'll notice that
besides that last shot and the first
shot there's not much there it's going
to be more than a second at best and now
you have a format for creating this
style of video and you go okay I'm going
to take my same product I'm going to set
up my cameras maybe a slightly different
angle a little bit different look
because you have something different and
you're going to execute that same style
and what's nice about having a lot of
products having a brand is that you
probably have a lot of different things
that you can unveil that you can show
you can try these formats on and if you
haven't made multiple videos for all of
them then you probably really haven't
tried to see on social media right and
you have an infinite cannon you can do
by just doing this style of videos know
what this style of videos is also
amazing for is to go on your website on
your product detail pages to show people
the closeup of the product and you'll
see this now on on my Shopify site so I
just put these cashmir hats for sale and
I have the standard kind of a lifestyle
product photo of this up first but
second I have literally a video like I
would put on a real and this is just a
quick one on an iPhone but I'm showing
people in a short form format how they
want to see it if I was going to do this
in a real style I would literally just
chop this into like half second blocks
so it cut quicker between things but
like you can just put this right under
your PDP in your carel images and give
people an experience where they get to
actually see it which just means that
the time and effort you put into this is
worth than putting it on your product
detail page putting that content into
your emails Etc get the most value out
of the content you create all right so
I'm going to bring up a second type of
content this is a key walkthrough video
so this is a video where you are going
to go through your product and discuss
why something about it is special so
literally you'll see is a lot of these
shots they're all about 2 seconds
seconds long where he's walking through
the details of this particular fit and
it's not about the outfit it's about the
product itself it's not a complicated
video it's all on iPhone just captioned
above and this is like a standard capcut
caption style and he's literally just
walking through what makes it special
and stands out and if you have a product
that does have things special then talk
about that and obviously he's a
beautiful viral looking product now if
you are making products you don't look
like that and you have the ability to so
I'm to start thinking about how do I
make things that stand out in social
media but that's probably a whole
separate video I actually think that's
going to be the next video I do is like
building luxury products um we'll talk a
bit about this but even if you have a
basic product you can still have that
conversation and I show a lot of
clothing just because I get out clothing
content served in my feed this is
applicable to anything so this is olive
oil and they're literally talking about
why do we choose to use a can for our
refills and they're having a little bit
of fun with it obviously like old boy is
in his science costume in front of his
whiteboard and uh they're having some
fun with the captions and like that's a
good thing to do have a little
personality with your brand if it fits
your brand or be a little more serious
and buttoned up if you had a more
serious brand and someone's there like
in a suit in a nice setting that could
equally resonate in the same way but
he's literally explaining a key thing
around their brand into this content and
this format of like a key explainer and
you can be shot on iPhone candidly you
can be shot you nice in a different way
is a great thing to do where you think
of what is a some a story I can tell in
like 20 or 30 seconds about a key thing
of my product where you're providing a
combination of value and kind of your
product sales and are these always going
to Skyrocket no but are they a useful
content format to have yes now we have
doing this content in action so this is
actually a project I worked on where
we're doing all the tutorials about gel
blasters and basically how to use them
and it was like okay well do we want to
do just a standard content about like
how you use something like this or is it
better if you're actually in a gel
Blaster battle at the same time that
someone's giving a tip it is obviously
significantly more
exciting if you're giving the tip while
you're inside the battle and if the
audio is on it's not here going to be
telling her she's literally telling you
like how to hydrate and refill uh your
gel so you use like inside inside this
like while you're doing the video in
action and this has 60,000 views whereas
a video of us just explaining this is
how it works would have like 3,000 views
this is another one I worked on when I
was doing social lift foils uh and this
is actually one like I will give the
videographer full credit like on this I
had the concept that we need to be doing
more of these educational videos about
how to do things like wake foiling
because people just don't know and
understand and then they actually like
miked up Brian here and like executed
this like while he's actually on the
board which just adds this like
captivation element to the content
that's huge right because you're
basically seeing two things at once he's
explaining what he's doing while he's
doing it you're like immediately asking
questions like oh he's like miked up on
that is he going to fall in the water
and you get to see it in action
happening and this was like a one .8
million view video and then immediately
there are more of these and they also
hit like equally as well and so
obviously these are like more like
outdoors and products that have a
natural exciting element to them but you
could easily have just made this same
content and had it not be this exciting
and had it not go anywhere and so if you
have that ability to have excitement and
especially if you are athletic wear
workout gear or supplements or whatever
it is like give people some action
inside of it and then even if you're not
like what else could you be doing from a
lifestyle perspective to explain those
tips like you uh and this goes two ways
too like you can explain how your
products used inside that context you
can also be like explaining other things
or giving tips in other environments and
something I like to think about for this
is like if I had an auto themed clothing
brand and like if I'm giving tips about
like how I can fix a carburetor while
I'm in the gear or whatever like there's
another degree of connection that can
happen there but this content is really
exciting to me the idea of like give a
tip about your product or teach people
how to use it but add that second
element of doing it like in some kind of
non-standard circumstance ideally like
while it's in action but like even if
someone's walking or running or in I
think a great thing that um my friend
Alex Garcia did at the collective is
they were doing these and they had them
inside the cold punch like while they
were doing it just add that second
dimension to it it's a kind of thing
that is pretty easy to execute from a
production standpoint but it is
significantly more exciting when it's
actually seen in the algorithm and
becomes significantly more sharable and
now who shown some content this is a
good opportunity to step back and talk
about content funnels um I think I had a
video where I interviewed about this on
a podcast go viral on on Instagram and
um it's one of those videos where like I
didn't accept the collaboration request
and I was like ah you know it's not
really kind of a fit and of course it
goes viral uh but uh so content funnels
if you're familiar with the concept of
funnel funnel goes down I like a lot of
people will know sales funnels and
marketing funnels you're trying to get a
customer from the top of the funnel down
to the bottom of the funnel where
they're close the top of funnel for
content is something I love to talk
about because a lot of Brands don't
understand and can't separate I need to
sell this product I need to be selling
my service or I need to sell what I do
as a Creator every video and the way the
algorithms work especially Instagram Tik
tok's a little different YouTube's a
little different but like if someone
likes your content on Instagram or they
follow you on Instagram you're
immediately shown like four or five of
that person's videos the next few times
that you log in and scroll they will
automatically give you more content it's
great for the Creator it's also great
for the brand but what this is is gives
you a crucial step you need to think
about in The Funnel which is like how do
I make content that gets millions of
views whether or not it achieves my
objectives or gets me followers or gets
me sales if I can get content that my
Target demographic or people that will
my product C then I'm immediately going
to get my other popular videos fed to
them and they're going to see probably
the next thing that I post and if I
think of this like a funnel I go great
what is the things that I can attract
the most attention with and then when we
talk about middle of funnel it goes okay
then how can I educate them about
actually making a purchase and if you
think about content like this it becomes
really important so top of funnel videos
that just get attention don't add sales
may not even need to have your product
I'll show you examples the do middle of
funnel these are just videos your
standard videos that either Drive value
like we talked about or entertain but
like are more based around your brand
your product and your story and the
things you're trying to promotee but
they're done in ways that are natural to
succeed on social media but they have
that element to them where people are
going to look at that and they I want to
buy that or I want to support that
person or whatever it is and then the
bottom of the funnel the bottom of the
funnel is that of stuff you have to make
where you're like okay the drop is today
we need to make a video about it like
all right hey we got to go make some we
going was some sales dro the
video about it and that's something
where like that's the least of the ratio
of content of what you should be making
but you still need to consider it inside
where what you're creating and so if you
balance this out and you go I want to
have one or two every week top of funnel
videos and maybe they don't always hit
but I'm trying and I want to have two or
three this middle of funnel was my core
content sometimes they get big sometimes
they do all right we're knocking them
out there and I want one where I'm just
going I'm going for it I got to go get
the job done that's a great mix of
content for a Creator or for a brand and
your strategy will be more sophisticated
and 99% of brands that are out there so
what are examples of top of funnel
content this first one's a bit of a mix
it's giving the educational elements of
value content but it's meant to go viral
and this is the idea that you can take a
tip or take something like a creation
and then just make it like excessive so
this is recipe content he's making an
old fashioned he's just making a massive
oldfashioned so basically you take a
core video or like a tip video and you
add a viral element to it which is
literally just like size is a great one
can you do an extra large version this
works all the time on social media so if
you do have content where it's like I'm
going to show you how to make a protein
shake or I'm because I have a supplement
that goes inside of it or I'm going to
show you how to do extra y like doing
the crazy version of that like adding
scale this is something I talk about in
if you haven't gotten my like creative
Ops like free report thing I did I have
a whole like creative Direction this is
one of the strategies it's like how do
you make it extreme or how do you pull
something back to like just its Essence
to take an idea or a reference and make
it more interesting and this is just a
perfect example where if you have some
successful content as you know for a
brand already make it super sized and
then there's using viral elements and
like these little mini waffle makers
like always have a bunch of viral
elements I I have a lot of food content
chused on here another great example of
stuff that was like a natural viral
element was when all the creators were
using those little treadmills and like
walking on the treadmills or talking or
running on the treadmills like you can
kind of see what's happening in the
world around you and create something to
that but not all going to be food here
this is one of my favorites and one of
my favorite strategies this is these
tiny aesthetic reels this is like a 6 or
8C reel from 2js who are smashing on
social media and literally it's one
visual concept our jewelry on a
turntable they have like eight or 10
shots they let it kind of you go in an
interesting way and it's something where
you're going to watch you're going to
stop scrolling on reals you're going to
watch it for a couple seconds be like oh
what's happening here oh can I see that
piece again and then the video is
already played like three times it's a
genius top of final content strategy
it's based on just a visual mechanism
their product on a turn table and you
can think about what could I put my
product on or what could it do that
would be interesting another great
example of the same thing they just
literally flipped a video of their
Ceramics on strings so it looks the
opposite way which is just super scroll
stopping and just an excellent top of
funel piece and so especially if you
have a creative team or your creative
like really be diving into like what are
those little unique things that we can
try that will just stop people on the
page and those few that you know that
I've just shown are like great Styles
and looks that you can kind of build
your own references and then if you have
like if you're from a bigger brand or
you have a real creative team or you
have a particular skill set on that like
go Artful right um so this is I mean
this is big budget this is on and post
archive faction from from Korea but like
this looks like unlike anything that is
on reals today and if you have the
ability to do that and to get people to
go holy I need to stop and watch
this then that is like the best of of
all worlds especially for us as
creatives creative directors art
directors like this is the goal right
you may not always have the production
budgets or anything like that but like
if you do have the resources in the team
like this is what what to try to make
and I like to look at this from uh like
Martin Rose has this as a Trope where
they have this kind of like rotating
thing that's on there and this content
is a little you know a little niche U
but again kind of has that same like
okay if we took an Artful approach to
top of funnel content so now let's hit
some middle of funnel tactical content I
love this concept of the Showcase so the
Showcase is when you put a setting
together and then you rapid fire show
off whether it's your work as a creative
or an agency or your Rebrand or your
line and so in this video they set up
the stage of they go like hey we have
this brand uh we have a mood board what
we're going to create and then here's
what we built out of it so it sets that
up in the few seconds and then it just
gives you still images in a row and
again that video is like what 6 8
seconds long like what stories do you
have from your brand assets to be able
to put things like this together
extremely similar format for behind the
scenes like you're doing a Photoshop Etc
where like they just shot again that's
three leadup shots and then just the
photos and then this is already going to
be done and that these are the little
vetts that can come dayto day that are
really easy to show and great content
that has a potential to go viral and no
matter what is brand focused and
educational a great version for a
clothing brand literally the first shot
is he just pulls this rack out makes you
wait and then just shows the different
pieces in the collection snapping back
and forth like and then then it repeats
this is not complicated but a lot of
just social media teams just kind of
overthink what they have to do when like
you have formats like this like for any
collection you have any setup of
different things any photo shoot that
you do any new Rebrand assets or
campaign assets this type of video
should be on the list every single time
you do one of them now if you have a
great storytelling team you have good
copywriting you people with the ability
to write good content um these are great
formats as well you literally write out
a story and you're just using lots and
lots of shots to kind of quickly tell
that story two words on screen Max like
using your b-roll to move along with
this takes more editing work these move
super fast but again you copyrighting is
part of the strength of the org that you
have write these and take examples like
this and like literally it be like all
right how would I in the same word count
same time count tell a story about my
brand whether it's our origin story why
I made this product why we're based in
wherever we're based why we hired this
person who's on our team what our vision
for the future is like where our
warehouse team uses to do their work
whatever another person who's done a
great job with this is Spencer he was in
uh like the first cut 30 cohort like we
ever did and just is an amazing
Storyteller he was only on on Twitter I
think before that but just understood
how to write again knows how to put
these shots together like has mapped all
this out into a storyline and there's a
lot of people that have that skill set
and especially if a videography
background but this is all act thought
it's just lots of zooms and lots of
texts on the screen to read and like
dominates on Tik Tok and he runs it as
an ad as well and it's just really sick
if you haven't seen his product Tails
it's like this uh it's like a a game you
can play with other members of your
family to uh learn more about their
history which is super sick he's
crushing it and like a really fun time
so recommended to check out and so
there's like hundreds of more content
examples I could go through of things to
do but this is a pretty good setup to
get you started and thinking about
content that you can do for your brand
that is and almost all the things I
applied apply to creative work as well
if you're showing off your portfolio
it's a lot of the same principles like
those showcase videos I just saw or like
even in unveiling uh like if you
actually made something or a prototype
like taking it out or covering the
screen or showing the mood board first
and then transitioning it into like the
little pieces of the of your of your
your piece like into the whole thing uh
there's a lot of those same principles
that can really apply overall no matter
who you are think about that Chain by
making value or am I making
entertainment or am I failing and then
am I making content for the top of
funnel am I making it for the medium
middle or am I making it for the bottom
and I'm about to start making content
for my brand I've made a few videos like
test videos already just seeing what
they can do on the algorithm I'm about
to start doing a lot more and I'll share
a bit about how those are working as
well and so so you see here I've got th
followers here some of the things that
they have kind of worked here is like
I've done these little compilation
videos kind of a little more
motivational but again just super quick
shots something that you know people can
like like like and share same thing with
this kind of idea of that opening hook
shot and I'm just showing a bunch of my
products like shot after shot with some
lifestyle kind of cut in between these
are just simple like set the stage
videos that I'm using to explore the
algorithm a bit before I dive in deeper
but I'm going to start sharing the
things that are working the things that
are not and the ideas I have in some of
these future videos but anyway if you
want to dive deeper into content with me
we do our cut 30 thing uh once every
month it's like a 30-day boot camp I'm
trying not to sell a bunch of stuff
inside these YouTubes but uh we do that
every 30 days people do ask about it a
bunch and um I think our next one is
Tuesday May 21st coming up so if you're
interested in that it's cut 3.co and
then I did put out this creative Ops
guide for free that you can find on the
hypers site I'll link it down in here
too um you have to go on Air's landing
page and you sign up and then it will
they'll email to you uh but this has
like a bunch of creative Direction
strategies for how to look at content
how to think about content as a team and
how to like analyze Trends to make good
content so if you're part of a bigger
team at like a org uh and you're like
building brand content there's a ton of
strategies I have inside that and anyway
that is content drop more questions at
the bottom I know I didn't cover a lot
of like starting from scratch hoping to
do that pretty well and like what I do
documenting my brand Journey um and know
a lot for more like existing Brands and
social teams so we'll conquer that in a
new video but uh appreciate you watching
and let's go