There's a trend going on on social
media, but it's spilling over into real
life, too. Larping, or live-action
role-playing. Not the medieval cosplay
or bardcore, but basically the act of
making fun of the influencer world while
also participating in it. The posts
about it are massively popular, 1.8
million likes. But it ties to a bigger
trend that we're seeing about all of the
consumption we have. The knockoff brands
becoming the most popular brands, the
duplicate replacing the original, the
advent of luxury with this new premium
boring that makes the world go round. In
this video, we're going to talk about
it. We're going to dive into why this
larping trend came up. We're going to
talk about why this actually happened in
luxury consumption over the last few
years and where it went wrong. The rise
of the dupe economy, how influence
around buying expensive things has
shifted. And then we're going to talk
about the brand recipe and brands that
are executing this well, or succeeding
inside this economy where we're more
price conscious and realize you can get
these aspirational items for a lower
cost. And I'm going to end with the
playbook if you are a marketer or
developing a brand and you're working in
this niche, how do you position to
actually succeed? So whether you're a
consumer or marketer, or just interested
in how these trends are shifting the
world around us, let's lock in. So
first, how do we get to this how to larp
like a pro series? How do we get to
everyone saying, "Oh, I'm going to buy
replica Lamborghini car keys online. I'm
going to visit a local car dealership
just to take pictures. Turo the
Maybach." The core seller larp, but now
brought as an activity to show up on
feeds. I do appreciate the empty
designer bags from Etsy. So it started
with everyone was marketed luxury,
especially in COVID and after. It was
the first time online there were lots of
people talking about these brands.
People were introduced to Rimowa
suitcases. Goyard was taking off in
popularity, a lot because of its dupes,
which we'll talk about later. People
really into lifestyle influencers. When
everyone disliked their life or was in
lockdown, they were looking to other
more interesting lives. Social media and
video, especially, exposing us to rich
people who'd never really been online
like that before. And it was different
than watching the Kardashians on TV
because it seemed like people just like
us. It seemed like they were just
spending more on those things. And this
led to a lot of consumption. Luxury
brands have raised their prices and
their sales have gone through the roof
because it became normalized to buy
these things that really only the 1%
should be purchasing. There is no world
in that if you are not in that bracket
of consumer, you should be buying a
suitcase that is over a thousand
dollars. But people do buy them. In my
friend group, we refer to it
affectionately as the Rimowa effect
because it then had this fallout. People
spent this money on these luxury items
and then they realized that they weren't
worth it. Rimowa's the perfect use case
cuz anyone who's actually used those
know they dent super easily. They suck.
Yes, they have lifetime repairs, but
you're using that lifetime repair. It
simply is not worth the bulk and the
quality to have for anyone that doesn't
have a huge amount of expendable income
where they don't even have to care. And
it's a reminder every time you use it
that you chose to waste that money on a
status symbol. Whether it's that or
another purchase, so many people had
that experience. When you go to actually
buy something you needed, you'd be like,
"Man, I really shouldn't have gotten
that $700, $900 pair of shoes, or
whatever it was." And while it shot up
luxury brand sales, so many new people
were participating in it, also raised
awareness that there really is no
difference in those goods. And now
LARPing has taken this full circle.
Because in the LARPing world, and this
happens in tons of influence online, the
goal was attention, right? The goal is
to get attention from whoever on social
media by using expensive things to do
it. One of the cheapest forms of
attention, but it works. But they don't
care by what means that they achieve it.
This is where we enter into the dupe
economy. So, I remember when I was in
China in Guangdong, going through all
the different cities, the quality of the
dupes was incredible. We would be in
factories that were quite literally as
you see it described online where
they're making shoes for clients I have
or brands like the things I operate on
one side of the warehouse, on the other
side of the warehouse they are churning
out Yeezys or whatever. And then there,
very easily you can get delivered to you
the highest quality of dupes. I remember
we would purchase some dupes of things
that we had to compare the quality cuz I
was going to do a video on it. And we
actually laughed because one of the
bags' quality for a YSL bag was higher
than the actual one. And you've seen the
same thing with lab diamonds, right?
Where the cost uh I was there in China
in the jewelry city in front of the lab
diamond machines. It was massive machine
about the size of like the height of
this room that just spits out a diamond.
And when you put that into perspective
of what that means for a cost, you begin
to look at everything significantly
differently, especially when they are as
good as anything   real.
And so it was different when it was a
cheap duplicate. When it's an equal
duplicate, you begin to realize you're
purely paying for the status. And when
you don't get the status because so many
other people have it because larping is
taking off. That leads to a very
positive consumer shift. Are you buying
for the experience or for the attention?
And if it's the attention, then larping
wins because it's more effective. You
can do more. The dollar goes longer. And
that attention is now worth very, very
little. And that is where we are at
today. We are at the precipice of this.
It doesn't matter if your Goyard is real
or not. There are so many fake ones.
That wallet is the most duplicated item
with the least amount of fighting by the
original brand to try to get it taken
down cuz they like the popularity. It
has no signal. And so now people know.
People don't look up to those luxury
influencers the same way. So one of the
big influencer shifts we've seen in just
the last year is that all of the like
perfect aesthetic life influencers, male
and female. You would see there's guys
who are really stylish doing get ready
with me in Dior or look at these new
expensive perfumes I bought. And their
entire feeds are really about
consumption of expensive things. And
they're showing that off in these
aesthetic ways. And they're really
offering you very little value beyond
that. They're not being like, "Let me
explain to you my thoughts on
Nietzsche." Or "Here's these really
valuable tips for your life or your
career." They are showcases of
consumption. There's a obviously whole
genres of female aesthetic influencers
who just showed off their kind of
beautiful perfect lives. And that
content has fallen really flat. And the
last content left is people like
I get sent this guy all the time. This
is a poor person's version of what a
rich person does every day. Yeah, I'm
going to purchase this new Rolex like
inside my G Wagon. Every single thing on
here is an expensive purchase. Let me
show you these Bottega shoes without any
semblance of why they're consuming, what
they're doing it for, any reasoning, any
backups of life or story, any any reason
to connect to the person beyond the
aesthetic of what they're presenting,
which is the most lowbrow form of
expensive consumption. All kudos, an
amazing creator making videos that get
consumed quite a lot, but an example of
the only things that are left in that.
And they are not selling to the market
that can afford it or would want it. But
this is the opportunity, and the
opportunity for the brand space is now
the consumer is aware that they are
being taken advantage of. They've made
those mistakes, and now they actually
want a good thing at a good price, which
is the right way to consume. And there
are a lot of brands, I'm about to walk
through a whole list of them, that
actually do this very well, and some of
them that do it a little more sketchily,
and we'll break down the difference. And
that's an opportunity, whether you're
consuming or whether you're building, to
be able to get outsized value. And so,
one story I will tell about this is I
was at a friend's house in Beverly
Hills, and they had this coffee table
that I have seen online on like First
Dibs or whatever. And it's really
expensive, and I was like, "Oh, like,
where did you get it? Original piece,
whatever." And they'd gotten it from The
Essential. And The Essential has a lot
of the pieces that it's hit expiry on
the design in the United States, so that
anyone can produce it, and they will
make a version of it at a more
affordable price. And we'll get to
brands like Interior Icons like too far
a little bit later. Such as like a good
in between. But it was funny cuz I had
not heard of it. I ended up actually
talking to the team from there
relatively shortly after. But it was
this idea that this is a pretty like
abstract item. This is a like what I
like to call this one in particular is
it was in a home surrounded by other
interesting and expensive things. And
they're like, "Yeah, I actually can't
get this other version I want, and I was
able to get it here." And you were able
to like achieve this like interesting
look. But that's the business, right?
The business of what are these amazing
artistic things, and if you have an
idea, bringing it to market in an
affordable way, because we now have that
ability. Or looking at what are all
these expensive things that are being
produced that don't have to be
expensive. We'll get to a playbook and
how you do that in a moment. But Keens
is the ultimate example of this, right?
A little hit or miss in terms of the
quality, but their entire brand exists
to say that things you used to have to
pay an awful lot of money for, you can
now get at these lower prices. And
especially for bedding, home goods,
travel, and now furniture, they have
options across everything. And they will
showcase the price you save versus
traditional retail, right? And they are
just taking advantage of direct to a
factory and they are marketing it that
way. What they've done is gone wide.
Once they're known for a few good
things, they've said, "Great, we have
this customer base that has in mind that
we offer them a great value where
they're not getting taken advantage of
and they still get good quality. And we
have factory relationships. It doesn't
matter what we sell. Our brand isn't
based around the fact we sell sheets or
homes. We can really sell anything. Our
goal now is to raise the LTV, lifetime
value, of those customers by selling
them as many things as we can."
Basically becomes a replacement for a
traditional department store all owned
by one brand focusing on a singular
value proposition. Very smart play. And
probably the first to do this. I think
they were significantly earlier than
Keens, but I'm not exactly a scholar of
uh when these brands started, but Italic
is another one where they I think had
did an incredible job. I remember them
early on being like, "We have the same
factories as this Italian luxury. You
can purchase it from us at this
quality." I have had some great
experiences with this brand. We have I
had done in my product versus brands
sheets video, we'd ordered tons and tons
of sheets from all these different
brands, and theirs ended up being the
ones that I am most excited when they
are on our bed. But again, the entire
brand proposition is offering you these
luxury experiences at a cost that
doesn't have a 30X 40X markup. And this
is a new position, right? So, if you
look at how brands used to position in
the past, you would basically have
lowest price used to be a huge thing.
Okay, someone's selling something, can
we go a lower price? Cuz people would
just assume most things were the same
and pick the lower-priced option. Amazon
basically killed that because now if you
go lowest price, you end up with
something that's like really bad. Also,
you cannot compete with direct from
China or selling on Amazon. We will
happily do this for a couple percent. No
business is going to be built off
competing off that. So, that basically
eradicated competing at the lowest
price. So, now the new category is
replacing luxury with something that's
just as good at a typical price. That is
where all the businesses are being built
that we're talking about here. And it's
an excellent opportunity. And I'm diving
into the data here, so I'm going to go
into the actual particle data. I'm going
to show you like the size of the
opportunity and how it's done, right?
So, in the furniture business, this is
Interior Icons. Interior Icons is not
like the sketchy scale. I put The
Essential on they are working with the
IP of a lot of these companies where
that's expired. You're allowed to
reproduce things after a certain amount
of time. Then you get people like
Interior Icons who just knock stuff off
kind of directly. This is where this
curve goes inside of this. You can kind
of decide which level you want to live
on. How comfortable are you with having
that in your home or purchasing that or
promoting that? Some people will only
want to support the thing from the
original designer or whoever bought that
IP. Some people will be fine with the
expired thing. Some people will be fine
with the dupe or knockoff thing. And
Interior Icons plays in that space and
does not give a what you think
about it. And you'll see if as you go
inside this, the data you see here in
particular, you look at their best
sellers, look at this average discount
column. So they are running the very
gray area. We're going to show you what
the price of this would be if you bought
it full price from one of these luxury
providers. And we're going to show that
as the sale. Similar to what Keens did
there, but I think they do it even more
aggressively. But you'll see, this is
the margins that they're being operated
with. So if they were able to say,
"We're discounting their most popular
item that they sell for $200, normally
goes for $1,200." And then we can I
guarantee you in a Google search we can
find it for that. That's a 90% discount.
Now they're making margin on this. Maybe
it's only 25%, 30%, 50%, but there's
still margin. And they are producing all
of these cuz if you look at the
quantities of sale, and this is why I
love Particle to actually get in there
and look at that data. It's like, all
right, yeah, they've sold two units, but
they did $16.4 thousand in revenue.
Expensive couch, three units, 98 units.
That means for a lot of these, besides
98 units, they're just producing it on
demand whenever it gets sold. It's an
excellent business model, especially in
furniture where because of that model,
everyone's used to waiting 5 to 6 weeks
for something. So you can just offer the
low price, have the factory, and produce
it, and that's how these businesses
function. And a business like this gets
very aggressive on, "We're just going to
copy anything we can." It also works for
original designs if you can get the
interest, right? They capture the
interest of things you've aesthetically
seen already. And that's where this gets
pretty interesting. Because so, Gentle
Monster, you've I did a full art
direction video on them prior. They are
incredible brand. They do incredible art
direction and campaigns. You know, their
marketing is unparalleled. Korean brand
that sells eyewear, right? And they use
all these principles of art direction
inside what they what they create.
Celebrity, just really interesting
visual campaigns of of all kinds. I can
literally play a game here in my browser
to promote whatever sunglasses is. They
do some best in class stuff, but the
other end of the day of this is they
also make really really expensive
overpriced products. All right, I'm not
going to play the Gentle Monster zombie
game live. This is not one of those
operations. This campaign is super sick,
too, but I'm I'm trying to get through
to here to get to where I can actually
buy something. Cool. $345, $335, $356,
$315, $325. They're all sold out. Those
are actually some of the cheaper ones
I've seen from them. $275, $305. These
are expensive sunglasses. I actually
remember them being a more expensive
when I did this prior video on them. So,
what happens is you see all this
incredible marketing, and people maybe
buy in once, but so much fewer people
buy into the brand than know about it.
But they're now interested in these
products and style. And that's where you
end up with I've given this anecdote
before if you've watched my Tokyo video.
I always look at just as a marketer, a
person interested in sociology and
consumption in general, I always look at
what people are buying when I travel
places. Now, I was in Tokyo and there
was kids, Gen Z age, lined up at the
Blue Elephant stores all the time. And I
was like, "Cool, what's Blue Elephant?"
And I basically found out that Lore,
that they were knocking off Gentle
Monster, have been sued for it in Korea,
but they're selling $70 versions of the
same thing. Which again, this is where
those opportunities are, where when a
category is created by someone with the
infinite luxury budgets, but no one can
actually afford that, can you provide
the alternative? And obviously I will
never be an advocate for just knocking
off directly the products, but can you
do your own spin on it where like, "Hey,
people do want like radical avant-garde
eyewear." And I have my own creative
vision, I can put that on it. This is
the time to do it now, cuz you can ride
the tailwinds of all these luxury
experiences. And even if you want to be
more direct, I found this brand where I
now own multiple pairs of their shoes,
cuz I was looking at the Bottega derby
shoes and I was like, "You know, I just
really I buy a lot of luxury stuff. I
cannot justify $2,600 on shoes." But
guess what, they make the exact This is
the exact shoe, same exact look, $175.
And it's just an entry point into that
brand. It's one product in their product
suite that is solving a user need. I
guarantee I'm one of many people who've
come into that brand through a Google ad
looking for the Bottega shoes and then
being like, "Oh, is this brand up to any
level of quality?" And look and they're
great, 165 bucks, great great cost for
this. And you'll see the volumes they're
doing, right? I'm in Particle, 241
this month, 146 this month. And just
quick shout out to Particle, they did
sponsor this video. And all the things
you can do in here, right? You can check
those prices, check those volumes, see
when they introduced it, sales over
time, how often they're running a sale,
like they just launched this like a
final sale here for Memorial Day. It
will break you down your their website
changes, how they price, what discounts,
what colorways sell. You can literally
do kind of competitive analysis. So, if
you were thinking of launching something
in the shoe niche and you wanted to look
at whether you were looking at the
Bottega sales, whether you're looking at
this. This is the data that allows you
to make some of the decisions about if
the volume is there to be able to do the
things you want to do and then how
they're marketed from there. It's an
excellent piece of software. You can
learn more about it now in the
description of this video. We'll also
link to your Claude or ChatGPT, so you
can just search or ask and it will just
bring up the data directly from in here,
so you don't even have to do the
browsing that I'm doing as well. So,
that's the foundation of a playbook,
right? Whether you have an existing
brand or you work at a brand or you're
thinking about one. Now we can
understand the consumer habit, like
where is the alpha? Find price alpha and
lay into it. What I mean by price alpha?
If someone is doing a 20x markup, the
Bottega shoe, great example of a 20x
markup, probably more. It does not cost
them $2,600 to make that shoe, maybe at
an absolute maximum it costs them $130,
probably less than that. But I'm going
to assume the highest qualities of
leather and it was put together by a
tiny Italian man who makes the maximum
wage in the country. That 20x margin is
your opportunity because then you can
still get a normal four to five x margin
and have a very healthy business. And
now in something like furniture, etc.,
when you see that and you look at cool
if it has something higher ticket,
you're buying a $100 chairs, couple
$1,000 couches, whatever it is, you may
be more comfortable with a 30% margin,
20% margin, 50% margin, which is way
different than a multiple because you
don't have to have the cash, you can
actually make it on demand. That becomes
an interesting playbook. You have to
find where that alpha is. We've looked
at sunglasses, we've looked at shoes,
we've looked at furniture. There's It's
It's already been done on a lot of
these. But where are you seeing things
that we every time you're overcharged on
something, you'll be like, "Man, could I
solve this?" because I guarantee that
trip to Guangdong, you probably can. And
then the biggest secondary point is
don't just dupe, do it better. That's
what we see in all this economy. Some of
these italic sheets we got when I tested
them versus Frette and shades of that
nature were better at a fraction of the
price. So, the goal is not to duplicate
something, it's to make it better. Like
if I was doing that Bottega shoe, that's
a dead ringer and maybe that's a useful
skew for them to bring stuff in. But,
I'd be just as excited to have that like
in a dark navy or gray or something
interesting. Couple changes, the clear
sole on those, way they did those
A-Cold-Wall Doc Martens. There's some
ways you could actually play into that
that would be really interesting. Now
all of a sudden, again, your ideas start
to spin. Oh, I can put my design on
this. I can make this unique. I'm using
this as a basis knowing that there's a
consumer group there, but I can have my
own unique product. And then your goal
is to prove it. If you're making
something at a cheaper price that's just
as good, prove it. Do comparisons. Have
influencers do it. Have you do it. Cut
those things open. Get testimonials from
people. Come through on your customer
service. Make people believe in the
brand as much as you can. Don't come
across just some random internet stuff.
And as you begin looking for them, you
will see these things come up every day.
Uh I want to shout out Jake. Uh he's a
Jake is a master troll uh in terms of
tweeting things that make uh angry
fashion people come out. Because he's a
good fashion newsletter. And he was
saying, "Hey, like you could buy Vans
for $70. You could buy these The Row
shoes for $990, which looks
significantly better." And the alpha
there is, "Yeah, guess what? Those are
probably bang at 195 and a bunch of
variations. That sole's a little too
thick. Can I thin that down? Okay." And
that's an opportunity. And if you are in
the development of products, you ever
want to launch anything, those are the
things you need to think about. Where is
there demand? Where are people being
overcharged? What could you do inside
that same thing? And then how could you
make it better? That is the formula for
a wide, wide variety of product
development. Same thing goes in
software. Same thing goes inside of a
service. It's a mentality with which you
can approach the world to monetize it.
And I want to call out there are so many
layers of abstraction for cost, too. One
uh final anecdote I'll leave you with is
when I was working at a toy company, we
had middlemen we didn't even know until
we went to the factory in China. We
actually sent a team there to work
through some back and forth. So, some
pro tips if you've ever been working
with factories in China, you'll notice
they're not very good at like showing
you the full swath of options or all the
ideas. They'll be like, "Send me all
your coolest leathers." They I know what
that means. For us it was like, "Send us
all your coats and dipping and materials
we can make like a cooler looking
plastics. And we'd get like a handful of
stuff and it wasn't really doing it
justice but then you'll send somebody
there. You'll be like take me to the
place that you get the leathers or take
me to where the plastics are made. All
of a sudden you'll see all this amazing
stuff they just will never think to send
you. But in that trip we discovered that
a middleman right now people use brokers
help them find factories whatever
actually marking up the invoices. And it
was so little we had thought we had good
cogs. But in reality it was getting
double marked up by a middleman you
didn't know about.
like on invoices in that trip and I
basically say that entire anecdote to
tell you that there are so many layers
of abstraction in products that you do
know of two that you may be surprised
with the actual cost and margins are
once you get down there and see the
factories and see how things are
produced and see what the materials are.
And your goal is to uphold a standard of
quality not to go to the cheapest thing
or the worst thing but to look at can I
replicate this luxury end of it with
innovation with production with
understanding where cost goes and be a
student of it. And that is where a lot
of these businesses you see right here
that I went through are making their
advantage right now. If you want to talk
more about this or you have any
questions about any of this in general
I'm always work shopping any of this on
the community calls. We'll link that
down below. You can check out particle
if you want to do research inside any of
these niches and I will link them there
as well. And as always thank you all so
much for watching.