so in 18 months I went from no social
following Beyond friends and family to
about half a million followers on social
media and then in 24 months which is
where I'm at now since starting that
it's now become just a significant part
of my life and in this video I'm going
to talk a lot about why I feel creators
should be creating and then give a
really tactical guidelines of how you
actually do it from how I record all of
my videos how I use green screen how I
edit what networks I post on and why
scripts and formats that I feel are
impactful to actually make a difference
how I plan my content write my content
publish my content and then some
narrative about why it's important
inside a creative career to do this and
what leverage that gives you cuz it's
really about leverage and I'm going to
start there because I started making
content mainly because I felt out of
touch I was a former marketing leader my
last job was really operational I was a
president of about a 200 person company
I was dealing with distribution with
sales with Trucking with retail stores
after that I was like Hey I want to get
back to marketing back to design and
then I realized I didn't understand what
is going on and I like to be just
dangerous enough at everything to be
able to successfully manage someone at
it and understand the expectations I
have of them what I'm asking them so I
decided to make content and I had JT
Barnett in my phone on my feed saying
everyone should be a Creator and I saw
it enough it resonated enough I was like
you know what I'll try this but
something funny happened and it's the
main reason I'm calling this out inside
a video to my community which is mainly
creative people and entrepreneurial
people is how the dynamic shifted so
when I developed a little bit of a
following 20,000 30,000 on Tik Tok that
took about 6 months meetings started to
change all of a sudden people started
asking my opinion on social media even
people that I thought were savvier than
me but who didn't have their own
followings at 50,000 followers I was the
authority inside the meetings internally
on the projects I was working on at
100,000 followers I was making money and
that at 100 plus the whole dynamic
started to shift in conversations
externally too so at that time I was
working with a business that had a lot
of retail sales we were in Costco we
were in Walmart we were in Target and we
started getting these conversations
where I would be in a meeting or be in a
retail meeting and additional members of
their team would like ask to join
because they wanted to meet me because
they were fans of my content about
marketing and branding and then that's a
whole another Dynamic shift because then
when you present a marketing plan or
some sort of combined initiative people
are really excited about it because
there's someone that they respect that's
behind it and that's when I realized
that this has a lot more legs than just
me understanding how to manage teams
that do it or me getting extra money
from doing brand deals this is actually
a shift in being able to get my creative
ideas executed and be able to help
Brands actually do what they're supposed
to that I'm working on versus get caught
in this endless argument of is this
creative idea going to work is this good
enough why should we do social media and
that's where it comes down to you
because I get a lot of comments on this
channel of people that work on different
teams who are like I have the vision but
I can't get her the cross and the number
one thing you can do to get you there is
to just develop an audience that gives
you enough credibility so you can push
back on those ideas and so that people
who look you up go or when you're not in
the room they go hey you know that girl
has 100,000 on social media or 40,000 on
social media and it's just crazy how
much of an impact that that has
especially when it's expert content
that's what we're going to talk about
here today cuz I'm not an influencer my
content is not based on how good I look
or how funny I am or skits dances any of
the kind of stereotypes you have there
it is based upon establishing my
expertise as someone with experience in
marketing branding and design and so
we're going to go step by step through
what it takes to develop things like
that and the exact tools and stuff I use
so you can walk out of this video with a
road map to start creating some of those
things on your own so I started on Tik
Tok and I feel Tik Tok is a great place
to start because if puts your content
out there to an audience whether they
know you or not it will give you views
from your first video you will have 200
to 500 people that Tik Tok will show
your content to to see if it resonates
and if it does it will find more people
and I have content that does millions of
views I have content that does a couple
thousand views but basically even when
you develop a large audience you're
essentially starting from scratch with
every post and I posted a lot posted
hundreds of times at the beginning I
tried to post once a day now I try to
post five times a week I built it into
my schedule we'll get to that in a bit
but as you can see as I scroll through
this I am doing what's called green
screen content on all this that means I
talk over images so how do you do this
it all starts with an app called cap cut
cap cut is owned by Tik Tok this is the
app that you need to use whether you
have years of experience in Premiere or
Final Cut or you've never edited
anything at all this is the app you use
it on your phone I also use it on
desktop I'll swap into a desktop view
here there's a video I'm editing right
now about packaging and you can kind of
see I have a single clip I recorded on
my iPhone I cut out the background and
put images behind it that's basically
how this works but I recommend capcut
because it is so easy and so fast with
all the core features you need to make
videos and none of the stuff you don't
and the biggest thing is green screen I
use What's called the green screen
effect it's how I talk over those images
on video and you don't need a green
screen I record them right here in the
same place I'm recording this YouTube
video with a ring light so I used this
it was like 100 bucks it's got a
diffuser on it on Amazon The Ring light
is so crucial that I haul it around
essentially everywhere because that
lighting is so good even when I'm
traveling I'm not taking the big ring
light cuz all the smaller ones just
haven't been as good I point it right at
my face and I talk and that is the
extent of the production I use an $80
Road mic that plugs into the lightning
Port of my iPhone I don't even have the
latest iPhone and everything is recorded
on there this video is on like a pro cam
but all my short form is done on iPhone
so Road video mic me that is just a
standard Big Ring light I think it's
newer that's the brand name I have an
atomtech tripod that has a little
Bluetooth there for when I film myself
like walking around or doing things and
Bluetooth to your phones you can hit
camera start stop and that is the extent
of the equipment that is involved in
this process to make this easy I'm going
to screen capture cap cut right now and
put it on the overlay so you can see
exactly how this is done so I go over
here I go to camera point the camera at
myself I click effects on the bottom
left corner you're going to see a little
menu I go to green screen there are two
green screens there's green screen photo
and Green Screen Video so if you want to
record over a video you switch it so
photo you can actually pinch and resize
yourself and move yourself all around
the screen to decide where you're going
to record at video You're static so
you're going to have to use your chair
or your tripod if you want to record
over a video to be able to move yourself
and get creative I do primarily photo
and you literally select a photo to
record over got this photo here from the
Olympics you record yourselft talking
you can speak over it and then if you
hit effects again it's going to bring up
that effect and you can select another
image and talk over your next image that
is the core of that workflow that is the
important part of that workflow the
reason this format is so impactful is
someone just sitting talking at a screen
isn't super visually compelling and
you're competing when you make short
form with just tons of amazing content
and creators and things out there so you
want to be visually compelling so
putting images behind yourself helps it
be captivating to tell your story and
have images there I make 9x6 images for
all of these that I'm able to talk over
and that means there's a nice full bleed
in the background no black bars or
anything and I do this in canva is the
easiest tool for the job by far you can
go create an Instagram story in canva
which basically allows you to make
slides that are 9 by6 autosized um you
can see here I have this plant I use the
magic edit on this plant to Simply cut
it out if you hit edit image and
background remover it will cut basically
anything out there I put text on these
images you know if you hit the the plus
side it will add a new template I resize
larger things to be full 9 by 16 I stack
images on top of each other I will go
make slides in here that I then talk
over in my green screen videos but that
is the flow I make graphics and Cambo
it's combination of screenshots from the
iPhone images I find on wherever that
I'm talking about things I cut out or
edit all sizes to 9 X6 I bring that into
cap cut and use the green screen effect
I'm using a ring light I'm using the
road mic I have it on a tripod that is
the end of the logistics and I want to
break that down that's a lot of the
common questions the number one reason
people don't start is they're like how
do you do those videos where your head
is floating what gear do I need oh it's
expensive it's this or that it's not it
is just those things you can try other
styles or formats you can just talk to a
camera you can do vlogs and edits
there's a million types of content you
can do and I've talking about some of
those in my personal brand for creatives
video but here I'm really focused on is
explaining how you do the basics of that
green screen content so you can see in a
video like this I edited this pretty
heavily I cut all these Graphics out and
made them all in canva I put the
captions over them and cap cut I'm
moving around on the screen it's
relatively Dynamic and I'm talking about
a subject versus something like this
where I'm kind of just throwing images
up there editing few of few things and
talking over them but I didn't put a
bunch of time into the graphic but this
combination of me talking and then
putting captions on there and those
captions are autogenerated and capcut
there's an option to go autogenerate it
will put text up there you can edit and
shorten a certain amount of time is the
core of what these videos look but I've
been making as you scroll through this
roughly a video a day now for two years
I've turned it into a recurring thing
that's a part of my life and you don't
have to go do that and make as much
content as I have and you'll see in some
of the other videos I talk about
basically just getting into a creative
flow where you're putting out a video
even every week or two every week you're
recapping some of those videos into an
email every quarter I've talked about
that in previous videos but it's about
establishing a creative Rhythm where
you're showing your work you're showing
your expertise and if you want to grow
you do a lot more and you should try to
post every day or like five times a week
so how do you organize or know what to
talk about if you look at the things
that I'm doing on here I have reference
videos it's one type so reference videos
is you talk about a bunch of different
things so this is a packaging Tri Trends
video I am simply putting together a
bunch of references that are worth
talking about to show you different
types of packages if you're a graphic
designer you'll see a popular format for
that is people talking about fonts
they'll gather a couple reference fonts
together for you know luxury fashion
fonts this is Brady he was a a previous
cut 30 cohort I did and has has stuck
with it really well but again he's just
putting a reference video together a
bunch of different fonts this is Jason
who crushed this last cut 30 Ste my art
direct
bookmarks and this is example of like he
is literally making all his references
public for all his bookmarks making a
video about different tools that's the
first type of video it's just a
reference video a compendium of things
that other people might find interesting
it's a great format for creatives toble
to put out there to help enable other
people I'm going to talk about
perspective on this and why you should
do this like whether you're an expert or
you're new and how you look at that here
in a moment and then this what I call a
story so this video from Jason is
another good example of just a story
video he is telling the story of what
someone did this YouTuber who has a
certain design style certain thumbnails
he is walking through the end to- endend
story of that one of my first videos I
had that did well was very similar I was
talking about the story behind Monclair
which not a lot of people know and
that's literally you are kind of just
explaining someone else's story and then
adding your input then we have Playbook
content so Alex does tons of playbooks I
started off doing a lot of this I do a
little less of it now but literally A
playbook is like let's explain a common
thing and then give you five or six
steps that someone else could follow to
do it to actually explain how something
works and it could be a playbook for
whether that's art direction or design
or dance or wrestling or whatever it
ends up being doesn't have to be purely
a creative thing you can basically say
hey if I want to accomplish a thing
where are five or six things someone
should know and then break them down
then we have IDE aidea content so I do a
lot of idea content where you say what
if something could be how would I do it
or what's a concept that I'm thinking
about I want to resonate with so for
instance with this one I take a scenario
and say hey if I wanted Laos to resonate
more with American gen Z here's how I
would do it and I put an idea out and I
explain the idea another great format of
the five I'm going talk about here the
last is a comparison or a function so I
did this video this last Sunday it's
about Ala yoga versus Lululemon why I
like ones better than the other and this
format does really well when you
actually put things in perspective and
you ask people to make a choice or look
at a decision or weigh different factors
uh one of the series I got popular with
was called Product versus brand where I
discuss if you were buying something
because it was a good product we're
buying it for The Branding this concept
is called brand battle where I kind of
put two brands in front of each other
and compare what they're doing well or
not uh but things like that where you
begin to develop opinions Etc are really
interesting ways that people like to
look at and and reflect on those are the
five types of content that I feel most
expert content falls into one of those
buckets and you can use as your guidelin
so talk a bit about where you're at in
the journey and making content because
my content has resonated because I'm an
expert right I wasn't an established
expert people to know who I was but I've
spent 15 plus years designing marketing
working in teams working in retail so I
have a lot of expertise to share for
people that are in the same shoes as me
but I've seen things a different way or
people who are coming up underneath me
who are learning a lot of the things
that I've already learned and can
benefit from getting to it faster and
having someone really simply explain it
to them which is really what my my skill
set is I can simply and sometimes
entertainingly explain but no matter
where you are in the journey you can
document it I like to pull Katrina
Katrina is like a you kind of watched
her in her content evolve from let's say
like a junior mid-level designer to like
a senior designer and she's kind of
documented the whole thing you know
moving to La the different types of
designs she does designs she did in a
year and I like to bring this up and I
love her content because you can
actually kind of watch the designs
improve and things go on over time and
this is an important concept cuz it
doesn't just apply to designer if you
are anything you are a copywriter a
brand owner an entrepreneur a
bodybuilder whatever it is where you're
at is interesting to somebody now the
total available Market of where you're
at may not be huge but I guarantee you
even if you're just beginning your
journey there is someone else that is
beginning their Journey who would like
to follow along with you and learn how
you learn and so if you are a junior
copywriter or you're a junior analyst or
whatever it is your first job if you
show what you learn what you're good at
what you're struggling with there are
other people who are in that same
scenario who are going to learn from
that and who are going to engage with
you and again maybe that's a 100 people
not 100 thousand people but it doesn't
doesn't matter it's about honing that
skill set it's about getting some of
that following together and what I like
to say is if you are in a more Junior to
mid-level part of your career it's
talking about things that you aspire to
do or want to learn about or research
things that you are struggling with
things that you've learned that have
been valuable and then cataloging things
that are going on in the world around
you one of my friends Nate um I think
he's under 30 he runs a newsletter
called Express checkout he's really
interested in the cpg industry so
consumer package goods and he literally
just curates the news I think he at
least at the point when he started this
may not have felt he was at a point in
his career to have tons of strong
opinions or be giving tons of advice but
instead he said you know what I'm going
to make one of the most straightforward
places where you can go just to get the
news about this industry if you care
about it aggregated into one place
really thoroughly and I think from this
he has built an audience of people that
are from junior level people all the way
up to like C- level Executives who also
want to take advantage of the fact that
he's putting the time in to aggregate
this and learn from this and I believe
it is a you something that will get him
hired and intros to tons of people in
the future because of what he's built
from there and he does content around
the same thing where he'll talk about
some of the things he sees inside his
newsletter he has a couple thousand
followers it's not huge plenty of videos
have done well but it is a key
Cornerstone of whatever he wants to do
next he'll have had this newsletter
where he Aggregates this he'll have had
this content where he's explaining
different things that are happening in
consumer package goods and what he likes
about them and not this helps refine his
opinions engage with him to go into new
people and provide a basis for whatever
springboard he wants to do
professionally or entrepreneurially
going forward and I say all this to say
it doesn't matter where you are there's
an audience for it it's about
documenting the journey where you're at
not trying to be something that you're
not and just continuing to make content
around so we talked a bit about the
tools and how I do it talked a bit about
the content types about where you are in
your career how you kind of document
that so how does the actual workflow
work to write and create this kind of
content and how do you keep that going
week over week month over month so I
have this notion doc it is the Orin
videos notion Dock and you'll see what I
do is I write down ideas so in this list
here is just ideas so every week as I
record content as I meet people as I
have meetings as I read things I put an
idea down there and it can be as simple
as like a brand name like Umbro matsuda
packaging you know the maximize the
vacation whipped cream whatever I'm
writing an idea down and then I start to
add bullet points to that idea my goal
at the end of every week is to have
bullet points on a couple videos I can
turn into but you'll see this is a long
long list of videos because ideas is the
core of this but there should be no
shortage of them right anytime there's
anything interesting or a question or a
brand you might want to do a future
content piece on you just simply put the
name in there and you begin to flush it
out like this um video is not ready yet
but you'll see I started to put bullet
points I put down Community their art
director the viral garments they did the
right collabs they leverage existing
brand Equity I'm beginning to put
together the foundations of what I'm
going to talk about versus this matsuda
video that's pretty much ready I've now
script it out I have line for line
roughly what I'm going to talk about
with this and it's not quite ready but I
will always have some of these in
progress and my goal by the end of each
week is to have at least these bullet
points for about five videos ready going
into the weekend and then I start
writing them out adding some jokes I
literally script it line for line and
every one of these lines becomes a
graphic that I make in Cana like I
showed before so I will go make a line
for this intro for this luxury bucket
list idea for this first time I showed
mitsuda for the second time and I now
know I have 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12
of these here I need 12 Graphics I'll
get imag from the matsuda website I'll
take some pictures of the mudas I just
got you know again I'll go look up Umbro
if it was the umro content whatever that
ends up being and I will put all those
images together I will have that script
and I will prep multiple videos and I'll
sit down and I record them all one at
the time swap some hoodies whatever it
is or break it up in a couple sessions
throughout the day but this flow where
I'm constantly writing down ideas and
I'm working on the bullet points and
then I then know at the end of any given
week I've got enough bullet points to go
into scripts I make scripts and Graphics
together and then I record and then over
the week I will edit them before I post
them like every day so every morning
before I post I'll finish up an edit for
20 minutes and that is the flow that has
worked really well for me I think it's a
flow that you will probably be able to
take some inso from as well because that
getting that big list of ideas is super
important and you can get them online
you can get them from inperson combos
whatever that looks like I will probably
end up doing a whole like references
video at some point where I dive really
deep into like all the places you can
get creative inspiration and where you
can keep up with like stuff inside
creative niches but that flow of putting
those down and getting into a weekend
has allowed me to kind of create this
framework where I can create content
without having it take up too much of my
time yes I spend time on the weekends on
it that's part of it this is something I
do that is a extra income Source right I
still work I still have Brands uh and so
there are stuff that has to happen where
this is always going to be extra but I
am able to create make time because I
think it's worthy enough especially now
my size where like it's worth the effort
for me to put into it but for you
wherever Point you're out like I did
this while for about 20 of the 24 months
I had a full-time job while I was doing
now I do not have a full-time job I have
a bunch of like part-time things in the
brands I have ownership in but I still
prioritize it but you can do that within
again your own framework set your own
rules for it one thing a week two things
a week five things a week depending on
how much you want to grow but that's
really the toolkit if you look at what
you actually need to record look at the
formats you can use to talk about look
at the perspective of where you can talk
about where you are in your career and
you look at tactically how you put those
ideas together how you script them out
and how you make a video like that's the
foundation from this like my goal is you
should really have no excuse if you
really want to do it not to start
because all those questions or really
have been answered there's plenty of
little things like hey go crop the
beginning and end of all your Clips so
the sound is there or use the Adobe
audio enhance filter if you want to like
make your audio sound perfect and you
know like there's lots of little tips
and tricks you can get but like you're
watching me on YouTube and I feel like
anyone that's on YouTube knows how to
answer your questions right every one of
these things I learned learned from one
of two places I bought Jimmy Farley
who's another kind of YouTuber Creator
he runs creators Corner uh I bought his
like initial Tik Tok course he did a Tik
Tok course before he launched creative
Corner was 100 200 bucks and I got the
basics very similar to kind what I put
in here um and then YouTube everything
else literally how to get cap cut how to
do this how to do that and so if you are
here watching this you have the skill
set to go YouTube and the things that I
didn't talk and the best part about all
this is that the networks grow it
happens naturally algorithms incentivize
new creators and new content so I'll
talk a little bit about the different
networks it's kind of the last thing
I'll really hit here so Tik Tok like I
mentioned is great Tik Tok there is a
setting on here when you have a new
account you can set where it won't show
your stuff to any of your followers U
discover I think it's discoverability
I'm not 100% sure where where it is
while I'm sitting here on desktop but
there's a setting in there that means
that no one who's on your phone will be
able to see you with any more likelihood
than anybody else you can deselect so if
you want to test and try things out Tik
Tok is a great place no one will ever
see it no one saw my Tik Tok videos for
the first like 40 Tik Tok videos I made
and just for reference I like had some
mess messes up before I actually hit it
I started making content my first idea
was to do non-alcoholic drinks cuz I
don't really drink and at that time I
didn't drink at all I was going to
review that I made some videos they
weren't very good I killed that account
second one I was going to make an
account all about consumer package of
goods and cpg two Niche also wasn't
quite right my third account I slowed
down I started talking a little bit more
about marketing and branding and um and
turn into what it is today right and so
again that's fine you have 40 or 50
videos and no one watches that's fine
you keep going you refine it you get
there but Tik Tok will serve your
content out to people and it will show
it from the very beginning and you have
just as much of a chance to get views in
your first video as your as your 15th or
20th Instagram is roughly the same not
quite to the same extent um but a lot
more work happens on there like Tik Tok
you can get a lot of views you get a lot
of interest but like people will hire
you you will find people in your Niche
and more important people in especially
in the creative world are on there but
content needs to be a little bit more
higher production Tik Tok you can have
more fun you can try other different
formats you can kind of lean more into
some of like the trends and things you
see on there and it's very casual and
it's a fun place to grow and experiment
learn and I feel like if you are a solid
Creator on there and you really learn
what you're doing that really translates
12 Network Instagram is going to be
where you end up getting your core you
make the most money I'd recommend doing
them both roughly at the same time I
didn't go over on onto Instagram until I
already had like 50,000 or so on YouTube
Sorry on Tik Tok YouTube shorts is
really mainstream basically I don't
think it's like a good primary to grow
on two things about YouTube shorts it
doesn't have a ton of value and it's
very mainstream so what do I mean by
that so very mainstream is the things
that succeed on there are super
mainstream ideas it's like content for
everybody Tik Tok and Instagram are very
good at putting you in your Niche Tik
Tok will get you in a really specific
Niche like if you're really interested
in marketing around like localized
businesses in California you'll get
content around that it it shows you what
you like in a very Niche level Instagram
is better on that kind of broadly
they'll show you design videos marketing
videos that kind of thing you can fall
into a broad Niche that ends up being
very good you get a big audience YouTube
is just wi it's just showing that [ __ ]
to everybody so if it works has to be
super mainstream appeal the other thing
about that is those subscribers aren't
super useful they don't watch your long
form content you can't really do sponsor
content to them that succeeds it doesn't
get you a ton of value to build a huge
shorts audience it does potentially if
you have have like a really specific
mainstream brand or going into retail or
whatever but as like a Creator or
personality it really only goes so far
for you and I'd be better off putting
your your time into long form just my
opinion but uh if you want to post on
there anyway it doesn't take that long
and it's helpful if you are a business
person LinkedIn is really incentivizing
video right now and if you are
comfortable posting your content on
LinkedIn even if it's less polished it's
probably going to do pretty well and I
would say it's a great place to be in
video right now and if you are Comfort
the cont I would 100% be posting over
there um as a networker you're included
as well I'm posting all my stuff on
there almost every day with the ception
of like less serious content but the
core of your starting is going to want
to be Instagram and and that's really it
like like I've said before um I do a
program on content creation cut 30 if
you are like a college student or your
Junior your career whatever it is like I
will say this 100 times don't ever buy
anything that I have it's not for you do
all the free stuff I said uh if you are
mid-level or you're in your career and
you're trying to advance it and you want
like a fast Dum by professional way to
do stuff I make that I make solutions
for that uh and cut 30 is great for that
you be a 30-day boot camp where you
actually do all this content like with
accountability the next one launches
like August 13th so anyway drop any
questions you have around this before
here I will probably do like a followup
to this like going pro or something like
that in like a month or two if people
are interested um but let me know
questions about that process or any the
content that I've made and I hope this
was valuable and I hope it gets you
started on that Journey because I do
feel like wherever you're at in your
creative career putting some of the time
to understanding how these networks move
and then doing it um is really worth the
time