in this video we are going to talk about
how to make cool products that people
want to buy sounds easy reality is less
so and we're going to do this by talking
through a number of actual brand
examples we're going to break down the
two main tactics aesthetic
differentiation and functional
differentiation and why one is way
harder than the other right now we're
going to talk through why so many new
brands fail and look at tools that can
actually help you decide what products
you should make whether you have your
own brand and you're trying to Branch
into something new stagnant trying to
find something that works you're a
Creator or a potential entrepreneur is
trying to figure out what you want to
launch or you work at a brand just
really want to understand why this all
works this is the video for you let's
lock in so first we're going to talk
about aesthetic differentiation making
things that look better this is what
most people who do apparel Brands launch
products feel like they're going to make
something that looks cool that they can
sell but aesthetic differentiation is at
the hardest place it's ever been so I'm
scrolling here through a brand I like
called House of Errors who makes AB
absolutely amazing clothes at pretty
reasonable prices but this is your
competition if you're trying to make
Street Wear you're competing with them
you're competing with badon you're
competing with kids for a lot of these
folks their hoodies are say 150 to 250
bucks their bottoms are 80 to 150
they're not much more expensive than new
brands put out and the designs are
frankly amazing and the same goes beyond
Street Wear into more classic garments
like male and female stuff you see here
with gaun strictly to women's wear if
you want to succeed off of Aesthetics a
few things need to happen one you need
to have a strong point of view what is
your unique visual ID and I talk a lot
about this in my how to create a brand
vibe video but you need to have an
ownable aesthetic that the algorithms
can translate they know that there's
people that like it they can put it in
front of and that's why things like
Western Gothic Americana coet big
categories often take Center Stage but
Aesthetics is that it's hardest time for
differentiation right now cuz as I
mentioned design is at its peak the
design of small to midsize Brands is
amazing what this also means is that
copying is at its peak as many of you
have watched my videos know I've worked
on I've been a partner with a women's
SAR brand for about 6 years and we get
knocked off all the time we actually
have an article that just ran about our
lawsuit with Forever 21 it's the second
time we've been in bridled in something
like that with Forever 21 we're just
taking one of our designs is one of
maybe a dozen of those things have
happened from Major Brands just in the
last like 18 months and the duplication
is out of control if you see something
aesthetic that's good it can be
replicated extremely quickly and there's
only so much you can do in fact we found
we've actually won lawsuits of people
taking our ideas but I found that the
resources and the time and the mental
energy as a small team that gets spent
putting into doing that isn't even worth
the money you get back it's worth just
staying on Target and focusing but that
means that you're competing with an Ever
quicker Ever Changing landscape where
you have to be that good at design and
guess what most people actually aren't
and you also have to be amazing at
content inside this same world because
for aesthetic Brands to work the content
organic content paid content has to be
the driver and the standard of that is
extremely high so if you don't have both
the design quality and the content
quality it's going to be a hard run and
again there are plenty of brands that do
but it's worth thinking about as you
begin to dive in is this aesthetic
you're going for enough is the design
Acumen enough because the second
category I want to talk about is
functional products one of the reasons I
often recommend when everyone says they
want to start a fashion brand I'm like
hey you should actually Niche like look
at active wear look at niching into
sports and not cuz it's any less
competitive it's just as competitive if
not more but there's more room to create
function so we have aesthetic how it
looks and we have function does it
actually provide a difference inside of
people's lives and so I want to call my
friends at Bandit and one of the reasons
I call Out Bandit is I wear their shorts
and their products and they have really
thought through user experience for
running I just like the actual details
of how the product is for how I train
they have a functional advantage on top
of an aesthetic Advantage it's why one
of the reasons I recommend their
products all the time is because of the
function that they've put together and
for 90% of entrepreneurs and people that
want to be out there even if you are
design-minded I can't recommend enough
to not be going in apparel but be going
into something that is specifically
functional maybe it's apparel adjacent
but finding anything where you can have
a consumer problem solved and so what do
I mean by that let's look at my brand so
valuables is a fun project for me a
creative Studio where I get to bring
some of my ideas to life but my
bestselling product by far are my shoe
bags and that's because they have
function you see any of the other ads
I'm selling you on aesthetic and that's
fine if you like the aesthetic I can
sell there but when I'm selling you a
shoe bag I'm saying hey are you putting
your shoes in a plastic bag when you put
them in your luggage or you just raw dog
in the shoes inside of a duffel bag let
me solve this problem for you for an
affordable price with a product that has
thought through that experience and that
video of me delivering that is an
excellent performing ad asset and you
will find if you've been advertising on
aesthetic things on meta and Facebook
ads or working on organic when you
actually start playing to a consumer
paino when you start solving a problem
for them your ads immediately do better
function leads to more quality products
and we are an aesthetic generation in an
aesthetic world where saying something
like that seems like it's common sense
but for many people they're so obsessed
with the aesthetic look of it they
forget about the function angle that
goes with it and what's nice is if you
are good at content you are good at
creating Aesthetics you also realize
that a bunch of these functional things
that exist in the real world or in
retail their teams aren't good at
Aesthetics and aren't good at content
and haven't brought that over to the
internet and there is white space there
to operate so I'm going to talk a bit
through how you actually find data and
dive into this category and think about
what you actually might want make and
I'm going to roll through a bunch of
brands that have this perfect world of
they've established an aesthetic and
they've established function they do
both together because that's the ideal
State you want to get to with your idea
and your brand is something that looks
amazing that has the content that also
has the function to go with it there's
plenty of examples out there some
leaning one way or the other so I'm
going to go inside particle and I use
particle all the time for research for
Brands whether I'm doing competitive
research I'm looking to create my own
stuff I actually found a lot of the
insights I use to launch some of the car
accessories I launch La specifically by
going through a process like this
particles agreed to partner on this
video so you can check them out at the
description below if you are doing
research or you want to do competitive
analysis for any Online category but
they have this section over here called
Trends and you can select Trends by
their growth status and buy their type
and you can see here things that are
growing in volume so for instance you
can see living room sets are having a
moment versus 2 years ago I have this
set on a 2-year time Horizon so you can
see seasonality that's important here
look at these graphs you'll see oh this
is just a wintertime Spike if you look
on a one-year Horizon and you see a big
spike and realize that's not the holiday
where everyone buys way more then you
can lose yourself in the data a bit
you'll start to notice okay accent
tables Rising costume jewelry kind of
Flatline you can begin to go through and
look at these different angles but this
one's interesting to me industrial
storage cuz look at this it's going up
on a steady line and it has a huge
holiday look at that holiday compared to
this holiday industrial storage is Happ
a moment so I'm going to click through
and say okay what exactly is happening
here what happens is it's actually going
to show me a market side show me a
volume of what it's tracking show me how
it's changing over the last year and
then the product types metal storage
cabinets storage hooks plastic storage
and it's going to show me a bunch of the
brands their average price points who's
selling it that I can dive into the
category for and the industrial storage
one is a really interesting one to me CU
when you talk about Aesthetics and
function look at this the brands we have
here the grip store is selling full-size
cyio crates now cyio crates is an
amazing example of a standout product
that ties together everything that we
are talking about here so these are CYO
crates they are $34 full size they are
$24 half size they come in all these
different colors they have the options
to add Lids but this is basically saying
if you are looking at storage in your
house or in your office or for your work
and you want to have a bunch of options
you want to have it look good this looks
good this is like tactical man adjacent
solves this work built for professionals
right cool hey I want to carry around
all my camera gear look at how I can
divide it look how I can put it together
this video is worth like a th words
right at a cheap price supports this
weight have all these options this is an
example of they took an existing Market
crates storage they applied an aesthetic
to it there said hey we're going to go
towards the more like the Tactical guy
aesthetic the yeti aesthetic we're going
to have function behind it right you're
going to be able to divide things easily
they're going to look good they're
customizable they're stackable they're
collapsable this is a thing that a lot
of people use for a lot of different
reasons and they created a brand around
it and this is where you can begin to
look adjacent and say hey is it actually
does it make sense should there be a way
more female leaning version of this
where we go really far in on specific
colorways or functions or a sleeker look
do we want have a brutalist version of
this you can begin to look at categories
and find your own aesthetic and these
kind of things are makeable just like
you can find a manufacturer for active
Weare you can find a manufacturer for
products like this like this is join
plastic.com this is a company in China
that makes crates of all kinds wholesale
for customers with your designs right
and you can go hunt this down on Google
and Alibaba and import Yeti same way you
can anything else you don't have to
limit yourself to something super
straightforward that everyone else does
I'd much rather see creators and
entrepreneurs tackle the problems like
CYO has versus tackle the same exact
thing but let's look at a smaller
example so this is my friend flock
manufacturing who has a product that is
a car gauge so basically he is saying
that if you really care about your car
your car gauge's speed is wrong
companies intentionally have it wrong as
like a consumer protection and so he has
built a product that has a level of
function but then built a lifestyle in
and around it right he's doing videos
like what's your name what's your car
with other people that are drifting and
he's selling a thing that's really
specific to a niche but setting it up to
be like hey here's this one functional
thing here's this lifestyle that's built
around it that I'm now synonymous with
so that this list and his following will
be able to attach to any other
functional product that he made inside
this world that's why I encourage people
to look at anything that people consume
already in bulk and be like what are the
functions that we can add to that and a
controversial example I like to bring up
is is the ridge wallet right Ridge sells
nine figures of these wallets I look at
this wallet and it's extreme corny to me
as a consumer the Aesthetics of of Ridge
are like repulsive but from a marketing
perspective I couldn't have more respect
for it because they have said hey we
realize the traditional wallet aesthetic
is bad we can advertise this improved
function by what we put together here
and we can hit a market with massive Tam
which is Guys Without taste we can
always have stuff on sale and we can
promote to them this like easier simpler
lifestyle that makes them feel good even
little things like RFID blocking things
that like aren't actually real consumer
problems but if you begin to put inside
of your marketing begin to add on to
that story to that function helps
differentiate the product that's out
there and you look at any one of those
categories you can look at socks and be
like how do I make a hotter version and
you can look at active Weare Act is one
of the most saturated categories in the
world but right now with what's going on
with make America healthy again and the
based movement you can have brands that
literally just say we are not made of
polyester you're not putting much of
plastic on your body the same way Ridge
is saying hey would you want like a
metal modern wallet instead of like a
big old leather wallet like this mate
here their whole proposition they make
very similar clothes look and feels
could be any active Weare brand in the
world but it's 92% cotton 8% spandex
versus like 100% polyesters they are
positioning entirely based on materials
detox your closet like organic
Essentials and that is basically just
looking at any core category and then
finding a position that appeals to
people and you can manufacture a lot of
that position but noting cultural
insights around it is a really important
way to look at it and the cultural
Insight that people care a lot more
about they're wrapping their body in
plastic to work out is a good one
another one I want to call out here is
my friend Brandon who has blank Studios
so he makes desk accessories primarily
right he has hangers and a few other
things but he makes things for an
aesthetic desk he's basically said
brutalist aesthetic now if he was
selling brutalist clothing that would be
one thing but since you're selling
something where your only options out
there there aren't other brutalist desk
accessory Brands like maybe there's a
handful but he is marketing it on
Instagram with great content and being
like hey this is a functional thing this
is a holder for things this is a lamp
this is stuff that makes a difference in
your life it's not just purely a piece
of clothing or a lifestyle item help
helps you organize and I applying my
unique aesthetic to it and building an
entire world around that aesthetic and
that combination of hey this is actually
something that I will use on my desk or
I will use in my life versus just
another thing I will wear is just
entering you into such a better scenario
to be able to sell and how I would
encourage anyone who wants to break into
these brands or into these worlds to
think and I'll end this with a bit of an
exercise to Think Through in your head
is anytime you're creating something
whether that's a hoodie a coaster a
beverage is about creating a blank 4X if
your brand does not have a strong four
so you say shirts for I mean if doesn't
get really specific from there it's in
trouble so if you're shirts for Hispanic
guys under 5'5 that is a niche that is a
okay I'm tapping into a lifestyle and a
background and a culture and I'm tapping
into a specific pain point of I want
shirts that are going to fit guys who
are of shorter height let throw an
example out there the perfect active
wear for health conscious Pilates moms
so right we saying hey like the ones who
care about the antip polyester zoning
into that one person but if you're
saying that why if you're just if you're
saying oh this is just Street Wear
you're missing that one Lev deeper that
separates a lot of these Brands out and
it can be pretty simple one of the ones
that is a favorite of mine is Iconic
Club to call out where they're making
very similar street wear to tons of
other brands they do a good job but
they've put themselves synonymous with a
particular type of like Bay Area car
culture and adjacent car cultures where
they are making hey I'm making this
thing for this extremely specific
audience and they are owning that and
making great content around it and you
can always Branch out from a certain
place but that's a lot different than
making it just for car Enthusiast right
it's niched down to one really specific
area if you take anything away from this
video is that whatever you want to
create get down to that one level deeper
of who it is and attack it as hard as
you can so anyway thanks to particle for
sponsoring this video and their
information is down in the description
if you want to any competitive research
in the space or use any of those Trend
analysis tools they are a great place to
start and as always I appreciate y'all
watching
[Music]