in this video I'm going to give you the
existential question of how do you build
a Vibe I'm going to start with mood
boarding and then Concepts behind a
brand I'm going to go into iconography
I'm going to go into application and
iconography on product I'm going to go
into using your ideas and your Vibes to
like curate an audience before you
launch and I'm going to show you my
stuff as an example for all this I'm
going to show you all the mood boards
bunch of the design files bunch of the
finished products so you can see what
that looks like and hope you get a ton
of value out of it and you can come back
to it anytime you are trying to make an
interesting Vibe for a project you have
let's hit it all right and so if you are
trying to Crea A vibe for your brand
clothing line whatever it is it starts
with this interplay between the ideas
that you have and the visuals that you
want to feel like the brand so I'm a
huge mood boarding advocate for valuable
we did like extensive we have hundreds
and hundreds and hundreds of images
across different places and different
boards kind of representing different
looks and feels but with that there was
also like some interplay as to what we
actually felt the brand was for my brand
take a lot inspiration for my history
setting the vibe and so I lived in
Arizona for years I lived in Texas like
the last six and then moved to
California and been Beachside the last
three and I kind of wanted to make a
visual representation mash up of ranch
Southwestern culture and the beach
culture that plays through deeply in the
iconography and the garments and the
whole thing but the through line of it
all is kind of like car culture
celebration culture life maxing for lack
for better term half Ranch half Beach
all foot on the gas pedal and another
theme is celebration they want to do
unique objects I want iconography that
basically made it feel like when you buy
a special piece it has something on it
that like feels almost like special in
Old School in that way that you could
see on like a championship ring or a
trophy so when you go through these kind
of mood boards we have here it's kind of
indicative of that like the chest pieces
Wings you could see on kind a trophy
like a special piece of jewelry like
having that feel of like something
celebratory mixed in with that same
lifestyle element you see before a lot
of like place behind the pines I like to
think about like sometimes when people
are move boarding now there's always
this like pressure from the internet to
have things be like cool on a certain
level and oh we shouldn't reference
things that been referenced before or we
need to like we can't use common movies
or anything and I'm more of like
especially when you're trying to make
something has like mainstream appeal is
like lean into those ideas put your own
kind of Spin and look on it when it gets
there and like people are going to get
the references are going to be excited
but having these boards is important and
having like multiple people participate
on the boards are going to be a part of
the brand like stack their images and
share it like Al also is really help cuz
it's going to be the basis for like
social media curation so I'm talking
about like curation as part of building
like in a minute like finding people
Based On A vibe I have these images on
here but we had a bunch of like 7s car
exploitation movie stuff on some of the
initial mood boards this is all some
some related and it was like old school
Dodges with like big eagles painted on
them and stuff like that like um like
Smokey and the Bandit type type [ __ ]
that's like stuff we pulled out of to be
like oh yeah we should pull from a lot
of Caron we should pull cobras we should
pull like the things you saw in like old
western ads as part of the iconography
for the brand package so then what do
you do from there from there once you
have all that mood you create icon
here's a bunch of the iconography that
we put together for the now I one
designer do a couple of the core things
like he did these two logos up here he
did the cowboy and then I had an
illustrator come and pull things like
like the eagle and some of the other
illustrations you see and then like you
can basically from those mood boards
designers are going to get the idea and
get the vibe and I'm going to ask for
things be like hey I need something I
can stamp like I I need something that's
like a simple thing if we want to make a
mold versus we want kind of more complex
we need things that look like signage or
official logos or we want to have stuff
that's like more applicable to shirts
these are versions like not all these
have made it or going to be on stuff but
this is like the variations we ended up
working with and and choosing and one of
the other brand themes I wanted to have
in here that influenced a lot of things
like the fact like we've seen like the
Marlboro font or the Ferrari font um
things like that I wanted it to feel
familiar like those are choices you
should have when you're creating
something do you want it to feel
completely new or do you want to feel
like it's been around for a minute like
it's strangely familiar and I liked that
because I feel like we are stuck with
For Better or For Worse like Nostalgia
for like this entire era everyone's
always going to be reminiscing for
something better and they're always
going to be attracted to things that
have been around and if you have a
visual feel that kind of matches that
it's one way to tap into like that
feeling without while having like you
know a newer brand versus if you come
out with some completely different
iconography Etc it puts you on a
different playing field as the kind of
content you can make what you have to do
ET and at some point I might play in
that but I love the idea of having this
feel like something that could have
easily been a part of like a previous
generation of things but getting this
iconography and choosing it and saying
what am I going to do with what and
what's the application is like key to
setting the vibe right and you'll notice
we distressed all the logos like
afterwards versus like sticking with the
original versions of them that were
clean because every time we use them we
want to have that aged feel we distress
a lot of the shirts you know there
there's a thin line between going like
full Affliction Etc but like I'm going
to ride that line as hard as I humanly
can in the meantime we're like playing
with some more imagery and thoughts down
here of things that working but it's
important to think about application
like these are like the fall hats that
that we're looking at it's like having
something like the V that I can put on
multiple things or okay what can I
embroider like this like this is a patch
you'll see it on the hat later like
being able to have that logo and run it
as a patch being able to have this logo
run it as a patch being able to have
like a core word Mark you know
everything else to actually say valuable
like all right being able to run
something like this as a patch like it's
important to think about like how things
are actually going to get applied like
and when they're put on as well these
are like the two we ended up actually
running and you'll see one of those
logos becomes a patch on both you know
we have like a kind of a main logo type
I didn't want to stick with the um the
Imperial font for AR piece of this
forever so we basically kind of quickly
went into a mod of it where like I'm
going to run this for a little bit to
start and then it's going to go away
pretty quick and that will have been
like an original and then we'll have
leaned it into like our kind of cleaner
variant but that's why like I don't ever
feel bad about the inspiration right
this this is a mashup of nint of sorry
of Atari and Ferrari which I think is
just like funny in its own right but
like it's Unique looking enough but
feels familiar you wonder what the
reference is and it doesn't live forever
right it's like an introduction that
feels somewhat familiar and then shifts
kind of quickly into like our own
variant and like logos and iconography
especially when you're a brand that's
going to be producing you know shirts
and things that you have multiple
iterations of should be able to grow
with the projects that you're working
and you start to see like all right cool
let's run that into footwork like so
there's a through line between and we
ended up putting uh up there on the on
the sneaker we put a uh like the the
lines from the other logo okay we're
going into bags which of these could be
potential for a all right let's run that
as a patch let's have this iconography
that we can work through it and like see
how it extends and we did a lot of this
work before anything ever went into
production to see what does that look
like over time be like yeah I'm not
going to run it ever to look like that I
might run this to look like this yeah
okay this ended up looking this started
in here as a design but now end up
looking way better subtler as a patch
like that application of the vibe of the
look onto what you're actually making
and like how that's going to going to
roll is like critical to be thinking
about since day one and we're in a world
where you can mock all this stuff up at
the same time and that's part of the
journey it's it's content all right so
after all that what do we end up with as
far as what we actually produce and do
so I have a bunch of items that are
getting ready to launch and we're going
to walk through them so first you can
have the icon if you're pretty good on
some standard stuff it's only going to
take you so so we spent a ton of time on
the washes on these garments these are
like the heaviest shirts possible fabric
took months to hunt down uh but then you
and you see we distressed everything
both the shirt itself and made shirt was
on the experimented with washing after
we printed it versus before it for the
look we want but basically even basic
pieces need to be statement with a name
like valuable with the iconography we're
going for to see how we applied the
cowboy on this one um and I made sure
like those hotter designs like this and
theob like aren't available on anything
but like a color like when they come out
they're going to be a cobra joint that
are out already on a slightly lighter
shirt you notice everything is two color
that plays back into the vibe I don't
want to do any full color no printing
that's not a screen like we wanted
everything to be like have that almost
like tattoo simpler nostalgic feel well
this goes for like I want to extend it
to like in the vehicle like what would
you put on your vehicle and feel stoked
about if you're putting something in
your truck I wanted you to be like have
that right feeling for it and so like
extending the vibe into those products
so it's not just shirts it's not just
clothes was big for me to come out the
gate hatot you you'll see as well do a
little things like picking the mat on
the thread to the label in here it's got
the vehicle on it the automobile one
from the uh you see on the other shirt
and the design but in here like as a
patch most of those icons are designed
you know besides the Cowboy and the ones
with the in illustration to be able to
double as patches this is a color we
roll with roll with a different design
up using the VM of contrast here and how
do you bring that same vibe to other
products like the shoe bag same Cowboy
look another vibe for it here and as
you'll see another icon functions as a
patch so why I like to have a lot of
Icon a people are like yo you should be
sticking with One logo doing one design
like I don't really feel that's the case
you need like a canvas wheel to work
with and overarching visual kind of
seames and words that the play off that
there's only one thing where the
valuable isn't isn't at play and that's
what we're going to kind of focus on
being like more of a main mark But like
you need a canvas to work with I feel
like and I don't want these to look at
like they're just a t-shirt design these
are designs that we could reflect and
then for some of the logo of the stuff
like then how do you match that so I
have all these knits to go with so this
is a sweater knit this is actually a a
first sample this is heavy we're going
lighter cuz I'm putting it out end of
summer so different weight but you get
the idea but no no logos on these at all
um besides on the tag this this color
end up being too light we went with a
darker brown for production but you'll
get this is kind of like the lighter
version here but even the little stuff
paperclip zip and it's like how do we
kind of pair that pants same thing
keeping this beach Vibe somewhat alive
and included like making sure these
knits have a feel have a texture to them
you notice every one of these products
has texture I love texture cashmir hat
with the horse you can you could see the
texture on the cashmir you can see you
can kind of feel and see what's going on
here on the pants same with that waffle
and even on the shirts like we did you
know the shirts aren't standard like at
all and you can kind of see that there's
a feeling and a grain to to everything
and it's like that text is what
separated kind of standard from premium
and I'm obsessed with it and you'll see
that on everything even with something
simple like belts it's like same thing
like real pony hair and hide and then
like this is an extension visually of
what's going on it has the Western
extension but it's not overt it's not
beating you over the head with it
massive buckles or anything it's got
that same kind of modern subtlety of the
rest but it's extended through materials
Choice through kind of some of the
basics of what do we choose for the
details like what we have on the uh on
the tips on here and then inside we're
stamping with the the valuable word mark
That's same thing like you're going to
be a car posture brand make car
accessories like you doing the dice
having something just just like fun and
and that like add that ties in the
lifestyle portion of this so it's not
just like a picture of a car on a shirt
you know I like to think about what
spaces do your items live in right
you're building a lifestyle You're
Building A vibe you're going to live in
someone's like okay you have a statement
item they wear out they layer it's part
of an outfit they have a bag that they
carry some days when they're going to
the gym you know can you be in their car
can you be in their home what does that
look like and the car particular is like
for people that take cars seriously and
for anyone really dudes girls whoever
like a car is like a Haven of sources an
extension of a personality to for a lot
of folks and so giving like a CRA mon
within that to make you feel sick about
it like is just developing this closer
bond with the brand then we have the
shoes and the shoes took forever we do a
whole separate video on the shoes we end
up going with a sole being the same
color and there's some other details
these are a different color print on the
on the tongue we beefed up the tongue
even more the laces went thicker this is
the closest version I have uh to what's
coming out but it's like if you look at
this from above to Longhorn you know
every little subtlety like what the
brand looks like pretty I'm going to
talk a whole thing about sizing and
molds and how shoes get done uh that'll
probably be next week's video but uh for
vlogging I know this is less like me
rolling around and going places but we
are locked in to get this stuff out and
uh I'm going to break that down this
next section when I talk about the
content like how we're using all this as
content to launch to see how you kind of
tie together this whole like we created
the brand we created iconography we
created products using it to have some
Concepts to okay now we use a story tell
with it all right talk with the roal
vibe in social media so I'm building
this account from nothing 1370 followers
is a grind to build these accounts from
nothing um I have done some I've shouted
it out on my account obviously I have
like hundreds of thousand um I haven't I
haven't ever made a video like fully
about it um or a video kind of cross-
linking it I've done some carousels that
kind of cross link um I did a co- video
on this bag design um you like select
like some little subtle stuff I haven't
pushed it yet and I'm hoping when I I
want to have a base before that before I
like lean too heavily on my audience for
it but like It's a Grind to work through
it so there's a couple type of like mood
Vibe posts I feel like are really really
useful and so the first one is just
videos like this and you can literally
see the mood board we looked at before I
just took my favorite imagery from it
and popped it on here now this is a bit
of a gray area for like established
brands people are selling a bunch of
stuff I'm only putting this out for an
audience yet like pre-drop even then
still a complicated area like how much
of other people's content can you post
like there's whole accounts that are
like you know dedicated to posting like
other content with their own unique
Twist on it my favorite is definitely
this one but you this is also else's
content but with his Vibe he's selling
his things and we're in this weird time
where we're like having that
conversation as to what is allowable and
what's not we're all kind of dabbling in
it the internet wants you to curate
everything it's almost like there's a
massive collage out there but at the
same time big Brands will get sued for
using the wrong music or a Paparazzi
shot or whatever so my view of like the
safe version of this and it's definitely
not like a lawyer going to tell you
don't do any of it but like if you on a
Creator account you haven't done your
your selling stuff yet and you want to
curate and form a community around a
Vibe doing projects like this and being
like and curating interesting things
um my boy Clayton does an excellent job
of this where he will kind of find a
recurring theme he's grown really fast
too um where he will be like cool I'm
going to look at Jack Nicholson you know
or I'm going to look at like the fits of
uh the NBA draft you know like he's kind
of finding a way to get the Men's Wear
vibe that he's looking for like you know
he's uh he's bringing into these posts
to like be able to find people that are
interested in that same Vibe this is a
great way to begin to build a social
following before launching a brand is to
dig into those kind of aesthetic and I'm
doing that same kind of thing thing on
carousels is why I just posted today um
and just like having that like bringing
some of these visual ideas are going to
represent where the brand is going like
into it before we actually start putting
anything out of like our content so
those you know visual types of like
reels that show this are comp compile
stuff together like at your skill level
you know carousels of curation like like
what Clayton was doing are like angles
you can use to begin to build that up
the other one recurring series I'm doing
are these like vision is coming together
um where you're just showing like the
video clips of the lifestyle I'm sh you
the behind the scenes of the different
things that are going on in my life that
is indicative of the brand with the
product developed so you can kind of
have that 50/50 mix of something is
being lived along with it being going on
these all get like thousands of views
they don't get huge but like it's a way
of beginning to like combine those
things into a compilation story so if
you want to make videos like this it is
literally a 1 and 1/2 second intro shot
best shots would be your intro nothing
else on here is more than half a second
there's one or two one second shots that
are particularly like purposeful for it
each of them you'll see as a slight Zoom
I do that with key frames and cap cut
and it is like 12 to 15 seconds Max and
the general idea is just like show life
and show things coming together as they
go these aren't ones that are going to
like Skyrocket your account like what do
we got we got like 2,000 9,000 and this
is like a mood board version of that um
you'll see the count of things I'm
summarizing for my brand where I'm like
putting those things together in one um
but it's literally just like a a footage
compilation but like couple thousand
9,000 8,000 8,000 this one just just
kicking off this one's starting to get
some leg and um collab post this why why
this one big but that's the kind of
stuff that you can make that is low low
work if you're documenting your life you
have an interesting life if you have
access to footage or if you're a good
curator you can make that stuff it does
not take a long time but it begins to
find you the people and begins to
explain the vibe when someone comes to
the page someone comes to my page and
they go through this they go through
that and they're like oh there's a brand
coming or oh there's there's something
happening here they're going to begin to
understand from some of the imagery like
what it is exactly that we're going and
that's where I think brands have the
opportunity to build ahead of time like
based on their Vibe like as soon as you
have your Vibe nailed be doing this
content be doing curation to get as many
people interested in that Vibe as you
can like until you're ready to roll this
is a this is a good example of like a
similar style where this is like purely
a curation account in running and they
just literally put out like running
curation posts they store stuff from the
community they take photos from other
brands they've kind of created their own
like running lifestyle piece um people
will feature it they'll do co- Force
they'll do these little same kind of
thing that I was pointed out before
they'll piece stuff together to like for
people that are interested around
running you know and they'll then have
this as a platform to be able to do
something that they want with and like
by picking Vibe you can sort of lean
into that and the person who's the best
example of like picking a Vibe is my guy
Zach he's like extremely talented at
this but he's able to you know kind of
find his particular carousels and looks
that like tell his his story um and that
like you collect things together like in
a more motivational way that again is
just kind of building the basis for when
he inevitably drops his brand by him
like picking the things that relate to
his like Moody creative Vibe uh he's
really good at all right if this
content's been a little bit different
than the previous week's Vlogs it's
because
my time is definitely changing as I get
closer to this brand launch so I am
expecting everything in the warehouse by
July 25th I'm trying to go live by that
Monday or so the 28th uh and then I go
to China like a week or a week and
change after that so I have to be super
prepared all my content has to be ready
before I go um and then everything else
I'm working on as be on Hiatus while I
go visit these factories I will document
all that as well assuming everything
goes together for the trip uh and then
right now you know it's a lot less of
traveling around cuz we just ticked off
the latest cut 30 we got 100 plus people
in there this time so I'm super focused
on making sure we're being attentive
there still got my brand work I still
got all the sponsored content so it's a
lot happening today I'm much more often
in my house or in the studio a little
less running around but that's the point
of these right to show you a bit of what
it's like when you have to lock in or
not and uh yeah excited for you all to
follow the journey if you're doing any
of the stuff I talk about in these
videos you're creating Vibes launching
Brands you're working all strategy share
let me know how it's going drop it in
the comments we love to see how people
are using it how it's applied how it's
going appreciate yall watching