Today we are going to talk about the
identity marketing playbook. Thank you
to HubSpot for sponsoring this video.
You may have noticed if you walk into a
new environment or a new job, people
gravitate together. One of the easiest
ways they recognize who they might be
friends with is by the products they
use. Say you started a new job, you're a
sneakerhead and you recognize somebody
else wearing whatever cursed pair of
Travis Scott's or perhaps someone with
the road lip gloss phone case. It's an
easy question to ask about one about
sneakers, another one if they're going
to Pilates later. In a world where our
relationships are continually online,
products become a signaller. We all know
that brands signal identity. But growing
up, brands used to use identity as one
tool in their sales toolkit. Now it's
become one of the primary tools, a core
piece of marketing. So in this video,
I'm going to go through what happened,
how the modern world has got us here and
the idea of the loneliness economy and
how brands participated in it whether
they planned to or not. We're going to
talk about the transition of how brands
are now facilitators for experiences in
life that culture has left behind. We're
going to talk about early adopters of
this playbook, go a bit into the Stussy
and brands like that who defined
identity as part of brand on their own
terms. And I'm going to go into how to
think about identity in terms of any
brand you represent or work for or
anything you consume. We're going to
talk about personas, signature designs,
different archetypes of consumers, what
type of identity they're playing into.
Then we're going to end with identity
beyond affiliation around things that we
all want to be and aspire to and how
brands positively can help solve that.
If you've ever been interested in the
psychology of why we buy or how culture
is changing and sort of driving us apart
and the role brands play in connecting
us back together, this is the video for
you. Let's lock in. So I am on my way to
Cannes Lions, the advertising and
marketing film festival where I will be
all week in a villa with a bunch of
other creators making a lot of content.
And one of the panels that I am giving
is about how advertising and organic
content like you see on social media
have started to become one in the same.
They're more similar than ever. The Venn
diagram doesn't have a small overlap in
the middle, the vesica piscis has grown
a lot bigger. And in preparing that
talk, it got me thinking a lot about how
do we actually get here where what we
consume for fun and consume for ads is
basically the same. If you'll be in the
South of France this week, I'll link
some of the events down below. But
diving into it, it started with this
idea of loneliness. The modern world has
made us alone, and then made us justify
that feeling of being alone and consume
around it. So you see things like the
solo trip economy. Don't wait for your
friends to go travel the world.
Restaurants redesigning to allow for
more single person dining. Products you
can buy as a signal to help you attract
other people. Now many people will say
there's a difference between being alone
and being lonely, but more people spend
more time not around other people than
ever in history, which is not an innate
human experience. And so we
subconsciously, no matter what we
believe our culture has taught us to
believe, will always want those
experiences to bring us back to each
other, and we'll connect around the
things we have. One of those big shifts
is this idea of third spaces going away.
The fact that people would all go hang
out at a bar, or a bowling alley, or a
Knights of Columbus, or whatever it is.
You used to have those places they would
share with each other, where they would
be able to congregate and make friends
and have a locality. We have less of
those than we did before. And the ones
we do have are all kind of built around
consumption. The line for matcha,
whatever it is. And that's shifted a lot
to experiences. Because we don't have
those same third places, we gravitate
towards everyone getting ready and going
to the festival season together. The
event, waiting in line New York. The big
experiences of the run club. It's funny,
of my friends who are still single, and
I was married young compared to a lot of
my friend group, four [snorts] of the
six of my boys who are still single all
met their recent girlfriends in run
clubs or like workout related activity.
That is now one of these congregations,
and their events all the ones near me
are put on by brands. A lot of them
start just as congregations and build
brands on top of that, or are run by
influencers. This is all slightly
related to commerce. And none of this is
bad, it's just a shift we have. But
what's gotten interesting is brands now
have double duty. They serve both as
products and connection points. Because
we associate so much of our identity in
what we buy, which again, is not a bad
thing. People can argue against that,
but it's one of the consumable things we
do. It's something that we as human
beings, we buy things, we make decisions
about it, we're proud of it, we justify
it. It's part of our lives. It gives us
an opportunity to reflect ourselves. And
brands are dragged into this whether
they want to or not. If you have a
Stanley or an Owala, it says a specific
thing about you. If you have the
specific workout set of the moment, if
you have a Represent 24/7 pair of pants
or shirt with a big logo on it, the
Outdoor Voices sorority dress, other
people who know what that is,
acknowledge it and represent it and they
think it's a good thing and they like to
meet other people that are into those
similar things. It is a connection point
established through our experiences. And
this is exaggerated by algorithms. Now,
I'll talk about the pre-algorithm
version of this in Stussy in a sec. So,
first, if you want to take what we're
talking about, actually apply it to
really tactical marketing, I would take
insights, like all the stuff you see in
this video, any of these videos you've
watched from me, and take them right
into your ad account in Meta. And
HubSpot's put together an excellent
download, the 20 highest converting Meta
ad swipe file, that can help get you
started. So, the difference between like
a $10 cost per action and a $40 cost per
action is usually one of three things in
an ad. It's your hook, how you're
reeling people in, it's the offer, what
you're actually selling, and then the
structure of the copy, the idea, the
script. And if you don't have a
reference point for what works, you risk
you starting from scratch each time.
That's where Ben Heath comes in from
Heath Media. He's managed over 300
million in ad spend, generated 1.2
billion in client revenue. And HubSpot's
put together a free swipe file of his 20
top performing ads. These are frameworks
that are built out by business type,
covered e-commerce, local, lead gen,
SaaS. They have hooks, they have body
copy, and CTAs you can adapt to your
offer in minutes. You can take things
like identity, personas, and put them
into these frameworks. The part I like
most is how the guide shows you how to
make these your own ads. You know, just
copy willy-nilly. There's an structural
logic behind what makes it work. So, if
you're running Meta ads or you're
briefing someone that is, this is a
reference doc you want to open before
you start. Link is in the description,
it's free, and thank you to HubSpot for
sponsoring this video. Cuz now
algorithms are very much driven towards
people performing for the same gender.
We talked about this in my boy marketing
versus girl marketing algorithm video.
But right now, more so than ever in
history, guys do things to impress guys,
girls do things to impress girls. One of
the big viral things that was on the
internet the other week was all these
street interview TikTokers asking girls
what the preferred arm size of guys is.
And this is a topic I talk about a lot
cuz I work a lot in in health and
wellness and you've seen a lot of videos
I have where I have peptides and stuff
like that. Where guys have been
basically trained by performance for
other guys to over lift, to engineer
themselves to a body type that isn't
actually appealing to the opposite sex.
It's been done by these performative
algorithms. And the same thing's
happened to women in completely other
ways on the other side. Cuz there's less
overlap than ever. And so they end up in
communities and with clothes and with
activities that only signal to their
existing gender. We've been performing
in a very different way than we did
before and then the actual products
shift and adapt to that. And what we
talked about in that video that ended up
was a brands have to have different
marketing strategies. Hugely different
to reach those two demographics. You
can't hit them with the same
advertisement even if you sell to a wide
base. And I actually look at in a world
where algorithms have taken over a lot
of how we communicate and shown true
desires in weird ways, brands serving as
facilitators as connectors, as
representations of our identities, and
ability to go meet somebody is a good
thing. And it also gives if you work in
marketing the ability to understand and
more nuance communicate your value
proposition to other people. So going
into identity marketing, I want to call
out the early hitter here, which was
Stussy. I've done a whole video on
Stussy's art direction, but they were
one of the original streetwear brands
that was hyper focused on who you are as
someone they decided. You could talk
about Polo Ralph Lauren as a kind of
interesting other case where they made
the products for certain demographics
and it was co-opted by people around the
city. The whole the low life movement,
etc. People began to form the brand into
their own identity, whatever they wanted
it to be. It grew beyond what the brand
wanted. Whereas Stussy was surgical.
They introduced the Stussy tribe, people
that represented them, friend groups,
not necessarily famous people or always
pros. Had a lot of overlap with pro
athletes and musicians, but also just a
lot of people, designers, creatives,
interesting people in the world. They
put chapters in different cities. They
facilitated connection between cool and
interesting people. Their lookbooks were
what we now call the homie lookbook.
Where it's your friends and members of
your community versus traditional
models. So, them taking that idea,
multiplying it by the locations and the
chapters, has been adopted by a lot of
people. This is why you see storefronts
early. That location had a huge
presence. When I was in the UK and I did
the video with about Blank, you may have
seen, they were talking about how the
London pop-ups were kind of a
relentlessly part of their part of their
growth. They began to realize that those
experiences and and house music and a
few of the kind of connection points
they had there were actually bigger than
just the brand itself. They were
bringing people together and they're
able to grow legs beyond your kind of
typical one-to-one advertising
connection and there's a power in that.
But then also influence draws people in,
right? Yeah, that's a multiplier. And
Stussy had that right, too. Very They're
picking the right influential people in
skate, in surf, in music. Not
necessarily the biggest, but the ones
that would fit into their existing
community. That you would feel an
identity because you knew about. And
then they adapt that with lookbooks and
content that shows that lifestyle
visually. And you still see that to
today, right? Where a lot of their
campaigns today are shot around where I
am in California. They shot with a lot
of specific cars and specific looks and
people that look and feel like your
friends, not like some other models. At
least for me as someone squarely in
their target demographic. And this has
been adapted in a million ways. Rod took
that idea of the lookbook and basically
made an aspirational identity version.
They would do emails where they have a
night out with one of their models and
they would show the espresso martini
with the lip gloss next to it and the
club that they were going to to be a
profile of an individual person. A woman
that their consumer might aspire to be
or would might just know that was in
their friend group. And they got to
adopt that identity even just by opening
and consuming an email. That's not like
a whole section, here's why you buy.
It's showing a life. So, they brands
show a life that you want or are in.
Then how do you begin to develop this
for a brand or how do you begin to think
about what a brand is trying to say to
you? I'll get there in a second. All
right, so how do you begin to think
about personas and anything you're
marketing or selling or begin to wonder
how you're being classified and sold to?
So, first, if you have a brand, you
don't have any idea who your customer
might be. You want to start with what
you have. And so, what do I mean by
that? Location is a big one. Is your
brand based in a place? Is there an
identity around that place? Being a
northwest outdoors brand versus a
Southwest outdoors brand say
significantly different things. An
Americana racing company versus a
British racing company versus an
Australian racing company or a Chinese
racing company. You can make a unique
brand off any of those angles. That
could come from your background as a
founder. It could come from someone
you're working with's background, the
place where you're located, or just the
place where you took intense
inspiration. If you already have some of
that data, what you'll start to find is
over time, the customer may not be what
you expected. I have a whole video about
archetypes and personas, but you'll know
that my go-to there is you basically
take your email list, run it through
Audience Signal. I'll link them down
below, too. And it'll basically build
you out personas from your email list.
And I love to do this exercise with
brands cuz often they'll think they have
one persona. Oh, well, we sell to like
the hip Gen Z girl. But then you pull it
up and you're like, well, actually you
sell to the older Gen X woman. But that
perception you have of maybe that older
Gen X woman wants to be that younger Gen
Z woman. You begin to start noticing
these shifts of, okay, we're marketing
to one person, but the customer that
attracts actually has a different
desire. Or our marketing isn't
connecting cuz we're actually marketing
to the wrong person. The person actually
ends up buying us isn't even discovering
it through our funnel. This is how you
can begin to have those conversations
that are important. So you start with
your persona knowledge. And then you
begin to think about signature designs.
What you'll notice about all the
identity marketing products that we
talked about, whether that's a No walla
water bottle, whether that's a Rep
T-shirt, whether it's the choice of your
company to be a Google versus a Teams
organization, all of these have visual
signatures. It could be colorways. It
could be form factors. When Dior had
cosmetics that went viral, it's cuz they
had basically like a little Dior
keychain attachment to it. It would
signal that you're a Dior person, give
you a luxury signaler from their their
logo on a low-cost purchase. It's an
identity play. Patterns, tags, like
subtle things like you see with
Margiela. I did this video with Grant
Owens, I got a lot of comment on my Bad
Son jacket. You can immediately tell
it's Bad Son because they have that
particular raised stitching pattern that
they do. These are all visual
signatures. They can apply to basically
anything. So people will associate
themselves with those brands. Color does
this as well. When I was in the toy
category, Nerf associated itself with
orange. Zuru was competing with them and
owned red. At Gel Blaster, hyper-focused
on green. You could see in big color
blocking on the shelf. You want people
to know, not get confused about which
you're buying. You want to be able to
go, "Oh, I'm going to get the green
one." These are little things that are
associations cuz they want to associate
themselves with whatever the marketing
was. I was recently talking to a luxury
grocer doing meal prep and they were
talking about packaging as a
differentiator. And everyone has the
same meal prep packaging and I was
telling them that they should go matte
green cuz you could still do that in the
same compostable style. Silk or do like
a emboss or deboss of their logo on it
and they would probably quadruple the
amount of people taking pictures of it
versus of the plain plastic top. It
would become an identity play to signal
that you got that meal kit because it
would look sick. And stick to that
demographic who's buying that kind of
luxury thing. And you could also do this
with iconography. Obviously, the logos
tell this story. And you'll see it white
fox, scuffers, all like the hip brands.
It's the easiest way to play it. Nude
project, iconography and logos tend to
work in some regards, especially with
younger demographics, but the more
subtle way is in kind of more different
differentiation when you're working on
color and pattern and things like that
end up being kind of usually bigger,
more sophisticated ways to do it over
time and in more categories. And then
I'm going to walk you through five
archetypes for lack of a better term.
Basically, five reasons that people will
associate themselves with identity for a
brand. So, first is belonging. I want to
fit in with people like me. This is
sneakers. Sneakers basically only exist
to find other people that will think
that your sneakers are cool. And by
doing that, you immediately have a
friend or have someone that will think
like have some respect for you and it's
completely about belonging. Every single
one of those purchases is around that.
And that's an excellent way to for a
very lonely demographics, right? And
sneakers appeal a lot to lonely people.
It becomes an obsession point. Fashion
in general is a large a larger extension
of that. To be able to find people that
have that same interest or that same
thing becomes a very easy signal. And
then there's a second out there. It's
hey, I'm better than the others. That's
another thing. There's a lot of people
that want to prove they're better than
other people even subtly. You have
brands like The Row that position
themselves entirely. I'm more tasteful
than everyone else in my friend group. I
have The Row playlist. I have a bag that
not everyone would know. I have this
subtle look. It's the it thing. You are
proving something to others and making
people aspire to what you have, but
subtly. Then you have the rebel. I don't
play by your rules. If you're marketing
to Gen X, this is like your go-to. I'm
going to choose not just the more
extreme angle, but the more outsider
angle than anything else. Which is
Liquid Death to some regard. There's
room inside kind of like a
counterculture rebel take in every
product category. Then you have
standout. You have flare. The I'm
special call. Look, that bad sun jacket
is flare. I own that jacket cuz I know I
can go on a podcast and it'll stand out
on a feed. is a flare piece. You only
have things like that if you are trying
to prove a point about standing out from
something. There are plenty of brands
that say something about you in a loud
way. And then there's the idea of pride
in a subculture. And if you know, you
know. And you can base that around
geography, around race, around hobbies,
around gender, but saying that you're
proud of your background. That yes, of
course I'm going to have this
Chinese-founded brand or whatever it is
that tells that story to a subculture.
Those are just five that you can work
with. Fitting in, being better than
somebody, not playing by anybody's
rules, standing out, or having pride in
a subculture. It's an amazing way to
just begin thinking about how an
identity marketing playbook could work
for any product. I want to end with
identity beyond affiliation. Cuz
identity can also be deeply personal. It
doesn't have to do anything with others.
Almost all of those have to do with a
signal you're sending to others. But one
of the core points to think about in
marketing is if people have a weak point
in their internal identity, how can you
help resolve it? And a great example of
this was uh I worked for years with Lift
Foils on their marketing. They're a surf
foil company, electric hydrofoils, etc.
And we had a big advocate, a customer
advocate. Drew Brees. He's a famous
quarterback. He bought this product.
While I was running marketing there, we
had a massive gift given to us that he
went on Ellen after he stopped being a
quarterback. He talked about one of his
favorite things to do was ride on his
efoil. And he actually did like a
training with Ellen. And it was a huge
sales process for us, but not just
because a celebrity was showing it off.
Because of what it solved. Not to get
too deep into hydrofoils, but basically
you have classic hydrofoils that have
basically a mast and you ride waves and
there's no motors or anything on there.
And it's a work of modern physical
mastery to be able to pump and foil. I
have 14 stitches in my forehead from a
foil, so my my days of any of these are
gone. But then the electric hydrofoils,
you're basically flying on water, and
you have a motor and a remote control,
and it's an incredible feeling and
experience. But for either of those
product, but in particular the motorized
one, there's a lot of guys who get to a
certain age, and they have the same
experience as me. I got 14 stitches in
my head from a hydrofoil. It was proof
to me that yeah, I'm not young anymore.
I can't do extreme sports anymore. It
was like my third injury in a row. I
fell off an ATV. I had bruised a rib
snowmobiling. I was just I was like,
"Okay, I still think I'm 22, and I'm
not." Happens to a lot of guys. But you
see a product and you're like, "Hey, I
can still have that experience. I can
still have that feeling of flight, of
exhilaration, but I can do it in this
really modern way, and that's a problem
I can solve with money that's really
cool, that someone I respect, a pro
athlete, is doing." That solves a weak
point in so many guys' identities who
had made that water sports a core part
of what they do, and who could continue
doing that in a way that was cool and
fun. And uh and this ties into kind of a
last strategy I'll outline here about
about testing that. Because what was
interesting there is we tested all kinds
of ads, right? I was in the same
framework I talked about how when I was
talking about HubSpot earlier, what I
did I ran all the meta with an agency
inside there. We worked on ad creative
and collateral, etc. I worked with
Vervont on that. Shout out Vervont. But
we were testing traditional, like, "Hey,
let's get our our team on there. Let's
get We have We have pro surfers. We have
We have Laird Hamilton. We have Brian
Grubb. We have a lot of pros we would
have in the ad account." And let's test
people who look like our customer
avatar. Let's test older surfers. You
would get this wide swath of different
consumer types like inside these ads
like to see what worked or not. And we
found that it's not the person that our
consumer wanted to see themselves in.
They didn't necessarily see themselves
on the board. Some people did, but a lot
of them wanted to see the younger
avatar. They wanted to feel like they
were the younger person. It was like a
50/50 split. And those would go to
different landing pages, different
experiences, people that bought for
different reasons. And that's what I
would encourage you to test when you are
inside building ads, building organic
concepts. Think about who is your actual
demo, and who does that demo think they
are, and then who do they want to be,
and then who do they want to hear from?
A friend of mine has a a brand that
sells to elder women. He actually found
that young UGC from like younger
good-looking guys worked a lot better
for him than that demographic being
shown to themselves. You might find a
mix of that. But that combination of
what those archetypes look like, why
people buy, and who they want to buy it
from adds up to sophisticated marketing.
And if you're in one of these funnels
and you're being advertised, do you
start thinking about what does it say?
If it's actually solving an internal
problem that you have that is a weak
point for you, that's a good thing.
You're being shown a mirror of something
you may want that may actually solve
something for you. Or if you're being
shown something that's selling you a
version that feels kind of dirty, that
you don't quite want or feels off,
that's a bad sign for a brand. And the
more conscious we are on how we're being
sold and why and why we buy, the better.
So anyway, I'm excited to be cutting
some videos from the French Riviera here
next week with a bunch of the people
that I'm inside our Cannes house with.
In the house [music] we have Dara
Denney's there, JT Barnett's there,
Sammy Cohen's there, Tayden Brandt, a
bunch of creators you may or may not
have heard of. We're making all kinds of
interesting content we have scheduled
depending on timing, and so I'm excited
to drop some of that on this channel
too, so you can see some more
conversations over the coming weeks. I'm
working on a video about actual French
luxury as well. So for those of you
waiting for more luxury content, that is
coming soon. And as always, thank y'all
so much for watching.
>> [music]