In this video, we are going to walk
through starting social media for a
brand from scratch going into 2026 or
how to fix and scale one that you
already have. I am fired up for this
because this is something I get asked
about in the comments all the time.
Since I work with all kinds of big
brands, I am deep in our direction,
content strategy. I know a lot of you
are just trying to get off the ground or
fix something that has gone off the
rails and we're going to tap into that
in this video. We are going to cover the
three content types that you should
really be doing that will give you the
biggest bang for your buck in terms of
return, virality, and generating real
business value. We're going to cover
your posting cadence, what analytics to
pay attention to, how content plays into
your bigger overall marketing funnel.
It's basically going to be like a
7minute MBA of what they should teach
you about business, all presented here
in context of social. And I'm actually
going to rip through all the common
misconceptions that people have about
social media, what account types to
have, where to start them from, so you
can just cross all that off. My goal in
this video is that you have no excuse
not to get started with a plan or fix
your existing social media, and we'll
have some fun along the way. Let's lock
in. To make this even more actionable,
we are bringing back the Cut 30 free
3-day challenge. I've linked it down in
the description, but you can make
content with us for three days with
Zooms where we will feedback it live
each day and a curriculum to show you
exactly what to do. Videos on how to
record that is coming at the end of
October. We only do this a couple times
a year. So, if you want to take action
from some of this, you can lock in with
us below. So, first to start, who am I
to talk to you about this? And if you're
new here, I want to break a bit of this
down. So, not only have I built pretty
massive social media for myself and for
brands that I have led, now I actually
work with large brands specifically on
their creative strategy. So, I get to
see this from a high level and a
personal level. I am in the trenches.
But also, I have now gotten over 2,000
people through Cut 30, which is a
program I do with Alex from Sweat Equity
and Lambforce, teaching them how to do
social media. We've had hundreds of
success stories. And here's why this is
important is that the people that have
succeeded there are all kinds. dentists,
doctors, lawyers, people that make
baseball slide training tools,
homegoods. We have frameworks that work
no matter what product you are working
on. But also, we get to see the data.
There is a 100 people in each cut 30.
And we get to see exactly what is
working for them every moment, every
month. Between all of these things, I
feel like I have a pulse on social media
that nobody else has. And I love being
able to share all of that information
right out. But in this video, before we
even get to the exciting content side,
we are going to talk about the why. I'm
going to give you a 7minute MBA and what
they should teach you in business
school. And in this video, I'm going to
zone in on what I think is the best
thing you could be doing on social right
now. And that is one, a services
business. So, if you have an agency or
you are a freelancer, that could be
website design services, that could be
roofing, that could be dentistry,
whatever it is. If you have a service,
this is going to be ultra applicable to
you. And that's one of my biggest
requests is okay what if I don't have
some amazing looking product in creative
direction. So we are tackling that. And
the second piece is if you have a
product that you can make expert driven.
So what do I mean by that? The cheat
code right now for branded content that
really drives sales and leads is when
there is a person or a lens. You can do
this with carousels too and we'll get
into that. That delivers expertise
around the product category to somebody.
That is the content that performs the
best right now in this moment in 2025.
And I'm going to break down those exact
formats. scenario, content, breakdowns,
rankings, all that. And you could apply
this expert approach to services, to
retail locations, and to physical
products. But to do this, you have to
take a step back. Everyone's views on
social. Everyone wants success. Every
wants to go viral, but they don't really
understand what they want to do with
that in their business. We're going to
lay that out. So, every business follows
this marketing master plan. At the top
level, you have how do you have
awareness for new customers? You can pay
for that awareness with advertising.
That's type number one. You can get
referrals from your existing customers.
That's type number two, word of mouth.
Number three, you can go cold and chase
those down. Cold calling, cold emailing.
The last agency that I ran was based
entirely off those last two. It was
referral and word of mouth. A little bit
of content, but the majority was like
cold calling, cold DMing. It still
works. And then the biggest opportunity
being organic social where basically you
put time and energy into production, but
you get uncapped rewards. How far that
can travel on the internet and how long
it lasts. And this is one of the first
misconceptions I'm going to talk about
is people think that short form content
in particular is ephemeral. It's done in
24 hours, 48 hours. But now, especially
that Instagram has been added to Google
search. Something I've been talking
about with Ash and Jordan and the brand
fathers a lot is like the ripple effects
of our content. Right now, you can
search a lot of sports marketing terms
or specific campaigns, etc. Our content
comes up in Google and it keeps getting
views 3 months later, 6 months later.
Seasonality, too. Every time Canton Fair
happens in China, all my Canton Fair
content blips right back up. You would
be shocked at the longl lasting nature
of content on short form if it has
value. If it's not a skit or something
ephemeral in itself and this is why in
this video we're going to preach no
slop, no quick wins, no I'm going to
throw up some jokes to get views. That
is not what this is about. It's about
business value. You are replacing that
layer of advertising cold calling. So
what happens there? That follows a
traditional marketing funnel. If you're
not aware of the funnel at the top is
awareness. You generate attention. Then
you go down to nurtures. Gives people an
affinity for you. How do you make people
like you and want to work with you?
That's level two. And then level three
is actually closing them and converting
them. And so for the majority of
companies we're going to talk about
here, you they think that they need to
go from social media content to a sale.
But that is not how real sales processes
work, especially for a service. And also
most products, people do not typically
go see the content, go to the landing
page, buy the first time. So we're going
to talk about hard and soft sales and
landing pages next. So when you begin
putting together your social content,
you have to think about where are they
going to go? What is the call to action?
And they're going to end up on a landing
page on your website 90% of the time.
And that landing page is a website
that's designed to take an action.
There's two actions they can take. One,
buy right there. It's a hard call to
action. Number two is get their info.
Have them become a lead. That's a soft
call to action. So, let's go to example
one. So, if you want people to convert
right away, you need to make sure on
your landing pages that you have called
out the objective they're trying to
solve. Are they trying to grow on social
media so that they can go on more dates?
Are they trying to lose weight to
achieve X goal? They're trying to cut
down their runtime, get the most protein
and the least amount of calories,
whatever that is. calling out their
objective there, listing the benefits to
the person of what your product has, not
just your specs, testimonials and
reviews right there on the page. And
then frequently asked questions, what
objections they have, can you solve that
in the lander? That is the core of what
a conversionbased landing page will have
on it. But soft CTAs are often much more
important, especially for businesses
that sell a service and also for
businesses that require some education
to get someone to buy, which is way more
businesses than you think. You want to
just get someone's email. So for that,
we have what's called lead magnets. This
is when you give somebody something
information typically in exchange for
their information. So this could be a
PDF like a checklist or a diet plan. It
could be a free quote or an estimate.
And so for instance, a great example of
this is those big reports I do with Vang
Group. We did our big luxury online
report about websites and luxury. That
is a lead magnet for them for people
that want to get a luxury website done.
And here's how that exact flow works,
right? Thousands of people sign up for
those reports. We get 5 to 6 thousand
people on a report. Only a fraction of
those are their end customers. But
that's fine. Those customers take it's a
long sales cycle. When you decide you
need a website, you actually make the
decision to go on it. You build a
budget. It's often like a year. So, they
are just getting those people on their
list then educate them and nurture them
over time until they're ready to make
that decision. But when they have, they
now have read this incredibly immaculate
piece of content created with an
influencer and people know what they're
doing, promoted that drives a ton of
value for them to think about and they
become top of mind for that choice. Now,
you can have more tactical content that
leads to a quicker release, but that is
the idea. Get that information, get them
on your list, communicate with them
regularly. That is typically where you
want to go for social media. You want to
get people then into the next stage of
your funnel, right? Like, okay, they
follow you on social, now they're on
your email list, they're on your SMS,
they've signed up for a call, whatever.
Now, a typical business flow for
anything is usually there's a call
involved, right? A pitch of some kind.
So, what happens is they'll sign up as a
lead and you want someone to get on a
call and you have what's called pre-all
assets. These are really important for
every marketer and social media person
to understand is before someone gets on
a call or makes a decision, you want to
give them as much information as you
can. So, sales people can send it over
in an email. You can send it an email
automation. If it's an e-commerce brand,
using something like Omnisand or even
just a regular band services brand, send
it over. You're basically giving them
information before they actually get on
a call to make a decision. And after
they get on the call and you pitch them
on a new roof or power car washing or a
website, whatever it is, afterwards, you
want to give them even more stuff to get
them to actually finalize and get to the
purchase. And all of that is content.
It's why I call this out. Every single
one of those stages has content. Content
on the landing page, content pre-all,
content they show on the call, content
after the call. And if there's no call
involved and they're just buying, it's
just emails that go to them, SMS that
goes to them. Every piece of content
that you make should be used in all of
these places. So even if it only gets a
couple thousand views up front, if it's
then used these other places in the
funnel because it achieves an objective,
that is how content should be thought
about for marketing. Used to think about
a marketing budget and content's a small
amount. Now it's like what is my content
plan and where can I use it in marketing
is the new way to think about this. So
having that framework going into this is
really important versus just like I need
to put up views and make sales for my
business. It's like no, I need to get
people I need to be able to give them a
lead magnet. I need to be able to give
them a reason to give me their info.
Then I need to be able to educate them
enough to actually get them to make a
sale. And I do that by repurposing a
bunch of this content and thinking about
content more holistically. That is the
end of the 7minute roughly MBA. Now
let's get into the fun part. Let's get
into the content types. There are four
types of content you are going to zone
in on. Storytelling, rankings and
ratings, breakdowns, and scenarios.
Those are your four content types. And
you can do them in two formats.
Carousels visual or in video. And the
video could be a talking head, it could
be an edited vlog, it could be a green
screen. whatever that you want to be.
But that means with carousels
especially, you don't have to be on
camera and on video to do this. You can
do succeed on social media purely with
carousels. You just have to care about
the design and the editing of them. But
what are these four things? So
storytelling is actually telling the
story of your business. 64 days ago, I
decided to buy a bowling alley, etc. You
are going through the process of the
things that you are doing every day. So
a great example of this is this Yon
Mavan. He literally bought a bowling
alley. It's a great visual example for
this. Not everyone has that. And Carson,
shout out, Carson is a designer for his
freelance graphic design business and
for the job he works for. He was able to
make content where he's just showing the
process. He's telling the story of
creating something. That's content type
number one. Now, storytelling doesn't
always have to be your story. So,
someone who's done an amazing job with
this is Ken from Front Office. And I
wouldn't aspire to have his content. His
content is amazing. But even if you did
a dumb down version of it, he talks
about stuff that he likes and respects
that he is learning from to build his
clothing brand. So, for instance, he's
talking about salvage denim, cashmere
sweaters. He's talking about hunting
jackets. They're not the ones that he
makes. He ties in his products
sometimes, but also he just tells the
story of these two different hunting
jackets, for instance. And this is why
expertisedriven content is so important.
So, if you sell hunting jackets and you
sell the tell the story of other hunting
jackets, how could that possibly make
sense for your business? Well, it shows
your expertise in the content. People
want to know about these things, but
they don't inherently want to be sold.
So, his ability to say, "I care so much
about hunting jackets. I can tell this
immaculate history of why they're
important or why this material is
important." gives him credibility that
when he goes and drops denim or drops
his own jacket, people are like, "Wow, I
really resonate with the how the care
and intensity this person puts into
their craft and I pay more attention to
it is a lower stage in the funnel. He's
used his expertise at the higher stage
and this expertise can be used studying
it, right? But for instance, like a
fragrance brand that educates people on
the most interesting fragrances in the
world and then releases their own
fragrance and tells that story is the
one of the best ways to get real actual
credible attention on the internet. And
you can do this from the perspective of
the student or the perspective of the
expert. So Ken positions himself a bit
in the middle where he says, "Hey, I
love clothes to this extent, but I'm a
doctor. I don't know a lot about
clothes." So I am like a student of the
game who's growing into an expert. Now,
if you're at the beginning, you're like,
"Hey, I just discovered these scents.
What makes them tick?" You're showing
your journey through a story. On the
other hand, if you are a doctor and
you're being like, "I know everything
about this and here's exactly how it
works." You're able to do it from a
really credible standpoint. They both
work. But your job with storytelling
content is to pick your story or the
story of interesting things in your
niche. And are you approaching it from a
student perspective or an expert
perspective and to then make that
content and to do that content well, you
often want to follow what's called the
hero's journey format. This idea that
when you make a story, people are
compelled to follow it if they have a
setup that's interesting, some big
conflict that happens, the conflict
tries to get solved, it doesn't quite,
they try again, they make it, oh, now
they persevere. That is just a common
thread. And being able to use that
storytelling perspective is a really
important thing in story content. But
that is definitely the hardest of the
options we have here. Next up, we have
ratings and rankings. So, this is a
dentist that was in this last cut 30.
This video has hundreds of thousands, I
think, coming up on a million views. He
is a dentist sitting in the dentist
chair rating whitening toothpaste on
whether you should use it. This is the
power of expertise. If you have it,
again, student perspective or teacher
perspective as a crucial thing to bang
in your head is this same video may not
succeed to the same extent, but if you
were not a dentist and you were trying
to build credibility in this niche, it
would literally be like, I bought every
one of these toothpaste or I'm
researching every toothpaste to
determine if it's the one I should use
or not. you are building that
credibility, again if you had your own
dental care brand or whatever, you are
showing people that you are putting in
the work to learn it and you're giving
value along the way. But if you have the
credibility, which a lot of people
inherently do, especially if you have a
business and you're a roofer or
whatever, giving your opinion and
sharing why is crucial and people want
to know. And why this is important,
there's a bigger sociological thing
happening here where the media doesn't
educate anymore. You don't read
magazines and learn about toothpaste,
right? And everything on the internet is
so crowded in just these like Google SEO
results that maybe you learn some stuff
from chatbt if you ask it. But we just
don't get real human information from
people in the same way. I go see the
dentist. I don't really get a chance to
have a 20-minute conversation with them
about whitening toothpaste. Right?
You're in the chair, you get your stuff
clean or any questions. All right,
you're out. And I'm not going to engage
them on a lengthy conversation about the
ingredients of whatever it is I'm using.
But the access we have via the internet
is an amazing thing and gives that same
perspective. And this applies to
anything. Another cut 30 student. This
is an exercise we do in inside cut 30.
This woman has a bakery in Vermont and
she's literally ranking premium
ingredients that are used in food and
why people are inherently interested in
someone who's an expert's opinion. And
you'll notice some of the subtle things
here. He looked like a dentist in
dentist chair looking like a dentist.
She is wearing the baker's guard. Stuff
like that matters if you again you are
coming from the extra perspective versus
the student perspective. Use it. Wear
the scrubs. Look in the outfit. Look the
part. Do it in the kitchen. We'll talk
about sets later, but it's a crucial
thing to think about. And then know this
is in a different language. This is out
here to go to prove like this is a video
that's doing great from four days ago. a
thousand plus likes already about golf
in whatever country this language is
from. Apologies to all my Nordics, but
he's just talking through golf
misconceptions as a passionate person
about that that has a golf business.
Same thing, another cut 30 student
talking about roof sighting. Again,
they're pro promoting a service of
business for roofing by talking about
the types of things that they like to
use, why they think someone should use
it or not with candid opinions. And so,
the reason this content does so well is
it shows real personality, proves your
business is real, starts conversation,
and drives value for people things are
already thinking about. And this won't
last forever. This period of expertise
won't be forever. But for the next 9
months, this is your surefire solution
to win. A year and a half ago when we
were really getting into cut 30 to
start, this this didn't work. This has
become the zeitgeist over time. And this
is the stage we're in. So we had
storytelling. We had rankings and
ratings. And I will keep banging in
there. Perspective, student perspective,
expert perspective. There's no excuse
not to be able to do this kind of
content. You either know enough or you
are learning at the same time. And the
next is breakdowns. How do you take
things that your target user wants to
know, needs to know, or that are
happening in the world and talk about
them. So, back to the Carson example.
Shout out Carson if you're watching this
video. He's giving great packaging
examples that his audience of aspiring
graphic designers and if people that
would want his design services both
would want to know. And he's just
sharing that with a breakdown of why
it's good. And I call out this video
because this would work if you are a
packaging company, if you are a design
services company and you can design
stuff like this. There are a lot of ways
to crack through this breakdown. Josh,
another cut 30 grab. He's breaking down
advertising for meta ads and he's
basically giving away the playbook. And
this is people are always afraid of this
when they do breakdowns. Oh, what if if
I give people the whole workout, they're
not going to hire me as a gym coach.
Yeah, they they are. I give away
literally everything. You could never
buy a thing from me, never hire me to
consult, and I've given away 99% of the
things that I know and do on all these
YouTube videos. But guess what? Most
people aren't actually going to go
through all the YouTube videos. And if
they do, they aren't going to do the
actions themselves. And if they do,
amazing. Great for them. But the people
that are in my demographic of the
executives that want to hire me at a
high budget level, they just want me to
prove my expertise. They're like, "That
guy knows what he's doing. he knows what
he's talking about. He has a proven
system for this. Let's bring him in. And
that is the same thing you're doing.
Most people don't want to go just
replicate all the things you said. They
want your proof of expertise to then
hire you to do it. And any of the people
that then go do it, you're just building
advocacy and people that will recommend
you and people that are gaining value
and affinity for you. Your customer is
hiding within that. You are proving to
them your expertise. So he walks through
literally this entire flow of Facebook
ads and how you have to think through
all the stages of awareness and what
kind of ads you need to design there for
them. It's a complete breakdown. He's
selling ads as a service. And while some
people may find find value and roll with
it themselves, if you were like, man, I
like the way this guy thinks about this.
My business needs that, you are becoming
a lead. And the last type of breakdown
from the need to know or want to know is
to what's happening now. So Scott,
another cut 30 grad. All he does is
naming. He has a brand naming
specialist, hard niche. A lot of videos
are going to flop in that niche. That's
totally okay because the ones that hit
are really going to hit. And so he's
doing a content about Stiller's new
launch. So Ben Stiller's new soda
company, the name, other root beer
names, kind of talking about his
expertise and context of this thing that
happened. And if you care about soda or
you care about Ben Stiller or you care
about naming you're interested in in a
whole variety of ways. It gives him good
top offunnel content. But now we've gone
through storytelling. We've gone through
ratings and rankings. We've gone through
breakdowns. The last one I'm going to
talk about is scenarios. Putting
yourself in someone's shoes. So Ryan his
plan to save country style and dethrone
Tim Hortons. He's talking about a chain
that he would redo. And he is a business
person who provides consulting services.
And he's talking about what he would do
to bring back a noted chain. So scenario
video. Scenario videos are amazing.
Another great example of this, uh, one
of my favorites, my guy Bobby Maximus,
absolute legend. Five exercises to fix
95% of problems after 40. He is zoned in
on scenarios for guys after 40 in a
bunch of his videos. The best
testosterone boosting diet for men over
40, six exercises that do years of
damage, how to get rid of man boobs,
he's zoning in on an exact scenario. If
you are a guy over 40, that's what makes
this an exact scenario, not just in
general, and you want to do X thing, get
rid of man boobs. Here is a playbook for
interior designers. If you have 700
square f feet of space, this is exactly
what you can do to make it feel X.
Again, it's developing a scenario that
your target market might be in. Scenario
building content has the fourth style of
content. Now, one thing you may notice
about all these content, this is all
intellectual content. This is all not
the simplest content to write. Guess
what? That's what works. If you try to
do simple stuff, you're looking for the
easiest answer, you're not going to make
it on social. But if you're willing to
think about it from a student
perspective or an expert perspective and
attack these angles and actually write
useful stuff for people, it's going to
be really hard to go wrong. And the best
part about this content is if you get
600 views on it, you get 600 views.
Anyone that actually watched 30 seconds
of it got a tremendous amount of value.
You are building people that will become
real customers out of that. All right,
60second blitz. We're going to put 60
seconds on the clock. I'm going to walk
through all the common questions and
misconceptions you have starting an
account before we get into a flow. So,
the first is what network should I do?
You should focus on Tik Tok and
Instagram. If you're already active on X
and LinkedIn and you're willing to put
in some work, I would also crossost
there. And you can crossost a YouTube
shorts, but it's not going to drive a
bunch of value, but worth just throwing
on there. So why Tik Tok and Instagram
give you the most value for what you're
posting? They give you free views no
matter what. From view one, you can go
viral from video one. You have the
biggest total available market for your
business on there. Also, the content
that does good on one is good enough on
the other. You may specialize in one
more than the other over time, but at
the end of the day, both carousels and
videos do great on both of them and you
should just roll with that. Post on
both. LinkedIn and X, if you are willing
to be on there and talking to people and
engaging and commenting, that can do
well as well. I wouldn't base it on
that, but it is a great place to add on
if you want to drive more value from
things you already created. YouTube
shorts is not going to drive much
business value for you. Even if you put
up a bunch of views, 30,000 views
doesn't really do [ __ ] for you. A
million views maybe does some stuff for
you. Maybe is not good viewers. It's
against find a cross post, get the
awareness. Do not expect anything for
your business from it. You got to go
into YouTube shorts with zero
expectations. For your type of account,
you should always have a creator account
on Tik Tok and on Instagram. You can
still run ads on Instagram with a Tik
Tok account. Doesn't affect your ad
account. Tik Tok, the only reason to
have a brand account is if you have a
Tik Tok shop store. And even with that,
you'll see most people will then have a
business account the store is on and a
separate creator account they use to
make videos because those brand accounts
are deweeded in the algorithm. Everyone
else creator accounts country. Your
account should be started in the country
that you want to target for Tik Tok. For
Instagram, it should be set to that also
ideally set up in that country as well.
This is why if you have an account in
Singapore and you can't actually reach
anybody because you're trying to reach
the US and you wonder why. It's cuz it's
showing it to people in Singapore. Start
and get the location set up and post
mostly from that country or else it's
going to really impact the organic reach
you have. If you're traveling naturally,
totally fine. The algorithm knows, they
know you're a South American traveling
in Europe and they're going to show your
content and then show you content based
on those things. So, it's important to
consider. Again, it doesn't always have
to be like that, but it's really
important where you start and build the
basis of your account. US and Canada
kind of has a lot of overlap. It's not
as important. Same thing with like
English speaking Europe countries, but
it makes a lot of difference uh for
basically everywhere else in the world.
And if you cannot do that, you should
hire someone. Hire someone on Upwork to
set up the account, use the phone number
in the right place, and then maintain
and post that content and make sure you
have access to it. maybe a backup person
to use in case that goes south. But that
is a huge thing of why people wonder why
their account doesn't work cuz they
literally have it set up in a country
that doesn't matter. If you go and you
set up your account in Sri Lanka while
you're on vacation, that's actually a
problem. And then no schedulers, no, we
actually tested this in Cut 30 for
hundreds of videos and could prove
definitively that every single
scheduling app, including the ones
native to the platforms, hurts the
performance. You should be uploading and
posting exactly whenever you want to do
it. And then people are always like,
"Oh, can I crossost or I do X and Y or
like can I hire someone to post out my
other stuff from overseas?" is no, just
post it. Guess what? It takes an average
of 2 to 3 minutes for every post you're
going to do. So, if you're posting on
Tik Tok, Instagram, LinkedIn, X, YouTube
Shorts, just throw in Snapchat Spotlight
for the hell of it. That is going to
take you 12 to 15 minutes and you can do
it. It's not deep work. You can do it
while you're on another call. You can do
it while you're walking the dog. Just do
it. If you are trying to optimize and
that is too much work for you, that's
actually a symptom of a bigger problem
of you not wanting to do the work. Just
crossost. End of my 60cond rant. I hope
I hope I made it in time.
This week's video is brought to you by
Omnisend. They are my email marketing
platform of choice for e-commerce email.
If you are using Shopify, it is a
no-brainer to use Omniscent. But as
always, I want to make sure these
placements are full of value. So, we are
going to talk about founder email, how
to use plain text in your email
marketing. So, a common misconception
with brands is that all their emails
have to be these immaculately designed
product promo heavy emails. But one
thing that you should absolutely
consider, especially as we go into Black
Friday, Cyber Monday, and the holiday
season, is what we call the founder
email. This is a plain text email
written in the voice of the founder or
the CEO or a personality at the brand.
It comes from a human, doesn't have a
bunch of fancy graphics, if any, and
tells a story and isn't just a one-off.
If you need something, you can introduce
a sale, explain a product release, tell
the story behind an ignored product,
celebrate a milestone that the brand is
going through, or explain a mistake or
issue. This is a recurring tool that you
should start and use for your brand to
basically have in your email toolkit and
you will note the plain text email
asking people for something or
explaining something can be a part of
that ongoing repertoire you pull out for
big moments and also when the brand
messes up. I'd also recommend using
features like the automations in
Omnisense. For instance, your welcome
automation when someone first becomes a
subscriber or the automation after they
make their first purchase where you kind
of can introduce them to more about the
brand. throw one of these plain text
emails in there so the founder
introduces themselves and maybe explains
the backstory, etc. So, it's something
your consumers are used to seeing from
the start. Anyway, if you are looking
for a strategy to kick off your Black
Friday, Cyber Monday, or your holiday
season, you haven't done that yet, a
plain text founder email is an awesome
way to do it, walking through some of
their favorite picks or some of the
stories behind the brand, which I'll
have done getting into this holiday
season. And I would highly recommend
using Omnisend. A they are significantly
more affordable than some of the
competition and they have full features
from segmentation to automation to
analytics for your brand. You can learn
more about them at the link in my
description. And I do have a fulllength
email marketing video that's also on
this channel if you want to really dive
in. So now we're going to what are you
actually going to do? You are going to
pick two of the things that I put up
there. Three if you are ambitious. And
what do I mean by we're going to pick
from these charts. You got video and you
got carousels. So you have storytelling,
breakdowns, ratings, scenarios. You can
make videos of each of those. You can
make carousels of each of those. Choose
three. Two is probably for the week, but
two is the minimum you choose. Choose
two. Choose three if you want of that
combo of video and carousels of any of
those. It could be all carousels, could
be all videos, could be a mix. And your
job is for those three you picked. Two
to three you picked. You are going to do
two of those every week. That is your
four to six posts. You are going to make
four to six posts a week. You don't need
to post every day. You should post four
if you want to really do this and get
after this. If you're like, man, I
really just don't have the time. Pick
four. Do two of two things. And you're
going to do each of those for a month
before you even evaluate or decide on
anything. That is the core of the social
strategy to go from from scratch. Two of
each a week. That's your four to six
posts. And you're going to do each of
those four times. And then you can
actually start to look at some data and
and make some decisions on getting
better. And then you're going to layer
on some of those are going to start
doing well. It may take you a month. It
may take you three months. But if you
follow that formula, you're going to see
some of that content is going to start
doing better than others. And you're
going to start getting comments and
questions. So you can layer on top of
that to get to more posts. You're going
to attack the common questions and
responses. So, say you did that ratings
and rankings videos on cameras as a
cinematographer and people really
started asking you about color
correction. Then you can basically take
those common questions and say, "I'm
going to hook my video with that common
question and I'm going to answer it."
You can layer in more content around
that expert driven content. And if
you're a student, you are going to go
find out the answers to that and come
back and present that as what you think
and engage in that conversation. And you
never stop. All right. So, that that is
your basis. That is your plan for every
month for the next 3 months. And then
we're going to get to level two. Once
those videos start to hit, once you get
some traction, don't even think about a
CTA. No CTAs in your videos, no buy my
stuff, go to my email list, go to my
page, until you have traction. If you
would do that, you are hurting yourself.
You are shooting yourself in the foot.
Get traction first. All your videos are
getting 5,000 plus views. Then think
about CTAs. If you're in a really niche
thing, construction, SEO, then that can
be like 2,000 views. Then you start to
think about driving to lead magnets.
What can I give that has value that they
will download? Or is there some sort of
like advertorial page I can do? You can
ask people to go there in the bio or on
Instagram you can use many chat or stand
to comment and you can DM people the
link. Those both work very well. But the
biggest note the biggest thing I'm going
to call out here that no one does that
is an absolute driver and the people
that do it are get way more value out of
social than anyone else is you need to
engage and DM reactive and proactively.
[Music]
>> If you are not responding to every
comment with a personalized thing,
responding to every DM with a
personalized thing and then trying to
sell those people, you are leaving money
on the table. And then if people comment
and they seem like legit leads, you DM
them. This is a sales process. Social
media is a sales tool and it is social.
There's a social in social media. So
that if someone on TikTok is asking a
bunch of questions about your service or
what you do or whatever, DM them and try
to sell them or get them on a call with
your sales team or whatever it looks
like. But you are going to get so many
more sales if you proactively do that
and you respond to everybody and you go
actually be like, "What more information
do you need?" You know, like, "Hey, you
can get this now with this deal. Here's
this 10% code. Hey, you want to get on a
call and talk about that today?" That is
what separates people who get a little
value out of social from people they get
a lot of value out of social. I have had
this happen to me multiple times where
people who would never hit me up as a
client, but I'm seeing them commenting
on all my stuff and they're like CEOs or
CMOs of major companies. I am sliding in
those DMs. And the same thing works for
a business, especially if you're trying
to get clients. Like get after them. You
are now warmly in. And it goes down in
the DMs.
>> Goes down in the DM. And if you don't
want to do it, get your sales team in
the DMs and have it be fast. Your goal
is to get people from social media on
calls with your sales and have them
respond as fast as possible or to do
that selling yourself or with a team
that is on there. And remember that that
engagement level and that efficacy is
going to make a huge difference in just
taking advantage of the content. The
biggest thing I I can tell you to give
you any lessons, if you make one piece
of content, you are doing yourself a
disservice not putting as many places as
you can because you already spent all
the time to make it. Push it out there.
And then if you're then not actually
chasing down the leads that come from
that, even the soft ones that's just a
comment, again, you're not making the
most out of all that energy you put in.
That might be someone else at your
company or it might be you, but just
chase it down. You'll be shocked how
your life will change, how many clients
are at your fingertips, even if you're
only getting a handful of comments. Last
tip, ignore every [ __ ] guru hack. 2C
videos. Oh, Tik Tok has text post now.
Post your Tik Toks to your stories. Use
this audio to go viral. None of this
matters. All this is a distraction. The
only thing you should spend time on is
making quality content. Go to that list
of things above and make the best videos
you can in your niche. Everything else
is a hack to get views. It does not
matter. Is a distraction. It is easy
dopamine. You want to build an
expert-based business on social media.
No matter what it is you sell, you want
to have a person front and center. That
could be you. It could be a founder. You
can batch content if it's someone else
in the company. Prep all these ideas and
bunch of the prompts and scripts and go
shoot with them once every two weeks is
the way most companies do it. or do it
through educating through carousels and
kind of faceless videos where you're
telling those stories. It'll be a little
harder that way. Nothing else is going
to drive the efficacy for your business.
And the last thing I want to think if
you if you want to basically a bonus, I
wasn't even going to put this in there
cuz this video is already going too
long. But level up your set. If you want
to stand out from everybody else, you're
looking at this, you might be looking at
this and being like, "This is already so
much. It's going to be overwhelming.
Great. Don't think about this." If you
have any level of budget, any level of
thought, get your set together. What do
I mean by set? Like this setup. One of
my favorite new followers as a creator
is this woman, Internet Anthropology.
She just cares about that setup. She has
probably in her apartment, but there's
there's books, there's a candle. It
looks nice. It looks unique. You know
it's her. Fotic, he was in cut 30. He's
just he's doing his set. He has really
nice carousels to walk through. First of
all, showing that expertise in the same
way. I'll probably have to do a whole
another carousels video later cuz I
couldn't go as deep as I wanted to into
this. He's doing it in front of his
fragrances. Same as this DS Andurga
founder. He's doing a bunch of these
videos in front of the wall fragrances.
It immediately shows credibility. And
again, even if you're a student, you're
just passionate about this and you put
all the ones you've bought so far behind
you. You're showing how much you care
about it. And if you want to step it up
even further, people like Open
Residency, you may have seen me on their
podcast on this podcast here. They're
just taking a studio format and making
it look unique. But that is the one
thing I'd say if you want to go level up
all these things I said you want to add
a multiplier on that, the set is your
multiplier. That's going to be the
biggest creator topic of 26. Again,
that's probably a whole separate video,
but like sets is the new thing
everyone's hyperfocused on. But anyway,
as a reminder, we are doing the free
3-day challenge. If you want to do some
of this in the flesh with us as a group
for free, that is down in the
description. If you have questions about
doing this for your own, I will try to
hit as many as I can that you drop in
the comments about what to do for your
niche. I will note I've asked this
before and you just got to put yourself
in in these shoes, right? You just have
to think intelligently. What can I rate
or rank people or care about? What news
is relevant to my niche? You have to
stop hitting a wall and start reframing
and looking at possibility. I have so
much more I want to talk about, but I
didn't want this to be a 2-hour video.
But this is your framework. Those are
the exact videos. That is your posting
cadence. Those are the types of accounts
and networks that go on. If you are
looking at this, you're like, "Oh, but
do I have to do this or do I have to do
that?" You are the problem. This is not
hard and it's not easy. But there is no
shortcut. None of the things you're
trying to do or you're trying to get out
of or work. The answer is in the work.
The answer is in just doing the thing,
not being like, "Oh, what if I did X or
Y?" No, just bite the bullet. And I
promise you, you will be so happy and
abundant on the other side. That is all.
If you're looking for a personal or
creator version of this, my personal
branding video I'm going to link here. I
appreciate you all so much for watching.
[Music]