In this video, we are going to cover a
full guide how to build a content-first
[music] marketing team in 2026, no
matter what the size of your org is. So,
we're going to cover this from the
smallest to the largest of companies.
I'm going to go through examples, small
and large, to kick this off, all kinds
of brands that are going media company
first. We've all heard this trend, you
love to talk about on LinkedIn, every
marketing guru that brands are media
companies now, but no one talks about
how you actually execute it tactically.
After those examples, I'm going to talk
about how to build a marketing plan in
the content world. What does your team
look like? What are the goals to give
that team? What are anchors? What are
goals? Do you actually have the ability
to navigate if you're pivoting to this
new world, starting from scratch, or
just want to understand your place in
the world as a creative and a marketer
in this brand as media company era? And
I've been involved in this on every
level. I started as a content creator
when I was an SVP of marketing, and I
was pivoting my more traditional
marketing org to have to think like
this, and it was hard. Recently, I
advised on the build-out of an entire
studio system for an existing brand that
wanted to bring its expensive six-figure
productions in-house, working through
everything from their gear to the
facilities to what staff would look
like. And I saw that every single time
they brought in a traditional media
professional, the costs were going
radically out of control. It's a big
part of why I decided to make this
video. It's going to be super thorough.
I'm super excited for it. A lot of prep
went into this. Let's lock in. A quick
heads-up on the 24th, my next community
call, we're going to go through Q&A and
training just on this. If you want to go
deeper and ask questions, you can sign
up at the link below. We'll also have a
PDF summary of all the stuff I talk
about in here that's going to be
available for anyone that comes to the
call. Let's kick off with examples,
because becoming a media company,
building a content team, doesn't mean
just posting more TikToks or asking for
more from your social media manager. It
means structuring your marketing team
and your organization to be content
first. And you'll see a lot of hot in
the moment concepts, like social shows
are really hot concept right now, but
most people who are doing them flop
because they didn't know how to make a
content first org before that. A social
show won't solve all your problems if
you don't know how to make great
content. It's just a tool that you have
once you do. And so everyone when they
think of brands that are also media
companies, they start with Red Bull. Red
Bull was the original masters of this.
And I do want to shout out, this is not
a new concept. Social media has changed
it, but Red Bull did this. Patagonia's
had documentaries and ripping that
forever. Salomon the same way, early on
YouTube and just dominated with it. I
remember Arc'teryx used to have a
massive explorer section of their
website with all these deep dive
documentaries, etc. that I would spend a
lot of time on. And this used to be a
advantage for those brands to stand out
in their niches, and now it is more of a
thought of how you have to compete if
you want to last in this era. So Red
Bull still does this today, right? Where
they basically replaced a certain type
of TV that no longer really exists, the
Tosh 2.0, the ridiculousness, the action
sports era. Now it just lives out on
their Instagram. They've adapted it to
be very good for social media. But I
want you to think there's a lot of ways
to accomplish this of all different
sizes. So one of my favorites is Rapha,
they're a cycling brand. So they're
interesting because they actually do
long-form cycling documentary. They do
their great social media content
including really artful, well-shot stuff
like this as well as kind of more
conceptual carousel-based stuff like
this. But they really focus on
documentary films and using their retail
locations, calling them clubhouses,
putting screens inside them and doing
screenings of these documentaries and
other films and participatory
experiential marketing within their
network of retail. So it became a hub
for cycling media. Now it also gave them
the ability to debut the media that they
were creating, this long-form stuff, in
a way that builds real community with
their active users. That's why I want to
call out that being a media company
doesn't always just involve putting out
tons and tons of TikToks. You can do
this in more refined ways as well. One
of my favorites is Flamingo Estate,
where they obviously have amazing
editorial content. If you go to their
website any given day, you see all this
beautiful photography and brand content.
They really care about the editorial
look and feel that they have. But they
also do this, I believe, weekly letter
from the garden from the founder where
he talks not just about the brand, but
about the experiences, the places he's
traveling. They curate boxes from around
the world, and he'll break down the
intricacies of them. It's a combination
of the editorial that happens on written
as well as what happens on social media.
And I love to look at this brand as an
example because I believe the backstory
of this was during COVID, the founder
ran an agency, and they wanted to focus
their efforts on a brand as work went
away. And they basically turned the
media that they produced as an agency
into the media team that worked on the
brand. So, a common example of a direct
transition into "Hey, we have all this
quality. We have this network of
creatives. Let's apply that to a really
amazing story." And then they centered
it around the location. The Ling Long
Estate is the story of this physical
estate. It gives it this amazing world
they can document. Tracksmith is another
one where they have stories, they have
documentary films, they have Meter
magazine, a physical issue that they do.
They have these documents of this
amateur running that they've done online
on social media. They'll publish
everything from gift guides. It's built
into their flow as a brand that's come
up. They're ideally aesthetic. And then
the storytelling in the written world,
in the documentary world, and in the
short form world is a core part of the
brand. Now, in more social native, one
of my favorites I've called out before
that's local to me is the Cheese Store
of Beverly Hills that my friend Greg
works on. And I love calling this out as
an example of a small business. They
have a retail store that has a
immaculate selection of cheese, and they
literally just have their employees
interacting with customers, getting a
gift, recommending different cheeses for
different styles, explaining what came
into the store with all the characters
throughout that. All shot on iPhone, all
straightforward in a constant stream of
every single day. This is one post a
day, a new story from the store in that
location. They're documenting the same
thing at a pop-up. So, I like to
highlight this as it's become a
content-focused org, right? You can
execute something like this by spending
one day a week documenting a bunch of
what actually happens in the physical
location with a videographer actually
working through that. Shoot it all on
iPhone, and you have a content-first
promotion machine that works on all
social media. This happens for orgs
without a team or a contractor, too. One
of the recurring guests that we have on
Cut 30 is Chunky Fit Cookie. So, the
founders have come on. What I love about
them is they'll have come on and given
talks to the people we have in inside
the Zooms at the high points and the low
points of content. They're solving it
like anybody else, but at a founder
level. They're saying, "Hey, our
content's flopping right now. Here's
what we're about to test. Oh, our
content's at a high. We're going viral.
Here's what worked." They live and
breathe this as much as they live and
breathe the recipes of their product.
And that's the core how to start with a
media team. We'll get into actual team
later. You'll see they are shooting
iPhone content constantly. Founders are
on camera. They're documenting inside
the commercial kitchen that they work
in. They found a couple viral things
that work for them. They're documenting
the journey that they have. And you'll
see a brand that starts with this at its
core when it's just two employees and
how that can build to when you're much
bigger. One of my favorite examples at
scale, probably heard me mention before,
is Ladder, the workout app. When I talk
about team, they're going to be a
perfect example of what I mean by this.
So, they have their own internal social
media team who are creating content on
main, but then also, they've all the
coaches that work in on their app, their
fitness app, who all work with the
brand. I believe there's 10 or 20 or
more, who create content on their own
that also promotes the app. And they're
interacting characters with this. And
this is interesting because basically
every representative of their brand is a
content creator of their own right. They
have to interact with the main account
and they're all working towards one goal
and actually sharing advice. I spoke at
one of their offsites, I believe a year
or two ago, cuz they were looking to
educate more of their content team about
different tactics and techniques. So,
not only are they working together, but
they're investing in bringing in outside
people to actually talk to them and
help. And I'm going to overwhelm you
with examples here because I want you to
understand that every size, every
industry, there is somebody doing this
and it is working. Rare form, number one
of my favorites, they're taking all the
stuff they sell. They're a curated
marketplace. This is such a good
strategy for anything like second-hand
or anyone who runs a store distribution
operation. Every big retailer,
Nordstrom, QuickTrip, 7-Eleven, like has
the best opportunity to act on stuff
like this. But Rare form will go break
down the history of the different pieces
of furniture that they have in house
with their team members in all of these
different ways. They have an infinite
library of their own products to go to
work from. And then perhaps the best who
I look at kind of the gold standard of
this is Represent. So Represent has done
this in long form and short form
excellently. So not only do they have
the Represent YouTube, George the
founder has his own YouTube, they have a
24/7 YouTube for their athletic side
where they've created the persona of the
brand and they're documenting it there.
They also created the persona of the
founders. Then you go to their actual
social media, you have the Represent
core social media, very kind of
straightforward clothing brand content
at a high level, lifestyle, lookbooks.
Then you have the founder content that's
a little more personable storytelling
showing both behind the scenes and all
the action that's arguably more
important than the core brand account.
And they're not just doing that from
George and the charismatic leader angle,
they're also doing it from his brother
Michael and the creative angle and the
design angle. So you get to see all of
that happen and the core account and
they are the embodiment themselves of
what the brand looks like. Multiply them
by all the other characters in their
story, the people that they sponsor. And
you'll see if you are on TikTok and you
interact with Represent, you're going to
get with an onslaught of sponsored
TikToks from them of creators of all
kinds, small to large, doing sponsored
fit checks that they're running through
Spark ads. This is a sophisticated media
system operating at the highest level on
short and long form on all networks,
personal brands, and core brand and what
a modern media company looks like. And
it takes a lot of planning and time and
dedication and obsession to execute at
that level. We're going to talk about
events at the end of this and I'll tack
on the Kosis and Merit and a few that do
well there. But I'm going to end with an
example for software and an example in
the agency world. So Cloudera changed
how everyone markets software. Cloudera
has done a number of different things in
terms of spinning out tons of accounts,
obviously the much talked about. They're
one of the examples of someone whose
marketing goes further than their
product, right? They don't have a
product anyone's buying, arguably a
product that works. Maybe they're doing
okay, but their content's incredible.
They built a machine that whenever they
do find that fit, they'll be able to
work into. And I see a hundred software
companies who are copying this and
there's a website for this Social Growth
Engineers that documents a lot of this
really well. They are going and creating
episodic funny content around the Clewly
world. And they're doing this again for
software. It's why I want everyone to
think there's there's no way this can't
work for whatever program you're on,
right? If you remember, I'm a recurring
face on the Cash App social media.
Whether you're in finance, whether
you're in software, it works. And the
last example I'll give before we dive
into the tactic side of this is on the
agency side. So, many of you are
familiar with Darkroom, who I've
interviewed their founder on this
channel in my Art of Advertising video.
So, they have a world of creators on
their account, too. So, you'll see Max
Nodet, Cut 30 Brad is a recurring
creator they have on there. 600K on this
video. Tatum, another Cut 30 creator,
has recurring content on there. They're
collaborating with people to help them
make media about the core niche. They
designed my carousels, and we collab
post on those carousels. So, I'm
basically if I do a carousel about the
art of the marketing campaign, they're a
collaborator on it. They're also gaining
the followers, someone who provides a
service inside this niche. So, they
decided to build the world around the
creator economy, which is something that
they believe in as an agency. And we'll
talk about this when we get to team.
But, finding an agency that understands
something like this, the way someone
like Darkroom does, that runs your paid,
that runs your email, that understands
the creator flywheel, that's the
storytelling, the media co-component,
and then can use those assets to make
you money is a core part of
understanding how this new marketing
world works, not just the actual content
creation. Anyway, now that we've walked
through a ton of the examples, I'm going
to explain the actual world of how all
this marketing works and ties together.
I'm going to go through what you need to
do it and the team that needs to create
it. And we're going to talk about goals
and anchors. First, let me explain the
world. So, every marketing org needs to
look at what they're doing like this.
You have your owned organics, your owned
social media organic accounts. Maybe you
have one Instagram, one TikTok, maybe
you have multiple, but that is the stuff
that you own and control. Then you need
to have your owned paid, ads that you
run, that you create assets for. So,
your content team that you have is
making content for your owned organic
and is making content for your paid ad
accounts, whether you're doing full TV
ads, whether you're doing ads just on
Meta or TikTok. Someone needs to be like
be creating that. And then that ideally
in this generation starts in-house.
Maybe you have external partners once
you have an in-house team. We'll explain
that in a minute. But then you have your
world, you have your organic world with
people outside of that. So for instance
in the Represent example, George and
Michael are extensions of the brand.
They're part of the brand world. Same
thing in the Dark Room example. So your
organic world begins to get pretty big
pretty fast. Many of you know the brand
I've worked with this last year, Morphe.
They have thousands of creators that are
being seated product all the time.
There's thousands of creators
participating in their brand world.
They're posting organically, they're
getting their content sparked, where
paid dollars are going behind it to get
it more reach. And then for any brand
that's smart about this, they're taking
content from that world and pulling it
into their ad account. They're
additional assets that they're spending
advertising dollars behind. If you
understand that core thing, you
understand how this new marketing world
works. Cuz the efficacy of this is so
much higher than basically any other
media buying that you can do. Creating a
flywheel for this is the marketing. And
then you have the conversion aspect of
that. What are the landing pages that
people go to, whether that's the product
detail pages or pages to sign up for a
call or get a free download, whatever it
is. How good are those pages? What are
its messaging? And then what is your
communications? Your email and your SMS
that go out. And how all this
intertwine? Do you have the same assets,
the same characters, the same media, the
same faces? How do you fill up your
email automation and your email
marketing with the content that you're
making inside the rest of that that I
just discussed? That is your marketing
world. And everything outside of that,
anything else you are considering doing,
trade shows, buying banner ads on
whatever, sponsorships, any of this,
forget any of that until this part is a
money-making machine. Cuz any industry
that you are in from a retail store to a
fashion brand to financial services to
legal, this is the flywheel that gets
you the most results for the least
dollars in a combo of organic and
advertising that is extremely scalable.
And once this is a money printing
machine for you, you can expand outside.
Now we're going to talk about the team
and what you need to get it together.
But first, if you're like me, you keep
reading and hearing about agentic
commerce. But what exactly is it and do
you need to care yet? Let me explain. So
right now most e-commerce stores are a
collection of static pages, product
detail pages, checkout, your homepage,
your cart. And the shopper does the work
navigating through all of this. They
read the reviews, they may even leave
the site as part of the experience to
find validation for what they want to
buy. The journey is the same whether
it's their first visit or their
hundredth visit. And the data that the
store captures and gives the brand owner
on the back end doesn't actually inform
their experience as they browse. Now, I
want to make it very clear that this is
absolutely changing. We all understand
that LLMs are a component of search
discovery now, so you can discover
products or get to a website from Claude
or ChatGPT the same way that you might
from Google search. But, that's not
enough. The idea of agentic commerce is
you're actually bringing that into your
store. This near future of e-commerce is
beginning to happen right now. What's
called agentic shopping is where people
are going to interact with the site that
knows their budget, knows their sizing,
what they've navigated on before. It's
able to change in real time as they
move, answer their questions, and
present options. Give real advice on
mixing and matching, what works for
their skin or their body type. There's
going to be a significant shift in how
people shop online. So, Swap, who I
partnered with on this video, is leading
the curve here. They're the first
agentic storefront company. They've
already partnered with Drake's,
Percival, Frankie Shop, Retrofet, Tala,
brand names you've heard me talk about
on this channel, and many more to begin
implementing this agentic layer in
addition to your standard e-commerce
store, just like a new channel. But,
what's most exciting is the stats of
what this leads to. 2x conversion rates
with the AI-guided storefront, 3x time
on site with deeper customer engagement,
up to 20% reduction in returns with
better fit guidance, and repeat
customers increasingly prefer the
agentic experience. This is just the
early results. There's an entire
ecosystem that's coming here. For
everyone watching this right now, my
main focus in this video is just
awareness. I want you to understand
what's coming. Go to the Swap site and
visit it. Look at some of the examples,
look at some of the products, some of
the customer stories, and just begin to
think about what that could mean for
your business and how you might build a
strategy on it. And people who make a
bet on this for their career or with
their brands may be able to see a
radical amount of growth. And
opportunities at this scale do not come
around very often. You can learn more
about Swap at the link in the
description. All right, so now we talked
about all the examples of who's running
their brand like a media company. We
talked a bit through what the world of
marketing looks like. Now, let's get
into what you need and what the team
looks like. What do I mean by what you
need? So, to make media, you need a few
things. There's actual editorial and
media concepts. It's not just about the
cameras and the shooting of it. You need
a point of view. What is your content
saying? Why is it different? What are
you saying to your customer beyond just
pushing the product? Are you selling
them on a lifestyle or a function or
humor or a key insight? You also need
patience. Testing through this level of
media isn't something where you go viral
right away. It takes repetition over
time. If you watch any of my videos
where I talk about creating a brand
social media from scratch and the pillar
system and refinement, you are 90 days
away from publishing four to five times
a week and getting into a groove based
on real metrics. You can dive into those
in those videos. And you need some
editorial standards. You need to be able
to say, "This is good enough." or "This
is not good enough." and why. And then
you need some process. You need the
characters your brand's going to talk
about. We're going to get to that in
team. And you need product dev and
content dev to work side by side. When
you're coming up with product, content
needs to be in the room. They need to be
documenting the process as it goes
along. You need to be thinking through
the future of your content in the same
way you're thinking through your product
roadmap. And the best orgs are going to
integrate these at the core level.
They're going to be side by side
throughout this process. So, what does
this team look like? So, the key person
here, the most important and one of the
hardest roles to hire right now, is the
head of growth. Some call it a head of
social. Sometimes it's a really
high-level creative strategist,
marketing director. It's basically this
director, senior-level role that's not a
CMO, but whose job is to pull that world
I described from conceptual idea into
reality, action by action, relentlessly
every single day. This is usually
supplemented by an agency that gets it.
Like I brought up Darkroom before, but
someone who is going to be able to make
the assets that your team can't, that's
able to run some of the email campaigns
or put together the ads, or you have
some level of media buying and standard
operational support in-house. But then
the content teams itself, everyone's
asking, "How do I hire those? How do I
structure those?" So, what I recommend
is doing this in pods. You can't ever
have one person that day. I have a
social media manager that does this is
no longer the way this works. It's
always at least a two-person group
inside one of these pods. So, one person
is always a social media
manager/strategist.
This is someone whose job is to make
briefs, put together shot lists, run the
analytics for the accounts, do the
actual posting, do coordination of when
shooting etc. is happening, and
communications between orgs and media
buyers, and doing ideation. This is what
I train inside of creative strategy, the
program I have that's like cut 30 but
for brand strategy, and this is what the
orgs need to basically be the brain of a
pod. So, what does the rest of the pod
look like? So, most often the next hire
is a creator, someone whose job is to
make content. They're also working on
ideation but then they're actually
recording and making content, whether
they're the face or they're just
shooting. And ideally they're editing
it, too, at the start. A lot of this is
being done in CapCut. You will see brand
after brand that has one really savvy
girl or guy who shoots an absolute ton
of content and does all the social media
edits for it. When you pair them with a
social media manager or a strategist and
don't ask them to pull the analytics,
attend a ton of meetings, have to brief
all kinds of stuff, and you separate
that right and left brain, is where this
really starts to hammer. Someone else is
responsible for a lot of the
organization, someone's responsible for
a ton of the creation, and they work
together. And that's the core of a pod.
But what's great about the pod system is
that creative strategist can manage more
than just that one creator. So,
typically you'll end up seeing these
pods look like an internal creator,
three to four external people. You can
pull them from like Many Social or Super
Affiliate, allows you to now go into the
Meta Creators and like search through
there. You're basically finding people
that contribute at a cost per video or a
monthly retainer basis that you're also
briefing and ideating on, and then using
that for your either organic socials or
your ads. Going back to that chart I had
of what your brand world looks like.
Another great way to pull people from
these externals is Outer Signal. If you
haven't seen Outer Signal, it's a
software I highly recommend. It actually
goes through your customer base, and
this is one of the things it does, but
it actually pulls all the people that
are influential who are your existing
customers. Who are great people to hit
up and offer to pay to make content cuz
they already get it. And so, that pod
will usually end up being that
strategist, we'll say one to five people
working under there that they can
actually take care of the briefing and
ideation and reporting from. Their
meeting cadence, one-on-ones with the
strategist and those people every single
week. Maximum one-on-ones you want any
one of your team members doing every
week is maybe five. Creative review,
where everyone sits down and goes
through the creative that's about to go
live. Feedbacks that works on the hooks,
etc. Analytics reviews where you pull
the analytics from the previous weeks
and you're looking at this week over
week, month over month. You have to be
doing this. Have to be running something
like the pillar system I've described
before. This is absolutely crucial to
success here. And the reason that
everyone that comes out of creative
strategy knows how to win is cuz they're
running analytics and then they're
running it with their creators. People
know what to improve and say in testing
and saying, "Yes, this worked. No, this
didn't." Research where everyone's
reviewing the links and ideation and
stuff that they have. And use some sort
of product management tool that ties it
together. It doesn't matter what it is
as long as you have it. I run a ton in
Notion. At Gel Blaster when we were
running an org like this, we did uh it
all in ClickUp. Monday, Asana, it truly
does not matter. You just need to have
the tool. At the end of every week, the
social media media manager or the
strategist goes through and they
actually go through, "Okay, what did
every creator do? What are all the
assets that came out? What is on our
schedule for next week?" And they recap
that to their team and to management.
Everyone understands what's happening in
the media company side of this. That's
when you begin to get a machine. And
what's beautiful is you then get
multiple pods. You will see the smart
org start to have multiple of these. You
have their strategist or their manager,
have a couple people them creating
content they're getting briefed into and
reporting on. And all of a sudden you
might spin a second one up for TikTok.
Or hey, we're going to do the founder
content, right? There's a videographer
that follows the founder around. There's
someone that's helping strategize that.
There's an editor that works on it. All
of a sudden you're going to put a pod
together in that combination of
creators, outside creators, editors,
shooters, whoever can put together a
particular size of media around this.
And once you start to get multiple pods,
you may begin to have shared resources.
You can look at your marketing org as
pod, pod, shared resources. Editors
become a shared resource cuz they can
work across everything that you have.
Designers become a shared resource.
Someone needs to brief them. You can be
hiring people off contract for this.
We're hiring more designers than ever
off of there. None of these mentions I
have of software are affiliate or
anything like that. I'm just mentioning
the stuff we actually use. Production,
you end up getting a producer who's
working on the objects and the settings
and the booking of places and things. A
lot of times it can simply happen at the
pod level, but as you begin to become a
bigger org, it may be worth having
someone dedicated to that. This is what
you'll see when you start getting into
20-person teams. Then you want leads.
Someone leading e-com related
repurposing. Hey, all these pods are
making all this content. I want to make
sure everything being generated and
seeding and influencer and all these
different other aspects of the org are
all going back into content. Someone who
leads channel comms. Hey, I want to make
sure our marketing is supporting all of
our channel partners. I'm communicating
all the things our marketing is doing to
those channel partners and the people we
sell with. And eventually you land up
with actual creative director or someone
who has a vision for what all this looks
like. Can help coach the creative
strategist. Can help put a comprehensive
vision and standards into place. Has an
extremely hard job to find the right
people for. And that's what the team
looks like. And it complements your
traditional marketing org you may have.
A media buyer you may have an e-commerce
operations person. May have an email.
May have an influencer marketing person
or any of those going out to an agency.
Complemented by this media pod system.
So, what do you actually ask them to do
every week? Let's get into goals. Your
goals, net new creative in the ad
account. You want new ads that are
published every single week. I say a
good goal for a pod, even if it's two
people, is 10 really strong concepts a
week in the ad account or on organic
social. It's also worth it when you get
off from beyond those first two people
to have a unique concept to your team
with traction. The way we saw Cheese
Store Beverly Hills, there's a couple
really unique things that they show. You
want a unique repeatable thing. Your
goal should be to get your team trying
that and basically trying new ideas at
that until they lock it in. A social
show, a founder series, whatever it is.
And you're going to test into something
like that. Basically, like a film. You
try a pilot. You four to six test
episodes of something and you iterate on
it to improve it. You'll see wildly
different amounts of creative depending
on what the brand of the org is like.
Some people will be doing hundreds of
ads. Some people will be doing a handful
of really strong ones. But a good
starting point is 10 unique assets.
Let's just say five in the ad account.
Five that are going on organic of which
some are also repurposed in the ad
account is an excellent place to start.
And you'll end up seeing orgs that do
far more. And then last, what are the
anchors? How do we build the rest of our
world around this? What makes this
unique or what makes this work? So, fame
is always helpful. A celebrity, anyone
you can work in on that. Influence is
another one. You'll be able to tie an
influencer into this at any level. The
way AllSaints has done their recurring
series with a really famous influencer
in their niche and he anchors some of
the content they have on organic. If you
have an amazing story that you're able
to tell. If you have different
production elements, the way we have a
set, the spaces you have. Like Chunky
Fit was filming inside of this
commercial kitchen tells a certain story
for the brand. I love to call it F Zonal
where he's basically showing his house
and his lab and his personal collection
of fragrances is a big key part of the
story of that brand on social media. And
then events, a brand I love to call out
is doing real great world building
around events is Kosas. Kosas is a great
example of this. They have core social
media, they have their influencers,
their founder has developed social
media, she didn't start as an influencer
and does it really well and tells a
certain side of the brand in a
compelling way. And then they do brand
trips. They have this whole thing,
"We're going to get influencers out
there, we're going to create this
cultural moment that's unique to us."
And it's not like a huge brand like
Tarte doing that, it's an upstart brand
that's gotten somewhere. Merit is
another great example of this where
they're doing these like smart little
activations like they had they're doing
editor deliveries on branded Vespas
during Paris Fashion Week. An excellent
example of those branded Vespas and
delivery drivers is not a 100K
investment, right? Significantly less
than that and they're documenting it for
content and they're getting the actual
use out of it. And I'm going to end on
gear because I just went through this
exercise where people are recommending
like buying this ridiculous equipment to
do this stuff and how many people you
need to have on set. And I cannot
emphasize enough that you can do this
with an iPhone, an Osmo, and some decent
lights. Amaran 300s from filming this
on. If you do need something, a Nikon Z8
or an FX3, if the Arris are coming out
or people want Reds, you're going too
far. Stop. Use that money elsewhere.
Give your team gear and an excuse to
learn. This is the social media era. The
emphasis has to be on workflow, speed,
speed of in-camera to usage. You can cut
down editing cuz you're actually
shooting. You're not even shooting log,
you're shooting with color that's just
going to go right to social anyway. Fast
editing. Workflow is everything.
Optimize for that. But anytime you have
like a sound specific person, there's
more than two to three people on the
shoot team, anything with those hours
doing color, you are losing. It is not
that era. I cannot encourage you enough
to be focusing on this in a different
way. So like I mentioned, I am doing a
community call where I'm going to answer
all of your questions around this. You
can hop on here it is the 24th, it will
be recorded and we're going to do
basically Q&A around building these
modern teams and thinking through this
world. Anyone that comes to that too,
we're going to summarize all of what we
have here in a PDF, all the examples,
all the tactics, all the charts. You can
sign up for that a link below. Next week
a bunch of my Japan content is going to
start coming out. So I'm super excited
for that and for you to check out a
bunch of what's happened there. If you
have questions about this, drop them
because I'm going to hit a bunch of them
in the webinar. And as [music] always,
thank you so much for watching.