in today's video we're going to talk
about how to make a brand aesthetic that
people actually like and how to World
build around your brand visually and tie
it all together in a modern way I'm
going to be sharing my workflow in
milanote for my brand and for client
projects and this is actually really
important because a lot of creatives are
visual thinkers but they don't have the
right visual tools and until I got this
workflow here where as you can see where
I can go look at boards at a high level
and scroll through everything that I
have going on visually and like watch
the ti end and make notes about it I was
like stuck in a workflow that didn't
work but we will start with putting the
inspiration together visually behind a
collection we will go into building out
a brand theme we'll talk about
individual shoots we'll talk about your
social content we'll talk about Bridging
the Gap between Collections and then
we'll talk about building like a visual
world as a designer That's goes beyond
maybe what you do just with a brand but
what you do across projects since I work
on all so we're going to start here
inside uh my studio board and one of the
most important things that goes into any
pre-br process is putting the mood
boards together for it so as you can see
here these are the boards that were
initially behind my valuable brand
there's many call outs that many of you
will be like very obviously seen and I
put together like that summary of of
items and item ideas that I wanted to
have in there graphic and graphic ideas
and some kind of like lifestyle and
themed overlays that I can could go back
to that from the start anytime I want to
create a visual I would go back and be
like does it play inside this world and
you'll notice it's not a huge board
Maybe 50 images on here probably less
but they tie into a couple recurring
themes and anyone should be able to
scroll through the kind of board the way
you scroll through the board here and
have a general visual understanding of
what you're trying to do with the brand
and you'll see I would kind of Now
navigate that into what I'm actually
creating so next to it I would put
individual briefs of things that I'm
working on right so I'm working on these
duffel bags I'm about to release here in
a few months and then from the start I
kind of had these overlapping items if
you look over at the board to look at
the bags we have his references it makes
complete sense you can see visually how
one ties the other same thing with the
briefs I had for several products and
all the kind of references we put
together all the way to some of the tech
packs of the initial stuff whenever you
kind of have a visual display like this
you should be able to kind of see how
things work together that it all makes
sense inside of one world and with that
usually comes a list of iconography
right like when I put together that
initial board Eagles snakes leather kind
of car logos was the initial thing that
tied that world into what we wanted it
to be this is where I really encourage
people to find and lean into Aesthetics
that work where you'll see Brands always
is a Y2K brand this is an opium Brand
This is a western brand this this
Western world is one that I'm familiar
with as many of you probably know I've
worked for five or six years with a a
women's wear Western brand where we've
created a world around like a very
particular look and feel and so this
visual identity obviously much more
men's focus a little more Street Wear
Focus was very familiar to me but a lot
of these General ideas you want to look
at from aesthetic perspective you have
to look at who is it actually appealing
to and as the ability to create
something different and so what do I
mean by that I mean that you see all
these Brands pop up or it's the same
logos the same iconography the same
rough designs played out in a slightly
different color way or with a different
logo and with the way social media is
now you can get some popularity you can
even get to your sixf figureure drop by
doing that but it doesn't give you that
same longevity that understanding
patterns understanding materials that
building out a story and something
unique for a demographic does and so I
want to anchor because I had this
familiarity with the Western World
building I want to Anchor inside an
opening that I saw where I was basically
like hey there is certain guys in
certain places that enjoy this SP who
have been introduced to more fashionable
clothing into a more fashion forward
life into Street Wear by the Internet by
the Tik tokers that look like them to
help them style themselves buy some of
these accounts and Instagrams who begin
to kind of purchase more heavily but
there isn't really a brand that speaks
to them they may be rude which is kind
of way too expensive and feels way more
Street Wear there's kind of like the
Vintage era that's hard for people to
actually go find and hunt down and I was
like all right I think I can create a
world around that and more importantly I
could create utility products around
that cuzz I went and looked at things
like these bags and was like there's
just not the right product for people's
lives that exists out there there's some
good brands but they're not they don't
have that same aesthetic feeling of
what's like modern and popular today
that's why I centered the thesis around
some of my first designs on then tying
that into the same utility of hey a car
is a natural extension of someone's
style and personality how about we
create some products for that right
think about the areas with which this
goes to go beyond apparel and clothing
and map that all out like inside of
these initial boards one thing to
understand to be uh and lean on is that
your initial Concepts aren't necessarily
what you roll with forever right there's
there's the concepts you have there's
the applications of the concepts and
there's what customers actually think
ultimately what sells and then what you
want to do and I've been working through
all of that and there's basically no
content that talks about this on the
internet cuz designers often really
private about it I'm going to walk
through that whole experience so working
on a photo shoot is an extension of that
I like to work side by side board to
board on those so this is a photo shoot
uh I have a video about the photo shoot
I do with Garrett king um where we did
these kind of like Heist themed shots uh
with models for one of the latest
campaign releases uh and this is the
mood board for it we kind of mapped out
where again I want this to live in the
same visual universe as this but to be
more cinematic more shoot focused I feel
like it's important to have those
different boards because you begin to be
able to feel this idea of like fire
incorporated into it of motion
incorporated into it of the vehicle
being the star of every one of these
feeling like they're a frame from a
movie as opposed to a photo um like of a
model right when we began to put the
shoot together we began to have this as
what we like uncovered behind it and
same thing with even the colors we had
in the shoot and the colors this was
like the the clothing colors that are in
there I'm really pulling um hexes and
pantones and putting them up here so we
can see kind of what works visually in
the same place I can look at these Side
by Side and being like this shoot feels
like an extension of this brand story
and then I come down here into my actual
assets and the things actually came of
that and so this was like directly
inspired by what's above same here and
ties into some of the assets that we'd
run before I'm trying to make sure the
storytelling and the visual world is the
same I'm literally embedding Instagram
post in my Mill note here so I can see
how they work together right cuz this
this whole night of the Covenant idea
was for our Black Friday sale it's kind
of like cormic mcarthy Bas which is like
the brand voice and it lives in the same
visual world as these even though
they're shot by different people the
look is a little bit different it feels
right you can see the colors have
shifted across this well same thing here
different shoot but the cover ties it
together something with that other shoot
we're beginning to add the video game
element to it but I inside these boards
I'm saying okay here's excerpts from
social media here's excerpts from the
white background shots and the model
shots here's other shots I haven't got
yet from this shoot and that shoot that
I going to have here and then start to
think about okay what's missing what
ties together like this really warm
light here I need that warm light on
these before I release them to be able
to kind of make these visually make more
sense together you know I basically
outlining all these assets into one
place to see how things move and how
things navigate and adding design Styles
in that too like as we began adding
designs for carousels Etc this is a
different feel I'm beginning to explore
for the future I kind of have that shift
happening inside these boards and so
that's worth noting and exploring as
well is what happens between these
moments of these Brands so right now I'm
going through a shift in this brand
World building where I found some
success from some of these initial
products inside of some kind of specific
niches I found some success in meta ads
I found some things that didn't work or
sell as well I'm beginning to look
towards the future I'm also thinking
from myself as a designer what do I want
to build and this is probably a video in
its own right but there's this whole
idea of like luxury pricing and the end
of luxury pricing and something I really
want to position against is like you can
go buy $800 shorts and shirts and
whatever um but there's so few people
who can actually do that but more and
more Brands pricing there I want to be
able to deliver you know certain level
of quality in in this mid-range I feel
like it's going to be a bigger category
but with that as I began to build the
Brand Story it actually felt like At the
beginning I went almost too under luxury
for this where the things I truly aspire
to build and create where my design
talents are do Li higher end instead of
trying to create a story that almost
like lives too much in the middle and so
I'm thinking as I get into you know
ready for uh this next release I'm
putting out this next month and then I
get ready prepping for summer what does
a transition look like from what I
started with from what I validated what
I've sold to where it's actually going
and that's where we enter into this
shoot that we have here and into this
kind of summer collection so I'm getting
ready to uh release for summer we've
designed bags for it I have a bunch of
kind of samples something like newer
things coming redoing some of my popular
items like these Beach pants I have I've
kind of put together a board that I feel
like lives in a similar visual world but
is elevating it a bit is moving it a bit
more towards Summer where I want to be
able to connect the dots between the
more vintage Beach feel and the more
vintage race feel and like have it make
sense and then in the middle here I have
the shoot that we're about to do where I
want to bridge the gap between what we
did in this last shoot and getting to
this next World while I release so much
of these prodcts s and this is again the
power of having all this next to each
other is you can begin to see what all
this looks like because I'm tying all of
this together right cuz like over here
at the same time I'm also configuring my
visual world right so right now you see
me recording here in front of this this
setup here has no visual tie into to
what I do with my brand um and I'm also
at the same time redoing my house as a
creative space and I want that to have a
visual tie into the brand so I'm
actually literally laying out in the
moodboard what our plan is for my home
to be like okay where does that overlap
can I shoot content for the brand and
inside that can these stories kind of
align and the answer is like they don't
really yet but that's the things that
you're able to hack out on a board
because what there isn't just enough
conversation about is you have your
brand story you have your individual
shoots you have where your brand wants
to go then you have the environments you
created whether that's with
photographers or Studios or your office
space or where you shoot as a Creator
and eventually I want all of these to
kind of be synonymous so one of my goals
this year is to have my brand not feel
fully separate which it basically is now
have it feel more aligned with where I
am as a Creator since I'm a a very
primary driver of it so all this happens
like here inside this space and then
ties into what we're doing with product
like I'm working through these new
duffles here this is one of the duffles
I did for format I'm looking at the
colorways and where that kind of plays
in I'm looking at these products like as
they get released and the colorways and
things that look there and how that
could work on it and I'm literally tying
the releases and what those look like to
what I'm thinking about for my space to
what I'm thinking about for like the
future and one of the directions I have
for the future I'm outlining here where
as I think about where the products go I
want to leave these initial colorways
right where you saw hey it's red it's
cream and I want to build into these
greens these Blues I want to build into
more technical garments I want to build
into more bags and accessories into more
texture inside of the clothes now that I
see that there's a positive response to
that and having this mapped out this far
where this is basically fall next year
ideally I'd be mapped into early 26 but
we're not because the brand is like new
and still finding its Groove like all
that's happening like here inside these
boards so I'm G to talk talk a bit about
how I did this in Milano now I'm
actually going to show some of like the
garments that are tying this together
and then I'm going to talk about my
client workflows on the client story
inside this as well so as you've seen
throughout this video I use mote to
organize my brand workflow and they
graciously agreed to partner on this
video and so every project I do has a
master board like I'm showing you here
basically my brand Universe where I can
visually look at everything going on and
like track the workflow and make sure
it's cohesive so what I think I haven't
showed so far is like this corner here
where I have everything from like a very
simple to-do list to like the core
creative brief we have to some tech pack
links to where things are in terms of
production and like a list of the
incoming items is all happening inside
the same sheet that the visual universe
is again I I have the smaller versions
of my mood boards we share notes about
the project in here I these color call
outs about the color stories and how
they evolve they actually just let you
pick a hex and they'll do these color
code ones which is a little thing I love
but you can also create sub boards and
offshoots so when I talk about client
projects like I do a lot of product
design for client projects as well so
one of them that I'm working on right
now I have a subboard in here because
there is just a lot of overlap I'm using
the same designers I work on the same
team on it it's often the same
photographers it operates in a like a
Associated visual world when I do a
client project there's another one that
is kind of popping up here um for like a
sub brand all this I'm just happens in
the same board so I can easily jump
beneath them and then those subbs I can
share them separately if they're going
like direct to a client or a different
team without having them see the
masterboard um but I love this as a
platform because I can embed these
social posts like this is here like
literally I just copied an Instagram
link and was able to embed it whether
that's publish work or references that
we have and this is the exact type of
organization that works for my
creativity I need to see everything and
milanote is the app to do that in you
can get started with them at the link
that I have down below below and Millan
note is available for free with no time
limit popping back into this I want to
talk about some of the items that are
coming out and how those tie into this
kind of visual world that's being
created and I want to talk about some
client projects so one of the through
lines I had for this brand from the
start is texture I care a lot about
texture and material for anyone that's
experienced the shirts or gotten some of
the things that I sell you'll notice
that everything is just a level above in
terms of like texture and material
quality of anything else similar that
you've gotten because of my expertise
kind of in supply chain but as I shift
towards this future mood board you see
here you'll notice everything has very
intense colorways textures looks and
technicality and I'm beginning to bridge
the gap in between the in between where
I am now and where that is going with
this next release so this is one of the
first products this is a a textured
cargo pant and if you saw the videos
where I went sourcing fabric overseas
this is a material we actually found on
uh on the trip where I went to Wong Joo
it is a Japanese material is 100% cotton
it's almost feels like a like a heavy
denim but a little bit more flexible
that we found while on that trip and
that's how I build that story out right
is I'll find these materials I want to
make part of the brand and then bring
them into this work but the same thing
you can see some of the Branded bags
that we do is we found that in multiple
colors and so we have that same pant
coming out in black as well they begin
to have this more of a material story
that matches the future of where I'm
going with the brand while also still
having iconography that can Bridge there
and then it's releasing with this shirt
um which changes slightly had a lot of
people request to do unistress shirts
even and though we sell well on the
distress shirts I understand that again
my audience as a Creator is much broader
than my audience for the brand I'm
trying to increase some of that appeal
with what this works like here and so if
people don't want to say hey I can't
wear something that's that distressed I
want to give them some options we're
releasing just one blue distress shirt
to see what people think of it and again
it's the same iconography it's the same
feels one of the same designs on the
back that the cowboy have released in
like the previous so the line feels like
it has a bit of cohesion but you begin
to see the change of what's happening in
the colors like in the materials like in
the Silhouettes from this initial kind
of very American driven to a bit of
where I'm going and then same thing with
the evolution of the shoes as well where
I'm moving into that similar color base
you can see obviously the color of the
shoes and the shirt matches it's going
more into the blue and the blue and
green I eventually plan to have it's
incorporating some of the same
iconography but it's upgrading the
material significantly from the first
shoe we did which is much more casual to
this which is significantly more Lux but
it's this combination of having my
visual universe together of identifying
all these shoots and where they are in
the storyline of knowing really far
where I want to go and then overlaying
the sales data and the customer data on
top of this that's getting me to where I
want to go I know this is a process
right like I mentioned we've been
working on the women's wear brand now
it's like five or six years to get it to
where we want to be where it's a a
really consistent brand and on that like
I'm very focused on the ad and like
email like funnel and sales like on that
brand so I'm very much in the what
products sell what are the assets that
sell them and I think it's going to take
an equally long journey as what I'm
doing here but now at least have more
background and expertise inside of
understanding from the data like what
does this mean what should we test kind
of what works well together now let's
talk about client projects too because
all of this is you know while this is a
brand this is a a extension of of my
creator work of my creativity something
I'm trying to create it's a overlap
between my identity and work I still
design for a lot of other people and I
still work on a lot of other projects
and all of those things when you begin
to think of yourself as a creative as a
designer as a personality like have an
impact and how they tie together is
important to think of your work
holistically because I want people
eventually to be like see something and
be like hey was that Orin and when we
did the firmont drap people were like
immediately were like hey did you do
this because they knew the things that I
like and enjoy and the quality of some
of the stuff and the look of some of the
hoodies and the washes I've mentioned
they begin to see the iconography ties
into stuff that makes sense visually for
me and so I've renamed some of this and
moved it around just because I want
everyone seeing things like the exact
workflow here but you can see this is
the mood board for a project I'm doing
like another merchandise project and it
fits in the same world but there's some
differences right where like I don't do
anything in like Chrome or silver or
anything like that that's going to live
inside this Brand's universe but you can
feel the iconography and the garments
and everything tie back in reference to
the brand that's how I thought about one
of the through lines of me as a designer
to with with Brands is that like the f
bag was so good cuz I've been working on
a duffel bag and I was like hey I'm just
going to take this thing we've been
working on do a version of it on a
client project while I continue to work
on it for my brand and I view like all
these Silhouettes and things I've
created like if I work with a client and
they want to run a version of this cargo
pant and a different material like great
that's a silhouette I've developed I
know it works they get something they
already like and it helps my brand
Universe tie things together similar to
this like this is a a a new brand
concept we're I'm researching right
colorways all out there doing something
more female focused looking at bags you
have kind of the inspiration here
looking at a lot of like older Chrome
hearts and Chrome Hearts bags where
again this fits very naturally into the
visual Universe I'm in now but it's an
extension in a very different way than
where the current brand is going but
being able to keep these boards and
these associations and these iconography
like inside of one project and easily
reference okay here's what I have going
on with these other projects here's
where the core line is going does
something feel really off does it make
sense does it have to make sense like
that's a bit of of how like aesthetic
World building I think people should be
spending time on and so if you're a
designer I know you're designing and if
you're you're a brand CER I you have all
these things happening but having this
in one visual place like is absolutely
crucial and then overlaying it like if I
can recommend one thing having gone
through this a number of times and in
the middle of it now is like overlaying
that sales data like on top of all of
this and one of the big new initiatives
that uh we just kicked off a few days
ago is I have a someone who's just
dedicated to experience like on the
brand Team who is emailing every
customer of our first like our first
thousand customers basically to be like
hey this is like our starter group that
really believed in us to like feedback
that and to get early feedback on the
things that are happening and to be able
to tie that Community closer together to
what's actually happening and have that
not purely be online on social media
because some of those connections are
better directly cuz some of the
customers are bu aren't going to be in
your comments aren't going to be
responding to it and I do feel like
Aesthetics and result and where Brands
go needs to be more driven Now by
conversation because of how saturated
everything is so anyway I know we
covered a lot of Concepts inside this
video I really just want to show this
kind of like higher level thinking of
how brand visuals tie together of how to
think about products and generations of
things of finding your particular
aesthetic I and it's going to the actual
intricacies of brand building more than
you just print these t-shirts and run
these Facebook ads because when I look
at like the future of this at least for
me is I whether this is just an
extension of my creativity or whether
this grows into something bigger than
that like I want it to be around
generationally I want to be something
that is a a part of my life for decades
if not forever and to do that like
having intention from like Moment One
insert how you build your visual world I
think is more crucial than ever so thank
you very much for watching did you want
to try out Millan note it is below uh
this stuff is all coming out the next
few weeks it's all on a boat and uh if
you want to be early for that just get
on the email list we will go email list
first on every single release and make
sure people there have the chance to
purchase before we do mainstream release
and that's at valuable studios.com thank
you all so much for watching