Today, we're going to talk about why
creatives are so afraid of money and
what you can do about it in your own
creative career. We are at a very unique
time in history. If you do any type of
creative work from design to videography
to copywriting, if you're in branding,
if you've ever thought of yourself as an
artist or artistic related, there is
more demand for that work than literally
ever before. But at the same time,
something I notice constantly with all
the creatives in my life is they feel
bad about financial success and they
feel doing the things, the actions that
turn their creative work into a
business, they feel almost guilty about
it. In this video, we're going to talk a
little bit about how you've been forced
into that by the functions of your
bosses and the psychology of capitalism
over time. But also, I'm going to give
you a direct blueprint. You're going to
learn about offers, you're going to
learn about funnels, we're going to talk
about CRM, and how to structure those to
make the most out of your creative work
in this unprecedented era. This video is
in partnership with Framer, so I'm
actually going to walk through how to
build websites around these as well. So,
you will have both theoretical and
tactical application of stuff that will
help you as a creative be able to make
more money and also not feel bad about
it. My goal for this video is to be the
most tactical video on how to structure
your creative business and get your
creative work that you've ever watched.
If you have questions about any of this,
please let me know cuz I want to do some
follow-up specifically about creative
money and creative work. I can dive into
it there. I'm excited for you to take
advantage of it in this unprecedented
time. Let's lock in. I don't usually
start my videos with other people's
videos, nor do I usually Mr. Wonderful,
but Kevin O'Leary had this quote that
was going viral that's really important
to what we're going to talk about here.
In this video, he talks about the
transition from the social media as an
intern job or one person to a companies
have increasingly realized that people
that understand the internet and can
help acquire customers, whether for
products, agencies, services, or
personalities, and the teams that do it
have become some of the most valuable
people inside of a company command far
more salary than ever. But more than
ever, people don't know what to charge
for that. They don't know how to ask for
that much money. They're caught inside
that barrier of what was my last salary.
And this is a function, in a large part,
due to the big agency multiplex. Small
agencies, you get less than 50 people,
they're just trying to get by. Big
agencies are structured like they are
for a reason. So you will see the
Omnicoms, the Saatchis, the Havases, the
large agencies of the world employ all
these different creatives and they put
them into silos. You're an art director,
but you don't really get to direct
campaigns. You're a copywriter, you're a
planner, you're a strategist. You
operate inside these little bubbles and
those bubbles are worth really specific
things by the number of accounts with
specific multiples for billable hours.
They're designed for the infrastructure
around you and the other jobs and the
profits at the top to take that money
and not the creative and they've held
people down for a long time. Now
historically, we want to date this back
to the origin of arts and commerce. If
you've ever looked at the book Caps
Lock, it details a lot about how graphic
design as a function and a lot of the
other artistic functions really came
apart as supporting the financial
infrastructure. Designs became necessary
for currency, for banks to help
establish credibility inside monetary
systems. Same thing with writing,
holding records for the exchange of
commerce. And even when artists became
great, it was patronage from the rich
that would allow people, like famous
artists of the past, even be able to
operate or scientists. The creative
relationship with money is a complicated
one for generations. And then we get to
a societal shift. In the 70s, in the
hippie era, all the way through the 90s
and into Gen X and grunge, art was
looked at as something that was
anti-selling out. If you participated in
this, you didn't need the man's money,
you didn't want their support, you
wouldn't take that McDonald's deal.
Anyone of my generation remembers Reel
Big Fish's song Sellout. It was a bit of
a rallying cry about the willingness or
lack of willingness to buy into the
commercial infrastructure of music. But
that changed and it changed because at
the end of the day, a lot of artists
want the ability to make a living off
their art. And there's been more demand
for it than ever because what sells
commerce in our world now, that is a
world of attention of undifferentiated
goods, is increasingly art. Whether it's
the cover art of an album, the music
associated with the lifestyle, the
design of a website, an ad that got
created by a creator, all these are
extensions of the creative field, and
they're all involved in the business of
making money. Meta ads allowed us to
quantify this. Tracking in UTM systems
to websites from social media content
allows us to quantify this. The best
thing that's ever happened for creatives
in terms of their fiscal goals in
alignment was TikTok Shop being able to
directly measure if your video sold
units of a product and assign that a
level of value. And Meta ads, where you
could say, "I made this ad or I created
this thing, and I can track how many
dollars that came back directly from
it." So, creatives who wanted to go
within that mad that mad space
infrastructure, all of a sudden realized
what they're worth, and it was way more
than the agency infrastructure was
paying. But all that is just background.
What most people have never heard, what
most creatives have never heard, that
I'm going to tell you right now before
we get into the actual tactical part of
the video, is a message I want you to
remember. Your skills are in the highest
of demand. In the world that we operate
in now, as long as you are willing to
apply yourself, quantify the work, and
actually lock in and don't be lazy, your
creative abilities can give you fiscal
and life success beyond what you can
dream of. Act on it. Never feel bad
asking for what you're worth. So, with
that, there is a gap. There's a gap in
learning for creative people to apply
this to business. Then there's a gap of
actually doing that application and
getting it done. And last, there's the
willingness to sell. I'm going to tackle
that last one first, and then we're
going to get tactical. So, first is the
willingness to sell, willingness to
charge a lot of money. So, first I will
say, if you knew what these corporations
have made off of the backs of creative
work in generations, you would be sick.
If you knew what other people made in
these companies versus what their work
is worth, you would be upset. Hold on to
that feeling. But second, creatives that
charge a lot for their work enable other
creatives to do it and fund other
creatives. Let me give you an example.
I've done a lot of shoots in my life. If
you advocate for a budget for a shoot,
the difference between me getting
150,000 and 250,000 to put together a
commercial shoot isn't money that goes
in my pocket. It's my ability to hire
more creatives to make a better product.
And you will see actual creative
operators, the majority of them look at
it like that. They know what they're
going to make roughly either way. Maybe
they'll make a little more, but they get
to employ more people to make better
art. If you are the kind of person that
helps command that that breaks out of
the mold, that's able to negotiate in
those factors, that brings that in, that
brings up the creative ecosystem around
you, every creative who's been around
for a while knows a few of those people,
and those people are great. They get you
the work when you need it. They help
you, they facilitate things. Do
everything you can when you do get that
power to be one of those people. But to
get tactical, first you need what's
known as an offer. And I want you to
forget about If you've read any info
product books, or if you look down on
the Hermozis or the Brunson's of the
world, I am not going full This is how
you sell guru. I'm breaking down the
basics of how every business works, and
you're going to find it valuable. So the
idea of an offer is what do you sell? So
most people will say, "I'm a designer,
I'm a copywriter, I'm a video editor,
I'm a marketer, I'm a brand strategist,
or a creative director. I can do all
kinds of things, right?" That's how you
approach your look on life. But if you
are trying to get clientele, you need to
be able to fill in this blank. I do X
for Y at Z. I make landing pages for
e-commerce businesses for $1,500 a
landing page. I do brand identities for
tech companies for $5,000 in 2 weeks.
That is an offer. It is a singular thing
at a set price for a niche. That is how
you translate from I'm a designer, I do
all sorts of stuff to I can fit a
consumer need. Cuz let me play out a
scenario for you of how this flow works.
You post on social media, or you get a
referral, or someone's looking at your
work, and they need that service.
They're looking for a specific thing, a
brand identity, something for their
brand. They go to your website, they see
a bunch of work, but they don't see any
pricing. So I don't know if you're
expensive or if you're cheap. And they
don't really and you'll see a list of
services but you don't really know what
it looks like or what it does. Your job
as a service provider is to communicate
that to them. And to make repeatable
things that you know and what to expect.
This doesn't limit you from doing all
kinds of other stuff once you're in
conversation but it makes it easy for
someone to buy. Makes it easier for
someone to go, I need a logo. It's going
to take me 2 weeks. It's going to cost
me X and I don't have to get in any
awkward scenario or try to book a call
to find out. Eliminate that distraction.
Productize just one core thing you do.
And again, you can still offer a whole
world around it but the magic of the
offer is you get to see if people care
enough to buy it. You get to see if you
can develop and refine it, what you can
charge, etc. And this all goes down on
your website. So one of the most popular
ones right now is the brand identity
offer. And I'm just picking some from
what I showed on X. It's great landing
page, your product is sharp, your brand
is fuzzy, let's fix that. This guy
details himself here, the brands he's
worked with. And here is his deal. I
will give you a brand in 4 weeks for
$15,000. I will give you a strategy for
$5,000. You want to see an example of
the file? It's there. You can literally
click through and see an example of what
one of the deliverables will look like
in straight up in a Figma file. That is
a straightforward offer. Another
branding one, $10,000 3 to 4 weeks just
for B2B SaaS. They niche down. We do
design for this particular type of
company. We will do your brand and your
website. And they have this locked in.
That is their offer. And I want to call
out what differentiates a product,
right? If you've built anything that you
offer as a service, you've probably
heard the adage that you are either
better, faster, or cheaper. But those
are your three options. You have to
stand out on one, ideally two of them,
and you can never have all three, right?
So whatever you offer, are you
significantly better than everyone else
out there? Your designs, your edits,
that good? You can then sit on your
laurels. And I would tell you look
objectively at your work. Are you really
that good? And if you are, leverage it.
Don't give up your time. Don't
undercharge. Sit on it. But you have to
really acknowledge if you're that good
or not. And frankly, most people aren't.
I offered websites for a long time as a
side hustle I had at design jobs. I
offered corporate websites. I was not
making the best websites in the world.
But, I had a 6-week front-end process
that included copywriting and messaging
was one of the biggest hiccups that
people had. They couldn't work through
it. I would do the messaging with
people. It's something I was good at.
And my price was decently low. So, they
knew they could get something done in
time from me that hit a pain point of
messaging, even if it wasn't the best
offer out there. And now it's swapped. I
don't do much creative strategy anymore
except for the biggest brands. I do it
at the highest premium. And they work
basically on my terms. Cuz I've
established through internet credibility
in all the campaigns that there's hard
to get anyone that good who understands
the internet in the same way. And so, I
can leverage a different side of it.
That's how things translate over a
career. And so, to think about where you
are and what it is you can offer. If
you're new and you're starting out and
you're not as good, and you can't offer
it as fast, but you're willing to work
for the low to put those reps in, you
have the cheapness. And time has become
a big one. You will see this idea of
brand sprints, the ability to book a
sprint. 5K for 10 icons, five custom
illustrations, two to three polished UI
screens from this guy Dmitri. You can
get a There's brands that need a lot of
this type of illustration work. You can
get it at a set cost. You know what
you're buying into within a set time.
You know when it's going to be done.
This is the way that people consume now,
especially if they just go to your
social media profile to look at your
bio, go to your website, and then that
may be the last time they interact with
you. Give them the ability to purchase
what they want. And I purchased from
something like this. When I went to redo
the landing pages, so I had my website
done in Framer. We got all of this from
a landing page designer. What he does is
landing pages. I cannot buy anything
else from him. We tried to get him to do
some maintenance, some other stuff. He
does landing pages. One single page.
He's done pages for me for webinars.
He's done sales pages for products that
I sell. He's done core websites. But,
that is the offer, one page. But, I know
anytime I need a landing page for
anything, I want it done in Framer, and
I want it to look good, I can go to him.
And there's others like him on Contra
that have different styles and skill
sets and capabilities. But now we're
going to talk about the funnel. A few
key concepts for you to know as a
creative. So the funnel is the idea of
turning a visitor on your website into a
customer. So you look at all the Framer
sites that I showed, you'll notice
there's lots of call to actions to book
a call or get a download or sign up for
the waitlist as getting people into a
funnel where then they're sold through
another page on your website or through
emails over time. This is important
thing to understand. I'm going to break
down several types of funnels and how
they work for creative work here in a
second. But just understand that concept
first. You want to use your website to
bring people on a journey. They may not
buy off that first page. How do you get
them into your world and then
communicate with them until they close a
sale. And to understand funnels, you
also need to understand VSLs or video
sales letters. Let's go into the back
end of my website here in Framer. So you
can see this is an example of a landing
page I have in their back end UI. So I
can go here and I can click and I can
edit anything. But you will see there is
an 11-minute video, basically a YouTube
video, in the middle of this page. And
it's what's called a VSL. So when you
put together a description for your
offer, I'm going to help you do that
here in a minute. One of the tools that
you have, whether you're doing it for
yourself or you're doing it for others,
cuz putting these together is a really
valuable skill that people have, is that
there's people that read and there's
people that watch. And if you're willing
to sit down and do a thorough breakdown
in a VSL of what you sell, it's going to
help your conversion rate. Cuz some
people will be like, you know what, I
don't want to go read this whole page
with all the examples and all the things
on it. I just want to watch something.
And so in your VSL, you go through in a
really specific format. You talk about
the problems people are facing that they
can't solve. You give your background.
You walk through how you help them close
the gap on those problems. And then what
it looks like to buy from you. There's a
million frameworks of formats for that
that you can find online. But as a
creative, if you're ever going to sell a
freelance thing or if you're ever going
to have an agency or if you're going to
work for creators or people that do,
understanding the concept of a funnel,
understanding the concept of an offer,
and understanding a VSL are crucial
parts to knowing how the internet works
and how things sell on the internet. And
then I'll introduce you to a concept
called offer stacking. So some of you
have heard, you've probably heard me
tell this story before of Eddie who used
to film my YouTube videos. He used to be
behind this camera right here. He was a
videographer and he offered a
videography service. And he did what's
called offer stacking. So, it turned
into, "Hey, I can shoot the videos, but
also I can run the meta ads." He had
learned that skill through a course or
similar. So, you could get multiple
things from him. But then it's turned
into what he does now where he sells
literally he will create edited videos
that are VSLs that are meant to work in
meta ads for clienteles and services
businesses. You can click here to watch
some of the ads he does, but he has his
specific hooks, he has his specific
styles he does to run those ads, and he
will help them actually get off the
ground in the ad account and generate
leads at specific costs. So, he's been
able to take his stack of skills, "Hey,
I'm a videographer. Hey, I can run meta.
Hey, I understand VSLs and scripting and
putting together converting ad formats.
Now I sell an offer where the sum of
that offer allows you to get paid more
than its individual parts." That's a
great way to think about how you build
up your creative toolkit over time. And
this goes for the higher end as well.
Because if you're already a brand
strategist and you're at the top of your
game and then you also become a really
savvy media buyer or go to down a level,
become a creator. Then they begin
thinking like a director of production.
Adding in that skillset makes you even
more of a weapon throughout your career
and what you're capable of, what you're
going to be able to charge. I've noticed
this with several people who were good
creators, who were started as
videographers, became great creators.
Because they became great creators,
they're able to script and know what
works on the internet and now are able
to pitch their small production studios.
Instead of doing music videos, they're
competing for ads for global brands
where your budgets can start stretching
from 50K to 500K. But offer stacking and
skill stacking in general is worth
thinking through. And the last concept
before we get into how to actually make
some of this is the CRM. I'm not going
to dive deep into this in this video. I
will hit it thoroughly in a future
video. But the idea that you need
customer record management. So, all
those contacts that you have, people
that sign up, people that didn't
convert, leads and things you have, you
store them somewhere, you communicate
with them. If you combine all these
concepts we had, the funnel the people
are going to go through websites, you're
going to have to do more than just show
them a page to get them to buy, the
offer that you sell a really particular
thing, a a
or a video that helps you sell doing
that, a stack of these offers on top of
each other to sell something that's
worth more, and records of the customers
and people that haven't bought from you
that you're able to communicate to to
sell new things, you now understand the
services business. And so, if you want
to get started in making websites like
this, actually putting some of this into
action, I'm going to walk you through
Framer templates, which is the quickest
way to stop procrastinating and actually
build this. So, first, a few of the
templates that I absolutely love that
you should be looking at. First is this
abstract template. It's a good dark
mode, simple template. Artemis is one of
my favorite portfolio templates. If
you're showing off a wide body of work,
they have all these cool little ways you
can actually see it. So, you can see how
all the cards are related to their
various projects. You can see the
designs in action. This Drilio theme,
when we talk about landing pages and
building landing pages, this is a great
one. This is built for SaaS landing
pages. And what I like in general is you
can go to any of the categories on
Framer. And so, we were talking about
funnels, we're talking about landing
pages. You're going to be able to see a
ton that are either free, and all of
those ones that I showed were also free,
all the way up to 80 bucks, $129, that
kind of thing. But this one here, this
is one I actually chose on a previous
project. And I'm going to show you what
that looks like. So, we bought this
theme, this Swiss style theme, awesome
portfolio theme. So, what happens then?
So, if you've never been in Framer
before, this is what it looks like. So,
when you install a theme, you get all
the pages here on the left-hand side.
You have pages, you have layers, you
have assets. But the page will
automatically show in its different
responsive styles. So, desktop, tablet.
And if I change one, and swap that file,
it will swap them all. So, I'm going to
get all the different pages in this
template is going to outline for me. And
so, I can literally go, you'll see on
this right side here, you have all your
controls. So, if I need to link this
image, I can go link there. If I want to
add effects or styles, there's tons you
can dive into, but honestly, I would
just keep it super simple. You can see
when I go put text in there, I'm just
going to change this to my name. So, if
I was doing my portfolio site, and
you'll see it was going to move this
responsively across it. So, literally,
when you start working a template, you
can just go in and refill in with your
content as the first easiest step. And
you can get more advanced, you can apply
more designs, but even just going in and
swapping in your own images, down here
you see styles, fill, swap the image,
will automatically make it responsive,
and everything that I edit will edit
across the styles and sizes. And you can
see here some of the final results of me
working with the template. And I would
highly recommend just pick one of the
free themes, get it inside of one of
these, and play around. Swap your
content in, work on some messaging, put
together a portfolio. You will find as
soon as you start, it is so much less
intimidating anything. And so I know we
dove deep into offers here. I want to
get into funnels, too. I'm going to do a
whole separate video just on funnels. My
goal is to have you structure your
creative business, and then build a
toolkit to know how to sell it, and to
know what better to sell others, right?
Cuz you get good at offers and landing
pages for yourself, all of a sudden you
can begin to actually think in your
client's shoes for how they should
approach their business. You know, find
us where a lot of savvy creatives are
like. But as you do that, you're going
to get more and more confidence to ask
for the money that you deserve. Now, if
you have questions on building your
creative practice, structuring your
offers, things on the funnels, please
drop them below cuz like I mentioned,
I'm going to do funnels. I will keep
this series going, and I want to make
sure I can tap all those questions. And
you can feel free to ask them on the
next community call. I have the details
on that down below as well. So you'll be
able to find links to go tap in with
Framer, or join the next kind of group
community meeting where I'll go through
Q&A. And we can do some website building
inside there if you want as well. Hope
you found some value here, and as
always, thank you so much for watching.