we are going to Rebrand ourselves for
2025 so that we're more locked in than
ever creatively personally and in
business I built a massive personal
brand last year and launched a new
luxury business but like all creatives I
have that feeling of being
simultaneously at Rock Bottom
unsatisfied with the quality of the work
that I'm doing while also being at the
absolute Peak when I look back on
everything I've accomplished if you felt
this way or feeling this way then you're
not alone I've been here before it
happens really frequently around this
time of year and I'm going to share the
complete blueprint for rebranding your
life to take everything that you are
doing or want to do to the next level in
this video we're going to go through
rebranding the spaces that we work in
our Aesthetics and our lifestyle we're
going to build a personal operations
plan and a personal marketing plan break
down our habits and our commitments pick
Muses for how we want to create and set
up the action plan to do it I've got a
massive notion doc linked in here it's
free you can use to track everything
this is what I use to plan my year and I
firmly believe this is my most valuable
video ever you're going to take yourself
as seriously as you would take a
business and it's going to change your
life let's lock in so some quick context
my upcoming Rebrand is massive for me
this is going to be the biggest year of
my life so I took my family off the
coast of Africa to the Canary Islands to
work through this exercise and I
realized for a lot of y'all it's going
to be a big year as well and so I wanted
to do this together so I'm going to
share the template and talk through it
all I'm also going to talk through a lot
of circumstances what I'm doing the work
on it's you have an example of someone
at a specific stage going through this
exact exercise and to kick off we're
going to hit briefly on perspective
that's like there's three levels to
people that either have some some kind
of personal Branch some kind of creative
or freelance work there's level one
where you're just you you go to work you
do all the things that are expected of
you you spend your free time doing what
people in society are expected to do and
there's level two it's when you begin to
have that fire inside when you want
something extra it's you plus freelance
work or plus content creation your time
outside of work becomes something that
is a focus element for you to take
yourself to the next level and then
there's level three which is you as a
business and I did not understand this
until maybe 5 years ago and then really
didn't lock into it until about two
years ago but when you begin to look at
yourself this way when you realize that
you are intrinsically tied to your
potential and you need to be able to
treat your marketing your operations
your choices as an extension of that and
then understand the ups and downs of how
much you want to engage you begin to
think about things a lot differently and
invest with your money and your time a
lot different so with the first section
of this we are going to talk through all
the things in our personal life our
spaces our Aesthetics really our
inspiration and then we'll Circle back
around to operations and plans so we're
going to start start with our spaces as
creative your space is one of the most
important things that you have because
when you get into this Zone where you
come home from work or you're working
from home and have to then shift gears
your space can put you into the Flow
State or to the state of inspiration
with a varying degrees you're uninspired
by your space or has negative
connotations for you it's going to
inhibit your ability to get where you
want to go it may sound simple but it's
very true so we're going to do three
things in this exercise firsts is we're
going to create a mood board of what our
ideal space would look like we're going
to look at the dream state it's
something we're going to do in every
second M of this I love to look at where
are we at now and acknowledge it then
look at the dreams data where we go
ideally in our perfect world and then
we're going to Zone in on exactly what's
next what can we do now I like to work
around space when I plan for a year are
two things one is inspiration maxing and
the other is content maxing inspiration
maxing means when I walk into my
environment that I'm supposed to be able
to be creative in am I inspired one of
the easiest ways to do this by far the
best investment I've ever made is
getting those 4ft by 8ft white boards I
bought mine in a 10 pack from Uline was
pretty expensive you can pick them up
and most like art supply stores or ask
them they will have those big like
quarter inch or half inch thick boards
doesn't even have to be that thick just
those big areas will just dominate a
wall or an area of your a household you
can pin things on and change up with
your moods or your projects and the
active printing things out I I don't
have a working printer day in my life
like many I literally go down to a local
CBS to print things or Walmart for like
a couple cents every once in a while to
then update all the things I have going
on on these boards and that means when
you walk in there's this big tribute to
your project to your creativity to what
you have going on that is just a
Surefire way to turn your space into
inspiration but whatever it is I want
you to list out what would it be in a
dream state to make your space inspired
and the second thing to think about and
put photos and everything on the mood
board for is what would turn your space
into something content friendly you've
seen in much of my other videos I have
these big shelves behind me which I got
in the estate sale those shelves are
inside a studio with a garage door they
transformed that space completely it was
a pickup I got thrifting and allowed me
to feel great and look great on camera
with just one investment so I would map
out get on the movie more put everything
in your dream state of what your space
could be like and then go back to this
next stage of what would make content
look good what would Inspire then we're
going to go into style and personal
aesthetic and there are two levels to
this one the first is your actual style
what you wear what you want to be how
you want to be perceived and the second
is your actual personal brand kit if you
create content even if you simple as you
have a LinkedIn Etc is actually locking
that down with a plan so what you wear
is about feeling good about looking good
on camera it's about having confidence
when you are working when you're around
people or when you are in content it's
an important most people don't take you
know kind of take for Grant but we're in
this world where we buy things we get
over them we have a bunch of things we
purchase but we don't actually use you
want to be intentional for the year
about what you want to look like who you
want to be how you want to be perceived
and for some people if you have money to
do this kind of thing I would create a
budget around it because I feel like
it's very useful to not get carried away
because a lot of people do and obviously
we are in a highker consumer culture but
create a realistic amount that you're
willing to spend on what you want things
to look like and let's make a couple
notes so first is if you don't have a
budget to put towards this one of the
best exercises I ever did in my life I
did about 4 years years ago is I didn't
buy anything new for the entire year my
agreement was anything that I sold on
depop or gr or whatever I could reinvest
the money in things I sold into new
things and there a pack I made with
myself I think I made it from January to
Black Friday roughly didn't go through
the whole year I got cop by the essence
sale as one does but you basically trade
intention of hey I'm actually going to
take my time to list things out to sell
things to trade things in if there's a
local place to you that does that and
only use those funds and be intentional
about what that spend looks like so if
you are low on funds or even if you just
want to be intentional about it's an
exercise I would highly recommend really
makes you think about and the second is
you think about your style think about
pieces versus Fast fashion you know you
can basically get any look and feel you
want for relatively cheap in our current
world of Zara even aomi you can find a
with some time and intention basically
anything you're going for and if you
need or feel the need to the Persona
you're creating online have those
different looks and feels and maybe
something you choose to do versus hey
I'm investing in things and Brands you
believe in and things that are going to
last a long time they're important to
you but may not give you as many looks
or as many options and that is a choice
and I would make one of the two cuz
people get caught up trying to do both
and it doesn't quite work and I would
just acknowledge what type of person am
I do I want to be and don't feel bad
either way and go for it and then I
would create a chart of everything you
have that is wearable by Charing this
with software that does this but
honestly I just have the Apple note
where I've taken a picture of most
clothes I have and cut it out and past
it in there are most things on me you
can go scroll through to think about
being intentional about make your
wardrobe and an exercise I would do for
this if you're trying to be intentional
about your style is I would document
yourself every day challenge yourself to
document you in the same place one
environment one mirror whatever it is
one Photoshop technique or cutout or
thing doesn't have to be posted online
can be if you want to but every single
day capture what your style looks like
and how it evolves again it can just be
for you but when you have that
compendium or that one folder or that
Apple note you begin to really look and
think about what looks good what really
matches now we're going to talk a bit
about that brand kit that goes with it
so someone who I think has done a great
job with this is my friend BMA he does
it very simple he has a color purple is
associated with him he has it in a hat
he wears in every single video every
story you see from him has the purple in
the background it is included in all the
graphics that he does and when he shot
some videos recently he actually had
them paint the studio in that same
panone color he's becoming synonymous
with a really particular color and he
also has just his brand kit of the same
fonts and things he uses talking a bit
about me and what I'm doing this year I
am being more intentional about that
because I have done these more edited
videos with kind of fonts and production
I have the fonts I like they're the same
fonts that are in my brand me and my
brand relatively interchangeable at this
point I want to keep it that way but I
don't want to use the same color schemes
I was going for color schemes that would
be attractive on social media that stand
out on feed now I want to make that a
little bit more subdued and then bring
in a signature inspired a lot by we
beinga D seeing how effective the color
has been for him and every time I see
that color I go man I need a signature
color now I would encourage you
throughout this to go pick what that
color or two is that represents you and
then document how am I going to put that
into practice and then same thing go
into fonts I'd recommend choosing fonts
that are available in cap cut they're
simple or effective for you or in Adobe
Express wherever you use so you have an
easy workflow for that and then just
take the time to actually put them
inside the software you use so they're
loaded on your phone Google it figure
this out but they're in all the
softwares you have access but taking the
time to just cement it where you have
that color code in the note you have
those fonts available and on every all
of a sudden you begin to integrate your
brand into this and if you start
searching fonts on Instagram watching
font videos are going to serve you a
million of them so you're looking for
inspiration for that there's there's a
grip out there I know a couple people I
mentioned before designed by Brady he
puts some fonts into his videos uh edgy
Katrina she puts fonts into her videos
good places to start if you're looking
for inso there and if all else fails H
about could do spaced accordingly bold
hard to go wrong all right so next up
let's talk about the im8 brand brand I
recently called out their packaging in
one of my standout packaging videos and
I partnered with them on this YouTube so
the wellness industry in general is
still r with old school packaging and I
love seeing new approaches this jar that
you see here is what originally caught
my eye it's gorgeous it makes you want
to grab it whether you're in a store or
it's in your cabinet and stands out
amongst Brands is so often use green in
this category and then I enjoy little
things too like the excellent maroon
metallic that they have on these satchet
packets so I've been using the product
for a few weeks as y'all know I was on
the road at complexcon then this week
I'm doing workshops all across the US
and my biggest priority is my health and
feeling as Peak as possible at all times
despite the schedule intensity so im8
functions as a combination of immunity
boosting hydration and general energy
and I feel great if you want to give
them a shot you can check it out at im8
health.com and the last phase of this
inspiration segment before we get into
operations is Muses I want you to pick
at least one person on every social
media plat and if you're not big on
social media or if you're a designer or
whoever it is you were trying to get
some skill set from pick someone in your
field that is going to be your Muse for
this next segment of your life I think
this is actually a really important
exercise so I picked uh someone on
Instagram I picked someone on Tik Tok I
picked someone on Twitter and I picked
someone on YouTube because these are the
social networks I am most active on and
I'm thinking about strategy for so for
each one of those people you want to
list out their content pillars I look at
pillars whatever recurring things they
do with their content that you are
seeing them continue to use all the time
that are helping grow their account now
note those things down and I would list
takeaways for each woman what are the
things that I want to do why am I
following this person as views what is
it I want to integrate into my workflow
the act of thinking about that looking
at their accounts and writing it out is
a really powerful blueprint so you'll
see the people I chose when I walk
through this briefly is I chose Grace
Beverly on Instagram not familiar with
her she's a kind prolific female
entrepreneur you will see a frequent
through line and what I do is I Look to
female creators because they're just
better than male creators and at my size
on short form I'm one of the bigger male
creators inside the fields I'm in in
business that's not like completely gone
down mainstream like Alex rosi how much
protein is in a Chick-fil-A type thing
which I'm never going to do that's why I
have to look to more female creators
because they're the ones we innovating
so I like about Grace one of the pillars
she has I really like is she has put
together carousels something I'm not
doing right now that I aspire to do but
it's a combination of her imagery and
her titling there video clips include in
them she has diagrams in them they are
served as a documentation of her
entrepreneurial Journey they bring in
stuff from her other content sources and
they're a great anchor format that I
would like to attempt to do something
like I also like the way she uses her
podcast as a vehicle like inside her
content and it's done not in a way that
kind of fails it's done in a way that is
is unbranded interesting those are some
things I'm trying to work on on
Instagram so I've taken those pillars
applied to my way and the second on Tik
Tok I'm looking at girl boss town
probably seen me bring her up before
because her entire Tik Tok is based on
ideas in fact she's doing 31 days of
prediction for December where she's just
predicting things about all kinds of Pop
Culture about the Kardashians about
reality TV about Selena goz about pop
music she will put predictions out there
and which nice she predicts all kinds of
things occasionally they come right many
times don't when the C right she is out
there being like I called it and I think
that's a great format that I wish I was
doing more of because ideas are
dominating right now I share a lot of
tactics I share occasional ideas I've
done how would I create a direct this
format I want to be sharing more of that
and move away from I feel like
information is commoditized if you just
say this thing happened that's no longer
interesting content if you provide the
tactics for how that thing happened
that's kind of going its way out and is
purely idea driven going forward so I'm
leaning into that I want to take some of
what uh she's done how she's formatt I
love things even like this the second
year she's done her 31 days of
predictions like I have any recurring
themes like that I need to be thinking
like that that's why she's a muse on my
sheet then moving over to Twitter I have
Greg Eisenberg I was on his podcast I
wasn't super familiar with him until he
invited me on his podcast I loved his
Twitter account it's just pure value
that's all it is ideas and value for
businesses in text format no images I
already do images well on there I
already have my own personality but his
is less focused on his personality and
more on just like pure value and a
really extensive interesting and
different way I want to model some of
what I'm doing so now do we set our
inspiration up we're going to look at
our life and our habits and the things
that we do we're going to think about
ourselves before we go build our
operations plan and our marketing plan
the first step in this exercise is what
do I project now I want you to think
critically about what do people think of
when they think of me we're going to go
write that out and so I personally think
that when people think of me they often
think of value right the think of
Education they think of design those are
positive things I'm happy with what I
project I want you to think about that
when people you know people that see you
on the internet what do they think of if
they don't have an opinion they don't
think anything of you that's worth
marketing down as well you understand
where you're at this year looking at
what will I project my main thing I'm
thinking about is I because this is that
next step here you want think what will
I project you want to write it out like
that I will Project X that statement of
I am going to declare this is what I
want people to think of me this is what
I want to be perceived as and staring as
a declarative is important it's
important to write it out to acknowledge
where you're at and then thinkig about
where you're going so I want to project
I want people this year to be like he's
everywhere I want to feel like not
inescapable people be like wow this is
really transcended what I perceived him
as it's someone who does educational
short form videos has really gone to
another level and it's kind of a hard
concept but it is the thing that I think
gets me to a place I want to go to then
go to the next stage right we're going
to take that projection and we're going
to go to this exercise as a database
here this the first time we're getting
into a database inside what we we've
mapped out this is the database of the
life I want we're going to map out our
dream life here all the things you've
ever wanted this is a really important
exercise the first time I did this
exercise I realized that the dream life
that I wanted is significantly cheaper
than I thought it would be my friend
Zach is BAS a great videos about this
concept as well so go through and list
everything out I have a column for item
so a thing car payment your house Studio
X I'm investing in my cult CL whatever
it is the cost next to it monthly or one
off whatever list out the benefit it has
to you this is really important because
often times you'll find there you don't
have an actual benefit there's no reason
you really want something and you may be
able to just cross it off the list I
have some dropdowns inside here for
different types of benefits is it a
health benefit that's super important
right I want to be at you know going to
Equinox or whatever it is because it's a
healthit is it a happiness benefit does
this make me actually happy and that's
why I'm doing is there a wealth benefit
I'm doing this because it's going to
make me money an inspiration benefit I'm
doing it because it gives me the Crea
spark a signaler I'm doing this because
of what it means to other people and
it's okay sometimes things are signalers
right you only buy a watch CU you want
to impress other guys there's no other
reason and that's all right because if
impressing other guys gets you somewhere
that you want to go then there nothing
thing is worth doing be honest with
yourself about what those are if they
actually have value to you and
fulfillment this the last piece by doing
something that that makes me feel right
and in tune with the world and it
doesn't have to necessarily be a
charitable thing although it's great if
it is there are many things we do to
make us feel like things are worth it
and so I have those categories in there
and you you have to select one when
you're doing this again you adjust this
this dashboard however you want but is
is really useful to go through this
practice list out the items so it could
be hey want the gwag cost me $2,500 a
month we actually break down what the
payment will look like the benefit is
it's a signal or it's going to make me
get me a mate or it's inspiration
because when I get in the car every day
I feel a certain way or it's fulfillment
because I always want my entire life and
now I and I have the resources for I I
want that fulfillment to say I did
whatever it is think through that reason
and put a timeline on there it's just
something that could happen in the near
future or in the far future and what do
the actions need to happen to get
towards I would list everything out can
go through cars lodges trips Investments
you want to make equipment whatever it
is the dream items I would list every
single thing out inside because you're
going to get to a final I'm going to get
to a thing that shows you what the road
map is what you kind you're going to
reach it might be more achievable than
if when I did this exercise or at some
practicality behind okay I don't really
need this this doesn't really make me
happy actually I can't even do this
because scenario with my family or
whatever it is I realized that
everything that was on my current list
one year ago I could do I made some
adjustments focused a bit on income and
achieved it for many people maybe a few
stages away right I was in a different
stage I was already a part of the way
through this journey I'm on now once you
have your dream life mapped out you need
to look at the life that's going to get
you there are two ways at this point one
is sacrifices and the others are
Stepping Stones we have a similar map
here we have the item we have the cost
we have the benefit we have the timeline
the action the same same framework but
to get to these other goals you have
what can you change does that mean hey
I'm actually going to live below my
means for a couple years to be able to
do X or Y or for this year it actually
makes you and this is something I worked
on a lot for my whole life I drove
Hondas and Toyotas until I could have
the G wagons cuz it did not matter to me
either no benefit to me for being in the
middle I also recommend this to a lot of
people is you are either you're in
thrifting or you're a designer being in
the middle doesn't benefit you I would
think about that a lot everyone's
different but it's a worthwhile
mentality to have that I'd rather
sacrifice for X time until you get to
where you want to go than spend excess
along the way so think about what your
life looks like this year to get to that
dream state what would you have to do
whether that's to save money or to work
up to a certain thing or be able to have
access or be able to put yourself in a
position to get into working
circumstances that allow you to achieve
it that's what we're going to map out
I'm going to take this time to have a
little interlude about frugality and
about thrifting and how far it can take
secondhand is one of the cheat codes to
life especially if you are a creative if
you have taste or can want to develop
taste is every single clothing purchase
that you have could probably be gotten
at a fraction of the cost vintage or in
Thrift and you will probably be cooler
and more tasteful for it and the same
thing goes for furniture you've ever
been on like La Facebook Marketplace is
legendary state sales no matter where
you are there's something within
traveling distance if you become the
kind of person that spends some of your
time and finds some other people online
or some friends whatever go do it with
them state sales vintage secondhand and
making that a part of your life and
feeling great about it which you can is
a absolute Game Changer to save cost and
still Flex in your own way that I could
not recommend enough and you'll see look
I make a ton of money I'm still out
there state sales because I'm looking
for things that are different have taste
that perspective and we're going to end
this section with an exercise two column
exercise is your action State you're
going to put your name in there old
Julie did these things and you're going
to list out all the things that you used
to do that you want to a bad the nuli
does these things so list out all the
things that you want do now what are
those things you're going to change in
your life and they going to tie into
these two lists one is a list of don't
do what are the things I I want to
abandon and no longer have any part of
in my work match with the other column
of what are my habits what the things I
am introducing now that are going to
stay with me I want to make a consistent
part of my life I look at them like my
list here inside I don't do is like the
number one is sugar that's my only thing
in my life I Haven unable to cut out
unable to work around is I have not been
able to kick it and I am going to find a
way to do that know it sounds ridiculous
but to like identify the things that are
ridiculous and the second thing is
continuing my like anti-consumption Diet
where I've cut my content down signific
or how much I log into Twitter I use one
sec I use brick I have lined up the apps
in the circumstances to cut down the
amount of time I am consuming to where
it's only intentional to where I have
scheduled time to go watch YouTube
videos and look at analytics or to go
into Twitter and see what's happening
I'm only doing that on scheduled time
I'm getting into habits around my
content creation around introducing
carousels around my design process
around the communication I have with my
team I'm developing habits for that now
that we have those sections we are
headed into the final portion of this
which is our actual plan you'll see in
the remainder of this we have our
marketing plan we have our operations
plan and you'll see I have an action
items list and a calendar so we can
actually make this something that's
doable let's talk about marketing and a
marketing plan and treating yourself as
a business so if you are building
something when you're a freelancer and
one day you want to have agency or
you're a content creator and one day you
want to be a big content creator or you
work at a job and you're starting a side
business or you an eCommerce brand any
of these things you need to treat your
personal life more like a business as
well if you are any part of people are
choosing do work with your business
because of you or if you are F A facing
a vocal part of this which is going to
be the vast majority of anyone in inside
a creative field or anyone with a brand
nowaday so like any business you need to
invest in Market in a I look at
basically making a budget as a percent
of that income every brand invests right
sometimes it's 20% of Revenue goes into
marketing sometimes it's 5% but it's
always something that can be team that
can be advertisements that can be
support for Content creation but there
are things going into marketting we're
going to make a plan around it so you'll
see inside this chart we have the
program listed out so what is it so for
inance for me I have a person who helps
me shoot YouTube videos as part of my
Market at what are those things that are
putting yourself out there where you
want them to be and look at the stage
that they're R I'd recommend you have
one program at least you can have
multiple for each of these Stak
awareness nurture convert standard
marketing form awareness is how I about
getting attention for my for me or my
business or what I do nurture is once I
have that attention how am I getting
people educated on it so they can make a
decision and then conversion is how
actually get them to B what are you
doing in each stage of that and look at
the budget but what is it going to take
to me to actually do this sometimes
maybe running ads sometimes maybe hiring
somebody whatever it is look at the
needs what do we need to do to be able
to do that because in many cases you're
looking at a future tense right and then
you look at your notes and so there
going be a lot of things this year right
love I'm not going to walk through the
entire scenario of it but for instance
you can be going to physical events to
show off your art you can be promoting
yourself on upwork you can be listing
yourself on different job sites it could
be a featured vendor on X or Y you could
be running ads for your service on
Facebook or me those are all marketing
programs be sponsoring News letters
whatever it is decide what those items
are and for me it's a little different
CU I have all these businesses but like
some of the things I'm think about for
perspective is like so cut 30 we're
starting to Market more now and that's
my program for teaching people a short
form content so we start to do
newsletter sponsorship that's a
marketing program we're spending money
on it it's about you it kind of covers
multiple stages here but really it's
focused on conversion trying to reach
new people to get them to purchase in
the programs we're testing newsletter
sponsorship that goes in my marketing
bundle I'm doing these content shoots
that sometimes are great for my brand
but also I need more content it's a
marketing program for me but you need to
have at least one thing you can put in
each of those three buckets and think
really quickly about what that can be be
as simple as creating content you need
something to push yourself out there or
else you're not taking yourself
seriously as business you're going to
have a marketing issue and then next we
have operations this is probably the
most important piece of this and one I
did not dial in until this last year
even though I had run businesses forever
own businesses forever I did not treat
myself like a business until like mid
last year when I was really thinking
about quitting my job and it was
absolutely crucial and so no matter what
stage you're at people always get uh
caught up in the amount of time it takes
to do anything entrepreneurial to create
content to be freelanced and there's so
many of the things that you do that
other people could be doing for you if
you just built an operations PL that's
what we're going to do here there's mult
multiple Parts every operations plan but
the most important is identifying your
operational need and where it's at the
second most important part is building a
process for it documenting how someone
does it well and the third part is
communication between you and the people
that are doing it we're going to dive
through all this here inside this plan
you'll see these notes I want you to go
through and pick in the work you do say
I'm use being a freelance graphic
designer as an example inside the work
you you have the you're creating
proposals for people we updating your
portfolio with new work when it's
completed you're actually doing the work
you're communicating the work along the
way maybe you're sourcing graphics and
imagery and fast up on Trends a list of
all your activities that you're actually
doing I put what program it is cuz I
think for most people that are here
you're going to have like whatever your
day job is then you're going to have
like a side project or a side business
and you're also going to have content I
would Mark which these are because
they're all going to take some
operations I list out all those items
now I would look into the Outsourcing
segment of this is this something
impossible to Outsource is something
that only you can do and this doesn't
have to be about now but there's very
few things you'll find only you can do
so for instance the only thing I I can
really the only one that could do is be
on camera talking almost everything else
I can probably right now I still write
most of my content all my content really
some people will give me hook ideas or
video ideas and I still do a ton of
creative briefing because I'm better
than anyone I've been able to find but
that is a get a training issue for me
that's not an impossible thing so is it
impossible can no one else do this you
will begin to find be critical about
this almost nothing that you do is will
be impossible to Outsource we'll get to
when it's right to outsourced then we
have the stage of need provider that
means you've identified that someone
else could do it someone else could be
creating my proposals someone else could
be sending my weekly updates someone
else could be doing this part of the
design process but I don't have somebody
for it so I need to go hunt that down
and hiring is again that that's going to
be something thing actually you know
take some time and energy and the third
column is source for future that means
you found somebody or you found where
you would hire for like you know what I
can get this on upw work or I actually
have a bunch of graphic designers that
bookmarked a thread someone posted where
people posting their portfolios I could
go through that and DM people I could
find some you know it's source for
future that means you've nowhere to get
it I would put that in the notes segment
of like who would do it and Outsource
means you've actually done you said hey
cool this is someone does this for me
now like for instance I have YouTube
editors they do it Market over there you
look at the budget what would it cost
this is where it gets interesting right
so you start to look at okay someone
else could make my proposals for me and
it would cost me $75 each time I want to
do a proposal and you be a to look at
your time and the bandwidth you have and
you go hey it's actually not worth $75 I
have plenty of time right now I'm just
going to do it or hey I'm swamped $75
was a steal I need to get this other
person running proposals and you're
going to walk through everything on that
list and literally go through these
categories start to figure out who could
do it what it could cost and then is it
the right time and benefit value for me
right now and then you begin to fill out
an ops plan so you'll see right now I
have YouTube editors I have short form
editors I have strategy support that I
pay for for my content I have helpers
inside of cut 30 that are running
Logistics I have an assistant that
handles L hor things I'm working on for
my brand I have accounting outsourced I
have legal outsourced and then this year
I'm looking to do a number of things I
need to get clipping done I need people
clipping my YouTubes that's you DM me I
need better newsletter setup so I'm no
longer doing as much as I am on the
newsletter even though Clayton does a
good chunk of it I'm not answering my DM
someone needs to answer DM my management
is negotiating a bunch of things I have
going on that's perfect they can do that
in my design workflow I'm still
designing too much I have designers but
I don't have a process na now I'm going
to list out all the things actions that
I what can I do to get towards these to
actually fill out everything that's
operations plan to where I want to go
and now this is a blueprint for me to
scale whenever I need to this is the
thing that most entrepreneurs just never
build I'm not going to get into how to
build a process here but this gives you
the blueprint for your year all the
things you'd want to do all your Ops all
the things that allow you to pour now
you have an organized structure and that
brings us to the action end of this up
here at the top of the notion you're
going to see two things you're going to
see a to-do list and you're going to see
a calendar I put these here because most
people just need a solution they don't
have something set up I have a separate
to-do list structure I have an Assa I
have a separate calendar inside my
actual Google calendar but you're going
to go through and take all the actions
that you saw look at the dream state of
where you wanted to go all the actions
that get you there in the middle you're
going to list those out into a list
you're going to put your marketing tasks
in a bucket you're going to put your Ops
task in a bucket you're going to put
your to-do list in a bucket and here's a
huge Pro tip like a massive Pro tip
anything that's hairy it's super
complicated you're like okay I need to
hire graphic design where do I even
begin break it down so it's more like
our first I need to write a job
description then I need to Google sites
that I can find then I need to post the
description break any big item down into
smaller items and then we have the C
calendar section so here I put a
calendar on there for the year really
about what's on below it use whatever
framework you have for it this is what
you need to do to take your life serious
this every month you need to review your
finance and I would I use the calendar
because if you set a time for it it's
actually going to happen right so if you
say hey every Monday at 10:00 a.m. first
Monday every month I do a finance review
then it's going to happen and put that
under your calendar every month you need
a finance review you need an analytics
review and this is for anything whether
it's content your website your portfolio
views whatever you need to be looking at
your metrics what defin success for you
and how do you measure and a marketing
review is my marketing effective what am
I doing what am I not doing how do I
schedule going forward do at least one
of those a month you just set the date
again just like anything else again you
work whatever it is 9:00 p.m. Thursday
night there is there is time but setting
those recurring things so you know do it
when it comes up and treating it again
like a business is a way to get yourself
in the flow a finance one in particular
where you're like I brought in this
amount I have this amount coming out I'm
going to spend this much on marketing is
this realistic how do I adjust it I do
my billing it stops you from thinking
about it constantly and gives you a
concentrated area to worry about it
analytics the same thing if you look at
analytics every day all day you're
wasting time look at it every month and
compare it month over month start to
look at what their Trends are in a
dedicated session now you're getting
some now we have weekly if you have a
team of any kind whether it's editors
designers support and EA you need to
have your weekly touch points with them
one to talk through their expectations
early in the week another to review
their work at some point May that at the
end of the week we need be putting those
scenarios into play then last on this
calendar list out your major events and
your cultural events what are your
highlights what are the things you want
to do what are the things that are
happening in the world you should be
prepared for hey I should be doing a
campaign or a drop for Valentine's Day
or I us should be thinking about back to
school you knew I messed up Black Friday
this is why I like to do this right the
year cuz we're fresh on the mind of all
the things that happened from the summer
and all the things that just happened
for Holiday which is like really ripe
time for a lot of things obviously and
then we're getting into like this new q1
Q2 I just map all this out you begin to
have a calendar of the things that are
important to you so only so much I can
kind of get through in whatever this was
probably like a half hour of of talking
there's obviously a lot more to comes to
this but the notion Doc is listed down
here go through this mood board those
things out look at your dream state for
all these things what is your dream
marketing opportunity what your dream
creative space what is your dream
lifestyle what are the habits you want
to have really look through that then go
take that one step back like what kind
of action towards that list it out do
some work on it it will taking this kind
of thing seriously even just doing this
mapping session and checking it on will
change your life and change how you are
pursuing your creative Endeavor and I
drop questions or other things you want
to see or things I should add to this
template uh down in the comments I will
go through them and I appreciate you all
watching hope you lock in in the new
year