All right, I am back. The first video of
2026. I am fresh from the Swiss Alps.
I'm ready to talk to you about how to
get ahead of 99% of brands in 2026 and
the state of content in 2026. There's a
lot to learn for brands and a lot to
learn for creators, too. We're going to
talk about the size of the prize and
what we're fighting for in this world
where content, ads, and attention all
become one thing. I'm going to go
through the eras of content 2024,
[music] 2025, and 2026, and what worked
in each, what's about to work next. I'm
going to talk about what doesn't work.
If you've [music] been banging your head
against the wall as a brand trying to
figure out how to leverage this new
content world, or how to even build
outside of it, [music] wondering why you
can't get it, we're going to hit that.
Then, we're going to talk about the
short form brand playbook for 2026 and
picking an archetype. This is the
easiest way if you don't know what to do
[music] to get a plan together that will
fix it. Then we're going to talk about
building on top of that archetype for
more strategic [music] brands to get an
actual farreaching plan that takes full
advantage of the scenario that we're in
today. [music] And then we're going to
talk about perhaps the biggest
differentiator that I see brands who are
taking advantage of that era are [music]
using. I could not be more excited to
lock in.
>> We are back, baby. We are [ __ ] back.
So, first let's talk about the size of
the prize here because this is the part
in the adoption curve especially for
brands and for people using social media
where everyone gets scared. There are so
many creators. How can I possibly
compete? So many brands are good at
this. How can my brand build a following
now? Social media might be over.
Shouldn't I be looking at something
else? I see these threads or posts that
say exocial network is dead. This must
be true. And overall this big idea that
I'm too late. And for every turn for
five years now, people have felt this
exact same way. Tik Tok is going to be
banned, so I shouldn't start creating on
it. Look how that went. The algorithm
sucks right now. But somehow all these
other people are growing. And the truth
still remains that every minute spent
consuming traditional news on websites
with outdated interstitials, bad pop-up
ads, and pay walls you click through is
being taken by people who are simply
getting that information from carousels
online and from videos. And there are
literally billions of dollars and
millions of human consumption hours that
have yet to make that switch that you
are able to arbitrage because that is in
the middle of the swap of the adoption
curve, not at the end. And then now
every piece of traditional TV is
consumed with a phone in hand. So when
that ad comes on or the plot gets slow
and the game's not interesting, they are
on Instagram, they are on Tik Tok. And
this is a zero sum game that you get to
play to win and brands are winning it
where instead of all these things that
were traditionally entertainment that
weren't branded experiences that weren't
necessarily advertisements if you didn't
pay to be on it, you now get to get for
free. And you can tell we're at a really
critical point in this adoption because
the institutions are scared. Disney is
bringing their IP into open AI in the
hopes that they will be able to maintain
relevancy in a different era. Netflix is
bringing pretty nonvideofriendly
podcasts over onto their network because
they're scared of YouTube. Let's talk
about your blueprint as a brand to take
advantage of this. Starting with the
eras. So 2024 content, an amazing time
to make content was about value. Could
you educate people with your content in
a somewhat entertaining way? People
learned about marketing tactics. They
learned how to cook. They got their
fitness regimens, how to knit, whatever
it was. If a brand or a creator was
teaching people and giving tips and
tricks, basically they were able to
build an earned audience where very few
other people were doing it. In this era,
I was making Instagram videos by like
cool combos of colors for design and
getting hundreds of thousands of views
on them because simply no one else was
doing it. But now that is commodified
and that's the era that when you look at
a lot of big brands, you look at a lot
of big content gurus, they're still in
it cuz they already had their followings
and they can simply talk on camera and
it's done. But it's not that simple for
brands anymore. This is also the end of
the era, that 2023 time where your brand
could still have a couple pictures of
its product or something simple online
and because people have brand affinity,
they'd like it. That era is done. And I
want to implore brands out there who
think social media doesn't work for
them, that they should be marketing in
different ways or thinking of other
stuff and not thinking social first. If
you are still posting the same stuff you
posted then and expecting the result and
blaming the algorithm, the problem isn't
that. The problem is you. The codes are
there in front of you from myself, from
other creators, from so many brands that
are doing it. You just have to man or
woman up. And 2025 was about story
content. The storyteller thrived.
Experts explaining the history of a
fragrance note, the process with which a
paint color comes to life. Personalities
who actually had expertise in their
topic and brand owners and people that
represented brands in particular took
over. Value alone slowed. value wrapped
in a story took off. One of my favorite
creator examples of this, my guy Ken
Sakata from Front Office, who provides
amazing educational content about
fashion in general that shows his care
for the craft that then helps promote
his clothing line. The era of how-tos,
but wrapped in work and opinion. What
would you do in a scenario? The art of
the story. Resale companies would tell
the stories of the products and the
brands that they were reselling. They
would turn every piece instead of a
product promo into a larger story the
product could fit inside of. This was
the time when first movers and old
school influencers really got replaced
by genuinely more interesting people.
Follower accounts started to matter a
whole lot less. And it was the rise of
the thoughtful creator and the brand led
by thoughtful people who was able to
really succeed online. And this was an
incredible content year. If you wanted
to consume non-brain rock content, the
algorithm would give it to you. And if
you didn't see it, you should think
about the habits with which you consume.
And this era was the sweet spot for me,
right? For what we teach inside Cut30.
We had dozens of experts who just
smashed people explaining farm hotels to
hospitality to the front of their
fragrance brands to photography
businesses. So, we got to see firsthand
how this worked and what worked about
it. While at the same time, the bigger
brands I'm working with, our goal was to
how do we get pros on camera to help
tell the story? But people know the
secret is out. So, going into 2026, what
is the scenario? And there are more and
more creators, more and more interesting
people. So many folks who are putting up
100,000, 200,000 view videos all the
time. We're getting good at this, a lot
of them. What happens? What do we do
now? So, we talked a lot about social
and leveraging expertise, but where do
you go to get more topics? If you're
trying to find strong topics and do the
research behind them without spending
hours on it, then this free guide from
HubSpot on Google Gemini and Notebook LM
is exactly what you need. It's called
How to do 10 hours of research in 20
minutes. The marketer's guide to Google
Gemini and Notebook LM. This ebook
explains step by step how to analyze
competitors and build research flows to
understand customer needs so you can get
hours of research done in a short
working session. Google Gemini has
research functions and access to a
world's worth of sources. And I will hit
it with a bunch of questions to quickly
understand a topic or the place of a
brand in a market. A few quick examples.
What are the most common questions
people ask about a category and the
direct product? What are people
complaining about in reviews about a
category or a specific product? What are
the top complaints and objections for
competitive brands in your category? You
can even ask it to generate the
competitive list for you and it will
pull the results from all over the
internet. And these topics become the
basis for your expert-driven content.
Everything I just mentioned is for using
Gemini. But my favorite part is the next
step. Bringing all that research into
Notebook LM. When you combine that
research with your content scripts, your
brand guidelines, customer reviews,
other brand materials you have. You're
basically creating a queryable world of
content for your brand. You can ask for
really specific results. And this ebook
walks through that entire flow. You can
get this for free and learn more about
automated deep research and AI workflows
at the link in the description. And
thank you so much to HubSpot for
sponsoring this video. So 2026 is the
year of format. You find your angle as a
brand or as a creator, then you become
recognizable and then you expand your
brand out and around it. We'll talk
about archetypes and systems with which
to do that here in a minute. And so by
format, I mean, what are universal
things that make it recognizable when
you get on feed? So, for instance, if
you see my content, what I've been doing
recently, you'll notice that I have the
same similar gradient colored background
looks. I have a new editing style with
all the graphics that are on my page.
And you will see it's not just a green
screen video. It's an orange green
screen video. It's [clears throat] a
branding play. Creators I love like
Internet Anthropology is a great one.
She has a set that's in her background
as she talks makes you instantly
recognize it as her. Even though it's
just another talking video, the setup of
it makes it unique. And for brands, it's
the same exact thing. setting up in
their warehouse, in a doctor's office,
in the R&D lab, inside a storefront,
creating these repeatable scenarios
where people who like the angle of your
content, they see it. It's instantly
recognizable so that you don't just have
to work on the hook up front. You're
already hooking by being comfortable to
somebody. They're tuning into their
show. Now, on that note, you've seen
tons of my content now for years on
social shows. That's another extension
of this, getting a concept and working
through it. And we're going to talk
about this. this. We're also going to
talk about what it means for ads and
what it means for the world of creators
and things around your brand as well in
a minute. But first, let's talk about
what doesn't work. And first is trends.
And everyone always talk down on trends,
but a lot of brands are able to
participate in them and work in them
well. But now, things happen so
immediately fast that for 99% of brands,
it's not even worth pursuing. If you
were a brand who wanted to post about
Taylor Swift's new album release or hop
on an audio that's working, you have to
be able to turn it around the same day
that you learn about it or it's not
going to work. And so if your brand is
not set up for same day concept to
execution to turn, I would not even
think about a trend whatsoever. Same
thing with the day in the life or day
seven of building X or Y. People have
seen these videos so many times now and
it's so typical that no longer is
compelling. People aren't as curious
about what those look like unless you
have some special element. So one
complimentary thing to that that people
are enjoying is if you are opening a
brickandmortar store and you're building
out the construction or something
similar, those still go pretty well. or
if you add a really dynamic element like
we're seeing vlogs that are like
hyperedited like in a faster or insane
ways that could work in that same
methodology but the standard is over and
then tips and tricks anything that's not
wrapped in a story I wouldn't approach
it and Craig Hill is an amazing example
of a brand who does it wrapped in a
story right so they will go show off how
they made a widget how they made a pair
of scissors how they made a bottle
stopper and they will tell the story of
the design choices they made like hey
typically products used to use a hinge
like this and it was developed by this
person in the 1800s but we don't like
this hinge because these three things
happen. So, we set out to actually
design our own hinge and it does X. It's
different, but we had this challenge in
production. This is what we ended up
with. And their videos will follow these
formats where someone walks you through
those choices inside their product. They
do very well. Then, the era of low
production, especially for brands, is
over. Now, I don't want to talk about
high production, but low production in
general, just hopping on the camera and
talking. All the little intentional
things matter. dropping in images over
your content, the framing, the lighting,
it can still come across as lowfi or be
shot on an iPhone. But all of those
intentional choices make a difference.
Everything must be done with intention.
You're competing with content from
people who are savvy at it. This is
important because if you are running
ads, if you're using UGC creators, you
need to be making sure that they're
operating at that level as well. On the
other end, the overproduced content is
the biggest one that's entering. If
you're paying 50,000, hundreds of
thousands of dollars for shoots, which I
talk to brands every single week that
are doing, it's much better to be
intentional about the tools and the
spaces you already have, equipping your
teams with gear. So many brands are
doing this themselves with one or two
cameras and one or two team members or a
freelancer that comes in X and Y because
they can. Because with YouTube and
editing tutorials and everyone making
content now, there is actually lots and
lots of creative people who are able to
execute these ideas and do it. Amazing.
One of my favorite examples of this is
Capria, the restaurant that did these
storytelling vignettes. This one that
went viral about someone leaving their
green hat when they got a phone call to
the restaurant. They're describing their
night, describing the things in the
restaurant. And this was shot by one
videographer who comes in, shoots a
couple videos every time he comes in,
who had a creative idea, was given the
reigns to execute it. It looks like
something that would cost a lot more,
but this is the era that we're living
in. And if you're looking at it and
denying it, you're going to lose. You're
going to waste money. and then faceless
content. In the age of AI, its value has
collapsed and gone to zero because of
how easy it is to do. Without human
connection, it's harder and harder to
generate real leads and real sales. In
the last 3 to 4 months, I haven't seen a
single brand in our network who has been
able to put up real sales numbers
focused on entirely on faceless content
without someone being on camera, some
combination of storytelling that is done
really well and professionally. And this
matters because it used to be optional,
but now it's just noise. And then last,
jokes and memes. You used to be able to
grow your brand pretty far with being
very humorous. And now it's great as a
part of your funnel. It's great for
maybe a quarter of your content. But
another thing that is just incredibly
commodified and [clears throat] also
where people are losing the intention to
buy from it. It is purely entertainment.
So that's part of your content funnel.
Awesome. But it can't be all of it. And
so if you're a brand, you're wondering
what to do. This process is for you. I
put together four archetypes. You just
pick an archetype from this list that
will guide you as to where to go. And
the archetype is a style your brand will
consistently execute and it's a
northstar. And if you don't pick one,
you end up with a hodgepodge of
unsuccessful [ __ ] And brands
eventually become a blend of archetypes.
But to start, we're going to zone in on
one. So the four I recommend first is
the expert. Position a team member or a
credible creator or an actor or UGC
person that someone credible scripts for
to tell intricate stories that educate
people on your brand's world and the
things around it. Everything from cyber
security to dermatology. It's an
authority first approach. Second is the
artist. Social optimized creatived
directed content that's conceptual and
visually exciting. Whether it's lowfi or
immaculate production doesn't matter.
What does matter is there is someone
very creative who understands social
media who is making things to be
entertaining within that niche and that
is the number one focus of the content.
The ideas come first. This is best if
you have a one-of-a-kind social or
creative talent that is on your team or
you can work with. So some examples of
these the expert I love I point out this
brand Tonster paints for the expert
example where literally the person uh I
believe it's the founder of the brand is
there in front of their paint rig that
is his set like we mentioned before and
he's talking about their popular colors
and the blends and you get to see it in
action and it's a very aesthetic
process. If your brand has any kind of
production facility or warehouse use
that to your advantage to create content
like this. Now if you don't want to have
your founder do it or do it yourself. A
great example of a brand who's done that
if it's also outside of the product
space is Opel. Opel is a app like an
antisocial media use app and they put a
creator talking about mental health and
the impact of phones and it's a girl on
a whiteboard iPhone content who is just
educating about those things and she is
not a founder. She's someone the brand
employs to do this not even on the
brand's main account. If you were a
brand I wouldn't be thinking about
multi-count or anything unless you're
much larger. If you do want ability to
test without ruining whatever you have
going on main it's a great approach.
These are two great examples. And then
then the artist one I love to point out
is Reigns. Over this last few months,
they had focused a lot on conceptual
content around games. And why I like to
call this out is that look, this is
great content. This content they
probably spent a decent amount of time
and money on. But if you were to think
about how do I execute a creative idea
at a relatively medium budget, this is
really at the end of the day a white
background studio and then they are
fabricating games. It started simple
cross word puzzles, things you could
print out, moved its way up to guessing
games, other board games, things that
may cost them more like a couple hundred
to produce, but it is not insane. is an
example of a wellexecuted concept in a
medium budget range that a lot of brands
if they were creative enough could do.
And the third archetype is the wild
card. Humor, memes, skits, unexpected
choices. Attention first content
designed to get what falls through the
funnel. This is where you'll see
humorous brands like the Chinese food
restaurants always have skits of like
people getting hit by cars to cut off
their videos, right? So, this is one
where it's cheap attention. It's going
to be hard to build a ton of value over
the long term, but it's a great place to
start if you can just focus on we're
going to be oddball, we're going to be
funny, we're going to get that first
attention and we can build on top of it
over time. But knowing that you can lean
into your weird streak if that's your
superpower as a brand, this is a good
angle. And then fourth is the world
builder. This is choosing to say our
core feed us as a brand matters actually
much less than enabling creators,
affiliates, and influencers to tell the
story for us. Earned media value over
owned content where distribution beats
organic. And this is totally okay for a
lot of brands. What this isn't okay is
to say our organic social doesn't matter
and we're going to handle things
completely elsewhere. You have to have
other people doing this participation
for you. You have to be saying we're
going to let other creators and seeding
and all these things do the story for us
and we're going to focus on that. But
for a lot of brands where that has more
power potentially than their organic or
they have that kind of figured out but
have struggled with it. This is it's
okay to lean in that core organic
branded feed if you're good at the rest
of it can matter less than ever. But now
you have to be laser focused on how do I
enable my creators? Are we making sure
that their stuff is framed well? That
they're lit well, that they have props,
that they're doing sets, that they have
recurring bits, that we're sharing hooks
and themes, that we're creating unboxing
packages that are going to work really
well on social, that we're connecting
them to each other and building a
community, that we're compensating
people to go above and beyond and
building out a world around that. And
then once you're good at this, you found
your initial take, what angle you want,
you're going to use the pillar system.
I've got whole videos about this pillar
system, but basically where you're
picking a couple methods of content. So
if you have your expert driven content,
for instance, you're doing carousels,
they call their stuff out, while you're
doing hands-on explainer videos, while
you're doing like more uh say higherend
campaign content with them, you're
building a couple approaches around each
of these or the pillar system. You can
I'll link [clears throat] the pillars
video at the end of this video. But then
once you're good at that one thing, what
comes next? It's about expansion. You've
got traction. Wins are happening there.
If you haven't put an expert on screen
yet, that's the next thing. So you have
great art directed content or you're
building your great brand world or
you're doing your more risque or funny
content. The next step for everybody I
cannot recommend enough is get that
expert on cam. Whether it's someone from
your organization, a paid professional
you get, a creator you get, whatever it
is, get that expert on screen. That has
to be your next step. If it's not the
first thing you do, then it should be
that second. And then the next is build
a signature series. This is a thing that
people call out for creators a lot. They
have a recurring thing that they do.
Brands need the same thing. What is that
hit format you can have with your expert
or with your campaigns? You can do a
lot. You can do it every week, every
month, and people are going to want to
tune in and recognize it. What can you
tell around your niche? Needs to be a
repeatable format with clear association
and batchable production so you can do a
bunch. So, a few examples like Bape has
one where people go shop in store and
make an outfit based on a color they
pull out of a bar. It's great for a
storefront. Alexis Petar has a
serialized drama. Built has their
romcom. Even that whiteboard self-help
channel that I mentioned is basically a
signature series. but thinking in that
like social show format. You see a lot
of brands now are using puppets just
trying to find some recurring bits that
they can do to think of it like our
brand is TV. I have a whole video on
that as well. From there, it's about
expanding your world, collaborating more
social, being social. So, you've built
your core, you've added on your expert.
Now, get that expert working with other
people in their niche and doing collab
posts. Get more people on screen. Enable
the staff and the teams that you use
that are on social media or the people
you have in production to be part of it.
You'll notice there's a trend now where
the DPS, the people that are executing
the content that post the behind the
scenes, go bigger than the campaign. It
happened with one of Diesel's recent
campaigns. That's great. Enable those
people to post, encourage them to do it,
incentivize them or pay them to do it.
Have them collaborate across the board.
You need to take advantage of the whole
world of people around you. Same with
your customers that are posting content.
How do you encourage them, collaborate
with them, get guest appearances, work
it out, really map it out like it's a
landscape. This is how worlds scale. And
a great example of how to do this is say
you were doing a release and you're
sending out a new mailer and it has a
theme to your campaign. Got one sitting
here up here above me that um from from
Morphe who I work with. It's a big stick
of butter, right? And so say that you
were able to send that to your top
customers and you were also able to give
it to your UGC creators and you had it
in the campaign that you had on Maine
and everyone had like a recipe theme
thing they were going to do cuz there's
a food on it and your expert is
collaborating with one of the top
influencers you have actually with them
doing like a mini cooking thing. It was
all part of the same campaign. You're
involving every layer of your world and
you're centering it around an object and
that is smart world building that will
help build out your social world. Now,
I'm going to end on maximizing ROI. One
of the biggest differentiators brand can
have in 2026 and that's actually using
comments and DMs. Let me tap into that.
So, you've seen creators run many chat
where you say comment report and I'll DM
you the link. Like this is 100%
something brands should do, especially
services brands, but works for product
brands and stuff as well. If you are
doing a release, get the link sent to
people early. give out those free
downloads. If people have questions,
give them ask them to be able to say
comment or DM or whatever. Get in that
response format because these are
selling. One thing you'll notice,
something that this brand Elf had done
very well, if they were doing community
management and comments, they're saying
instead of just commenting back when
someone messaged something like, "Hey,
we're messaging two emojis or whatever."
Viral Nation, the team that worked with
them on it was providing product advice.
They were providing recommendations and
pairings. They were actively turning
comments into more of a selling and
educational tool versus just a response
tool on their own videos and on other
videos about them as a weapon for you to
be able to say we're going to turn our
commenting from just acknowledgement
into conversation into recommendation
into this product might go great with
that or have you looked at this prior or
you have any questions about X. Turn
that proactive turn that conversation
on. The DMs is the same thing. Services
brands especially would pay attention to
this. one of the brands we had in Cut 30
that was doing roofing. They were
saying, "Hey, we're getting a lot of the
right people and we're getting a lot of
comments on there, but people aren't
asking about buying a roof." I'm like,
"Well, you might need to ask those
people." So, for instance, if you are I
think they were in the Midwest. I was
like, "Cool. If any people that comment
are in your state, click there and look
on them. Doesn't take you long. There's
34 comments you can click through and
see if anyone's also in your state."
Well, message them and see, are you
thinking about a new roof? Because
you've commented on multiple of our
roofing videos. Take that proactive. DMs
and comments are sales tools. If you are
an agency or a services business and
you're not doing this, you're actually
foolish. It's stupid to not do this. And
if you're a product brand, it comes down
to bandwidth. Can you how much can you
work on this? You should at least be
working the comments like that and
answering the sales questions that come
in direct and incentivizing the team to
make that stuff work, giving them codes
that help track the conversion or get
people a discount if they engage in
conversation. Like truly, where else in
the world you get onetoone access to
your potential lead sources for your
business where you can just send them
messages? There's basically no other way
to do that besides cold email. So, every
brand needs to be DM and comment maxing
in 2026. So, anyway, thank you for
watching my state of content. I hope you
learned a lot here. Our tour in Toronto,
New York, and Miami is coming up. I have
the information down below for that. I
do have this all in written format.
We're going to have the guide with tons
of links, etc. I will also link that
down below as well. I have an awesome
video of the creative direction of sport
coming up soon. So stay tuned and I
appreciate y'all so much for watching.