In this video, we are going to talk
about how to make a marketing plan, a
2026 guide. As many of you know, I was
on tour earlier this year. We did two
stops in New York, Miami, Toronto, and
in each place, we had 40 brands come in
to do live workshopping around their
marketing plans for the year. I ran
through a series of five exercises, and
we had brands from small independents
all the way up to major airlines and
activewear companies, software,
workshopping how they can actually make
a difference in this really complicated
marketing climate. I'm going to walk
through all of those same exact
exercises here in this video. There is
downloads to accompany this with all the
worksheets we used, so even if you
couldn't make it in person, you can
still sit down and actually go through
it. I highly recommend doing this with
your notebooks out, actually walking
through it for your brand or one of your
clients, or just theoretically, and
really going through the exercise to
think about what you can do to make a
difference in marketing this year. And
then you can save this for any future
time you're doing year or quarterly
planning. They're a great set of
exercises to do. I'm super excited
because when I was on tour, I got to see
the actual differences [music] and
problems that businesses had, what their
problems are really dealing with versus
just the things we see on the internet.
It's a lot different in real life. And a
big part of why I wanted to go was to be
able to learn what challenges people
actually have, so that I have things to
make content about that are really
relevant to you. I feel like we've
really nailed that here. Let's get into
it. Lock in. So first off, if you missed
last week's community call, you can see
the recording in the downloads below as
well. We will have another one coming up
in March, so please get on the list for
that. I love workshopping with you in
person and online. It's one of my big
goals for this year. Now alternatively,
if you want to see the new tour dates,
and you want to be a part of that tour
coming up, Air, who put together this
last one, now we're talking about what
the next dates are. Let us know the
markets you're in as we are trying to
plan that actively. But let's start off
by walking through the exercises that
we're going to go through today. The
first is we're going to walk through the
brand's marketing funnel. Look at what
are we good at today, what are we good
at tomorrow, and explain the funnel in
general. Then we're going to look at
this chart of all the different
marketing initiatives that are going on
in the world and why you would consider
doing them in the world where there's so
many options now. It's really hard to
decide. We're going to show how the
marketing funnel applies to content in
the content funnel and why content
marketing are so aligned now. We're
going to talk briefly about asset
repurposing because we know not everyone
has the ability to do more each year.
Sometimes you have to do more with what
you already have. Then we're going to go
through your year planning calendar. So
let's start with the marketing funnel
exercise. And this is something I think
any company, even individual, if you
market yourself or your service or your
offer or your creator should do. If you
aren't familiar with the marketing
funnel, this is how people go from
attention at the top. What does your
brand do to generate awareness? How do
you get more and more people aware of
what you do? And then how do you
graduate them down through the funnel,
get them educated on your brand and
considering purchasing what you do,
following you, etc. All the way to the
bottom where they actually make the
sale. And so the point of this exercise
and how it works is that every brand
should look at, what are we doing right
now at each of these three stages of the
funnel? At the top, what do we do right
now for awareness? How do we bring in
attention? And then the key question is,
are we actually good at it? Does this
work for us? Same thing in the middle.
If you're getting good attention, you
bring people in with viral videos or
ads, etc. Are you good at converting the
attention you already get into people
that are interested to buy? How do you
educate? How do you nurture? How do they
build affinity with your brand or your
product, whether it's software or
cosmetics? And then to the bottom, how
are we getting the sale? actually
pushing people through the funnel down
to a sale? And this is where I want to
stop for a second and outline that
funnels are very different for different
businesses and for different creators,
anything you do. So for instance, if you
sell a very mainstream product, you sell
Toyotas, you sell lipstick that every
woman could use, you sell guys t-shirts,
your top of funnel has a lot of
potential to get to your bottom of
funnel. You have a wide funnel. So a lot
of people come in at the top, a lot A
lot can exit at the bottom if you're
good because you have a big market for
your products. So, your job is to try
and get a lot of people really educated
and buying at the bottom, and you don't
want to have a ton of drop-off from the
top of your funnel to the bottom. A lot
of businesses are in a very different
position, where they have very specific
people they want to buy. One of the
people at our workshop was a software
firm that sells only to like ultra
wealthy businesses with super high
needs. Their contracts are seven
figures, and they're like, "How do we
play in this marketing funnel? We have a
such a small other end." And the
difference is, it's not actually that
different. It's just that way less
people come out the bottom. You need to
figure out a way to reach your target
demo, and maybe you can get ultra
targeted with that, but for a lot of
people it's going to be somewhat wider.
And your only care, whether you reach a
million people at the top or a hundred
thousand at the top, is how many people
come out the bottom. Are you getting to
the sale you want to get to? And it's
important concept to wrap your head
around, because some people may want to
go wide to get to small. But in this
exercise, we map out, "What do we do
today for awareness? What do we do today
to actually get people educated and
build affinity with our brand?" And so,
that could be anything from educational
content to our email automation series
to the logo repetition in ads they're
reminded of it, to what we do inside our
community and events we hold, lots of
middle of funnel content and marketing
initiatives, to the bottom. How do we
get people to convert? And the bottom I
want to call out, and I have it here in
the chart. What are you doing for SMS?
Are you texting people to buy? What are
you doing for email? How's your sales
reps operate? Do they have the right
materials if you have a sales process?
What are you doing in your Instagram
stories? Are you pushing out sales stuff
on your broadcast channels? There's a
lot of bottom of funnel options. And for
a lot of brands who are already getting
decent attention but not converting
enough, you should just focus 100% on
this. And what I noticed inside this
event is there actually were a lot of
brands. We definitely skewed more
towards bigger and enterprise brands
that were at the actual workshops. That
was their real problem is they aren't
selling hard enough. They're actually
doing lots of top of funnel, but they
aren't asking for money enough, and they
aren't aggressively doing it or doing it
in a way that's compelling for the
consumer to want to engage in. So, then
on this chart we go through, "What are
we doing today?" And then we map out,
"Where do we want to be tomorrow? What
could we do? Are we doing great at top
of funnel? Don't change anything. Are we
doing great at the bottom? Don't change
anything. Or do we want to update our
strategy? So, how do you decide what you
want to update your strategy with?
That's when we get to this chart, uh,
which I love. One of my fun ideas, which
is the normie to fringe sales to
awareness brand options chart. This is
all the marketing you could do and it's
listed on a scale. So, on the left here,
we have normie. Things that you can get
approved, no matter how stingy your boss
is, no matter how risk-averse they are.
That's normie. This was the one of, uh,
I think there's probably three key
topics that came up on tour. One was,
how do you structure our team nowadays?
That's a big one that came up I'm going
to do a video on later. The second was
this, how do I get stuff approved? That
was a huge thing that came up. And we
just did a Brandfather's pod about this,
uh, last week. And the third one was
basically this, how do we decide what to
do in all these initiatives? And so,
I've put this chart together. It's not
perfect. You may feel that certain
things would be in different places, but
really it's designed to say, what can I
easily get approved and anyone could do
on the normie side. On the fringe side,
it's what can I do to be at the bleeding
edge. I want I want want to make a bet
on that I will I will bet my career. I
can advance in my career by being ahead
of it. I will bet my company. I I can
compete with people that are slower,
can't get things approved by being on
the edge. And then, where are our
focuses, right? Because sales and
awareness are very different goals. If
you are a business, smaller business,
you're probably hyper-focused on sales.
You say, we need to get sales to grow.
We can't waste our time on awareness.
And you're right. But then for a lot of
brands, they reach a cap. They go, we've
had all this marketing that's been so
measurable for so long. We've run our
meta ads, we've run our Google ads. We
do email, we sell on these accounts.
We've hit a threshold, we just can't get
any larger. And this is a hard point for
a lot of businesses. And we discussed
this in depth because so many businesses
have hit this. It's usually between 30
and 50 million dollars. Where you go, oh
my god, all this stuff that got us here
was measurable, was safe. The CFO liked
it, CEO liked it. Marketing was
extremely mathematical. But to get to
that next level, you have to make a
jump. The awareness level is a plunge of
faith and you cannot scale beyond some
of those numbers that you hit without
taking that plunge into we have to look
at marketing more holistically. We have
to get into awareness. And if you're in
this position, every business is in this
position. I've been in businesses that
have fallen apart in this position. But
bring them this video telling them there
are dozens and dozens of firms that we
met with in the last few weeks that are
at that point where like we need to
scale, we need to go into awareness.
Everyone feels it's too risky. How do we
how do we balance that? And for a lot of
people it's just assigning percent of
the marketing budget. Yes, we do the
same thing we used to do and we're doing
that with 9% of the 14% we spend on
marketing or whatever that ratio is for
your business. But what you'll notice is
you start doing more of that awareness,
it increases the efficacy of what you do
on Meta. It increases the efficacy of
what you do in wholesale. And you can't
measure it the same way you can measure
a Meta flow, which is important to think
about. So calling out some of the things
on here, you know in this normie sales
corner, wholesale selling into retail,
email marketing, Google Ads, Meta Ads,
YouTube Ads, cold outbound where you're
just reaching directly out to businesses
for your leads, you know what those are.
Going over here into fringe sales, if
you're putting creators on your
accounts, that is a slightly more sales
driven marketing approach, you're
running ads on TikTok. Or you're
seeding, sending out free product in the
hopes of getting posts. Do you run an
affiliate program? It's ultra sales
focused but more fringe. You're doing
affiliate on TikTok Shop or if you're
doing affiliate for software. SMS,
people are still afraid of SMS. I cannot
recommend more something like One Text,
no sponsor relationship. They have card
on file SMS text, an incredible piece of
software. AppLovin, a lot of toxic
shills on Twitter who don't disclose
their AppLovin relationships who have
talked about this, but it is still a
channel that you can scale in the same
way as Meta, it's just weirder. And then
live selling, can you get on TikTok,
Whatnot where you're actually selling
and generating profitable lives on your
own channels or with creators? That
covers the sales end. Again, there's
more on this. Take your own initiatives,
you know, and put them on this chart.
Move things to where you think they are.
I'm not acting like this is the end-all
Bible. Now let's go into awareness. So
LinkedIn posting is more of awareness
focused, going to trade shows hyper
awareness focused unless they're really
tied into wholesale. Instagram and
TikTok Uh, organic social. Influencer
kind of straddles that line. I'd argue
it's slightly more awareness focused.
And then more in the fringe, are you
doing organic YouTube? That's pretty
rare. But obviously you'll see people
like, I've made a lot of videos on the
Air channel. That was them doing organic
awareness on YouTube. X, godforsaken X.
If you're doing something more like a
social show, you have multi-account
strategy on social media where you have
five or six Instagram accounts,
clipping, you have a Snap strategy. And
then I put streaming at the other end.
Different than live selling, but if the
reason I want to call this one out is
say you are a brand that's really
hyper-focused on Gen Alpha. And when Gen
Alpha becomes comes consumers, and they
consume a lot through streaming. You may
not get a lot of sales right now, but
I'd be terrified. If I was Right Guard,
if I was Under Armour, if I was anyone
who had traditionally had a college
audience, they don't give a about
any of the traditional brands they have.
They get They only care about what's in
their own infrastructure and culture.
That's why you see brands like Jake
Paul's W pop up. And I would be saying,
"Man, we have to do a three-year
investment in streaming to gain
relevancy as an awareness play." It's a
good example of fringe awareness to be
able to own a niche. So, once you've
used it, once you run through this brand
options chart, you can go back up and
basically say, "What are we going to
do?" And realistically, for 90% of
businesses, what you're going to do is
just do the existing things that you do
better. That's going to be the primary.
But if you are business in a place where
you want to add more to, two is kind of
the maximum things that a the team, even
if you have a big-ass team, can really
do and execute well even in like a
six-month period. I would be putting
those on here for the year. And I would
say, "Where are they at? Is this
initiative helping our top of funnel? Is
it helping our bottom? Is it helping our
consideration?" Don't ignore the middle
even though my chart was more focused
the other way. "Where do we need the
most help? What are one to two
initiatives that we can add on here?"
And then you actually map that out. And
now you have the basically the top end
of a plan. So now it's up to you if you
want to do these other two stages and
what order you want to do it. But this
is the content funnel, which is
basically looking at social media the
same way. What do we do on Instagram to
get more attention? What do we do on
TikTok to get more attention at an
awareness level? What puts up views for
us? What do we do at the middle to
educate? And then what do we do at the
bottom? And my content pillar system,
where it says we have three to five
types of content as a brand we put out
at any given time. Look at your pillars,
and every brand has it, whether you
think you do or not, you probably
already have three to five types of
content. So, a pillar would be a format
plus a topic. I do we do green screen
breakdowns. We do vlogs for
behind-the-scenes. We do carousels of
our e-commerce photos. Any one of those
things that you repeat regularly each in
a month is a pillar. And if you don't
have those, you can go through the
exercise of designing them. Yes, we want
to do these pillars, and that's part of
this. You take those pillars and you map
them to the funnel. Does this pillar
participate in top-of-funnel,
middle-of-funnel, or bottom-of-funnel?
Let me do this as an example for my own
content. My product versus brand content
is top-of-funnel. I do product reviews
primarily for my top-of-funnel content
as a creator. That gives me a lot of
views. I get millions of views regularly
breaking down what products I think
people should buy, how marketing works.
That brings me people that are likely
interested in marketing. That's my real
target demographic, people that are
interested in marketing and branding.
They are also interested in what they
buy and why. So, that's the top of my
funnel. Then in the middle, I do lots of
marketing educational videos, lot of
content you've watched where I'll talk
about why truffles were, you know,
changed as a concept, or these five
brand campaigns, or let's break down how
influencer marketing changed in 2006.
That's my middle-of-funnel, I'm
educating. Not everyone graduates from
product reviews down there, and that's
completely fine, but it gets me my
target demographic in the middle. And
then at the bottom, I have brand deals,
and I have stuff that drives to my email
list, and that is my bottom-of-funnel
content. And my pillars reflect that.
What you would want to do is look at the
pillars you have today, and assign a
grade to them. Do we do them well,
especially versus the field that you're
at? Compared to other businesses in our
niche, and then in general, what are we
doing? A through F. We're doing good,
we're doing bad. And then you can look
at how does that map to the funnel?
How's our top-of-funnel on social today?
Okay, is it a C? How is our
middle-of-funnel? Okay, that's a B. Most
brands are pretty decent at
middle-of-funnel.
And then bottom-of-funnel, how are we
asking for the sale? How are we driving
KPIs? Are we using ManyChat to for
comments to drive people to our email
list?
Do we sell well on stories? Do we really
leverage retargeting in our organic
content and paid? What are we doing on
bottom-of-funnel? And it might not
always be related to content, you might
have to have this conversation in tandem
with your marketing. Then look at
tomorrow. What do we want our pillars to
be? What could they be? What content
could we create? How do we take these
grades higher? And how do we map our
content to the funnel higher? And that's
the conversation you want to go
workshop. And then most importantly with
this, a lot of people have great social
ideas. Who's going to do it? What's the
action that we want to get a creator on
our main account? Who's going to do it
on the team? Yeah, Shelby's going to do
it. Carl's going to do it. Important
exercise to work through. And then we're
going to map this to the calendar. And
this is an excellent exercise everyone
should do. Creator brand of any size is
go through the calendar for the year.
First line, and I do this by quarter and
by month, what's happening in culture?
So for instance, in February, I had it
mapped out that the Super Bowl is there,
Valentine's Day is there, and the
Olympics is there. And I make content
about each of them. And it was really
important content for me to be able to
be capturing the zeitgeist. So my Super
Bowl content put up millions of views. I
was probably the biggest marketing
creator participating in that moment and
got the most out of it of anyone because
I was prepared for it. And then I look
at my own content for culture going on.
We have the World Cup coming. Am I going
to participate in that? I decided not to
do All-Star Weekend because I didn't
think there was going to be enough
virality around it. November, I have
buying season. I'm just mapping out
what's happening in culture. Back to
school, all these things you could
participate in. Then you have your
industry. So for instance, when I worked
in camera drones, NAB was a huge show in
our industry. It's a broadcast show
where people go buy cameras and then
retailers go to buy products they're
going to stock on their shelves in the
camera space. So we'd always have NAB as
a big thing. CES in Las Vegas, those are
industry events. So in your industry,
are there interior design shows or
fashion shows or cosmetic shows or
things that your consumer goes to?
Coachella might be an industry show
technically for you if you sell a
certain type of product. And where do
they lie? Then go through your sales
heat map. Pull up your Shopify data.
What months did you do well? And look at
your goal. What month did we exceed
goal? What month were we under goal? And
map We usually uh in the downloadable
version of this, it's all white. Uh we
usually shade it or red, yellow, green
it. And then really look at, okay, do we
If you hit your sales goal, why did we
hit it? Is there something that we have
to replicate? Cuz a lot of people will
hit it and they assume they hit it the
next year but don't do the same actions.
So I actually write out on this chart,
"Hey, we hit it because we did a flash
sale or because we had this massive
order or whatever it was." Note it. Or
we had a successful social campaign.
Okay, how can you repeat that? Same
thing with social. When did we shine on
social and then when were we down? Then
you can look at both, how do we repeat
what we did and then how do we fill the
holes? And then here you can go through
your actual launches. When do you plan
to launch products? Do you want to move
that because of what's happening in
culture or your industry or last year's
data? And you can work through whatever,
"I'm going to launch my collections or
our new product or this new PDF." I
would highly encourage you, even if
you're an agency, "Oh, we're going to
launch a new service or a new offer or a
new showcase." That's a launch. Think
like you're marketing. I do this as a
creator. I have launches. I launch a new
series. I'm going to Japan and then
we're likely going to launch new
products. Like there's a lot of that.
It's the way to think about it. And then
last, uh, one thing that we added while
we were doing this tour was, "What did
we miss out on?" So you can often note
last year, your team will have been in
Slack, whatever it is, you'll be like,
"Man, we really should have done X." But
then you never have a time to do it.
This is your moment to critically think
back, go through your Slacks or your
Teams and be like, "Okay, what did we
miss out on?" Like, let's try to hunt
down some of those things so we know. So
now you have your marketing funnel, your
content funnel, your brand options, your
calendar matrix. Uh, two other ones that
I'm going to resume through quickly that
you're going to have in this packet is
asset repurposing. A lot of people are
like, "We don't have budget to do more."
How can you do more with what you
already have? So this outlines the flow
of your internal assets, things you get
from creators or influencers or sending
free product. What are all the things
you can do with them and then developing
a system to track them is a really
useful exercise if you can't create
more, but you want to make sure you're
doing the most and you're putting it on
your PDPs and your emails. This is a
great way to really task a marketing
team, especially if you have people you
feel are under-tasked, to make sure
they're doing actions with things you
already have that can result in better
middle of the funnel, bottom of the
funnel conversion for you. And then the
last is this campaign planning. I have a
whole video on campaigns, so I'm not
going to dive into this deep, but this
is a worksheet based on that. In that
campaign video, I break down how you
need to have a teaser, how you need to
unveil, how you need a lot more content
than you think, I need BTS, how you need
to then sustain your campaign. There's a
whole video on it, but this is a
worksheet you can now use for how to
think about it. And the key topic that I
will tell you here is you need to plan
about internal and external for your
campaigns. Internal, what do you do with
your content team, your email list, etc.
But every good campaign also has
external. Who are you getting involved
in the unveils or creator you can have?
Can you collab on the campaign launch?
Are you seeding that product out? How do
you get media involved? And can you map
that? You should probably have a 50/50
emphasis on where your internal
promotions go and how much external
promotion you can have as well. Doing
this in person was an entire day. We
have It was like basically 4 hours of
workshopping, panels, sitting down in
small groups. I'm not going to give you
the 4-hour version of this, but you have
these worksheets. These are how to use
them. If you are a marketer or creator,
you now have this in your toolkit. Run
this for your brand. It's something you
can expand on in your career. If you
want to learn more about this, learn
more about strategy, or you want to
train people in your brands, we did
bring our new creative strategy program,
very similar to what I do in Cut 30, but
it's for marketing and brand strategy
for marketers who want to become
weapons, brands who want to train their
people on modern. We have brought that
out of beta and we are back running. So
the applications for that are below.
That is something if you are at a more
substantial level in your career you can
tap into. You can grab all these docs
for free down below. Big shout-out to
Air who put on the tour. And we have
lots of images and graphics included
from that as we went through this
YouTube. If you have questions on the
marketing planning process, any of this
below, please drop them and I'll be
happy to answer. And we will be doing
another community call in March where we
can do it live. Thank you all so much
for watching. Appreciate you.