Brands are using memes to make millions.
We always talk about all the normal
kinds of brand content. We need to make
more short form videos. We launch more
carousels. We're doing photo lookbooks.
But rarely do we discuss one of the most
powerful tools on the internet that
shapes the way information moves. And
that is the meme. So in this video, I'm
going to cover brands that are using
memes for their own devices. Talk about
essence. We're going to talk about
Americana Pipe Dream, Reformation, more
interesting approaches like Death the
Stock using it on their own imagery. The
idea of creating something memeable and
Dualingo. We're going to go through the
whole gambit of what that playbook looks
like, why it works, and how brands are
making it happen. It's be unlike any
other marketing video you've probably
seen on YouTube. Let's lock in. So,
first, what do I mean by a meme?
Basically, a collaboration between
images on screen and text to form
something that inherently makes people
relate to it and want to share it. If
you look at almost any communication
between two people or a group of people,
memes are often a part of that. It goes
all the way back to our parents'
generations like forwarding email chains
of jokes to each other who argued that
comic strips may have been the original
meme. I'm not going to get into this now
the memeologist come for me. Really the
idea we could display a concept between
visuals and text often in formats that
are repeatable so people understand the
joke faster and more immediate and that
gets shared between people more than
anything else. And on social networks
because it is shared so much and the
social algorithms weight sharing very
highly in terms of how they feature
content. memes dominate how ideas move
across the internet and brands
participate in this. Essence is one that
I want to call out almost immediately, a
Canadian retailer of fine fashion who
use some of their trademark iconography
and a more typical meme format as one of
the core pillars of their social media.
So, we've all seen the essence
photography. Their photography looks
slightly different than anything else on
the internet. They have their own kind
of unique style that they put to all of
this that makes it definitively essence.
Same thing with how they apply their
text and their brand kit. and they have
brought their brand kit to memeing and
they do this absolutely constantly
online. You woke up and what are you
choosing? Whether it's self-care,
nourishment or chaos and they will put
all the items from essence like inside
these grids and that becomes a more
natural piece of more sharable
interesting content than if they're just
putting out more campaign stuff. Same
thing with establishing a grid and then
putting various Tom Ford forwards on it,
ven diagrams. You will notice they taste
take all these different popular meme
formats and charts and anything you
would normally see and apply their own
brand kit to it. And this is the primary
driver of their social media. They play
into cultural moments with this. They
have a toolkit for how their typography
and things are used. They have a bunch
of these repeatable formats that they
try and that is how their brand has
found success inside social media in a
way it really didn't prior. I want to
throw it out there. There's multiple
ways for brands to actually enact within
this meaning universe. The first is with
something like this. taking all these
popular formats on the internet and
applying your brand kit to it, having
that sense of humor, having it work over
time and pushing it. Talk about
Americana Pipe Dream in a bit who've
done this in an entirely different
niche. The second is taking existing
memes, existing things that are
happening in the culture and co-opting
them for your own purposes where you'll
see things like wjacks, all these
different pieces of internet
iconography, and you'll see brands
basically just using that internet
culture and trying to roll with it. It's
probably the factor I'd recommend the
least, but works really well for
services businesses or people that
aren't too concerned about brand. And
then there's the idea of, hey, can you
take things that are happening in the
world and in pop culture and apply some
of the things that are relevant to your
brand to it in a slightly different way.
So that's where we get Crown Affair,
pretty serious brand. They're taking
things like shots of this woman from
White Lotus, the note about scrunchies
like there are for Crown Affair. They
did this little clown affair drop and
they're integrating these different pop
cultural photos. The goal of a carousel
like this is for every individual item
in the carousel to be shared. They're
saying basically, hey, we're going to
take a shot at having 10 or 12 of these
in here, and we hope that when someone
scrolls through, they one of them is is
right enough that they're going to send
it to one of their friends, which then
increases you in the algorithm. And so,
they're basically taking a lot of pop
culture iconography and applying a
little different than essence, who
basically uses their brand kit and their
products to apply to memes to, but an
effective strategy again, if you have
the humor consideration to be able to
make something that's actually good
enough to do it. All right, so today we
are going to talk about connecting the
marketing experience and adding QR codes
to your marketing toolkit. I've
partnered with Bit.ly for this video, so
huge shout out to them for sponsoring.
I'm here in Wongjo. We just put on a big
event for people in fashion traveling
all over the world here for Canton Fair.
And one of people's favorite things
about it was this invite card. It's in
Full Metal, and it actually features a
scannable QR code where people are able
to RSVP for the event. But today, we're
going to talk about whether it's an
event, your merchandise, or your
product. How do you connect the dots to
the bigger customer journey story? I'm
going to use packaging as an example.
The two things I always encourage brands
to do with packaging is one, optimize
the unboxing. If you have an aesthetic
or interesting unboxing, even if that
gets just shared in a DM or a message
with a friend or ideally share it
online, that is such a huge additional
value you get for any product that you
put out by just getting that word of
mouth. And at the same time, brands
should think about how they connect
after, whether you're adding an
educational video, pro tips on how to
use or style the product. And this can
be solved by QR codes. Think about what
can you link to? How do you make it fun
and easy to attach that customer journey
from purchase to unbox to learning more
about your brand? And what can you
include on the packaging or integrated
into product that's easy to scan and
gives people some real value they want
to pursue. So, Bitly can generate QR
codes like this. And they have a variety
of different looks and styles. You can
customize it to match your brand vibe
from colors to actually how it looks.
And while you can send people to any
site, Billy now has a built-in landing
page builder as well you can use to
easily embed videos, add links, or
create a simple experience all there in
the same dashboard. All with measurement
tools to see what people really engage
with over time to know if you're placing
the code right or have a strong enough
call to action that people actually want
to engage with your brand. You can see
all that within the Bit.ly insights
dashboard where you can manage all of
your codes, landing pages, and
analytics. You can learn more about
Bitly at the link below. And again, big
thanks to them for sponsoring this
video. One of my other favorites from
this is Death to Stock. So they are a
image licensing company. Whenever they
do a photo shoot, they're now kind of
putting out these me'd versions of it as
opposed to just putting out a standard
carousel. And they're doing it and they
have a very particular brand voice which
they are using to execute this same
thing. And since they have kind of
off-the-wall imagery in terms of what
they offer, very well put together for
doing this. But again, this helps them
perform. I've actually watched in their
social, I've done collab videos with
them in the past where they've been
trying to find ways to promote these
collections, right? It'll just be like,
"Hey, kind here's a new collection.
Here's some of the background or here's
whatever." It never does as good as the
more cultural analysis content that they
do. But something like this has a lot of
potential. They're actually getting some
of those likes where they're basically
taking the same imagery they were
showcasing before, just applying this
mimetic format to it. And this is a
great structure for any brand that has
interesting or unique imagery to be able
to again apply that level of cleverness
or cultural resonance to to make the
stuff that you're doing more inherently
sharable. And I love this little gallery
format they're doing. But a brand that's
perfected basically cultural resonance
in general and standing out from
everything like it by having a
personality is Reformation. If you're
not super familiar with Reformation,
they were mainly noted for how unhinged
their emails are. Let's get married as a
subject line. Some stuff wants to go
home with you, espionage, frenemies,
wrong group chat. They're always pushing
the limit in terms of what's going to
get you to open. And I bring that up to
say they've established that brand tone
of voice. So then they brought over into
social media and what happened inside
their account where they're doing all
these same things structuring in that
same format running these type of
carousels where again they're applying
the text on the photo with like 10 or 12
different captions in the hopes of
getting people to share using the pop
culture memes in ways that make sense.
They are applying that toolkit as again
one of the things they have inside their
social strategy. Whereas essence the
social strategy anchors very heavily on
it. This is more of a tool they have
inside their overall toolkit. And on the
far end of this this is the Reddit for
the dualingo bird memes. When you create
something that's already culturally
resonant the way Dolingo has, the memes
come to you. There's a whole another
level of this. But by creating this bird
character that they have, by making it
as culturally relevant in the
conversation as they do absolutely
constantly, it gives things a life of
its own that people choose to create and
communities choose to create. I will
argue that brands can do whatever they
want to push these things forward.
They'll get some level of success with
it. But for anything to truly have
success, it needs to be in the hands of
the internet. The internet needs to be
in controls. You are better off if you
can creating the kind of culture where
memes get created around you versus you
pushing them out there. But since many,
in fact, very few ever will be able to
accomplish that, it's fun to stick to
that core idea of what can we use this
as a format. In the back of your head, I
always have that. Are we building
something that would be inherently
memeable in itself? Brings me to
Americana Pipe Dream. They are a surplus
store, like an Army Navy surplus store.
One of the best accounts on the
internet. They're using memes to talk
about MREs and the stock market crashes.
They're constantly incorporating this
language of the internet inside what
they do. And what they do is talk about
Belgian surplus neck ties, weird warf
facts, Turkish surplus combat pants, all
with their kind of cast of characters.
And their videos are equally unhinged,
but they're able to call out things
people recognize inside this world of
like extreme military and like MRE
enthusiasts like inside their little
cult niche that they're in. This is an
important one to think about. Your brand
isn't a niche. You're like, "Hey, we're
really deep in Japanese car culture.
We're really deep in army navy surplus,
in hunting, in people that like little
snacky snacks, workout culture, whatever
it is." There is a shared language of
jokes and experiences that form the
foundation for what you can make ideas
for. And if that ideas inspire some of
your normal content, great. But if they
inspire memes, that's an easy way to be
able to build a resonance and
understanding and show that you are a
member of the culture. And at this
point, they're actually leading this
now. They've not only shown that they
have this resonance within the community
that cares about this. They are on the
tip of the spear by actually creating
the memes and conversations that then
the rest of their niche plays into. It's
a really interesting account to try out
because if anyone says, "Oh, this
doesn't work for me or my niche." Like
if the guys were sorting through like
old police boots I can figure it out
then you probably can too. But how are
they doing all this? How are people
doing all this so well? So there is this
software called memelord.te. This guy
Jason Leven here has done where he's
created this old school kind of
interface and he actually curates they
have all the hottest memes. All the new
stuff is all here inside this interface.
There's most used there's stuff that
you've liked. So the things that are
happening in culture faster than what we
are like this white lotus thing is
literally from last night. Do you think
you live with no money? he has ready to
go with all the texts and the fonts, the
ability to do the things you would in
this old school kind of '90s interface.
It allows brands to be able to keep up
with everything that's actually
happening, keep up with the formats and
edit these things super quick. I know a
number of people that embrace these
strategies are using software like his
or they have designers that are really
wellversed, especially if you're
applying something like the Essence
brand kit to be able to do it
themselves. So, if you are looking to
actually dive into that, you want to be
able to say what is actually happening
in the meme world, this meme lord.te
stack is the thing to go to for that. So
it's a really interesting thing to think
about is what are these different types
of content that brands can do? Short
form, long form, carousels, tax is a
whole world of that and this plays into
top offunnel content number one and then
resonant content like brand content
number two. Let me break those two
things down before we end the video. So
top offunnel content is something I talk
about a lot and everyone in Cut 30,
which is like my content program, goes
through this is that you need to create
content that gets lots of views because
it helps your other videos get views.
You've all seen this. You're on
Instagram, you see someone's video, you
like it, you interact with it. The
algorithm shows you more of their
content. And you'll see this, too. You
have a banger video pop up, a lot of
your videos around it all start to rise
in views, which means that you need a
strategy to get content to get views.
And guess what? It doesn't always have
to be the most onbrand or resonant or
sales focused content. In fact, it
probably is less likely to work if it is
like that. Sometimes it should just be
something funny. And meme content is an
excellent way to drive that higher level
awareness that then trickles down into
people actually experiencing your more
normal content. And this is just one of
the many tools you have in your arsenal
to do that. But if you are the kind of
person who is funny or culturally
relevant or understands this in general,
incorporate it for your brand or your
personal brand. Then second is
resonance. A lot of people will follow
your brand. They'll know your brand, but
they don't really feel like they have
like a kinship to it, right? No
relationship there. It's just a brand.
But if the brand is continually making
them smile and laugh, and they're
sharing it with their friends, and they
feel like, oh, this brand understands
me, understands this subculture I love.
You're really into kits, hammers,
wrenches. You really are making the
right names and jokes around that guy's
like, god, these guys really know
wrenches. This is my type of brand. That
actually happens. and people feel that
and that resonant content is another
great place where memes can come into
play to do that particularly easily. But
anyway, thank you for watching. This is
a tangent from the normal marketing
content. If you want to check out my
thoughts on some other types of
marketing, I do had a recent video
talking about some of the best marketing
of the year so far that you can come
check out. I am Orin and I appreciate
y'all watching.