We're going to talk about creative
mindset. There's a lot of people on
YouTube, Instagram, Tik Tok that will
talk to you about how to bring your
business to seven figures or how to
build income. But if you're really a
creative person and you want to actually
design things or bring ideas to life,
there's more to it than the tactics and
a lot about how you actually bring
vision to life. And that's what I can
provide best because I've spent most of
my life bringing things into reality, my
own ideas and other people's ideas. And
I have a couple like key mindset
strategies that I'll walk through in
this. I think you all will find super
valuable. So, part of why I think it's
important to talk about this is that a
creative visionary life is kind of a
lonely road. If you're the kind of
person that looks around you and has a
personal vision that you feel you can
bring into reality, if you have ideas
for designs or ideas for creative things
and you're actually attempting to kind
of put your vision out into the world,
there's not a lot of people like that.
There's a lot of people that want to
think that they're that person, but
there's very few that are actually
making the steps to do it. And so, you
start looking around at your friends,
the people you spend time with, and most
of them aren't like that. And that's all
right. Not everyone should be, but you
kind of need those people that are
really pushing you in your life that are
also, hey, I have a hundred ideas and
I'm working on them and I moved them
forward. Because when you have those
relationships one by one together, oh,
you've launched this. Oh, I'm setting
this up. Here's what I'm dealing with.
And you have those text messages and
those conversations, then you're
beginning to really have momentum. And
the only downside of that is that when
you have those relationships, those
people tend to be super busy and
actually getting lost in the sauce of
their own obsession. So, when you do
have them, you kind of hold on, but you
know that sometimes it might be a couple
days before someone gets back to you. I
didn't have those groups for a super
long time. Now I have a ton of friends
that are like this and a lot of them I
made through the internet. And if you're
missing that in your life, you don't
have those people. Like I'm hoping that
what I'm going to do on YouTube is going
to help that cuz I'm going to be showing
a lot of the things I'm making and my
own processes and I can through the
comments or through the conversations
that we have. Try to be some of that
inspiration so that if you are trying to
bring your vision out, we can do it. But
that brings me to the first mindset that
I think is super important and that is
you need to think like a builder. If you
are especially a designer or you want to
be someone that is kind of has your own
clothing line one day or develops your
own product or if you want to be
entrepreneurial with a creative bend,
you need to have this builder mindset.
And what do I mean by that? I mean that
you need to look at everything around
you. You see, every product that comes
up that you're surrounded by, whether
it's a luggage tag or a mug or the cold
brew that's in it, camera lens, whatever
it is, and you need to ask a set of key
questions and train your brain to think
like this with this curiosity angle.
basically go why was this thing created?
That's question one. And in that
question, you think about who made the
decision to do it and why? And then who
is buying it? Whether it was you or
someone else. And you can look at that
from every car model that's out there to
a style of house to a magazine, whatever
it is. Starts getting you thinking about
not only who is this for, but also who
created it. And that ties into the
second piece, which is how was this
made? And this is a super crucial one
for people to understand the world
around them and how it works. I went to
this talk in college and I'm going to
butcher the um actual topic of it and
the related science but my takeaway was
important and it was about analytical
philosophy which the takeaway I had was
the amount of words you know in a
language enables the concepts that
you're able to understand and describe
makes kind of core sense that's a super
super the case for product development
and for creative vision if you
understand how this hoodie was knit you
understand the capability for how you
could actually make a knit hoodie if you
understand how a piece of plastic is
made whether it's injection molding Was
it a hard tool or a soft tool? Whatever
it is, you begin to have this framework
for how could I make it better? How
could I make my own version? We'll get
into versions and vision in this next
mindset. I would ask yourself on
everything you see, okay, this mug is
ceramic. How do you make ceramics? So,
this is a single person. Is it done via
machine? What kind of material is it?
Why would it last? And if you don't have
the answers to those questions, search
for them. Go on YouTube and figure out
how is a ceramic mug made? You know, how
is injection molded plastic work? How do
they make Nerf darts? whatever it is and
begin to relentlessly hunt that down
because then your understanding of this
is going to determine what you're able
to create and bring into the world. Same
thing goes for software. Oh, you was
this written in Python or C++, whatever
the right versions of that is. Is this
architecture on Kubernetes? Are they
hosted on AWS? Whatever it is, find your
framework and the language for bringing
things into the world that you
eventually want to bring in. And I I
would start with a wide swath. I want to
think through everything for how is this
beverage I'm about to drink packed? How
do they get it in the tin can? Why does
it have that form factor? How do they
wrap the label around it? If you are
going through your entire life obsessed
with how things came to be and you are
going to have the framework to then
actually make your own things come to
life. And the last piece of this part of
this builder mindset is how could I make
this better? I take a look at this mug
and I go, how would I make this cooler
or cheaper or more premium? How could I
make this appeal more to a different
customer? If you go through your entire
life and you are looking at almost
everything around you and thinking in
this method, why does it exist? Who put
it together? How was it built? How do I
make it better? You are thinking like a
builder. You are developing a massive
mind state and knowledge base that will
be super useful for how you approach the
world forever. And this ties into the
second part of this which is creative
vision. And if you're watching this,
you're either kind of in one of two
buckets. One is you are more of an
operator or more of a entrepreneur
focused and you don't have as much
creativity and you're trying to figure
out how do you find your own angle or
the second which is more likely because
it's where my followers and viewers end
to fall is you're a creative person
who's trying to figure out the
entrepreneurial side of things. So for
either of those groups, you need to
really define your vision. And it will
be harder for the entrepreneurial people
than it will be for the creative people,
but it's a hard exercise either way. So
what do you mean by my vision? So
there's going to be a set of creative
ideas that define you and who you are.
What do you like to create and why? And
you're going to zero these in over time.
They're going to become your trademark
style. When you think of lots of great
designers or interesting people that you
may mention, whether it's great logo
designers or people who did Bow House,
Emers or Virgil or whoever you might be,
you can start to think about signature
things that they do that represent them
iconography, ideas, materials, etc.
You're going to have to find your own
version of that. Like what is it your
vision that you want to bring to life?
And then when you're going through that
previous exercise of how do I improve
this, it goes from how do I make this
better to how do I put my own spin on
it? And I'd look at this framework if
you're looking for a way to get started.
You can say, "Hey, am I going to be
great at making things more affordable?"
And that's someone from more the
entrepreneurial ben that might be
perfect for you. Or you look at like the
minds behind somewhere like Uniqlo or
people who are saying, "Hey, how do we
take things that would typically be
higher price but then mass-produce them
and keep some level of craft involved?"
You can also say, "How do I make things
more luxury? I want to be a luxury
specialist or I want to have a super
compelling unique designer visual style.
Everything's going to be brutalist." And
you begin to develop your ideas on that
and then apply them to everything. So,
I'm obsessed with this concept. I like
to think that almost everything in my
life I can make a version of with my
ideas. Like the camera I'm looking at
right now, if I was going to be obsessed
with brutalism for the next eight years,
I could be like, man, I'm going to put
that in a concrete frame, hard edges,
it's going to be hard to use, but it's
going to look amazing. And I could do
the same thing with my toaster in the
other room. And I could apply those same
visual principles of the hard edge, the
materials, and maybe some iconography
that I have, and then say, "Hey, I'm
sacrificing usability for aesthetics.
I'm making that part of the vision I
have." That's an example, but that's
what you have to put your DNA together
of is what is the iconography that I use
that could be recognizable and could be
my tropes. And this is something I think
about a lot and I use actually it starts
even with core things like your emojis
on social media. I always use the trophy
and the eagle and the folder as like the
three primary emojis I use for almost
anything. And as I sort of think about
the iconography I have for my brand or
for the things I design, those are going
to be recurring themes. Like trophies
and the eagle is something you already
see in a bunch of my work that's out
there. And it's also a core concept of a
bunch of the things I'm developing. So
you can go everything from your
iconography and how you grow that to the
materials you like and are obsessed with
and use. That could come from your
familiarity or from things you're really
interested in. You could say, I want to
do everything I ever put together. I
want to use crocodile print only the
finest materials. Or you could say
everything I need to do is going to have
a sustainable bend and it's going to be
eco-friendly and I'm going to really
care about what that looks like. Uh, and
I think that building that cannon of
what your vision is from iconography to
materials to purpose to price point and
defining that so you can know who I am,
what do I stand for as a creative and a
visionary is going to be important and
it gets developed the more you go down
your career. But if you have that in the
back of your head that I need to develop
this vision and how I would apply it to
anything from a car to a piece of
clothing to a consumable beverage,
whatever it is, if you are beginning to
find your resonance there and you're
thinking in that angle, it's going to
get you to having a real vision faster.
And that vision is going to get you
recognized for your creative work and
it's going to be able to develop you a
brand that goes on more than just like
your marketing promotion, but on what
you actually create and produce. So now
we have two core concepts. the builder
mind state, always thinking through how
the world around you is created. And
then the second is developing your
visual DNA, your vision. Now, the third
is a mind state around your day-to-day
life. And this one was super important.
So, we can't see a ton around my office
here, but it's filled with tons and tons
of samples of all kinds of things from
acrylic business cards, this leather
jacket that I got from a manufacturer,
hat sample, sweater sample, this knit
I'm wearing, I designed and made. These
pants that I'm wearing are also
something I designed and made. This is a
retail display that's like the mockup
I'm working on for another sample. My
desk here is covered in materials that
I'm working on for a bag. This is
important because this isn't my core
work. I have a day job. I work. It's not
like your average I clock in at 9:00 and
move at 5. It's compelling. It takes a
ton of time. And then all the extra time
I have when I'm not working or with my
family, I'm basically on this obsession
arc of I want to create things. I love
bringing things to life. I love
designing things. And sometimes they are
have a vision. Sometimes they're just
things I think are interesting. And
there's only so much time for that. I
try to make sure I have an hour
dedicated every night to bringing
visions I have to life. And I spend some
other time on content uh on the weekends
and and every day, but really it's like
I have this super set time and I don't
do a lot of things because of that. Goes
back to the concept of this is kind of a
lonely life at least in some parts of it
while you're really building. Because I
don't do as much social things as I used
to. I don't watch any Netflix. I rarely
scroll social media. I mostly only
create on it. And the time I do have, I
am obsessed with making interesting
things that appeal to me and learning
how the world works. But where this mind
state really clicked for me was not just
because I develop things in work that
I've done, but also how easy it is for
you to develop your own things. So a
rule I like to have that this mindset
really changed my entire approach to how
things are made is all around cost. So
for clothing and most things that don't
involve creating a complex mold, so like
things that are made of steel, etc., You
can get a sample for roughly the cost,
maybe a little bit more, maybe a little
bit less of what a premium, but not
ultra premium version of that product
looks like. Let's take this sweater for
example. A sample of getting a sweater
like this is like maybe 50 to 100 bucks
depending on your factory. Uh, actually
buying one of these would probably be
about 100 120 bucks. And you don't want
to just go creating a bunch of samples
of things you're not going to make. But
if you want to validate an idea and
you're going, man, am I going to go
purchase a sweater for myself? Or, hey,
I need to buy this thing that I want.
and you go, man, that is a object I
could be bringing into the world with
that same money. That same $150 I'm
going to go spend on whatever is, oh, I
could actually launch this ceramic mug.
I have an idea for this marble tray,
this water bottle concept, toy or a
game, piece of clothing, whatever it is.
If you start to embrace that philosophy
that all of that money could just be
turned into bringing my idea to life,
and then if you have your idea,
especially in this world, you can
validate it, work on some level of
pre-order. We'll do a separate video on
that. Or begin to get the idea that I
should put more money behind this to
launch it. And then once you actually
start creating things or have a platform
to sell stuff, then really you're just
validating. And the more of those things
you do, the more opportunity you have to
make money, do better, bring your vision
to life. But that's super important
because now like it's so rare for me to
buy anything. I'm blessed in the sense
that like I have a decent audience on
social media, so I get sent a lot of
stuff. Makes that a little bit easier.
But like before that started, I was
still obsessed with this idea that I
should be spending that money on
creating things. And if you have that
same mind state where you go, instead of
buying a hoodie this season, I'm going
to make my own and I'm going to use that
money I would have spent to buy it to
validate a concept that I will then
launch. That's a way to approach life.
And you will go very far doing that. I
know some people who I've had this
conversation with who've taken this like
really far. And this is an area where
I'm really trying to go where it's like,
cool. It's the same thing with a couch
or literally anything in this house. I'd
rather design a toaster than buy a
toaster. And in some cases, that might
be significantly more expensive or take
more time or it's a mockup or a 3D
model, whatever. But if that's your mind
state, if you have this builder mindset,
you have a vision of your creative
ideas, and then you have this kind of
obsession with using your money to put
those visions into the world, then
you're on to something. Then you're
really a creative builder that's ready
for this era. And the last piece of
this, I think it ties a lot of this
together, is having that like obsession
with social media. Um, I've grown a lot
on Instagram and Tik Tok over this last
year and now it gives me a confidence
level. I think that's probably more than
anything what's out there is the
confidence level that that social media
gives you because you can create as many
ideas as you want, but how am I going to
sell it? How am I going to get out
there? All these entrepreneurial things
that seem so hard to go through. Well,
if you have even a small audience on
there, then you start to know, man,
okay, I have at least some people who I
could at least talk to about buying this
thing, which is more than what most
people can say, especially because it's
free to market to them. And then you
start to get more confidence the bigger
that gets. and then you actually sell a
few things on there and you go, "Oh man,
I can this is going better than I
thought or worse than I thought and how
do I adjust and pick that up?" But it's
not just the confidence of having that
audience. It's the confidence of knowing
how social media works and knowing that
because you spend time on it and because
you've learned it as things change or as
you reconfigure, you know, your plan or
launch a new business, you know, I know
how to build a following. I know how to
get attention. And if you can understand
those two things and you have that
hacked in your mind where you're like, I
am good at this, then the world is
really your oyster right now. So anyway,
my goal with these kind of series is to
really inspire anyone who's trying to
lead these creative lives or trying to
build things and doesn't have that like
friend group that pushes them around or
cops them forward. I want to give all
that energy to you and I'm hoping in
return I can get all those questions
that you have and all the energy that
you're bringing of your ideas coming
back to me in a great cycle that's
interesting. One of the best things I
found from social media is I become
friends with a hundred people I've never
known before who just like to send me
ideas because they don't have a friend
to send ideas to or send that cool
visual thing they saw because for some
reason their friend group or their
girlfriends or whoever it is don't have
that person. And I'm happy to be that
person. I love getting inspiration all
the time. And I think there's a lot of
people out there like that. And I'm
hoping that we can link in the comments,
link in the DMs, people can find each
other through that and we can put some
of that positive creative energy out
there in the world because I think we
have plenty of people that are doing a
lot of this just to get rich. I think
there are not nearly enough people who
are trying to create a either purposeful
or aesthetic or ideally both vision that
they're putting out in the world that
they absolutely love and the energy from
is super strong. If you have any
questions at all about any of this
process or anyone we hit these videos,
drop them in the comments.