This is how to make killer social
content for boring businesses. Time and
time again, whether it's people that are
in Cut 30, brands I talk to online, or
people that are starting a personal
brand, they're always saying, "Oh, well,
I'm an accountant. I'm a dentist. I have
a massage business. We make candles. How
could we possibly make interesting
social content?" And this is absolutely
the wrong mentality because there are
dozens of ways with which you can make
amazing, captivating content about the
most boring things. and we're going to
break down those strategies inside of
this video. I'm going to talk about how
to use exciting scenarios, how to put
strong takes out there that establish
personality, how to incorporate viral
vehicles, taking an education ccentric
approach, really leaning into lore and
depth inside of a niche, and using
things like formats and speed to stand
out. It'll be a fun video no matter what
your brand is or what you do. If you're
interested in making awesome social
content, there will be a lot to learn
throughout. Let's lock in. So, first I'm
going to start off by just rattling
through a number of ideas. I know can
work for businesses that want to make
content that stand out in the internet.
And the first is what I call a format
shakeup. You don't have to reinvent the
wheel when you want to make something
successful. So you could take the hot
ones format. Everyone knows it. You are
eating spicy chicken wings while
answering questions and you could do
that legal edition. Hot law came off the
top of my head. Sometimes sometimes you
win, but literally with legal questions.
Talk to people about why they shouldn't
have a beware of dog sign while engaging
in a experience similar to Hot Ones. But
there are hundreds of format shakeups
you can do that inherently are going to
make even something that might not be
the most interesting thing more
captivating to watch. The second tool I
think is really interesting is speed.
We've all seen normal real estate tour.
If you did the same thing in 10 seconds,
a speedrun of showing an apartment,
you're playing to the algorithm
strengths because it likes faster
content. But there's always the element
of can you do something people
understand faster than they're used to
it and make it an event that you are
doing it faster. That's why you'll see
things like 30 second makeup, one minute
recipes. Time is a vehicle. Speaking of
vehicles, I want to talk about the idea
of viral vehicles. And I don't mean
cars. I mean objects and things that you
can buy or build into your business that
will help guarantee you virality. For
instance, if you are a toy store and you
had a hydraulic press, all of a sudden
you were one of the more interesting toy
stores on the internet. Those videos do
super well. Naturally, people are used
to what they see and you're just
applying it to a different thing. And
that investment is likely worth it. If
you were to say, "Hey, we're going to
spend thousands of dollars on getting
not the hugest hydraulic press, but
something that works for our videos or
whatever that viral vehicle is." And
you'll see people who rent really nice
apartments for this or shoot everything
with a vintage car or whatever it is,
those are all expenditures that help
guarantee them virality. But if you did
that for your toy store or whatever
brand it was, the result in terms of the
views you're going to get on social
media, the notoriety, the being known
for being the toy store that has the
hydraulic press. These are the kind of
hacks you can look at and say, "Hey,
maybe I don't want to invest tons of
money every month in complex shoots, but
I want to invest in that one thing that
I know every time is going to help hit
and go viral." And one more quick
technique before I get into the middle
of this video and the big bulk of like
the longer tactics is the this is
amazing approach or using your skills
for good. But how can you do something
with that skill set that people go,
"This is amazing." When they look at the
content, for instance, if you were a
copywriting agency that was bringing
romance novels to life in 15-second
videos, all of a sudden, you're a super
interesting copywriting agency. All of a
sudden, you're showing your skills in a
way that is immediately applicable and
viral to others. And it's interesting, I
am built to think like this because I
workshop with hundreds of people in
brands every month inside Cut 30 and I
do this strategy constantly with major
brands. I'm thinking always in terms of
what's the angle. I know not everyone
thinks like that. So, I'm going to try
something new on this video where I want
you to comment your business. If you
have something you're like, I cannot for
the life of me figure out what I would
do with X or Y. Drop it below and I will
workshop in the comments throughout it
and we will see what ideas that we can
come up with. I promise I will try to
hit all of them. You know, when you're
running a creative studio, putting out
seven short form videos a week plus a
YouTube every week on top of managing
brand and client deliverables, you
really start to notice where your
systems and your process slow you down.
That's why Dropbox has been such a core
part of my workflow and why I was so
excited when they reached out to sponsor
this video. Whether I'm uploading
footage from a trip or a shoot or
reviewing a lookbook PDF with my team,
Dropbox keeps everything moving and
organized without a million apps or
unnecessary back and forth. So, when I
wrap filming, I head straight into my
team's shared Dropbox folder. From
there, my team of editors, my designers,
my management can pick it up based on
our shared calendar. Everyone's working
off the same structure synced in real
time here and overseas. Then I love that
I can literally mark up a PDF on my iPad
during a flight, annotate images and do
approval in one place versus a bunch of
systems. Pro tip, we use this to
actually mark if people have used
footage or not in the folders. And also
if something might make a great hook
shot, so I can easily go through folders
and a bunch of hook shots are already
identified. But maybe the most
underrated part is that we have years of
project files, and I mean years.
Everything from firstgen product mockups
to Tik Tok drafts from 2023, and it's
all in Dropbox. And Dropbox Dash uses AI
to help us find documents, images, and
videos across the entire library of
files that are less organized than I'd
like. You don't have to remember the
exact file name, and Dash can help you
find the content you need. So, if you're
managing a growing content pipeline or
just want your creative projects to run
smoother without the chaos, check out
the full features of Dropbox and see how
it can help your team push creative
limits, not deadlines. Now, let's dive
into the meat. Establishing personality
for your brand is going to be the first
one. The biggest thing that I think any
boring business can take advantage of is
leveraging exciting scenarios. So for
instance, if I were a CPA or I was an
accountant and I was trying to make
content, I would be starting with the
Brabbis G63. I would be starting with
the G Wagon. Break down the tax savings
if someone were to purchase a vehicle
like that. Show the thresholds of how
much money should you be making to
consider having it be worth it to buy
the G Wagon. Explain the differences
state-to-state. Similarly, if there's a
big trade that happens in the NBA and
someone moves from Canada to Houston or
New York to Houston, there's a tax
benefit of moving to Texas based on the
salary, break that down. Give your
expertise in context of exciting things
because the hook isn't how do I use
bonus depreciation for my business. The
hook is Gwagon then bonus depreciation,
tax difference between states like and
what does that implication look like?
you can put your expertise in context of
exciting scenarios and there is
basically no limit to how many of those
scenarios like exist and those scenarios
happen in real estate. There's obviously
all kinds of either weird homes or
expensive homes or controversial
neighborhoods or places where news
happens or famous people are from that
you can use and there is such a benefit
to just showing your expertise in
context is something that actually makes
people stop scrolling and if you follow
that formula is really hard to lose in
terms of making content. Same thing
happens if you develop really strong
takes about your niche. I want to shout
out Lauren Crease. He's the current CEO
of a furniture company and he makes
interior design videos online that are
just hammering hot takes. He'll be like,
"If you use this gray, I would never
speak to you again in my life." You
know, you are disowned for using kitchen
tile of this type. But he makes these
videos where he has his very strong
opinions as someone who is in interior
design, who produces furniture, and has
proven to be a notoriety gainer for his
pretty traditional furniture business.
But it's not just about putting content
out there that's educational or simple.
The power of his content is that he is
brave enough to have really strong
opinion, which is something we've lost
in the internet a lot along the way.
Everyone wants to be everyone's friend.
People don't want to be too negative or
too this way or that way, but we
actually need people who are barometers
to say, "I think this is good. I think
this is bad. I have credibility and
here's why." And you may disagree with
them or agree with them, but that recipe
for attention and the comments that come
from it and people discussing it and
people beginning to say, "Hey, I like
that guy or that girl's point of view is
super powerful." And this works for
everything. If you're like, "You should
never shoot on a Nikon camera ever
again," that video is going to do much
better than here's the new Sony A7,
whatever. Boring. But put your service
in context of recent events. Very
similar to the Gwagon attention
hijacking, putting a business in terms
of current events, something almost
every business can do, no matter how
boring it is. So, for instance, as a
therapist, here's my analysis of the
Secret Lives of Mormon wives, breaking
down the different characters and why.
Again, appealing to some kind of fandom
or a therapist going through the
different characters in succession. I
saw this recently where it was a a
lawyer who was actually leading off with
rap lyrics for like 3 seconds and then
breaking down what they would have meant
in court if you were to try and position
it to be not someone committing a crime.
But again, you take these things that
are happening in pop culture in the news
and you put your spin on it. As a
psychologist, I think as a massage
artist, here's the massage that I feel
that this person should get while
they're in China negotiating whatever
because you it shows your expertise of
knowing all these different things
around the world. recommendations you
have as an expert as pertains to people
out there. And we saw this trend really
take off in a really light format with
uh baristas and coffee shops where a
bunch of videos went viral where it was
someone being like, "Hey, if Lana Del
Rey came in, here's the coffee I would
make her." And it was like a, you know,
like a Pepsi latte or whatever it is
like this, but like having some sort of
fun or interesting vehicle that goes
with that. But this applies to almost
any business. Again, you are attention
hijacking. You are taking something
people already know and like and
applying your expertise to it. And that
has a surefire recipe for success that I
cannot say enough. When you look at the
kind of content I've done to get
hundreds of thousands, damn near million
followers, a good amount of it was being
my hot takes on brands, my responses as
a marketer to what I would have done
differently, not just what happened, but
what I would have done or what I think
from a marketing perspective should be
better about a campaign or a thing that
happened. Now, we're going to get to
education. There's always room for
education in the market. But a lot of
people kind of get wrong about this is
they make the education very
straightforward. They make it almost
dull, but it has to really have some
oomph to it. And one of the things that
I like to really focus on is questions
that people feel dumb asking that you
answer for them because there's a lot of
people that go throughout the world.
Acting like they know what's going on
but really don't. And giving education
to those people is a great way to start
and get an initial feedback. And the
second thing is education in a more
competitive format. One of the things I
always talk about in Cut 30, we've had
some a couple people blow up on one is
an education creator. Great example of
boring content. He it's a it's the
format's called a versus format where
you say blank versus blank. You're going
to compare two things. I would do this
in my series product versus brand. Are
you buying the product? Are you buying
the brand? This educator did it and it
was is this education or is this
edutainment? Are you just doing this
pretending it's education but it's
actually just a game? And you break down
a bunch of popular things and give your
take on that versus format. This is this
this is that and here's why. In this
video for an educator with a relatively
dry approach blew up because it is a
important thing for people to say I'm
learning. This is what I should use for
my kid or do in this education process.
Here's why a pro thinks like this and
here's an approach to a topic that makes
me interested to watch more and watch
through it. So, I always look at
educational content. You want to have a
lens. You want to be able to say, "Hey,
I'm going to answer the questions that
people feel too dumb to ask." Or you
want to say, "I'm going to put
everything in context. I'm going to
break it down between these kind of two
items. I'm going to make sure I have the
ability to help people discern and what
I educate." And this ties into the last
like big bucket I'm going to talk about
here. And that is lore and depth.
Because I think what people
underestimate is how if you are
extremely into something and you want to
be the most into it person out there and
you're going to get in deep into the
inside jokes and the lore and the
history of things, how many other people
there are out there who are just as
passionate or who would become as
passionate from it. So I like to use
Americana Pipe Dream. I brought them up
in my meme video, but these are a great
example of they sell army surplus. There
are plenty army surplus stores out there
that don't have any social media worth
recognizing, whereas their social media
is massive because they are obviously
gigantic war history nerds. They will
talk to you about the German Fauler
airplane, about what camo the Swedes
switched to in 1962. They'll not only
talk about it and educate about it, but
they'll literally make memes about it
and jokes about it. For the other people
that care that much, who had all the
model armies when they were growing up
as kids, they are going all the way in
and you can enter that world. And if
you're a little interested, you can
learn way more and all of a sudden, you
know, the eight types of Danish sniper
rifles, whatever it is, that are able to
come up from that there. And this
applies not just to something like army
surplus because people even will look at
that and be like, "Well, that's
exciting." Yeah, guess what? Most people
would be like, "How do I make content
about my army surplus business?" They
made it exciting. Most people can't make
that jump. This is more to my point of
there is no such thing as a boring
business. Only boring content. They're a
perfect example because you would look
at army surplus and be like, "This is
boring." Until someone made it exciting.
This applies to anything. Uh my friend
Ashman had a hook the other day where he
went to a dermatologist conference cuz
he's got a skin brand and he was like,
"I went to the Coachella of
dermatologists." That's a great hook cuz
right, we all go to these events. I go
to these events where I make viral
videos and it's like, "I went to the
fashion show with the most exotic
materials in the world." Like, of
course, that's exciting. When you're
going to a dermatology conference,
you're like, "How can that be exciting?"
It's like, "Hey, it's the Coachella of
dermatologist." Because they find it
exciting because X and Y, here's the
things that they love about it, you're
treating it with that level of
excitement and you're nerding out on it
to that extent. And if you try to be
like the most in-depth nerd out account
about this, whatever that ends up being,
again, massage, beverage, co-packing,
construction, roof work, whatever it is,
be the most knowledgeable and in-depth
about that, and then treating it with
fun and nerd and fandom and mimedics
around that can really get you a long
way. A few parting shots. Uh, one I want
to talk about a social media campaign
I've worked pretty in-depth on that I
thought was really interesting that ties
into this. Before that I want to talk a
bit about doing normal content with a
interesting approach. I was talking to
someone with a roofing business about
this the other day. I'm like, "Hey, you
can actually give roofing tips. You can
do basic roofing video, but if you do it
on a ladder, it's inherently more
interesting." One thing makes your
content more interesting. That's why you
see a lot of videos will like shoot from
a single angle. There's all it takes is
that one thing hydraulic press doing it
from a ladder where you can do normal
content and add on to it. But if you
don't have that one thing, it's probably
why the content's failing. But I want to
give a good example of uh some of the
work I've done advising my manufacturer
who I work with Crease Group where
they're look they're a manufacturer a
factory of clothes. There's people who
make good content with that. There's
thousands of people that don't. Yahoo
works for them went through cut 30.
We've worked on strategy. We've done
collab videos together. We spent a lot
of time together. We worked closely.
It's kind of natural. Is like hey the
goal isn't to be like here's our
manufacturing business. Here's how it
works. Here's what you can buy from us.
Cool. That's one part of the content.
The goal is to be like we are tour
guides to the hidden exotic world you
have never seen of Wong Joe of the place
where fabric happens where people make
product. and now expanding that as the
world changes. They're exploring Ho Chi
Min, going to Vietnam, going to these
different trade shows in other parts of
China. But like literally the job is to
enter people into this world they did
not know exist and be the tour guides of
it. And guess what? That is extremely
viral. And then you become the people
when anyone is interested or at that
stage in the company where they want to
go into and have that experience. You
are the people who know the most who go
to the places. If you're actually going
there to visit somebody, you're the
people to call. And that shift in
mentality from sell our thing to sell
access to this world that no one knows
about is the reason why they have 10
times as many followers, 15, 100 times
as any of the competitive people within
that basis. I like to look at that too.
If you have a world, whether that's the
world of the area around you or the
industry that you're in, you can
position as a secret, as something that
you're able to shed access to. No one's
ever seen, especially for international
companies, maybe never. You're from
Lithuania. No one even knows what to do
there. And you can share the intricacies
and interesting nature of that as part
of your content pillars. It's a really
unique way to think about what you make.
I will end by saying one of my favorite
phrases again. There is no such thing as
a boring business, only boring content.
So, there's a whole wealth of tools
within this video that you can use to
help move that whether you're a personal
brand or an expert, whether you actually
have a brand in one of these niches. If
you want to work with me on content at
any point, you can look at cut30.co for
when our next session is. I will link
here some of the many other videos I
have breaking down different social
strategies and approaches from
everything from carousels to treating
your social media like a TV show. And
you can learn more and go as deep as you
want. I have a whole playlist on social
media marketing. As always, I appreciate
y'all watching. Comment your businesses
below. If you do want me to workshop any
of the things you have and try to come
up with an interesting angle for it, I
will be doing that in the comments.
Thank you all so much.