Today, we're going to talk about how
this is potentially the last summer to
lock in and the skills and approach you
have to not be caught in the
quote-unquote creative underclass. If
you want to be a true one-person
marketing army for your business or
another business, how exactly to do it.
This is a bit of a different video for
me. You usually don't hear me with any
degree of fear in terms of how I talk
about branding, marketing, social media,
but we are in a pretty strange time
currently. But also, I want to have you
take tactical takeaways from this that
are super useful. This will be the first
time that we've brought the whiteboard
out. I've got the overhead rig. When we
actually map out tactics for you here
today, we're going to do this all on the
whiteboard and give you an exact
blueprint for efficiency in marketing,
entrepreneurship, and creative work.
Let's lock in. So, first of all, you may
have noticed online on social media,
there is a trend happening right now.
And a lot of it was sparked by Steven
Bartlett, rather notoriously saying that
if he had a glass of wine, because of
how optimized he is, he would be thrown
off for like 3 days. And so, a lot of
creators and people hopped on this and
mocked this, rightfully so, ridiculous
statement. And it led to this big bent
you're seeing in relatively viral
content about anti-optimization.
While that podcast clip may have been
the catalyst, this actually happens
every single year. Around mid-May to
mid-June, you will notice content starts
to tank, especially if you make serious
content, content with business value,
content you're promoting your stuff,
trying to make sales. LinkedIn,
Instagram, even YouTube, numbers start
to go down. And this is because it
starts to get warm outside, people have
Memorial Day, they start thinking about
summer vacations, some offices start
summer Fridays, and the desire to work
drops. But because of social media and
the way algorithms work, this also
becomes a pretty massive psyop. So,
you'll notice a lot of like media elite
influencers, like New York influencers,
people with substacks, people that
pontificate a lot, immediately hopped on
this trend. They started making videos
about how optimization is killing us,
how you should feel free to have a
couple drinks, don't take things too
seriously. But, they're not saying that
cuz they believe it. They're saying it
because it works in the social media
algorithms. Every summer, if you make
what we call excuse content, you get a
massive spike. And so, it makes sense
they'd all shift to this. But, then it
makes you feel. You start getting these
messages subconsciously in your feed
constantly that yeah, you know what? I
should take some time off. I do need
more work-life balance. Whatever it is,
which honestly is totally fine as a
message for most people most of the
time. But, in my opinion, not
particularly right now. So, last summer
was one of the most unproductive summers
of all time for almost everyone I knew.
Euro summer was in full effect. People
were vacationing. Offices were closing
early. People were really embracing
life. And what was interesting about
that, and uh I was talking about this at
the conference I spoke at the other week
in London. I was meeting with a lot of
friends of mine who have brands or work
at brands, is what that summer
productivity falloff. But, what's
interesting is this is going into year
five of this. You basically had 2022,
23, 24, 25, and now 26. All post-COVID
reaction. Where naturally as people have
been locked inside and frustrated with
the world around them, they want to be
outside more doing more things. But, the
first few years is a reaction. Five
years is a habit. And the hard part
about this is it now comes at this time
of what we'll call AI job loss. Where
brands are cutting 18% of their
workforce, 9%, 10%, 20%. And they're
using AI as the scapegoat. The CEOs of
these AI companies have made that very
easy. It is inescapable to not go on TV
or read the news and see Dario or
somebody basically saying that the
white-collar job class is going to be
disintegrated by AI. They are preaching
that themselves, which is a bad comm
strategy, at least to the consumer. But,
really what it's done is given these
leaders an excuse to right-size their
orgs. Everyone who says this is about
cutting jobs due to AI, it's not. Those
orgs are not seeing that uplift in
value. I can almost guarantee that if
you work inside of a company that's
adopting AI, you've not seen that
increase in value. Sure, maybe there's
this or that, but it's not 20% of your
workforce. What they're doing is they've
realized that culturally over the last
few years, a lot of these businesses
have adopted processes, management
layers, hiring practices, efficiency,
and guidelines that's made them
radically inefficient. And they are
doing whatever excuse they can to
right-size the ship while everyone else
is doing it, which leads to a flood of
people in the job market. And it's a
flood of people that are all used to
that kind of job, who are expecting when
they get a new job, it's going to be
similar to their old one and the
expectations, but those expectations are
shifting. Because you've noticed every
time you see companies get disrupted by
a new generation of companies, they have
an efficiency. So, for instance, when I
started making content 4 or 5 years ago,
all of this new wave of brands was
coming about that had discovered that
they could source products from overseas
just as good as these bigger brands. And
Alibaba enabled this, social media let
them reach them directly, meta ads
worked fine. They could literally with a
much smaller org and less investment
create something on par to a major brand
at a similar price point. And a whole
generation of brands were created this
way over these last few years. Now, a
lot of those brands to succeed built out
relatively decent size teams. And what
you're seeing now is you're seeing these
ultra lean teams do the same thing. Some
degree because of AI, but some degree
also because people are relentlessly
focused on the metrics that determine
success. And so you've seen a new
generation of brands, products,
services, etc. that are really lean
teams that work very hard but are very
efficient in their work displacing those
previous 5 years of brand. And this is
because that overspend era is done. What
entrepreneurs are realizing is that all
these big bloated companies that have
their technical and process debt. So,
what that means is that if you have been
investing in all these systems you spent
all this money on, but they're not as
good as new systems, or you built out
all these people and situations, but
it's not as efficient as what a new
company could do to start it, that is a
debt that companies have to recover
from. They are going to every day
execute on these antiquated processes
and technologies that are going to lead
them to perform less efficiently. And
for anyone new to succeed, they have to
be against that. They are against this
overspend era. And you multiply all this
together, how many people are applying
for jobs? How many of these new
companies are now relentlessly focused
on efficiency and old companies are
trying to right-size. And then this
widening gap between the chillers and
the hitters, people that put in a lot of
work wherever they are, who know all
these new skills that I'm going to talk
about here, that have embraced whatever
technology, that know how to be
efficient and drive results and money
inside wherever they work, whether
that's a marketer, a creator, a
salesperson, a creative, engineer,
whatever it is. And with now more and
more AI being used by HR to sort through
resumes, it's going to be ultra
competitive to get whatever jobs there
are. You've heard me talk a lot about
over the last few years how you could
differentiate yourself by being a
creator, establishing a personal brand
on LinkedIn, on Instagram, et cetera.
And if you've done that over the last
few years, you're reaping those benefits
right now because you are able to
circumvent those lines. But if you're
new and you're starting right now, what
you'll notice is in the last like 60
days, a lot of the gurus who preach
content creation have switched
everything to a Claude will solve your
problems for you approach. Write
everything with AI. And we've seen this
flood now of these AI creators that all
sound alike, all the content looks
relatively the same, everything on
LinkedIn kind of sounds the same, and it
performs at this like mid baseline
standard where it doesn't ever break
out, but it fills up, it clutters
everything with noise. And you'll see I
have a pretty strong reaction. It's
probably a separate video I have about
how I don't think you should be using a
lot of those tools for your personal
brand. But it now closes the window.
We've talked about how long do we have
before personal brand matters or not?
And now I think we are hitting this top
of the bell curve, right? Where you sort
of have, you're getting into that arc.
We're entering into a timeline where you
still have efficacy to start. And if you
started, how you cement yourself as
someone who belongs versus falling off.
And all of that plays into this summer
cuz because this becomes one of the last
time periods to make it into content
creation before saturation. If you are
already doing that, to gas pedal it
before that saturation, to make sure you
don't kind of fall off in this mid-level
rises, to not fall into the back end of
the technology and processes making
these companies win right now. And then
if you do have a brand or you're trying
to hit your numbers for this year, Q4
starts now. If you want to execute your
T5, uh your your Black Friday to Cyber
Monday timing. You want to order the
right products, have everything in, have
your promotions there, have your
campaigns laid out. If you want to nail
the rest of the year, that is a summer
exercise. If you start it end of
September, when everyone's back in the
office and fully working in the right
way, you're too late. And I want to put
that out there cuz to me that signals
that this is one of the last summers to
lock in before this becomes really,
really, really, really hard. And no one
wants to hear that. They want the excuse
content, right? You want to know you can
check out. And that's fine. Depending on
whose life you lead, what you want out
of life, you do it however you like. But
if you want to lock in right now, I want
to explain this one-person marketing org
that's such a popular concept. Break
down an exact format, what you need to
know, and how you would need to operate
to be effective in 2026. So to go
through that, I'm going to bring the
whiteboard out. We are going to talk
through this is any business. I know a
lot of my videos focus on product
businesses, but I'm going to talk about
this from the lens of services
businesses, B2B, software, product, any
org. We're going to talk through
establishing your product and process to
be successful for word of mouth and
referral. We're going to talk about
messages, scaling information release,
developing new creative, performance
marketing, email and CRM, influencer,
and structuring your week as a small org
or single person to effectively execute
on all this. Probably one of my favorite
videos I've I've put together. Cuz I've
done this a bunch, right? I still
operate all the marketing at our women's
work clothing brand on the side of all
the other stuff I'm doing in a few very,
very deliberate hours a week. And I've
done that now for six, seven years as
that scaled into a multi-million dollar
business. I've been the first marketing
hire at a lot of companies. And then now
when I go do these conversations that I
have at conferences or come in with
brands, a lot of it is around how do we
structure our marketing org for the
modern world. And if you guys like this
video, I will follow up on one of how
you scale a team. For now, we're going
to focus on what does a lean operative
look like. If you want to chat about any
of this, the next community call is
going to be linked below where we'll do
a workshopping, live Q&A, and I'll talk
about some of my specific thoughts on
what operators look like. I'm going to
pull out the whiteboard. Let's get into
it. All right, so let's talk about what
does one person do in your business? And
you might be that person or another
business to be relentlessly effective at
generating leads, sales, customers
through marketing. So, the first thing
that matters most is word of mouth and
referral. If you're already selling
something, how do you optimize it to get
the most out of your existing customers
before we talk about any other channels?
Building with virality. So, this starts
before anything else happens. So, there
are a couple types of things that happen
here that are worth understanding. First
is when someone uses your product, do
they have to share it? Like Zoom, for
instance, has an inherent virality
because every time you use it, someone
else is forced to use it. The second
thing is is the person that uses it, is
it a billboard for them? So, for
instance, that would be clothes. If you
make their website, you make their logo,
they're showing something off that they
might be asked about. That could be a
referral scenario for them. So, any
billboard product is you absolutely need
to build it in. And for a billboard on
clothing, for instance, that can be as
simple as whether or not you have logos
visible and people care or not. If your
user is excited enough to be able to
share it, if they do share it, do they
have an incentive? Then there's just a
user obsessed about it, do they love it?
So, Clod's virality and growth, right? A
lot succeeds because so many other
people are interested in using Clod. The
users talk about it. Even when they
don't do anything efficient, they love
to talk about how efficient they're
being. Then is it in their content
cycle? So, for instance, with cosmetic
products, are they doing get ready with
me's? If you are a local shop or a cafe,
people getting the matcha and then
taking a photo of it. Now, how do you
optimize for that, right? You're more
likely to be in their content cycle with
cooler looking packaging, that unique
looking drink. If someone shows up to do
your plumbing and it has the wild
looking van, whatever it is, you're more
likely to be inside the content cycle.
So, you got to think about where does
your business live in this? Again, this
is prep for we even get into what
marketing looks like and then how do you
engineer the best possible solution
there? And then you layer on logistics.
So, for product sales, software sales,
what can you offer as an affiliate where
you give them a reward or a percentage
for promoting your products? You will
see a lot of people do this at checkout.
So, they will use something like Social
Snowball to basically offer to customers
in checkout and in the emails after
checkout to help support their products
and get percentages back. And businesses
like Grooons grew a lot on top of this.
It's just worth having that set up from
the beginning so that your sales will
having other compound sales and
establishing a percentage and a basic
program. And then for any services
business, etc. Where do you get
referrals? Can you make that easy? Can
you encourage it? Can you say, "Yeah,
we're going to give you a free month of
maintenance for any customer that comes
over?" What incentive do you have? And
then where do you ask for it? And the
biggest part for a lot of services
businesses is to build in when you
complete the project and they're happy
with it, are you able to ask right then?
Do you follow up once a quarter and ask
for any referrals? Do you send them a
gift when you do it? That is a process
that the marketing person needs to build
out almost immediately because if you
are not doing that, you are missing your
basically highest conversion level
customer that does not have a big
customer acquisition cost or CAC. So,
this is before anything. Now, when you
actually get into monthly, what should
you be doing every month as a marketing
person? So, the first thing I like to
focus on is messages. So, this is how
are you communicating the value
proposition of what you sell and is it
changing? So, at first you have your
value to your customer. So, for
instance, we talked about in my former
offers video about creative work.
Basically, any service businesses, you
are either going to be better, you are
going to be faster, or you are going to
be cheaper. So, it's thinking about
where do you live inside that cycle. If
you sell clothing, is it stylish to a
particular niche? Does it last longer?
Does it fit a certain body type? Is it
preparing someone for a certain cultural
event? What is the value you are giving
them? What are new messages that you can
test inside the cycle of your marketing?
And you need to look at this every month
because you'll start to notice trending
messages work. So, one note on this, if
you've watched the video on HubSpot's
channel that I do with Cody from
Allegiate Gym, who's had some great
success, we basically workshopped his
funnel on a in a very similar position
to this and he put ads in place about it
and he saw some of the stars actually
get real customer acquisition going for
his business. He had talked about how a
lot of people coming to his gym were
starting to ask questions about peptides
and GLP-1s and they didn't know how to
solve it. And he we basically decided,
"Hey, that's just worth introducing as a
messaging angle. Our gym can help you
from a professional level walk through
the right workouts to do if you are
experimenting with these new things in
fitness. Excellent example of a trending
value prop. In other word, I mentioned
the women's wear brand that I'm a
partner on and have worked on for years.
Festival season murders it for us. We
have a whole separate marketing and
sections just around festival and
dressing for festival. Coachella,
Stagecoach, EDC, etc. So, that is
example of a trending message. Same
thing if you are in electronics and
there was just like a big trade show or
release or people are planning summer
back to school or end of year budgets.
What is trending? You need to think
about those things happening this month
and these messages are going to play
into the rest of your marketing. So,
that that monthly meeting it can be you
with a client, you have a client, it
could be you and your business just a
brainstorm and your marketing team. And
then you are going to make sure by
reviewing customer support questions,
social media comments, competition. You
can use tools like Perplexity to kind of
go go through aggregate some of this or
you can just go down the lists and look
at it. What has come up that's
objections inside the sales process? You
can talk to the sales team, etc. These
are now all messages. Now, you have to
deploy those messages. So, the other
part of this is you need from those
messages to get into your info release
mechanism of this. Because you are going
to have a bunch of information and
answers and ideas from this and you need
to actually make a plan to release them.
So, this means adding more content to
your website. Can you have articles,
etc. that you go live on there? Email,
are you sending out emails to your
customers? I would suggest sending more
plain text stuff, whether that's from a
founder or whatever it is. You can
actually get into some of these topics.
You use that in the sales process, have
template emails for sales people if
you're converting on a service or a high
ticket thing. Reddit, if there are
subreddits to talk about this, you have
a Reddit for your company. That gets
aggregated quite a bit by actual AI
tools to answer questions. It's a useful
one to go on. YouTube, can you sit down
and yap about common questions? Cuz
another one that gets aggregated in AI.
And then adding that information to your
landing pages, which we'll get to in a
second. But basically anyone people go
to actually view your product and buy
it, can you layer on these items to
those either in part of the main or as a
test. So, this is that big kind of
monthly planning here. So, we'll look at
pre before you start doing any other
marketing, you will look at your kind of
monthly gander. Now, let's look at what
an actual week looks like for a
marketing operator. So, I firmly believe
that for most brands there's a
considerable upside in output for the
amount of landing pages, articles, ad
copy, SEO stuff for the blog, and sales
collateral for the sales team using AI
to basically help them with the copy and
scaling the copy. But, they need to do
with a strategic framework versus just
pasting the idea and then asking for a
version. So, I partnered with HubSpot to
put together a free guide. This is my
guide with them. It's called Teach AI
your brand voice. It's a complete guide
to building a copy machine in your brand
voice in your favorite LLM. So, inside
it we cover dialing in your voice based
on your actual customer experience using
personas cuz you want to make sure your
copy is actually relevant. We have a
whole segment on that. We talk about
providing LLMs with copywriting
frameworks. This is important. From
established marketing copywriters and
styles, things like direct response. It
will improve your copy versus just
saving you time. It will actually make
it so it's built for marketing
conversion. You can test different
voices and styles. And then tips and
tricks for reviewing this and deploying
this and not looking foolish. My
favorite part is the brand voice project
template. It's a complete system prompt
that sets up Claude or ChatGPT within a
project as your in-house kind of
strategist copywriter for this. You drop
in your brand context, your personas,
pick voice references, and it can write
home page copy, ads, emails, landing
page scripts, collateral, and more. All
in your brand voice ready for you to
review with the process we have there
and ship and take advantage of this
framework I've outlined here. So, if you
want to build a second brain for your
marketing team, knows your brand voice,
knows your personas, and can actually
help with outperforming copy, it's an
excellent free download for you and the
first time I've collaborated with
HubSpot on something like this. You can
get it for free from the link below. And
thank you so much to HubSpot for
partnering on this video and working
with me to put this together. I want to
talk about the legend of the Claude
operator for a second cuz there was a
whole myth not even a myth, there's a
whole kind of story going around how one
person ran the majority of Claude's
performance marketing if not all of it
for a long time as the business scaled
into billions. And people kind of
laughed at it, oh they have an
influencer team or they have agencies or
whatever. But, at the end of the day,
there's a lot of truth to one really
effective person monitoring this stuff
even at a big business, and using some
tools to help bring them in data and
generate ideas can go a massively long
way, and that happens even at the
highest level of companies. That's why
it's worth walking through this video is
cuz you're going to start to see bosses
be like, "Well, I read this story about
X or Y." And you having a counter for
that, or you having a plan for that as a
leader or a contributor, or someone
running a business is really important.
So, now that you have this monthly
processes, now that you know how to
engineer some of your copy to actually
scale into that and get efficiency, how
do you structure your week? So, you want
one day. I would say one day, whether
you split that into two half days or you
actually just dedicate a day to new
creative. I'm going to put all this in
terms of hours here. Let's say 8 hours
to be focused on new creative. So, your
focus here is on ideation, recruiting
people to actually make that content, or
finding vendors, assigning that content
and following up and making some of it
yourself if you have to. And we'll talk
about that in the timing here in a bit.
But basically, you want to for
advertisements create new videos and
statics. And to do that, you are going
to want to get designers, which you can
get off Dribbble or Behance. You want to
get UGC, or just creators who are going
to be help you to make some of those new
videos at decent rates. And so, you're
going to be able to get those from
places like Mini Social, where you can
just pay for a packs of UGC. If you use
Meta Creator Manager for outreach, you
can use Social Snowball. I will link my
guide down below that I have about
utilizing creators in the creator
economy. Tribe, where we can do it on
Instagram, we can put stuff in the ad
account on a percentage of ad spend. And
you need ideas for them, which you can
get from video database, which is the
one that we maintain, myself and the Cut
30 guys, around finding video
information. And then basically quickly
making briefs from that. You can use
Motion. The Social Growth Engineers
website is amazing if you do SaaS. And I
send out a content review newsletter
with the Cut 30 team we send out almost
every week that we can gives you a bunch
of ideas in your inbox. But your job,
you want to be able to get these, and to
do these, you need to ideate, you need
to recruit, you need to brief, and you
need to follow up. I will be spending 8
hours a week doing this. Again, this is
assuming you have other
responsibilities. When you begin scaling
this team, this is likely just a job
that just does this. One day of your
week is being, "How do I find more
people to get in this funnel? How do I
assign the people that I have with new
ideas? And how do I make sure this is
all tracked inside a doc. Could be as
simple as a spreadsheet, Notion doc,
whatever. So, you want to spend 8 hours
a week on that new creative. And you are
going to spend 4 hours a week in two
2-hour blocks, or you could probably
even do this faster, into performance.
You're going to load in performance
creative. So, on a quick note,
performance marketing is beneath no one.
Every single person should be running
ads for their business. There's a
massive alpha and upside there. And
also, media buying is commoditized. You
do not need an agency, you do not need a
specialist. It has become radically
easy. If you are this one person doing
this, you're doing this in your org, you
should do it. Facebook has its own
course teaching you how to set up these
campaigns and stuff. It's very
straightforward. Google Ads, same thing,
they have a whole certification program.
Start with that in your pre-prep if you
don't know anything else. Be spending
this time before you even load in ads,
spend those 4 hours a week learning that
and setting it up. But, you should
really just need two 2-hour chunks,
absolutely max, to load in whatever new
creative has been generated inside the
creative process. These messages inform
this creative that you then load in. And
then running your analytics, checking
what's working, and making notes. So,
basically, loading, analytics, learning.
Do not spend more time in Ads Manager in
those platforms than this. You are
likely wasting time if you are spending
more in there. Every business should be
starting with Meta Ads, supplementing
that with Google Ads. If you are a
lifestyle business, you're doing
clothing, you're doing that kind of
stuff, any physical product, you
probably want to run TikTok in a similar
way to what you're running on Meta.
Services businesses, additional scale,
you can look to YouTube Ads. And I would
be spending another 4 hours a week on
your funnel related to this. So, that is
your landing pages. Where are those
people landing? If you're trying to
figure out what to run that stuff to,
are you getting emails? Are those emails
using lead forms? Are they using forms
in there? How much rows are in the
forms? What can you test to make sure
you're getting that information? What
emails do you send to people after that?
That's specifically in this sales
process. Your abandoned cart flow,
things like that. So, now you've
basically eaten up two full days in new
creative, loading in the performance,
and helping improve the funnel from the
creative, matching the landing pages to
your messages, stuff like that. I'll be
getting another four in on more
collateral and email. What are you
supporting the sales team with? Can you
be giving people more PDFs, more
information, more testimonials, and
aggregating it there, sending broadcast
to your list, segmenting your list. This
is really getting into email marketing.
So, broadcast, automation, personas,
collateral, so anything you can give to
the sales team, templates. This is
enablement and forward-facing stuff
going out to customers. And then, once
you Once you're in this you're going to
start looking at influence and creators
and people that can actually broadcast
with their existing audience. This is a
very similar flow to what you see up
here, and that is another day. This
becomes someone again, you begin to have
When you begin to build a team, you have
a person that specializes on this
creative. You have a person that
specializes on the funnel and email and
performance. You have a person that
specializes on influencer. All of a
sudden, that's how you have a
multi-person team. This is the same
thing. You are doing outreach. You are
doing contracts. Okay, no excuses here.
Just have AI work through a bunch of
this for you. And as you get bigger and
more legit and have resources on legal,
you build templates out. Scheduling,
tracking, and deliverables. So, this is
getting external people, not the only
internal creative you're putting on ad
accounts, external people that do that
for different amounts of money. So, now
if you look at your week, you have one
day on new creative, one day on
performance and funnel, one day on
influencer, one day on collateral, half
day on collateral and email. That only
brings us to three and a half days. Now,
here's what else I'm going to figure.
You're going to have meetings,
follow-ups, all the stuff that comes
from this. That's going to be an hour a
day. If it's more than that, that's a
problem in itself. But, let's even add
that up. Let's say it's going to be
eight hours a week of emails,
follow-ups, and other random stuff that
doesn't come in here. So, we're going to
have another eight. This is going to be
logistics. So, now that's going to bring
us to four and a half full days. That's
if you're working a 40-hour week, which
I haven't worked a 40-hour week in the
last 15 years. It's all been 60s, etc.
I'm sure a lot of people are going to be
in a similar scenario. But, let's just
assume that. That gives you another half
day in addition to all these logistics
and all these stuff, and that I'll be
focused on how can you be helping turn
out content, content for organic And I
haven't even touched organic social on
here because it doesn't matter. You want
to scale? Want to focus on the things
you need to scale first, hammering
through a lot of this. Now, to actually
test and validate and do that well,
let's say you want to focus on organic
social for those the last 4 hours. That
should be you testing and yapping or
putting together carousels for a few
videos, etc. Or filming someone else on
the team if you have a team, but
actually getting more content out on
organic to help validate a bunch of
these ideas. But that is if you are an
efficient person operating in this. If
you run your weeks like this, you'll
see. Every business will be a little
different. I don't need as much time on
that. I need more time on this. But this
is a framework. Anything else Anything
else you're thinking about here does not
matter. If it can't be filled up in
those 8 hours of logistics, it's
probably not worth doing for most
businesses and most sizes. And if you
are worried about is my marketing team
busy enough? Am I busy enough? How would
I fill up those hours? Am I What do I do
with my procrastination time? You are
zoning in on all of this cuz you get
that complete weekly plan. So
opportunities that I see here, if you
are a person who isn't operating your
own business, but you want to be able to
help businesses, this here, that new
creative. So that's creative strategy
for that's for ads, etc. And ideally
some more of this both for brands and
for personal brands. Creators need stuff
like this too, especially this top up
here. A lot of them need this exact
framework. That is an opportunity to
sell into that you could be developing
as a business. It's probably a separate
video. So anyway, I will link obviously
the HubSpot copy guide. I will link the
creator economy guide to actually
finding influence and and creators and
working with them in here. And I will
link the community call where you can
ask any questions on this. We can go
over it live. It's all going to be down
in the description. Let me know if you
like the whiteboard videos and the
outlines if this is helpful to show you
how I think about this and how I work
with teams and I will keep those coming
in the queue. Thank you all so much for
watching.