This video is the creatives guide to
rebranding yourself. Putting together a
plan you can actually act on in 2026.
Now, if you've tried to have that major
year, rebrand yourself, or do the things
that take you to the next level, but
have failed, this video is going to
break down some of the reasons why. It's
going to call out [music] five distinct
paths you can take, and I'm going to
break down each one, who they're for,
and [music] the steps to actually do it.
To give you an actionable guide. And
what I like about these years, broken
them down into little brands, it may not
be for you this year, but it's a
framework [music] to think about for the
rest of your life of how to actually
deploy change. And I've been in the
middle of this as a creative. I started
making content when I was 37. [music]
I've been through the ups and downs.
I've owned an agency. I've been
freelance. I've worked at big jobs. I've
made major moves cross country for work.
Had to grapple with all the things
around money and expertise that many of
you are now. I'm just going to try and
share as much as I can to make it really
actionable. I'm excited to do this
video. Hopefully helps some of you get
to your goals in 26. Let's lock in. So,
first, let's talk about the five
different years and why we have five.
So, everyone tries to accomplish
everything. Oh, I'm going to go to
become a millionaire this year, or kick
off my brand and make it huge. And the
reason why we fail so much is you can
only do so much at some time. And I talk
to younger people all the time who are
like, "23, why am I not rich yet? 30,
how have I not gotten to here?" Life
doesn't work like that. It's not linear.
It's different for everyone. So, you
have to pick a scenario that's good for
you where you're at. There's five big
years that I think almost everyone could
benefit from having one of these
actually get to a tactical year they
have. The first is the money year, where
you really focus on how you spend money
and why, and make some decisions and
changes that allow you to save up and
make more of where you're at. This was
an important year for me when I had it.
My son had just been born. I was making
like 150 or 180, and it was always
disappearing. I had to really be like,
"How do I have no money when I'm making
what's a decent amount? And how I
grapple with this new life?" And in a
year, my wife and I readjusted how we
think about money. And I'll share some
of the tactics to get to that. And two,
we have the system year. This is the
year if you're too chaotic, if you don't
keep track of anything, you have a hard
time pushing everything together, you
feel like you're not making use of your
time. There has to be a point in time
where you turn a corner, and it takes a
while, and that is the system year. Then
we have the rebrand. If you really want
to rebrand yourself, change yourself,
change the perception of how people
think and view you both in person and
online, that is a rebrand year. It
doesn't happen. It's not a month. It's
not a week. It's a work of constant
progress. We'll go through the actual
steps to get there. Then we have the
master year. You may look around you at
all these people who are crushing it
online or who have do such interesting
things, and they knit, or they're
fashion designers, or whatever, make
amazing content. And you go, "How do I
get there? I could never learn a skill
like that." Well, with a dedicated year,
you can get to a significantly towards
where your goals are, and we'll talk
about that. And then last is the
obsession year. The one that everyone
thinks about. The one that's kind of the
hot topic now. It's like, "How do you
lock in like full monk mode, for lack of
a better
push all the chips in to making your
dream a reality?" And this is an
important one to think about, but it's
not for everyone. You need to already
know what you want. I have this with a
lot of friends in my life who are like,
"I want to be going after things. I want
to be all in." But they don't have their
idea, their concept, their business yet.
This is the perfect year if you're
already in something. You started your
business. You became a creator. Or
you're at a point where you know you
have what you want, but you need to go
all in to take it there, and you can
weigh the sacrifice of a year dedicated
entirely to that versus anything else.
So, from those five years, think about
where you're at, cuz you can't do it
all. You have to pick one thing. This is
where everyone goes wrong is trying to
achieve too much at one time, right? If
you're trying to radically change the
way you look next year and focus on
fitness, probably going to be a bad time
to also try to master a skill, right? I
would say, find one of these years and
pick the one thing, and dedicate that
actual year to it. We act like a year is
a super long time as how transient
things are now. It is a long time
comparative to watching a Tik Tok. It is
not a long time in your life to set
yourself up for success. So, kicking
off, let's start with the master year.
If you want to add a skill to your
toolkit, this is an amazing time to
think about short form content,
up-leveling in your career, learning
something that will engage in your
career path, or artistry. If you want to
lean all in like, "I'm going to really
nail illustration or 3D work, become a
master of these new AI tools, singing,
fashion design, whatever it is, dedicate
the year to it." And where it starts is
acknowledging where that skill is going
to be, building a daily practice, and
then building some sort of public
routine. Let's break those down. I had
this year when I decided to become a
creator. About 3 and 1/2 years ago, I
said, "I'm going to learn how to make
short form videos." Took about 2 months
for me to even get mediocre at it, but I
made one every day. I was working
full-time. I would do it after my son
went to sleep, basically before I went
to sleep. I basically had from 8:30
until whenever I went to bed figure out
making a short form video and whatever
else I had to do that night. It was
painful. It sucked, but I have made a
video every single day since then, and
for all intents and purposes, changed my
life. But even if I had done it just for
that year, it would have significantly
helped my career to just understand how
that works as someone who worked in
marketing. But that time I was going to
publish one thing every day is crucial.
Because if whether you are illustrating,
or you're going to do logo design, the
daily practice of I need to take
something from one to zero every single
day is a really important way to think
about things. Can really help you master
something by having to do that
repetition. And a lot of people who say,
"Oh, I do something more involved. It's
going to take me X amount of time."
There's a huge thing to be said,
especially in today's era, for learning
it with that time constraint. That what
is the logo I got done today? The design
I got done today? And if you are doing
something more intricate, what is the
phase? Okay, I shot two scenes of this
10-scene video that takes me to X or Y.
But getting busting one out every day is
the way to mastery. And so is the daily
habit. If you dedicate to doing it in
this year, no days off. Christmas,
Thanksgiving with the family, whatever,
make the time to prioritize the thing.
And the first way to do is actually pick
the time you're going to do. Look at
your time of day. Is it going to be in
the morning? Is it going to be in your
lunch break? Is it going to be at night?
When are you doing it? And schedule it.
And start looking ahead when you have
weird weeks or a vacation or whatever,
how are you going to work that in there?
But that planning is what's going to
help you get there. And every day that
you do it, you begin to ask yourself
that key question, how am I doing this
better than yesterday? And I highly
recommend some level of public practice
as part of this. Whether you're posting
that every week, every month, or every
day, we're actually sharing that
journey. Whether that's just on a
Instagram account no one cares about, or
on a LinkedIn. How are you putting out
there that this is a thing that you are
mastering? Again, it doesn't have to be
daily. Just having that accountability
that like, "I'm mastering this thing.
I'm doing one a month, whatever." is a
huge benefit to basically keeping you
going and to begin to see the rewards.
And where people get this wrong is they
think, "I'm going to start doing this,
and I'm going to get a bunch of money
from it after 90 days." No. Put in the
year. When the year comes, you can start
to think about where the money comes
from. But you've now set your
foundation. If it happens before then,
awesome, but don't even worry about it
until you've hit that year mark. So,
you've gotten 365 days of work on it.
That is the mastery year. And now
zooming over to the money year. So, like
I mentioned, I had this year, adopted
some of these strategies when my son was
first born. Our money was disappearing,
and started with us breaking down why.
This is where I would start with you
trying to understand where money's at in
your life. There's a couple key buckets
you're going to get into. First is your
consumption of the casual things.
Clothing, stuff for home goods, et
cetera. We all spend a lot more money on
that because we're marketed to
constantly in everything we do. There's
Klarna and Affirm, and it's a non-stop
flow of influence, but none of it is
stuff we need. We have to actually
mentally wrap your head around that to
do something about it. Then we have
subscriptions. What software are you
using? You'll find people that are like,
"Oh, I have Netflix and Hulu and Disney
and that. Oh, they're only $20, $40,
$10." But it adds up. And you don't need
everything. What if you just had one for
3 months, then switch to the next one?
Going out and vice, drinking and related
is a huge one. But we need to tally up
where those expenses come from that are
in your life. Cuz this is about making
the most of the money you have, not
trying to make more. Cuz a lot of
people, the answer to their issues is in
this. Cuz I get a lot of questions, "How
can I do campaigns like this with my
brand? You need to be making way more
money." Or, "Hey, I don't have the money
to to start a brand or become this or
become that." It's mostly lying in side
what you already consume. Now, it's not
for everybody, but if you are in that
like 70K plus bucket, a lot of it comes
down to decisions. And you can begin to
change that by understanding it. So, the
exercise that I would lean into for one
full year is in your consumables, your
clothing, your home goods. Can you buy
nothing new? Can you survive just off
what you have? Maybe your essentials,
your socks, whatever, totally fine. But
in terms of new things, jackets, shirts,
shoes, bags, you likely have enough to
not consume a single thing. Same thing
with whatever is in your home. If you
got every one of those dollars back in
your life and never spent on it, where
would it take you? Now, an exercise I
really enjoyed doing this is we didn't
buy anything new for an entire year. We
made it to to be fully honest, we made
it to Black Friday. I bought something
on sale there. But in the meantime, I
said, "Hey, I can buy second hand
anything I sell something to get." So, I
sold stuff on Grailed and Depop and
local second hand, and I could buy using
those funds anything that was also
second hand. Basically consuming nothing
new. And it really changed my
relationship with the dopamine of
purchasing something when that was no
longer an option for me, or I had to
actually sell something to get there,
and the value of what I was reselling,
what do I really use, and what do I have
to make an outfit? And it was a
wonderful thing that honestly bought us
back close to $10,000 a year. Cuz you
don't think about it, but those little
things kind of add up. And $600 a month,
all of a sudden that's $7,200 a year.
Then an even bigger one was the alcohol
and going out. Now, I was at a point in
my life where I could really think about
it, where that was all of a sudden I was
like, "I'm still doing this. We're still
buying beer and wine and all this stuff.
We just had a kid. Going out and buying
any of that in my house was money that
really wasn't achieving anything for me.
It wasn't making me happier, and it was
just a suck." And I would really think
about how can you remove that from your
life? Again, for a year. And then look
at the fiscal benefit of it. Same thing
with those subscriptions. Like I
mentioned, you'll find a lot of like, "I
have this $10 thing, this $40 thing. Do
I really need it? Can I have just one of
these and alternate?" And you begin to
look at how much money you can get back
and then think about the power of what
you have to do with it. Can you save
that for your retirement? Can you save
that towards your house? Can you save it
towards starting a brand or investing in
yourself? But concentrating that for a
year, for a year being like, "I'm not
buying anything new. I'm not spending on
alcohol or vice. I'm certainly not
touching gambling, crypto, stocks. If
you're investing money, put it in the
S&P. Don't think about it." Then you're
looking at how I can constructively
using every one of these dollars and
accumulating it in my accounts with the
resources I have. And you can pretty
realistically after a month or so make a
plan of what your change looks like,
what that's going to allow you to save,
and then what you're going to be able to
do with it. And think about what that
accomplishes for your goals. If you've
never had a money year, you have an
awkward relationship with money. You
spend money to feel better. Tackling
that year is a huge thing. Which brings
us to the systems year. Every creative
is like this where even if you have a
schedule at work, you don't keep a
schedule in the rest of your life. Or
you're forgetting things or things are
slipping through the cracks. You have an
idea and don't know how to do it. So
putting a system into your life is a
crucial thing to think about. And the
system is simple enough. It is using a
calendar. It is using some sort of
system to track things. And it is having
some level of communication and
accountability around it. Let's break
those down one by one. So the first
thing you want to do is start using a
calendar. Even if you have a job where
you don't usually want or a job where
you do and it's overwhelming. What are
you doing with your time blocks? So pick
a day each week, Friday, Saturday,
Sunday, whatever it looks like. Say,
"I'm going to plan my next week." And
then you do that and you go, "Here's all
the things I have to do, my mandatory
things. I need to make sure I've done
laundry, done this at my work, gone to
whatever appointment. Here's the things
I want to do with my time." And then put
it in the blocks. How long does it take?
I'm putting it in your Google calendar,
your Apple calendar, and blocking it
off. And then really realistically
looking at what time do I have and
what's my extra time, and can I
accomplish all these things and where
are my trade-offs? But when you start
doing that every week and you actually
mark it down, this is what I'm supposed
to do it, and you stick to it cuz it's
your systems year and you're acting on
improving yourself and improving your
life, you start to see a major shift in
where you spend your time and how and if
you do it or not. And then you add on
some sort of tracking system for the
things you have to do in your life.
Apple notes or Evernote or whatever it
ends up being. Whatever's easy for you,
you have to pick one thing. Ideally with
checkboxes. There's something satisfying
and dopamine providing about checking
that box, whether it's on an app or you
have a written thing in your house that
says it's done that helps you turn into
the kind of person who loves the system.
And the third thing is communication. So
for instance, if you are at work, you
start tracking what you're working on,
what you got done that week, and sending
that to your boss. If you have a partner
in an entrepreneurial venture, you start
to track that every week. Here's what
we're working on, here's what's coming
next. Or even just for you, journaling.
Here's what I got done this week. Here's
what my plan for next week. Those three
things together with when acted on for
52 weeks straight turn you from a
chaotic person to a action person. And
this is important for a lot of people
who wonder, "There's other people my age
who are more successful than me." For
some people, this is innate. They're
just built like that. They just run
through things, they have systems, they
they grew up in a way that made them
that way. But for most of us, it is
absolutely not. So it's really important
to go learn it and cross that off and it
will get you towards whenever you have
something to get excited about or apply
yourself to, now you're going to have
the kind of system in your life to help
get it done. We're going to talk about
the rebrand and then we're going to
end with the obsession year. So
rebranding yourself is an interesting
thing. It's looked at oddly. You there's
a bunch of videos that will come out
around this time of year about it all
the time, but it's this idea that you
want to improve how others perceive you
cuz branding is about how others think
of you. And it's important. People act,
"Oh, it's fake or you're going to turn
into someone you're not." We change in
life. I am so different from the person
I was at 23 or 27. And to give you an
example, like I'm an intense person now.
I get comments about my intensity in the
videos and how fast I talk, things like
that. If you knew me, shoutout to the
ones who did in like 23 to 27, I was a
bro. I loved to party. I was the center
of my friend group. We were out all the
time. I was super chill. And one day, I
decided that is not the person, as fun
as that life is, that's going to
accomplish the goals that they need to.
And over time, I became this person.
This person isn't fun. It's not chill.
I'm not an amazing hang unless we're
[ __ ] building something, in which
case we will drive it and take it to as
far as we can humanly go and it will be
amazing. But that took concerted effort.
And so your rebrand breaks down into a
few things. Starts with an exercise, the
archetype of who you want to be. How do
they dress? What do they say in
different scenarios? When they're
talking to someone of the opposite sex?
When they're negotiating a deal? When
they're in a scenario at work? When
they're hanging out with others? What do
they read? What do they consume? Build
that list. Start with that exercise.
List those things out and actually write
out what those actions look like. And
then it takes planning. This is why I
think this is a year. People think they
can just change their outfit and they're
going to be a different person next
month. That's the case. It takes
intention. The end of every day, going
into the next day or in the morning,
thinking about what would this person do
in the scenarios I'm going to see? In
this meeting tomorrow at work? At this
hang with my friends? With my free time?
How would this person that I want to be
present themselves? And then planning
for it. Planning the outfit, planning
the conversation, walking through that
conversation in your head, having the
argument in the shower in the other tone
of voice. You need the repetition of
being this new person to actually become
it. And that time, that year, needs
complete dedication to what is this like
until you are it. And in a year, you can
do it. And in a month, it is extremely
unlikely. And trying to focus on
anything else while you're doing this
beside achieving that goal, how you want
to look and how you want to act, is
going to be really hard. So I would just
zone in on, "This is the year I become
who I plan to be. I embody their
characteristics. I look and act like
them." And don't feel bad about it.
People will be weird about it for
whatever amount of time. You have to
pursue what you want and what you are
going to do. And one of the biggest
recommendations I have is that one of
the hardest things for people is to
change how they react to things, to
change how they talk in any scenarios.
And the biggest tool you have is is
pausing. If someone asks you a question,
if you have a scenario come up, taking a
moment to think. Cuz we overthink it. We
don't want to pause, we want to just
rush into things. Other people won't
even notice. You take a breath.
You think. If you consider your what
you're going to say before you say it,
it's almost good, almost respectable.
But you should need to have that
split-second moment of, "Am I
immediately reacting or what would I
actually want to say?" Have that inner
narrative, have that moment. Adjust and
then act. And just by noticing that and
beginning to incorporate that into your
life when you're at some of those
scenarios where you want to control how
you react, just taking that breath is
absolutely crucial. If you want to
sharpen a new skill this year, learning
the basics of all the different AI
models and what they can do is a great
one to lead with. I partnered with
Leonardo to walk you through actual
exercises that are going to teach you
how to use these platforms in a way that
actually makes sense for your creative
work. So first off, people often get
overwhelmed by all the names and models
that come up when you are creating
something. And this is one of the
reasons I love Leonardo is that they
have all of these models in one place
and they keep them super up to date. As
soon as something is out, it is in here.
So when you go to generate something,
you are able to select from this
drop-down menu what models you want to
try. So the first exercise that I would
get into if I was learning this is to
determine what models are good for what
things. Here's your quick cheat guide
for that. So Nano Banana and Nano Banana
Pro are ultra-accurate models. Ever
wondered how people actually place their
products into content like you see here
with uh what I do with this Muscle Goo
bottle. These are done in Nano Banana
where you take a reference image of a
product, you give an accurate
description of what you want to look
like. Like I said, "This product massive
in between two modern gyms in New York."
And it will very accurately put that
together. And then it's the same thing
for video. For instance, I found the Veo
3.1 is the most accurate to make videos
from Nano Banana content. So for
instance, I generated this eight pool
ball inside of a city massive and I was
able to use Veo to do this pull-out shot
from that. And it looks great for the
needs that I have to use this for an AI
hook in an ad. If you're doing video and
you want great sound and language,
there's Kling 2.6. And then one of my
favorites for accuracy, especially
accuracy with shots, is this Kling 01.
For instance, we did a logo animation
for this. This is a polo player logo. We
made it into gold in Nano Banana,
brought that reference image here into
Kling. And then my prompt was the horse
slowly turning in the air with cinematic
lighting glinting off of it. If you've
ever built a logo animation in 3D
software, you know how painful this is
to do and this is something you can do
quickly here and now. And it's an
awesome skill for you to try to learn
and piece together and add to your
creative toolkit. And it is definitely
worth checking out some of the more
obscure models as well. Like this one,
Hailuo, is great because there's a logo
setting that they have in here inside
the style guide. And I use this to bring
2D images to life when we need to. So
for instance, this riding horse player,
this riding polo player from the logo
image that we had that was 2D. So
Leonardo has all those models plus an
upscaler to upres things. The blueprints
that I showed before in a previous video
where you can basically do one to
two-click versions of placing a person
in a scene, doing custom relighting,
product spins. They're adding more to
those all the time. If you want to learn
more about using Leonardo as a home base
for generation, the link in my
description will tell you all about it.
A big thank you to them for sponsoring
this video. So now, bumping over to
probably the one I think most are
interested in hearing about and that's
the obsession year. This is almost a
controversial topic. This is my year
last year, by the way. We'll get into
that. With the idea that you're going to
sacrifice things that are in your life
to achieve a goal. This comes up a lot
because I think there's a generation of
people who believe you can have it all,
who believe that you can be massively
successful with work-life balance, that
you don't have to sacrifice a lot to get
a lot. And it's important to note that
for 99.9% of cases, that is just
absolutely not true. So you need to
really think, "Is this my time to do
this?" And again, if you have a brand or
you started something or kicked
something off or you're a creator and
you're starting to see some traction,
this is the time to think about it. When
you have some momentum. If you don't
have momentum, you don't know what you
want to do. You got to figure out
yourself first. You got to do your
rebrand. You got to build your systems.
You got to save for wherever you want to
go. This is not the year for you. But if
you have that idea, you need to go. So
last year for me was the year where I
was like, "Hey, I'm becoming a pretty
big creator. I made far more as a
creator than I did at my job and I had
left my job mid-year last year. I want
to say yes to all the opportunities I
like that I'm into. I want to see how
far I can push it, how much I can do.
I'm not going to have the same
friendships and relationships and casual
stuff I did. I'm I'm going to be able to
take care of myself the same way. I had
to really think about the time and
relationships with my family and how we
spend time. It doesn't mean cutting
anything off, but it means like
understanding what my responsibilities
are, what everyone's dynamics are, and
really planning for it. It's important.
And then putting my priority as it's the
work over everything. And for a lot of
people that will mean moving out of
where you're at, not hanging out with
the same people you did and don't have
the same goals, not texting back for
people that you feel bad about. Always,
every time for this year you are
choosing the work, you are choosing your
goal over everything. And if you really
do that, do not feel bad about it. Every
person you've seen get to mass success
has likely had to do this at some point
as they do it. That's a huge thing that
is highly worth thinking about. If
you're ready for it, absolutely go. And
I will say some of the ups and downs of
this, it's going to be a long year, it's
going to be a hard year, it's probably
going to be bad for your health. That is
what it is. You don't have to choose
this year. If you have some momentum and
you want to go all in, sometimes that's
all right. And again, we're in a culture
that has us almost feel bad about it.
Don't. And also think about how you can
embrace it with people. One of the big
changes for me in my life was with my
wife and I doing okay, we're not going
to be watching like Netflix at night.
We're not going to be having movies,
we're not going to do the same kind of
hang stuff we did. And that actually
went better than expected because my
wife was like, "Hey, I want to help. I
want to be involved." And now we have
the Status Symbols newsletter that we do
together and we work on it at night. It
helped her gain some focus and priority
and decide some stuff that she wanted to
do. And again, it's not going to last
forever. At the end of the year, that's
the key thing about the obsession year,
you get to ask yourself, "Do I want this
to keep going or am I done?" This is an
important time. Give yourself that year.
Give yourself going all in for that
amount of time. But then if you're over
it, if you feel like you know what, this
wasn't worth it or I don't want to
continue, you did it. You had that year.
You locked in. It's done. You get to
really be like, "All right, you know
what? Maybe I can relax a bit now."
That's fine. You did it. Also, you can
look at it and be like, "What if I did
another one?" You know, "Where would
that take me?" And that's fine, too. But
give yourself that year cuz it's not
forever. And that's the conversation
that I could have with on the family
side. It's like, "I'm going to travel
more than usual. Here's what that's
going to look like. Here's how I'm going
to make sure I prioritize it on the
other end." And you can look at the end
of this year coming up into these days
and be like, "What do we want to do for
next year?" And something we're really
thinking about. And if you do this,
there's only one guiding light in that
year. And that light is the most
important thing is the goal. Every
single action you take is it's
supporting the goal. If it's not, don't
do it. And I put a lot of absolutes into
these years because if you have a real
goal for a year, whether that's systems
or mastery or obsession, you need to do
it. You can't make an exception. You
make an exception, you don't lock in on
it. And that's why I like to pick these
individual things. If you try to do it
all, there's going to have to be
exceptions and all of a sudden you're
faltering. If you become the kind of
person who is honest with yourself and
achieves things for yourself, it's going
to go a massively long way. If you
haven't noticed in prior videos, I'm
going on tour next year. We are doing
workshops live and in person. I'll put
some of the dates down here. We got
Toronto, New York, and Miami coming up.
I'd [music] love to see some of y'all
live. And I'm doing a webinar so that
not everyone can get in the middle of
that. We are doing a creative strategy
[music] webinar here in the second week
of January, third week of January. The
info on that is down below as well. But
I would love to see everyone who's
watching and let's get to all of your
goals. That's going to take time and I
want to share as much as I can to help
in that process. If I get to meet some
of y'all along the way, that'd be
awesome. And I hope y'all get everything
you ever wanted out of this year. I
appreciate [music] you so much for
watching.