so what makes a good brand name what are
all the things you need to think of if
you want to start a brand and get your
name right most brands that come to life
start with an idea and then graduate
into a name but occasionally the name
can come first we're going to assume
that it's the former and talk a bit
about how you craft a name around your
idea and then all the logistical things
you need to think of to take it to the
Finish Line I'm also going to give some
examples of things I consider to be
interesting or good names and probably
some bad examples as well but why is the
name such a serious thing as I was
researching for this video series I'm
doing which is basically 30 days of
building a new brand uh one of the
things I came across was a agency called
lexicon so lexicon isn't like a
marketing Consulting agency in the
traditional sense they focus on one
thing and that is naming companies that
need a strong name sometimes they're new
sometimes they're rebrands of existing
companies but the impact that their
transitions had is extremely profound
like when you talk through them and
listen to them you really think about
the impact of a name so I'm going to
break a few of them down so the first is
a company called marxi M axi which
lexicon rebranded into impossible or the
impossible Burger now whatever you think
about plant-based meat whether that's
good or bad you can agree that maaxi
definitely did not have the potential
for Universal appeal or to have the
viral moments that impossible did uh
without that name change another lexicon
winner was Ring cone networks which then
became Sonos it's funny because uh I've
been thinking a lot about the audio and
speaker space doing some research as I
want to get some new things from my home
uh because my Sonos actually died and
then looking around and going through
that space and thinking of banging
olivon and Bose and so many names that
are in there son's coming as a kind of
new player in that space when they did
whenever that was maybe close to a
decade ago now I guess uh the fact that
they were able to achieve what they were
and the strength of both the user
experience the presentation and the
brand identity was a big part of that
and I don't think without that name it
could have had that same singular impact
because the name had such a feel that
just kind of embodied this new
minimalist effective Technology based
thing that seemed to make all these
other existing companies in the speaker
space seem kind of kind of old and out
of touch another winner prom mop became
Swiffer and perhaps my favorite Mega
male reband to Blackberry I remember the
name Blackberry very early I have a
brother who's 12 years older than me who
had a Blackberry like the first
generation this was like the post pom
pilot era and just the way that that
name was talked about and said had such
a interesting element to it and such a
Prestige and was so different it's
obviously become a you know quite the
lengthy story that we've seen on Netflix
and elsewhere now but the power of how
that brand was able to position itself
around that brand name is is a lot to
think about and something I think Brands
who are trying to make a big technology
play need to Aspire to but what do you
need to think about if you want to
launch your own brand the first and most
intangible is feel and connotation is
the brand name memorable does it have a
Vibe and there's lots of exercises that
you can work through to get to this um
one that I've done a lot of is literally
just having a like an emotion-based word
dump where if you have a feeling you're
trying to describe whether that's
professionalism or counterculture cool
whatever it is just listing out all the
potential adjectives for things that are
around that that you can either borrow
parts of whether it's like whole words
or just sounds of words that you can
kind of work that connotation of but
just making those big lists is always a
great beginning point for those
exercises but this leads to the second
part that I think is really worth
thinking through especially in today's
day and age and that is can someone
pronounce the brand if they hear it or
can they spell it if they hear it so
here's why this matter asop and ESOP is
a great example where asop is how a lot
of people pronounce it because that's
how you would actually see it red ESOP
is how the brands actually pronounced if
I was to hear ESOP I would probably have
a pretty hard time fig how do I search
that I was to hear asop I know that
pretty well it hasn't impacted that
brand who have been on an amazing
trajectory forever but if you're a brand
new brand now you're in what I call the
earned media era people are talking
about your products and what you do on
social media all the time the bigger you
get the more talk but no matter what you
or your consumers is going to have that
conversation and so what is the ease
with which someone's then able to follow
through in that conversation is the
person talking about it able to
pronounce it correctly because then
they'll talk about a thing that someone
else could go track down and if they are
pronouncing it correctly can the person
on the receiving end spell it well
enough to search it on Google or Amazon
or wherever it is they're going to find
you to buy what you're selling and if
they can't do that you're going to
basically get a massive loss of earned
media value so earned media value is a
term in marketing that talked a lot
about when it comes to you know relating
things to advertisement so for instance
if you were to run an advertisement on
the Super Bowl it would cost you a
certain amount for a 30 second spot
whatever it is now if you were to have a
similar say it's a 15 seconds where
someone is showing your product on the
screen for free because someone chose to
wear it who's a celebrity or whatever
that is or you're getting just a free
promotional moment for whatever reason
you're getting an earned value so you
did some other work that got you to that
point where you're getting that same
level of exposure people pay millions of
dollars for and it's worth X now you
take that concept and then break it into
social media so if someone is talking
about you on Tik Tok that is worth some
amount even if that is just a CPM the
way you advertise on web and so if
someone can't follow through on that
they can't find your brand and search
they can't connect the dots to be able
to pronounce it that's going to end up
being something that costs you money for
your brand because it would have
converted to sales otherwise and I would
highlight that uh don't don't
underestimate the stupidity of the end
consumer people cannot spell they cannot
figure out complicated things um one of
the brands I had worked on at a company
that with previously was called buku
it's French for more or plenty no way
the consumer is going to be able to
spell that or pop it into Google as fun
of a name as it is now related to it
there's a second part of this Google
test so not only do you have to have
people actually be able to find it once
someone says it and be able to put the
dots together for you you actually have
to be able to rank on Google and this is
a big one before you actually go and
lock your name in as your brand name go
do the Google search and be like is
there a big competition for this already
now there's services like atrs which I
love to use and and um semm Rush who
actually show you like ranking systems
of like the domain authority of a brand
which is How likely they are um when
compared Apples to Apples against
another sorry domain authority of a
website which is Apples to Apples if you
were going to compare two sites making
content about the same thing the domain
Authority technically should give one an
edge if it has a higher one and that
domain Authority is based on how many
backlinks it has from other parts of the
web and how people actually interact
with its content and search a number of
factors it's basically how Google search
algorithm works is centered around some
of these concepts of authority but if
you are competing against really
established brands with the same name
even if they're in a different category
you're not going to be able to own the
top of the search and that is going to
be expensive for you over time because
if someone has the same exact brand as
you in another category and they're
searching for it and they show up first
eventually you're going to start paying
money to Google to show up first because
you want to make sure people find you
and don't click away and give up those
will be lost customers so then every
time you search for the brand you're
going to be paying dollars for those
clicks and in some cases if you get
super competitive you'll be doing that
anyway but it's better to set yourself
up from the start to be found I work
with a number of smaller Brands who have
either like seated me product as an
influencer or I've done advisory work
for where they have that exact issue
cool name go search them on Google
they're nowhere to be found like doing
some of that SEO building is important
one of the projects I worked on where we
did this extensively for was a
terminology based product so I was
working with a brand called chlorophyll
water um they're amazing you can find
them all they're in sprouts and Mother's
Market all kinds of Aran places around
around the US and like specialty and
health markets really cool water brand
but they named themselves after the
category and this is something that you
know happens frequently another brand
that um I've worked with for a long time
it's called Jael Blaster same name name
of the product is uh also the name of
the brand name of the category and so
they are basically banking on there's a
positive and negative to that so the
positive is if you own SEO for that and
it becomes a bigger category beyond your
brand other people have chlorofil water
or other people have Gil blasters you're
going to own the Google search for that
and that is going to win you a lot if
you actually have established your
search the negative of it is you know
there's some like misinterpretations or
people know if this is a brand or that's
a brand or trying to like find there
could be some level of confusion that
comes in the market later but it's
typically if you're a first mover worth
having that ownership now with chlorofil
water for instance that brand chlorop
was actually a pretty hard term to rank
for and it mattered enough where I was
like Hey chlorop water in general you're
going to own this category and you're
going to do some of the launch plans the
founder had and he was going to do
basically like a shock and awe
influencer seeding campaign I like we
have to own search or else everyone's
going to get this product be all over
Tik Tok and Instagram which it was and
he executed amazingly but then they're
not going to have any way to connect the
dots so I basically had to convince him
for about 6 months to be like let's
invest in building up SEO let's make
sure we're ranking at the top of this
for chlorop Waters so when that happens
we get the search results and I think we
got to number two by the time we
launched was number one very shortly
after and we were able to kind of
fulfill the link in the consumer Journey
between the name people are searching
for and being able to realize that on
Google and then later on Amazon and then
actually follow through to a purchase
now this is important for other reasons
too like retail uh because you can
actually show people this transition you
can be like hey if I'm a person selling
online D Toc and I want to sell to a
major retail chain I'm pitching them I
can be like look I'm generating all
those interest for my new category uh
let's say that you know use creating
gummies as an example you own the SEO
for for creating gummies when that first
launched and you are trying to say that
you you're like hey I our brand owns
this all that search comes in we can
only fulfill so many plenty of these
people also want to continue their
complete their purchase in your retail
stores because it's the kind of thing
that people buy in in store and there
certain consumers that buy online
certain that don't and we want to help
complete that journey by being available
on your shelves here's a search volume
for this here's how we can then direct
some of that search volume to you by
having a dealer locator or whatever it
is these are conversations that actually
work like inside the retail cycle and
showing dominance inside that search is
something that is understood by retail
and they understand the advantage of so
worth from the start to at least
evaluate where you could show up in
Google with that and what the rankings
are and how hard it might be and then
potentially shift in Gears if it's going
to be an impossible task for whatever
reason I'm going to drop into a few
examples of Brands I like before we get
into trademark in the more complicated
category um there's something to me
about places that I think is really
interesting so there is a I think what's
the right way to put this like a a club
an online club for uh successful
entrepreneur e-commerce types called
Hampton Hamptons it's from the guys who
did one of the guys who did my first mil
s power I believe he owns it and I love
that name so Hampton is a great name
because it immediately connotates a
certain level of luxury due to the place
the Hampton and if you're going to do a
membership club being able to conate
luxury by associating it with something
where you just hear the word you
associate luxury great but even better
there's a dual story to this why I like
this is when people will assume they
named it after that because of that
place which I'm sure to some extent they
did but also it has a personal story to
Sam which he he saw this on Twitter
where he was like Hey I actually grew up
on a street named that in Missouri or
wherever he's from so he can kind of get
the best of both worlds oh it has this
Lux connotation which makes sense for a
kind of expensive prominent club for
wealthy e-commerce folks but then also
it's not going to be like oh we only
named it because of that cuz he also has
a story to back it up that I thought was
a cool interesting example of something
that's not like a physical product where
they're using the connotation of a place
to then associate the brand with the
right things and they have a story so
it's not like purely based on them
another one I love is goop so goop was
gwenneth ptr's like Health Website and
Marketplace basically and people took
health and wellness so seriously and she
was always a little bit fringed and
everything being presented on goop and
from the start you get that name and it
just has this inherent level of
unseriousness to it where it is playful
and exploratory and unlike any like you
know super rigid you know Men's Health
Magazine and we are we are the epitome
of opposite of that and it BEC something
it's so almost awkward or interesting to
say when it began that now is just kind
of second nature but I love the idea
that you can basically have something
fun and playful in a short way that
people will become you know basically
will bring that inherent playfulness
into their experience with the brand I
thought was really fun I also am a
sucker for numbers spelled out like the
brand 10,000 so I'm running equipment I
I own a much of their product they they
done a great job I love a a a numerical
spelled for some reason uh again might
not be the best for what we talked about
in SEO but it just has a certain thing
around it that I feel has a Vibe and
then counterculture uh counterculture is
always an interesting one because I feel
like for any brand that you want to put
out you want to position yourself to
launch a brand at some point you have a
couple ways you can position yourself
you can say I'm going to be the cheapest
version with what's on the market I'm
going to succeed based on value I'm
going to be the most expensive version
I'm going to succeed based on Lu your
experience uh and then there's always
the alternative like the the Death Wish
coffee it's a great word Death Wish two
word name get back to that later um but
basically by saying hey we're going to
be the strongest most you know
antithesis of everything Black Rifle
coffee another one twool letter name uh
and there's a whole kind of cottage
industry of creating counterculture for
various Industries liquid death also two
and uh I see this kind of go across
Industries like I remember when I was
younger and we were looking at athletic
gear Tapout was super popular and it was
basically this like all right well I'm
not doing your standard work or your
Nike like I'm a fight guy like I'm a
Jiu-Jitsu or MMA guy we tap now we see a
very similar Vibe today with um what the
guys that kill crew have crushed it with
like just where you know kill crew like
yeah [ __ ] sick you know it's like for
the right person immediately gives you a
con cultural connotation hellstar in
street wear same exact thing so I do
think there is this whole cottage
industry of do you want to stand out
like two words one of which is kill and
you see death multiple times like inside
that rifle hell like just putting one
you one word that cuts through the noise
immediately and you associated with like
oh I get it like this is counter I think
has an entire angle on how to position
your brand I know we've got a little
more than you bargain for and just a
checklist for naming but I think it's
important to explore these Concepts as
you think about it now we'll get into
the fun part which is trademarks and
I'll disclaimer this of for I am not an
attorney I'm not a trademark attorney I
have trademarked things myself I have
trademarked things with attorneys I've
had things go good and bad uh I'm going
to give you a quick breakdown but like
definitely always actually consult with
someone like don't just take my word for
it so the best way to start with
trademark least understand what the
scenario is for your brand is to use
test te SS this is the government's free
platform with which to search trademarks
uh the UK has a similar version too and
I'm sure there's some for other count
you go into tests and you can search the
trademark database and it will'll show
you live trademarks and dead trademarks
dead trademarks means someone had it
registered and it expired for whatever
reason live trademarks are either have
been awarded or they are pending which
means that someone has registered it but
it hasn't been confirmed all trademarks
have a category there is a big list of
categories available on the same website
and these categories get pretty Niche it
can be like from you know alcohol not
including beer to certain type of cream
to clothing items to hats whatever it is
and so you want to look for um one of
one of two things there's word Mark
trademarks and then there is like image
tra and so we're going to talk about
word marks just for now talking about
naming you want to go look for is there
someone that has a word trademark that
is live in your category that you plan
to sell in or a category that's like
close enough that it could be considered
a conflict this is a big one because you
actually go through and run this check
you want to go make sure all right
there's no one selling the exact same
thing with the exact same name even if
you hadn't heard it there's a whole
level of nuance to trademarks that even
if they don't have a trademark listed
registered in the database if they are
selling something under that name and
they're doing the same thing they do
have an argument that they are using it
in Commerce and that they own the right
to that trade Mark so you do have to go
do your diligence to make sure no one's
actually selling under that name as well
but even if no one you can find is
selling you should still check the
trademark database to make sure no one
has gone and locked that name down and
look this will save you a bunch of time
and legal money if you at least check it
and be like oh man that is an exact
competitor I should skip this or okay
here's two or three that I see exist I'm
going to take that to a lawyer already
researched to save some hours there so
then we can actually validate how we
would go about attempting to get a
trademark in your category next we're
going to get to URLs so I think the best
is always going to be a com uhco and net
I feel are also pretty great at this
point in the internet all the other ones
I think whether it's AI or IO or us or
TV or whatever it is are pretty much all
on the same Playing Fields think they're
not amazing but if you can't get one of
the other three great there is a service
called Dom do ai. NR that will show you
like combinations if you want to have
one of those like you know uh a word
that's made up of like multiple domains
and I do search pretty well I also use
name cheep a lot shows you a lot of the
domain options you want to you want to
like validate what's available um but I
think having a doom is obviously the
best I always love an appending word um
so for instance my brand name is
valuable I have valuable studios.com I
can't get valuable. comom and I think
that's completely fine it's even better
if it matches your social URLs uh and I
think I would just always note that it
should be an appending word put it on
the end of the phrase don't put the word
in the beginning if I had Studio
valuable or whatever that will screw you
in these minor ways over time and it's
little things like whenever anyone goes
to write you know Orin valuable
studios.com they can't find the email
address because they're when they put in
V because they forgot that I had the S
before it you know it's like little
things like that same search same thing
with social media that's the same exact
way you go search a brand on social
media if it doesn't start with the first
letter of the brand their URL doesn't um
or their their handle doesn't then it's
just they may not find it they may give
up on the search you're just losing
these incremental things over time so
anyway that's the the briefs on uh on
URLs social handles there's a service
called brand snag where you can search
through a bunch of those or just look
one by one it is annoying that sometimes
things will show available on Instagram
but they aren't actually available to
register and you kind have to find a
connect to talk to there which is its
own nightmare but uh there's services
that will go pick that up for money or
whatever um with those I think it's it's
important to have them unified I think
if you are going to choose something for
your brand name try to have the same
thing across all of them um and or at
least something similar and then to
start it with the actual word name so
it's searchable like we mentioned before
so to give a bit example about this
process so the brand that I am um
building right now with my team that
you've seen a lot of content on on
social media I talk about this series is
called valuable I love the vibe of the
word valuable because it implies in the
name that the brand itself has value
that and any item that says valuable on
it immediately implies to the person
that it is worth something and if you
are wearing something that says valuable
it then implies by association that you
are valuable that is a concept which
really does right for me and especially
because overall and one of the reasons I
had had come up with this over time was
that I feel like there's all these
people with these various skill sets are
doing all these intangible things out
here in the world that are inherently
uncelebrated and um as one of those
people that has just like an oddball
skill set that would never traditionally
win like any awards or anything it is
interesting to still think of yourself
as valuable and I want to create
something that celebrates that and you
also create objects with which I feel
have inherent value and this concept of
luxury and value you know selling
something that is a luxury item and I'm
not saying it's brand but if you ever
aspire to be one their resale value is a
big part of that people look at things
like an investment or not and I want to
play with that concept as the brand kind
of emerged and so all those things tie
well into the brand name so then for
URLs we had valuable studios.com so
great to get a.com appended something on
the end to match that up on social media
we have either valuable do Studios or
valuable Studios or every handle and
then trademarks pending in category
touching into a few other brand names I
love boy smells one of the ones candle
brand think I have one right here it's
actually unplanned it just happens to be
on the desk um I just love that name for
some reason I think it is a excellent
standout inside a really crowded space
for something like girl skateboards was
always one I loved uh growing up because
it basically was in a way to introduce
the entire female population of
skateboarding being like this is a brand
for you and then also for dudes who wore
it like it had it immediately kind of
had the connotation that you were like
down with skater chicks like had like
the right thing and just has a a lasting
energy that I thought was really
interesting I always like the idea of
things like some like beats Beats by Dre
um which I thought was a really
interesting idea is just like buy
somebody especially as we go into social
media personalities I expect to see a
lot more or buy and things like that to
take a existing word that may be hard to
own on search but then have it actually
work for your brand but overall this is
the uh the extent of what I'm going to
talk about as it comes to naming uh
we're going to be doing a bunch of
videos breaking out all these different
parts of the brand building process and
it is a complicated one I don't want to
give like surface level conversation of
like you know this is how you set up
your plan I want to give like real
tactical level this is what you actually
have to do and and deal with and uh
think we did that here with naming if
you have any other questions around
naming that are not like legal stuff I
probably can't answer definitely drop
them in the comments and we're going to
continue this series with a bunch of
other topics as time goes on