online culture in general has become
obsessed with luxury consumers are
interested in it Brands want to know how
to sell at luxury and premium price
points and it's something that I've
worked in almost my whole life but to
command those price points to be able to
call your product a luxury product to be
able to say I'm going to be able to
charge a significant worth you need to
have a certain set of principles that
your brand is going to be able to work
with and as a consumer you need to be
able to see these things and respect
what it is know whether or not it's
worth your dollar I'm going to Breeze
through a bunch of the brands who are
doing premium and luxury online Pres
business mostly on websites we'll test a
little bit on social throughout this
video and there's going to be a whole
series of different ways the brands come
across as luxury designer and premium
online one of the first Brands we going
to talk about is ESOP not just their
gorgeous website they have here but they
actually have an amazing design resource
called the taxonomy of design so this
website that you see here I'm scrolling
through is a catalog of every retail
store that they have and all the
materials and individual items used in
those stores this has come up pretty
frequently inside of projects that I've
worked on for interiors when we're
actually working on on the inside of
storefronts when we were working on
redoing our house because it highlights
all these individual features like these
really cool individual things that
people put together you can use for
inspiration and it's also an in-depth
catalog of materials that you can
actually see in use and then use as
references why am I talking about asop
is taking the time to catalog this for
all of their amazing retail locations
and put it online for free and they're
doing it as a resource for people who
are spending money on creating luxury
interior experiences to use them as a
reference and to showcase the care and
intention that goes into building their
brand this is the kind of initiative
that it's not some big social media
campaign it's something that's happening
in the background that's useful creates
value and then tells a real story about
the brand and the decisions that go into
it and uses a reference point to
continually connect back to ASAP ESOP in
professional work around Interiors where
the brand shines and it's filled with
quotes from whether it's John we or
thorough they're building their brand
identity with this kind of content this
is a good time to talk about the core
tenants of what makes a premium brand a
luxury the first is product quality so
before we even have the conversations
around how do we make this amazing brand
online or create this amazing website
you have to have a product that is Above
the Rest in your category and you don't
have to have the best but it needs to be
above good and definitely needs to be
above average if you're going to be
average and try to stand out through all
this Ultra Premium marketing until going
to get so far versus being slightly
above average and so if you don't have
that I would focus on that you'll notice
that almost all these luxury experiences
have that level of craftsmanship inside
them have that level of product
experience and this is good because that
extra bit is what you need to be to
storytellin forget about even though it
seems like common sense is you actually
have to tell people the difference
between your product and regular
products you have to explain that
craftsmanship those materials the reason
the experience is better or different
the thought and intention and history
that went into it cuz people don't just
assume something is luxury they have to
know and I like to talk about the 1% not
just the fact that the 1% of people who
have wealth are looking to buy these
products but the 1% of consumers who
really really really care about your
your website about your social media
about your brand experience cuz there's
two 1% that really matter in premium
branding the 1% where cost doesn't
matter because a lot of us are competing
for their dollars in an infinite amount
of products you want to be on their
radar and you sell to them in a
different way than consumers that are
more sales driven Etc and then the 1%
who care The Advocates because Advocates
are extremely important in premium
branding because a lot of Premium brands
are sold by tastemakers who can't
actually afford them fashion industry is
a great example of this there are
hundreds of amazingly curated mood board
Accounts at influencers who may be able
to afford like a single margel piece but
they certainly aren't frequently
shopping they aren't getting Couture but
they are the voices the people with
money look to for Taste and these
Advocates are the people dissecting
these web pages and these campaigns and
every lookbook and it is important to
cater to them because of the people that
they influence as it is to cater to the
customer demographic when it comes to
this level of Storytelling so when I
refer to the 1% you're going refer to
that as the wealth end of it and also
the taste making end of it and those are
the people that are going through every
single page being like what's that
sustainability program look like I
wonder how they made this and I don't
want to talk about this just in like
high-end fashion Etc I want to talk
about premium price points across
anything and performance stuff as so
arcx is a great example I love to talk
about because arcx has obviously become
very popular recently when I first heard
about them I was working in the outdoors
industry uh it came up in conversation a
lot with Hunters guys from the Marines
who I knew people who took um actual
like hey I'm going to go Summit this
peak you know like lifestyle very
seriously bought arcs because of its
performance and they were getting those
recommend ations from their Community
around perform but I like to highlight
the explore tab on their website because
they have tons and tons of initiatives
and storytelling in there so this whole
no wasted days campaign uh which just
kind of like a big marketing campaign
that they have where just have tons of
tons of content and all these areas you
can check out and events and things like
that they have the full who we are that
you'd expect but it's this kind of big
interactive story that's kind of being
told in all these in all these different
ways they put on their website super
expansive events acms films they sponsor
their whole athletes and ambassadors
page and building that out this is
another one I want to highlight because
like a lot of brands have influencers or
have sponsored athletes they don't have
a section on their website for them and
it's like think of every website like an
old school 9s skateboarding website like
people are going to go click on the team
see who represents you and if you've got
influencers now or whatever that is like
if you got some sort of deal with them
orong like put them on the site let
people know uh it may not build definity
for everybody but for the people it does
it's great and then it exposes you that
the brand is doing more to people that
may not know and this is cool because
like look I don't know much about you
know summoning Peaks but if I did I
would love to be able to go here and be
like all right I should go look into
what Isabella sanare is doing then
there's the brand choices and ARX is
another great one for this because
obviously cool logo they go into the
depth behind it but they also have put a
ton of time into putting their products
into nomenclature a lot of stuff happens
in these premium Brands behind the scene
you need to think about different lines
and setups Etc like I'm about to release
the valuable shirts valuable is my brand
and we have a couple different versiones
of them I have this first version I did
um that's like the core shirt or
adjusting the sizing and I'll fully like
name it but for now I'm not naming it
putting it in a nen clature it's just
the first shirt we second shirt we're
doing is this Ultra heavyweight like
extremely super distressed crazy wash a
shirt that's very very hard to execute
and we are putting it through like a
proprietary naming and it's be called
this it's the century wash it's like
specific wash that we developed with the
factory to be able to do this on this
really specific fabric that is like very
unique and hard to get and I'm going to
brand that shirt as like the flagship
and a certain price point for people
that want like a shirt that feels like a
chemar vest but then I have our standard
shirt which is the first shirt we have
but we changed some of the measurements
after the first run we're making it
slightly different more to our own still
heavy but not that heavy and more our
everyday and that's going to have live
in a different place and a different
price point and then over time as we
introduce new things we're going to have
those categories but if I just put those
out there and I don't start branding
them and saying oh this is the century
wash t-shirt and this is you know the
everyday valuable to whatever it ends up
being and then explain it people don't
know they're just going to see those
names and go away but if you begin to
build that up over time and you develop
that shows the intention that goes into
let consumers know I should choose this
or that or oh they actually have thought
that goes into why this is different
than that and our TX has taken this to
just a crazy degree right because they
make technical garments in all kinds of
ways people rely on in potential life
and death scenarios and so they have all
this iconography theyve built out all
these different systems and sub Brands
they have all these product modifiers
for how they're used and if you can use
it where or when product families I mean
this is extensive and they go they break
it down here on this website and that is
an important thing if you have developed
to go and show people and shows the
intention that goes into that brand and
immediately brings this performance and
premium to anyone who goes down that
rabbit hole and the same thing goes into
like the materials and the science
behind it they got this this whole
section on how high their Stitch count
is on custom lug designs you articulated
fit like this is a great art director
we'll get to Art Direct in a little
later area on their design and they have
a whole film series on how obsessive
they take their design now this is a
brand obviously is you know they've
gotten now I believe they're acquired by
like big Chinese group have B tons of
money over time have extensive
storytelling to do I'm not saying you
have to have this to start but if you
are a big brand if you are a brand
that's doing tens of millions of dollars
a year and you're not beginning to
describe your process or explain it
online you're trying to position
yourself as premium you're not doing
your brand job Justice and if you're
getting bigger than that you should
really be thinking about how am I
building that long-term brand affinity
and explain to customers what I do and
each one of these things um I'll have a
whole separate video on luxury and
social media later but like this is also
like the same thing okay we're going to
talk about high Stitch count why it
matters inside you know performance gear
they put all this together this isn't
crazy right it's just photos some light
text and explaining why they care about
this particular thing they do and why
they choose the things in their product
they do that is multiple social media
videos carousels and an email blast and
it's a core part of your website like
building marketing out and saying how
can we repurpose it make it holistic is
like a super important way to look at
content now and telling those stories as
a premium brand is throughout it but
enough about arct arter is a very
literal version of it let's talk about
Ambush and we're going to dive from this
idea that you need to have a great
product to position yourself premium to
you need to explain to people why it's a
great product to you need to World build
you to start explaining the why and the
about your brand a lot of traditional
luxury and Heritage brands have a rich
history right you can go back to 1700s
France when the first person you know
cobbled together this perfect boot that
became you the Louis Vuitton whatever
they're able to rely on that on time and
when you look at what luxury really is
it's this combination of product
experience desirability from users and
then execution actually hitting that
standard and then you have a time
underneath it like have you been able to
be desirable for a long time have you
able to execute your product standard
for a long time and the longer it is the
more entrenched in luxury it becomes but
for brands that don't have that Heritage
that are newer Brands how do you achieve
that and world building is really the
way you need to be able to tell a story
as as compelling as a story of a
Heritage or Legacy fashion house or
someone who has that real luxury feel
but in a shorter time period Ambush is a
fun example really cool and interesting
brand I absolutely love love their
garments the things they put together in
their world the clouds with Nike the
personalities and Yun but they go to
this universe tab on their site hidden
way we got Universe Art and Design
Theory we have a whole segment of the
literal art design theory that defines
the backbone of their brand so I can go
be like ah samun Gucci I don't know
anything about this oh now I'm actually
getting a lesson in art and design
history and the people that care about a
brand like Ambush care about this I am a
Target Ambush customer I bought Ambush I
will buy more Ambush and I am very happy
that they have now introduced me to the
amazing world of Asama nuchi and
whenever I'm going to look for some
inspiration this is a great place for me
to go I'm going to go to an entire
website of The Inspirations of a brand I
like and that's just one of the sections
that they're putting out there inside
this universe you know then we have this
whole field study section it's a bunch
of interesting things that are Happ out
in the world this living world section
whole series shating showcasing record
shops in Tokyo they artifacts and items
they've made that serve a specific kind
of art purpose I love this this Timeless
wash Design This aun and like highlights
and details of their campaigns this is
all content that most brands have right
like and putting together my brand we
have extensive mood boards extensive
references we're putting together
campaign it's just taking all that And
archiving it and cataloging on the
website so people can see separates you
immediately from people that won't take
the time and care to do that and then
the actual things that you collect and
showcase begin to be the world that
you're building when you look at someone
like like Lop Piana is gone got into
prominence with the Quiet luxury
movement people have begun to know a lot
more about the brand it's been around
forever and they've been selling a lot
of things based on like the gift of
Kings is the type of wool they have like
this really expensive wool it's an
$111,000 shirt because of the wool but
they're detailing you why this is the
world's most precious wool in you know
their like thorough multimedia web
experience right and they're able to
tell the history of how they put
together the gift of kings and you know
all that Heritage but a brand that I
love that has basically shortcutted the
storytelling of a really premium brand
is flamingo estate so first theyve art
Direction and we'll hit art Direction a
little later on but the way Flamingo
estate immediately clamped into this
luxury feel was by basing the brand
around an State this is a physical real
place uh that the founder bought is
immaculately curated a perfect place to
Stage the kind of things that they do
they set a huge amount of the content
they do in and around it and I love this
release that they did with Benny rugs
looks like these like CGI and animated
campaigns that people like Jac moo were
putting out but it's real they're
literally at the Flamingo estate rolling
out a real rug uh just shot via drone
and with a place like this like look at
this place like I have this kind of cool
very budget version of this like behind
me but like look at this like this is
the frame with which they get to set the
lens of their brand and literally by
picking an amazing location and
investing in that and even if that ends
up being the Founder's house or it's a
studio that you convert to be super
interesting like the idea of taking a
physical location and using that to
create the World building of your brand
is super powerful and can speed up this
world building process considerably if
that place has a rich history and has an
En Enon that is conducive to amazing
storytelling which brings us to our
direction we talked about product
quality telling your product story
building a world around your product
having to do that over time but then
there's intention every single decision
that you make as a brand that wants to
justify a premium price point has to
have intention the more things you do
without intention the more you are
devaluing your brand either consciously
or subconsciously to Consumers that have
high expectations so what do I mean by
that I mean look at this Flamingo estate
popup there's a very Artful picture of
these puppies that's very well chosen as
something that they feel like is going
to get this right response look at me
even their mother promo like look how
architected this imagery this imagery is
this isn't your average promo and didn't
take a lot more than intention of
creation even the styling of these
individual photos it's an amazing style
photo another great one look at this
look this is like Immaculate brand
storytelling for a soap it's like three
images in this Carousel but they all
have like extreme intention put into
them and if you are a brand that wants
to be taken seriously to premium price
point every single decision being
intentional and every photo you choose
and every part of your website
everything you choose put on social
media every email campaign every font
it's one of those things where you
wouldn't don't agonize over it to the
point of in action but just have
intention have a single good idea or
concept just put one concept one thing
into everything you do says this is why
this is special all right I'm bring up
Kelly wler site so this is another great
one where everything is Art directed as
you should she's like an amazing
designer uh and then her Target
demographic is people who are spending
money on design look at this popup you
know I have a lot of conversations I
consult with a lot of Brands they're
trying to achieve this kind of luxury
idea and they don't want to do standard
things that brands do to get leads or
you know get emails oh we want to do a
popup that's not up to our brand
standard like well popups is how people
get emails so either you're going to get
emails or you're not going to get emails
unless you have some new grand idea but
how do you do it and do it from a luxury
Manner and literally it's just intention
this pop-up right here is gorgeous I as
their target consumer de graphic
demographic someone who wastes a bunch
of money on great design I see this
popup I go this is immaculate I am in
intrigued to sign up in a way that
normally you just X out and that all
took what again was intention of design
and everything everything that someone
says oh we can't do this up to our brand
standard it can be up to your brand
standard with design intention with art
direction if you don't have that
internally hire art directors to do this
is a a jewelry brand that I love one of
the chains I wear all the time is from
them but again every single choice in
this website was made attentional look
at that
[Music]
hand one strong decision inside any
photo or video or popup makes a huge
difference which leads me to content
again we'll have a whole video on
premium and luxury social media later
but G is a great example where it's like
if you are want people to have a premium
item in their lives showing them how to
use it tends to be really helpful and
there's styling content uh for clothing
which is really useful but I love Gia as
an example because of its its drink
content look at these
recipes immaculately art directed and it
gives me a reason as a frequent geia
Drinker I have a
literal just gear after after gear more
flavors in
here I buy a ton of those I I don't
drink alcohol because I'm going to go to
their website and I've made like seven
of these and they're fun and it's
interesting and it's a different way for
me to engage with the brand I know that
it exists and for them like this is just
a way to flex amazing our Direction and
then each one of these again is a
amazing social media post you can turn
this into a carousel just of the recipe
itself and you can turn it into a short
form video of someone making it you can
turn into a taste test of this one
versus that one or a collaboration with
an influencer with h bar being like Oh
are these three you know like oh let's
make the D all this is just the
foundation of making content but having
to live on web has this extra propensity
to like build the brand standard out
gentle monster another amazing kind of
art Direction example obviously very
like postmodern in this in this Jenny
collab um shout out Korea Bon Marella
but one of the things I like most about
this is their stories tab where their
stories tab is literally Instagram
stories like is using these same uiux as
the Instagram platform to be able to
navigate between their campaigns and
they're showing every campaign and if
you have campaigns you should be showing
all of them give people that full
diaspora of what the brand looks like
and what I like about what they've done
is you know you can definitely go and
dive in into these pretty extensive and
weird campaigns that they've done like
these AI student ID cards and interact
with them in different ways and again I
know a lot of Brands aren't be able to
afford to or do this honestly you can
get developers to be doing some stuff
like this for like low thousands of
honestly you're really [ __ ] killing
probably hundreds they just have a very
wide variety of things in here displayed
in a lot of different ways I was looking
for one that I was trying to find that
uh that had like a cake I don't think it
wasn't the marshell one um it was like
super interactive but doesn't really
matter art Direction intention thought
and this is taken to the like most
logical most intense conclusion of it
but then let's talk about Bridging the
Gap to real life that's the last piece
of this cuz premium experiences rarely
live just 100% online we hit this
concept of CRM for a second CRM you
customer relationship management you
know like I uh I have bought a lot from
Louis Vuitton at points in my life I
have a Louis Vuitton rep this is a
salesperson who is assigned to me who
has me inside sales for or whatever
custom proprietary platform they use
pipe Drive God knows and they know to
check in with me they know that I buy a
certain amount from them based on what I
buy access to other things I really want
something I have someone I can go to and
be like hey i' would like to get my
hands on this drop uh they get to
antagonize me when I dis leave vuon in
videos but that is how a lot of luxury
sales
function is actually have that personal
element and obviously they want to go
into store but you have contact with a
salesperson those sales people have
quotas they're tracking you they have
ability to have conversations just like
any B2B or Enterprise sales and brand
should be really really thinking like
that and try to bridge that Gap to in
real life whether it's pop-up experience
experiences like bass had like a luggage
wash recently that was a cool idea but
these brands are all doing that they're
doing it in different ways and you can
stay on the internet but like try to get
these conversations one to one zone in
on providing that premium experience so
asop we talked a bit about before scroll
down to the bottom of their website
video consultation so literally you can
sign up for free and get on a zoom with
a trained asop team member who a help
you buy gifts for people from asop so if
you're selecting something for your wife
or your husband your significant other
and don't know much about skincare boom
they'll help you and they'll do it on
Zoom amazing or if you actually just
want advice on your skincare routine in
regimen so I can go for 30 minutes and
be like I don't know how to use any of
this stuff can you advise me what to buy
to achieve X goal and they have a person
that will help you for a video
consultation if asop is doing this it's
because it makes them money if you are
trying to get sales for your smaller
brand you should be thinking about these
things if you have an email list and
they're not buying a bunch you should be
trying to get them into one-on-one
conversations free styling advice free
consultation hey I we office hours you
can talk to ask questions about the
product How likely do you think the
person is to go buy from you after they
have a one-on-one conversation about how
to use or style your product or how to
make recipes with it or your story of
your brand than if they didn't and even
just having that ability to have that up
there allows you to accrate those those
customers there's another exercise I do
a bunch in consultations is we'll
literally go through people's entire
customer database we'll take a VA be
like we're going to Google everybody
we're going to call out anyone who's an
influencer who has a really interesting
background works with the cool job
because guess what like maybe send them
a Christmas package also send every all
your best customers like send them
[ __ ] gifts send them cataloges ask
them if they want to preview the next
drop or have Early Access to stuff or if
they want to have to be advice in your
product road map like engaging with
those people is a huge missed
opportunity there's tons of brands just
don't take advantage of so this idea of
of CRM and putting everyone inside a
pipeline looking at your email list
getting people to sign in one-on-one
having ways to activate Monclair is
another uh great example where I believe
they actually offer like styling like
literally you can go in store or online
and they will have someone help you
style Monclair stuff with your existing
wardrobe live they they'll personalize
things you go and shop at the boutique
they'll actually offer styling I mean
that's a great opportunity for a luxury
brand to do that you should be thinking
about that too and I'll save Dunhill for
another video um this Dunhill case this
example of like cre a product for for
marketing is something that uh deserves
its own segment of video but this is
what you want think you want to justify
premium price points tell the story of
your brand make great products tell the
story of those products art direct and
have intention inside everything begin
to get those relationships from just
tons of people out there seeing your
stuff to onetoone relationships with
your best customers your biggest
customers or all your customers if you
can swing it uh if you're beginning to
work through all those things and
presenting those stories online in
multiple ways you are building a world
for your brand you are giving your brand
longevity and life and value and whether
you are just starting or you're doing it
someday or you're already deep in it
like these are the things to talk about
and um I work on doing things like this
at a super high level with with big
Brands um where at Van where I'm Crea
from residence we do like these really
like large scale websites and branding
projects for larger groups but there's a
hundred ways to look at it from small to
large I'm bringing the same level of
atttention in what I'm creating as a
brand that's coming from from nothing
and I think no matter where you're at if
you ever want to command those price
points if you're selling a brand on
value that's a whole different story and
like this video is not for you if you're
building a brand on something bigger
than that then you should be conscious
of these activities like writing them
down and using them as as North Stars
any questions about this kind of stuff
as always just hit me up um drop them in
the comments whatever it is I'm going to
do a series on on this that goes beyond
like the web I talked about here today
so any ideas that would be good for that
just let me know but uh social media is
definitely one of the ones we're going
to hit and we'll be back soon thank you
so much for watching appreciate you all
so much