In this video, we are going to talk
about the art direction, creative
direction, and marketing of technology.
And thank you to HubSpot for sponsoring
this video. There's a million things
here we can do. We're going to zone in
on one, visual worlds. How do you create
a visual language for a modern brand?
Where does that even play out? And then
we're going to dive into Apple. Why I
love to use them as an example is not
just cuz they're iconic, but because
people focus on the wrong things.
Really, I feel like the best way to
learn from them is to look at all of
their different eras and then map that
to things you can learn about how you
visually present a brand and orchestrate
campaigns at different points in a
brand's arc. We're going to go through
some of their best campaigns. We're
going to go through their different
stages in history and then dive into a
bunch of other really interesting
brands. Cash App and how they developed
a new unique visual world around
finance. What's happening with
technology and media and how people
present it. The era of artifacts and how
brands are using product as marketing
even when they make completely different
things. We'll cover nothing. We're going
to cover venture capital, Teenage
Engineering, Teenage Engineering. I'm
super excited to make this video. But I
think that anyone who's a creative,
anyone that works in technology, is a
part of this ongoing kind of complex
taste discord there will really enjoy.
Let's lock in. So first, why listen to
me about this? For those unfamiliar with
my full arc, after my career as a
designer where I started in lifestyle
brands, food and beverage, hospitality,
I worked in technology for an extended
period. I worked for defense companies
on campaigns there, for optics in the
outdoor space. And then where I gained a
lot of rungs in my career was working in
marketing for consumer and commercial
drones. From before they were regulated
camera drones as we know them, to when
they were first sold into big box
retail, to their applications in the
world we see them today. And from there,
I was one of the partners that started a
contract engineering firm that still
exists and has 40 plus engineers. Where
we have everything from government
security contracts to doing development
for software, hardware, anything that
touches an autopilot or telemetry has
been our specialty there. And it's funny
because that's where so much of my
expertise is, up until the last about
decade, was the one I've done the least
content about because often when you're
working you want to do content about
things you love, not necessarily the
things that you're in deep on. But now
with the discourse where it is around
technology, it's a perfect time to put
some of that expertise into the
zeitgeist and talk about some of these
things. Now starting with Apple, if I
was being generic, if this was a generic
design video, I would talk about
simplicity is power. Look at the text on
this page. Look at the white space. Look
at how they photograph their product.
Apple doesn't design minimal because
it's trendy. They design minimal because
it clarifies intelligence. That's what
Chat GPT would say. Clarity signals
intelligence. But this was a different
era. This doesn't work for your average
company anymore. That's not what you
should learn from them. So many things
have been pulled from this and inspired
this. Like this Garamond font is a great
example. I saw a note when the new
National Design Institute put out this
this new website and incredible looking
government website. And there are a lot
of people being like, well, it looks so
good because it's using Garamond. It's
using a derivative of the Apple font.
Instrument Serif is the I think the
generic Google font version. And that's
why it feels so credible. That's one of
many reasons the design is. But everyone
will always refer back to Apple as the
minimalist king, as the font king. And
that's not what we can learn from this.
What we can learn is stages where you're
at as a company. Let's start with one of
the most known Apple campaigns, Think
Different. This is a campaign that's
constantly referenced as one of the best
marketing campaigns in history. Where
they put iconic people at the top of
their fields and had them represent the
Apple brand. Someone who thinks
different. This was an important part
for Apple at this arc in its brand.
Steve Jobs had just come back. They
needed a campaign to signify what they
stand for. When we talk about the eras
of Apple, I want you to map to whatever
brand you work for or have, where it is
inside its cycle of its life. For many
brands, whether you've just started in a
product or you're in the market but
haven't really gotten that fit, that
take off, what you're missing is you
haven't developed a brand worth
watching. This was Apple at that same
time, where they had existed, they were
in the market, but they weren't worth
paying super close attention to. And if
that attention was paid, they didn't
know what that brand really stood for.
Or it stood for something kind of far
different than where they wanted to go.
This is a common problem in many brands'
arcs. And this is where something like
an extremely strong campaign can begin
to bridge the gap. Now, in 1997, they
leveraged the tools they had at the
time. That was an era of monoculture.
Celebrity themes where all these people
were known by everybody. That's not the
era that we're in today. And we've
actually seen a company in a almost
similar scenario, not quite the Steve
Jobs coming back, but a company trying
to give you a reason why should I watch
this brand? What do they stand for in a
complicated space? Riff off this
campaign. So, this is Claude's campaign.
Keep thinking. It's a direct play on
Think Different. It wants to encourage
those same people in the new iterations
of them what they can do to be their own
unique selves. But, this is the biggest
shift that we have in terms of how you
think about creative direction, culture,
celebrity, and who and how concepts
represent your brand to today. Is there
aren't famous figures in this. They're
not going and getting Miles Davis, or
even the popular people of our time.
Instead, it is in the hands of the
people. They are showing you a version
of you, a person with a garage band, a
person out hiking, a person trying to
tinker and solve with nary a phone in
sight. They're putting normal people in
aspirational scenarios, and using that
as the thinking. That's a perspective
shift I think everyone should be
thinking about in this era, is that the
individual in our world where it's not
15 minutes of fame, everyone has years
of micro fame, basically. How do you put
everyone front and center inside a
campaign? That's an iteration on that.
Going into their second era I'll discuss
here, the iconic product era, the iPod
era. This iPod campaign, quite
legendary, and it positioned the
product, the artifact itself, as
something that by its form factor could
become prolific within the market. And
this is another thing that a brand at a
certain stage in its arc should think
about. I talked about the Claude Keep
Thinking campaign. And if that got you
thinking about how to actually put
Claude to work beyond just prompting it
back and forth, then this free guide
from HubSpot called the Claude Co-Work
Stack is worth checking out. So, here's
what's happening. Co-workers
fundamentally different from regular AI
flows. You've probably heard about it,
don't know how to actually use it. Right
now, most marketers are copy-pasting
context into AI one prompt or project at
a time. Then their output is device
versus deliverables. You still have to
go actually build the thing or complete
the work. So, Co-work flips that. You
give Claude access to your actual files,
your campaign data, your browser, and it
works through the problem in the
background while you do something else.
HubSpot put together 12 prompts
specifically engineered around this.
Local folder access, background
processing, real file creation, not like
generic write me a blog post stuff.
Think about entire campaign assets built
out across channels, deep research done
while you're working on something else.
And my favorite part is the marketing
campaign builder. You drop in your brief
and your brand assets, and Claude does
the heavy lifting of what can happen
across every channel. So, go check out
the free Claude Co-work stack under the
link in the description. And thanks to
HubSpot for making this resource and
sponsoring this video. We are in a
visual era, a packaging era. I saw a
video from Casey Lewis who does the
After School newsletter the other week
where she was talking about how Gen Z
was consuming things that look good on
camera. That was There was an article
written about this and like data out
there supporting it, which makes
complete sense if you live on the
internet, but is a new concept for older
people, for technology people. And we're
in this era where your value proposition
is a lot based on the aesthetics of your
product. In almost any consumer good, in
almost any piece of hardware, it has to
be a flex in itself. You may have saw
the video where I reviewed the friend,
the AI pendant, and a lot of it came
down to just a bad industrial design,
right? Where if that was a industrial
design, whether the product works or
not, it signaled something that looked
more akin to what Frank Ocean did with
Homer or had a cultural play. There's
more of a chance for acceptance. You see
this now in all these headphones
beginning to look like earrings. It's
how do you engineer the product into an
artifact? But then campaigns like this
and the art direction, creative
direction of it have to accentuate that.
They have to put the product out into
the culture. You need to reinforce that
visual language. And so, it's a
worthwhile thing to think about when you
look at through lines. What am I going
to do for my visual campaign, for my
social media, for what I'm putting
inside my ads? How do I continue these
things? Do you have an iconic
silhouette? Or do you have a unique look
and feel? And if not, do you have a
unique visual language for your
products? Teenage Engineering has done a
decent job of this, where you kind of
expect this look and feel that they have
on everything, and they extend it into
different universes. Where you begin to
recognize the sampler, you know that
they can live as much in the world of
reggae as they can live in a medieval
world. The colors, the combos, it feels
a certain way. And in the marketing,
their product form factors, this
language can kind of take over. But
nothing near where where Apple has gone.
Perhaps one of the biggest plays on this
would be the Rhode lip gloss iPhone
holder, where they were able to not just
make the lip gloss with its lightly
unique form factor into a marketing
play. The They are selling a product
that is also the marketing. Nothing has
been working hard on doing this in a
competitive space to Apple, right?
because there's always going to be
someone to position against, no matter
how big a company becomes. So, they have
been looking at how do they have this
almost like noisier visual language that
counter positions itself against the
clean lines of Apple and all their
clones. The dot matrix aesthetic. But
the campaign I think the most people can
learn from. In the era of Apple that I
think is actually the most impactful
from a marketing perspective, is the
shot on iPhone era. As part of my
toolkit when I work on creative strategy
for brands, whether it's organic or for
ads, I have a list of formats I know
work psychologically inside of a piece
of content. And one of them is what's
called prove it. So, for instance, if
you're working on a product that has a
24 hours and it doesn't wear off, how
can you show a full 24 hours? Like
inside your video or your ad? How can
you take someone on that journey? Prove
that the 24 hours there in the harshest
circumstances. Morphe was a brand I work
with is always doing this well, right?
They allow us the setting spray for
makeup, and they're on their stories
they are doing
like some super intense workout in
Pilates classes in partnership with a
studio, where they have the girls
showing before and after you get a deep
sweat or you get whatever in there, how
the makeup stays on. Prove it is in
their DNA. But shot on iPhone is one of
the most interesting examples of this,
in that you want to prove that it takes
good pictures, use the pictures in the
campaigns. That's an easy line to to
cross. But then, when you start to
really think about it, you're like,
"Wow, they can blow those up to the
sides of buildings. You can put an
iPhone image on a billboard." When you
begin to look at this as it compounds
over time, when sometimes it's
relatively normal photos, and sometimes
it's really artful, interesting photos,
they're showing you the arc of the
complete depth of possibility there. And
they carried this over into full music
video shot on iPhone. It was prove it
embodied, and obviously even better
because you can actually turn it into
the asset of the campaign. But for every
brand that has a value proposition where
you are selling a transformation, which
is so many products, and Apple for a lot
of people is basically selling in your
hand that you have creativity at your
fingertips. You have better photos. You
can capture your life in an amazing way.
How you show that transformation is one
of the most effective techniques to
bring into our direction. So, if you're
thinking about, "What is the visual
theme for a shoot? What are we going to
show?" How are you doing that prove it?
How is that happening within it? If you
have a rain jacket, and you're taking it
out inside the harshest conditions, and
showing that they're dry underneath. And
then, how do you elevate that visually
and conceptually on top of it? But the
root of that is going to be one of the
most effective things you have in your
toolkit for any level of creative work
is getting back to that core point of
how you integrate the product is proving
it. And there's obviously a million
other ways you can do it, and selling
the lifestyle, and concepts, and themes,
and ideas, and user journeys. But when
it comes back to it at its root, what is
going to be the most effective? Well,
likely be this. Then I want to talk
about the era we're in now, because a
lot of people do look at Apple. I
remember thinking this myself, too. I
was one of the creators that was invited
to Apple's WWDC last year. So, I'm
there. It's iJustine. It's Marques
Brownlee. It's Rachel from Linus Tech
Tips. It's Emily from Feed Me. And I'm
watching all the things that are
happening. I'm watching the campaigns,
and what they're rolling out. And this
all of a sudden is around F1, the F1
movie. Apple's like extremely integrated
in the F1 movie, right? And they have
all the cinema that they're integrated
with, cuz now they have their own doing
TV. And you begin to realize this is not
I mean, look at the eras. Like, they
don't want to compete inside this the
social media grind that the rest of us
are on, inside the normal ad buying
grind. When you are at a level of which
they are, you need to be be intertwined
with culture at the highest level with
true monoculture action that represents
the brand right, which is Brad Pitt
movies, which is the Apple Music is the
Super Bowl halftime show sponsor
multiple years in a row. Now if we look
at what does a company that is a leader,
what do they do to capture the premise
that they're on top in that same way?
That's a very different challenge than
thinking about a campaign like think
different. They have no need for that at
this current point until they reach
another inflection point like that,
which maybe they get to at a certain
time. But it's not the same. We can't
expect the same marketing at companies
at different points in their arc. And if
you are working at a big business like
that and you are trying to get some like
interesting niche initiative or campaign
off the ground, you have to really
think, is this at enough scale that it
aligns with the vision? If you are
working at a Fortune 500 company and you
really want to be the one that gets them
into streaming as a marketing engine, we
want to do campaigns with these light
personalities, that may not have the
scale that's necessary to make an impact
there. But if you were like, hey, we
could do this with a hundred streamers.
If you can corner the market on
something, the ambition level needs to
rise with the level at which the company
executes. It's a big reason why
creatives who have more niche ideas
struggle inside some of these larger
scenarios. Now I want to talk about
building a visual world today. Who's
doing it differently now? And one of the
most interesting ones to me is Cash App.
And they have their design and brand
guidelines public, which I think is fun.
But where I'm most interested in them is
they are extremely counter-positioned,
right? So you look at all the existing
banking and finance infrastructure. The
colors, the visuals, everything wants to
promote safety, security, longevity. But
it's from these institutions that people
don't really trust. They're not really
built into their lives. They feel
antiquated. And Cash App from every
piece of visual is meant to feel
integrated into its users' life. And
they've built this design language
around that. And so I was at the last
Cash App event in New York, too, where
they were debuting their their fall 25,
like all their new releases. And I was
chatting with the design team there, and
they were talking about the process with
which they do that. And some of the
concepts that really stood out to me in
that conversation was the idea like
having fun in the mundane. So basically,
there are all these little micro moments
in your day. How do you have some joy in
them? How do you make them personal? And
in this fall release is when they were
giving people the option to be able to
choose from photos behind when they send
people money. You could choose all these
interesting graphics that you could send
along with reimbursing somebody for
dinner, etc. A little micro moment in
there. When when the brand was talking
about how they made all the items they
had, they're basically they just gave
all these different graphics. The ones
that you see here inside these
animations, everything from bread to
croissants made of dollars to matcha to
like these slices of cake. And when they
were talking about the process to come
up with all this, they were basically
saying that the design team's coming up
with thousands and thousands of items.
Where they're looking at the data from
the transactions people make. What do
people actually buy? And that starts as
basically their starting point. All
these things people are purchasing,
let's use those to create iconography.
They're rooting it in the visual
language of the user and it's in mass. I
said thousands of items. And they're 3D
scanning a lot of things in the real
world. So they have these kind of
realistic things that they're able to
then pull on to make graphics like what
you see here. And that visual language
of the user is a really important thing
to think about as you look at what the
visual language of technology looks
like. Back to that theme I had
discussing the claw app, it's no longer
about this hero celebrity or this hero
answer. It's about empowering that
individual and about showing that you
recognize their life. That's a marketing
concept that technologists need to wrap
their heads around. Especially in this
taste economy era where everyone's like,
"Oh, I need to have this taste or that
taste." What is the taste of your users?
What are they consuming? How can you
surprise them, delight them, educate
them, mirror them? Where you're showing
them that you understand them back. And
Cash App has done this in a few ways
that are interesting as well. One is the
design of the card. Right, this is an
artifacts in carousel where they've
actually collected the unique designs
people have done where they can
customize their own Cash App card. From
MF Doom to Vape Nation memes, all these
kind of funny sketches, the yin yang in
the design, all the way to like now
there's a Brat Charli XCX card, right?
But it's turned into something that like
means something to somebody. Again, for
a little transactional thing, these are
fun, they're funny, and it's a moment
inside their users' lives that another
company doesn't own. They have it
uniquely. As just as unique as a metal
card from MX was where everyone took it.
I love to point to them as someone doing
it differently in a large established
industry. And they've done this on
social, too. As you may have noticed if
you are on the Cash App social media,
it's a wide array of content. Yeah,
yeah, you should see look at the top
here. I'm three of these last eight
reels. I'm one of several creators that
work with them. They have BK, Coffee, uh
the like skit creators. They have their
racers. So, they have a wide variety
from a from more business intellectual
creator like myself to more like skit
creators to what they have in racing.
They're building a world that mirrors
all the different things around their
users. Where it's going to be a variety
show versus just a singular brand ethos.
So, if you're not familiar with the
podcast TBPN, they're an extremely
popular podcast in technology. And they
announced a rebrand recently assisted by
Area. And this brand identity is applied
to their podcast and YouTube. You'll see
it's in the shyrons. They're doing a
couple things here I think are really
interesting that brands should be aware
of. One is they're using their brand
identity to establish credibility and
recognition, right? Which is what most
brand identities are. People seem to
have lost that. They'll think, "Oh, just
having it be nice establishes
credibility." For them, having it look
like a news network that's been around
forever, that operates at that level,
that's unique on a YouTube feed. Again,
I see this live streaming. It does not
look like anyone else's podcast. There's
a visual power there. It's done that
well. And then thinking about the
applications. So, obviously there's the
shyrons they have while they're talking
where they're able to cut a call out
different things that are going on and
different colorways and looks. How it
actually applies to social media. This
is one of the biggest things we look at
when you actually get into social.
First, branded content like this doesn't
work for everyone. But for podcasts or
for media networks or for people that
are making announcements, doing
carousels, it matters. Don't over design
into this. But if you are participating
in the culture and can do it at a high
level, you should. And this is something
we looked at when we were doing the
Brand Father's pod when we were trying
to get our identity redesigned. One of
the things we were requesting is stuff
like this, right? We want social
graphics where we want to call out
different events or news or things. And
the designers just kind of couldn't get
what actually works on social. There's a
dissonance there where you have a unique
advantage you can take advantage of if
you do understand it of I understand how
visuals are cool and I understand what
works on social media and I understand
what people are trying to do with their
content. And I can build identities and
systems and design to push that. And
this is something Area has done. I
imagine it's collaborative with what
TBPN is already working on to create
that level of identity. But this ties
into this idea of artifacts. Creative
direction and art direction now are more
tied into the fabrication of things than
ever. And do we have to make some big
blown up thing or create some set for
whatever video we're going to make or
the product itself is so tied into how
the content is made because of the
virality of product. But the TVP and
hats and jackets and polos have become
part of the identity, right? You can
only get them if you're a guest. They
send them to people after they're on the
show. But it's an artifact for the
brand. That's an extension of the brand.
It's a big part of the identity we look
at now for such a product driven, post
driven culture. And I think brands,
especially older technology brands,
don't realize what their brands can kind
of mean to people over time. Like the If
you haven't seen the Lockheed Martin
streetwear brand in Korea where they
have a kind of completely like full
complete selling lines. Perhaps the best
example is Anduril, the defense tech
company, making Game Boys out of the
same metal that they use inside their
rockets. Yeah, the same metal as attack
drones. Creating the artifacts and lore
is as much of creative direction, art
direction, and marketing now as some of
the initial value proposition stuff. The
objects matter and when they're whack,
it's actually the much worse. When it's
the same generic thing with another
piece of trash you have to throw away
versus taking the time to make anything
with a story. Now after artifacts, I
want to talk about the concept of
rituals as well. So when I was still
working in technology, one of the
software companies that I worked at was
funded by this company Lux Capital. We
got a six and a half million dollar seed
from them. And I remember at the time
they did a thing they did a quarterly
letter that they would send out about
the things that they were focused on as
a fund, what they're seeing, the
conditions everyone should be aware of.
It became a regular thing that everyone
who was kind of privy to it wanted to be
able to engage with it, read it, know
what they were saying. Then they began
releasing versions of this publicly as
well and you began to expect, what are
these people's regular thoughts on
technology? I think rituals like that
are really important for brands in this
space in particular to consider. The way
you see an Apple WWDC each year, even if
you're only doing it at the size that
you're at. And another one I want to
call out from them is they also have
like an event thing that they've done as
well. You can function them online but
they just have this risk gaming like
scenario based walk-throughs. Like
strategic multi-hour scenarios you can
work through with other people, salon
experiences. They are taking their idea
of venture capital, their idea of them
marketing these scenarios happening in
the world. They have to think through
from a fiscal perspective and how do
their portfolio companies navigate them.
And then putting scenarios out there of
those same problems that people can
actually go in and work and try to
solve. I thought it was a really unique
way to approach the marketing of venture
capital cuz we're seeing a lot of that
capital have to market way more now. And
what I want to call out on this is A16Z.
So, Andreessen Horowitz rebranded this
American dynamism rebrand you've likely
seen. They hired some of the initial
workers at TVPN who are understanding
savvy of new media. And they're doing
things like this, putting out American
dynamism carousels, right? Doing actual
well-edited interview reels. Carousels
from insights from Sam Altman using that
new branding. They're navigating the
modern language in a way that almost no
other VC firm is. This one actually did
well. These startups don't exist yet,
right? A lot And what's interesting
about this is they're in the carousel
game, right? The carousel game on
Instagram right now, if you have
credibility, is a great one. If you
don't have credibility, you're just
another carousel in the noise. You are
literally putting stuff out there that
no one's going to ever associate with
you. It's why I put my face on all my
carousels. At least I'm associated with
it. But if you're A16Z, if you're
someone who has that clout, like ID
Magazine is another good example. ID
Magazine is putting out you know, a lot
of publications that finally caught on
that oh, there's some social media we
understand we're not going to get
torched at. It's going to be carousels.
Basically, A16Z has done this where it's
it gives them immediate cred, right?
Where you're like, wow, this stuff is a
thing I've heard of if I'm in that
niche. There's content coming out here
and they're in that social conversation
effectively. What I think is interesting
is it's a few steps from right. And this
is another big thing we look at Apple in
context. Everything for Apple is always
perfect. Everything is always set up
exactly right. They are the brand
marquee of perfection as a brand value.
Is it up to the standard? Was it Steve
Jobs' standard or the standard they have
now? But this is not where A16Z is.
That's an important distinction cuz it's
happening for a reason. They are trying.
These are attempts. They are new at
social. They are figuring it out. A lot
of it is not good. It's several steps
from right. But enough of it is good.
They're putting wins on the board and
they're actually actively participating.
And that's what most technology
companies are missing now, especially
established, especially VCs. They're so
afraid not have the perfect strategy.
They're so afraid to have things flop.
Well, this is an iterative scenario. You
have to be in the arena. There is no way
you can be out of the arena trying
You cannot have eight levels of
approval. You cannot have the perfect
campaign. You have to be iterating.
You're not going to figure it out
because every single brand has to have
the combination of its account, its
team, its fans, and each algorithm. You
have to decipher that. There is no
silver bullet. I'm one of the foremost
experts in the world on brand social
media after we've done thousands of
brands in Cut 30. And I will tell you as
that expert that you cannot I cannot
walk in and give you a silver bullet
that will 100% succeed until we
understand the interaction between your
customers on social media, your brand on
social media, and the content formats
that are there, and what's happening in
the algorithm at any given time. It is a
moving target. And by the time you do
some fancy approved campaign, that
target may already have moved again. So,
they're doing the exact right thing
here. It's not the Steve Jobs era. It's
the in the arena era, the imperfect era.
That's what any technology company
watching this, one of the big things I
would take away. So, we've covered a lot
of concepts here. I could yap about this
for hours, honestly. Maybe we'll do more
If you like more technology videos, if
you want me to break down other
companies or all things in there. I'm
debating trying this more. I'd love to
talk about tech. If it does resonate,
something I would love to talk about
significantly more. And if you are in
this space, you're looking to learn
these creative strategy toolkits, all of
the various programs and newsletters I
think uh that I have are down below. We
are working with brands to train their
teams. We're working with individual
people all the time on working through
these exact scenarios. As always, I
appreciate y'all watching. We're going
to keep doing new topics and new things,
and I appreciate y'all bearing with it.
Thank you.