All right, today we are going to hit a
subject near and dear to my heart.
Making money on social media and how to
run a successful personal brand account.
Everything that's changed so far in
2026. This week marks my 3year
anniversary on Instagram, about 3 and a
half, making content total. And I have
made a video every single day for over
a,000 days now. In the event I didn't
post for a day, I made up with it for
two the same week. And although it was a
rough start for any of you that were
there at the beginning, it has
significantly changed my life. But in
this video, I'm going talk about what's
different going into 2026, the
commodization of Faceless and Carousels,
with so many new creators, what's still
working, and we're going to go through
some specific formats and creators that
are standing out. Then we're going to
talk about how to zone in on a niche. If
you have a niche that you want to go in
on, what are the different content
types, and how do you position yourself
to design an offer that makes you money
if you are selling a service to position
yourself to get more work? If you do
want to set yourself up to get brand
deals, what does that look like? And I'm
going talk about the traps that people
fall into. What's happening with high
production right now and where that's
going? What happens to people that just
copy and look the same as others? Talk
about the three levels of social media
in 2026 for personal brands. And we're
going to have a lot of fun along the
way. I am hosting a monthly community
call as always. This Sunday, February
22nd, I believe the link is down below,
is all about workshopping creative
strategy and creative direction to be
able to provide guidance on whether it's
brands or personalities to get better at
content. So, if you want to join us and
workshop live on Sunday, the link to
that is below. Let's lock in. What's
really interesting to me right now is
just how adopted the short form really
is. We have had a rash of new students
in Cut 30 who got the program
recommended to them by their teachers.
There are teachers in business school
are saying if you want to start a
business you need to go out there and
learn how to make content and start
learning now. That's the level of
adoption we're seeing. We have
journalists at major publications from
around the world who join. Everyone's
realizing that all the traditional
structure we had around attention is
shifting. And whether or not you want to
have a personal brand or not,
understanding it is crucial. I've been
in the middle of this for a while. It's
interesting to watch. But one of the
reasons I feel equipped to make a lot of
these videos and why I dislike watching
a lot of other gurus videos is they
don't have enough data points to really
look at it. So we've had 2,000 people
plus through Cut 30, the 30-day boot
camp we do. And Colin Lanfor, shout out
to the god, has all of them categorized
in a video database that we've built. It
tracks every person by cohort. It tracks
every graduate and what outlier videos
they have. Does it do 1.2x or 1.5x or
higher of performance? It also tracks
all of the accounts that I'm using for
my creative strategy work. all the other
accounts that we want to track around
the web in one centralized location that
we can query and see trends from. In
addition, I'm obviously working with
brands heard me talk about my work with
Morphe, but I did prior at Gel Blaster
or Lift Boils or any of these brands
that are out there where we are still
doing active creative strategy and
reviewing tons of briefs and competitive
analysis each week. And I'm creating
videos still every day in my own right.
And as many of you know, I am partnered
in the firm that manages me, DMG, that
manages a bunch of influencers in
different niches. And one of the biggest
superpowers from this is the ability to
see exactly what's happening. I know
every single month from the hundreds of
creators that are in cut 30 exactly what
being posted works and then we have data
to back it up from the aggregator. This
allows us to actually have a finger on
the pulse and then see when we introduce
new strategies or types, does it work?
What's the adoption like? It's been
critical for my work as a strategist.
But in addition to this, in the first
time in December, we ran this thing
called Cut 30 Legends which was for
grads or large accounts only where we
were working specifically with people
that had bigger social media accounts.
And this was really interesting because
a lot of the conversation was around how
are you monetizing? What does your
funnel look like? What do your offers
look like? Are you getting brand deals?
How do you position yourself? How do you
plan your content as a successful
personal brand? And it was interesting
to hear those questions and hear what
those people are dealing with. I'm going
to talk about a lot of it in this video.
First, let's talk about what's changing.
So, at this point, as of about 3 weeks
ago, it's pretty official that the
Instagram and Tik Tok algorithms,
especially once US control took over Tik
Tok, are now radically different. The
same things very rarely work on both. We
still encourage people to cross post,
but you will find it is a very different
network to grow on. But one of the key
differences is how big carousels are,
especially designed carousels on
Instagram and how much spam there is for
simple carousels on Tik Tok. Basically,
all these software apps are spamming
hundreds or thousands of carousels each
day with AI in the default Tik Tok
fonts. And there is just so much default
carousel content on Tik Tok that it's
really invalidated the formula if you
want to grow a carousel account for
anything but getting the cheapest of
attention. Basically eliminating a
pretty powerful segment of the market
there from being able to succeed. It
only works for personal brand accounts
now if it's in conjunction and tying
into everything else you have going on
as a personal brand. And then on
Instagram, so many people are dropping
design carousels and these accounts blow
up and they get tons of followers. But
all of them I talked to a group of these
accounts like how can I monetize? how
can I make money? And for the most part,
most of them can't because the content
is so commodified. Brands don't want to
pay for it and they don't have enough
personality built up that people want to
buy their offers. So, they do monetize,
but it's really hard. And at the same
time, faceless content has gotten taken
over by all the AI accounts. There are
awesome AI aggregator accounts who are
making really beautiful looking stuff.
Whether you agree with it or not, the
content is impactful. But what this
means is there's so many of them. People
are doing it from around the globe that
again those views show up in the feed,
but they don't build affinity. And what
that has done is taken a lot of people
who are able to build faceless accounts
over the last few years and really made
it very hard for anyone to get actual
money at the end of the rainbow from
doing it. But what's good is the
personality still reigns supreme in all
of this. In a world where AI can
manufacture a fake influencer that looks
mediocre or a fake carousel or whatever
it is, actual stories, actual tea,
actual affinity, having real
conversations with your audience is the
separator. And you will see the people
that are doing really well on TikTok,
especially newer accounts, it's a
conversation. They respond in every
comment. They're doing reply videos from
those comments. They are sharing the
parts of their life. They are building
that gauge, particularly on that social
network, on personality. But one thing
that's happening that's crucial right
now on Instagram is the proliferation of
intelligent content. I want to call out
Zoe here. She makes intelligent content.
I believe she either works for or did
work for a VC and she's doing a format
that we call graphic YAP. I'll talk
about in a second, but she is doing
intellectual content, videos about real
technology, hot startup rounds, AI
agent, social networks, Apple's
acquisition, startup matrix. Far gone
are the days of like joke accounts or
thinking social media is unserious.
People are putting up major views
talking about real things and businesses
are doing this too, right? Doing design
history of a really specific stool or
design format, walking through the
particular choices of an item or the
news that happened. Educational content
is at an all-time high. She's doing like
an obsidian tutorial. We are getting
obscure here, but people do not want
surface level stuff, the same stuff
everyone knows. They want to go indepth.
And you're seeing content like how to be
disgustingly educated pop off. Even this
this design talk series that she has.
She's going into the manufacturing
processes to work on metal and putting
up serious views, right? It says 10,000
likes, right? Six figure views. We are
in a hyperintellectualized world where
people who consume online, if you do
want to reach an intelligent consumer,
they are there waiting for you and they
want to be rewarded with really
interesting stuff. So the format that
appeals most is what you see here,
almost all these examples I've had, what
we call a graphic yap. A lot of people,
including myself, came up in the green
screen era. You would talk over graphics
on a green screen. That still works
well, but a lot of people have found it
effective and easier, especially now, to
do this. Position yourself halfway on
screen, eyes slightly above level in
whatever setup you want, and put
graphics over you while you talk
relatively rapidly to help make your
points aesthetically while you're
talking over them. This is a format that
I do as well. Doesn't matter if you do
it on an iPhone or you do it on a Pro
Cam, but for instance, this is me
talking about couches in the same exact
way in format. I'm talking about what
they mean from a luxury perspective. I'm
literally putting images over me while I
talk in that same exact way. But there's
never been a better time to do
intellectual content on the internet
because the algorithms reward it. And
you know what's nice is when you follow
or like content like that shows you tons
of other creators and there's huge
conversations right now going on around
taste, going on around design, about
startups and technology and about
hospitality, which we'll get to in a
minute. They're just waiting for more
experts and interesting people to join
with algorithm support. But one of the
biggest changes around this is this idea
that I cannot state enough that
personality is everything. We are in a
copycat world of content. A lot of
content looks alike. It sounds alike.
People literally put my scripts into
chat GPT and then put the output on the
other end out and call it their own
content with the same hooks. In a world
of this where that stuff can put up
views, what do you do that actually
resonates? How do you get that bottom
line of what makes you money? And
personality based content is the
strongest point of this. When I look
back at that thousand videos I made,
what's the biggest regret I have? is
that at several points during that on
Tik Tok, I started making more candid
videos where I'm talking about the
vacation I went on or how I made money
in this or why I married an extroverted
spouse as an introvert and begin to talk
more and more about my life, build
rapport with the audience, have them
learn more from me than rather just
value and advice. And every time I made
a few and then just got caught up on my
normal content flow cuz it just makes a
lot of money. And my biggest regret is I
just did not continue that continually
so people have more affinity with me in
particular versus just the value I
provide. And you'll see the creators
that are succeeding now from day one are
having a combination of those, right?
You can put up a lot of views that
intellectual content, but if no one
cares about you, it's just views unless
you have a great offer for them. But if
you add that personality on top of it
where you're actually explaining a bit
of what happens in your life, where
people really feel like they get to know
you, you can do really well with I want
to call out uh Rye, who I met at a cash
app event, who does an amazing job of
this on TikTok. So, he talks a lot about
his financial life as a younger person,
credit cards he's using, financial
decisions he's made, how he's investing,
but in the same time, he takes you along
on his life, on every vlog, on every
decision, on going shopping to replace
an iPad. And you really feel like you
know him. He's done an excellent job at
his core niche, which is basically
educating you on financial products that
I'm sure makes him a lot of money. And
then also on the back half of that,
making you really feel like he's a
friend that you have in your life from
the content that goes on screen. If you
are developing a plan for personal brand
in 2026, that split I just outlined is
extra crucial. The graphic YAP format
where you are talking about true
intellectual stuff, not just some
low-grade and you're doing
your research and you're putting real
work in to make a video or two a week in
that style, and you are backing it up on
the other half with actual content where
people can get to know you in different
ways is what is going to make creators
who actually generate money from social
media. So, next up, we're actually going
to talk about finding your niche and
doing that and the exact content types
you should work on. And so, I want to
call my guy Brody here. Bernie is a
videographer and editor. He's been with
me on my China trips. He was with me at
Premier Vision last year. He shot some
of the videos you see on this YouTube.
And he started making content maybe a
year ago. He did cut 30. He was making
content about content, giving advice for
making better videos. I remember at the
time being like, "Hey, there's a lot of
people who do that." And I don't really
think this is going to be that amazing.
You need to find something you're
interested in or your niche. And it's
funny is uh at some point a few weeks
ago, he started making videos about a
thing that he's passionate about,
gaming. and his gaming videos have way
more views than the content videos ever
did because you can tell he's really
interested in it. It's compelling and
it's more of a niche than more people
talking about content on the internet.
But then it's also led to people
reaching out to him in that niche to do
the work that he is already good at.
There is a superpower in talking about
the thing you're passionate about. There
is also a superpower in locality. This
is Sam. He's a friend of mine who was in
cut 30 recently where he's following the
easiest way to success right now where
he is talking about the area he lives.
He's talking about the South Bay, Roondo
Beach, Manhattan Beach. and he's
providing recommendations and starting
conversations there around simple
things. The best sushi events that are
happening, the best dumpling spot, what
homes cost. Algorithms are built for
localized content. You've heard me talk
about this before, but that doesn't mean
that you need to just be a OC food
account or a Athens, Georgia tour guide.
That's a leverage point to bring in your
expertise, right? So, I've known Sam
from the internet for a long time. He's
built tons of businesses. He had a
really cool website business. He's done
a lot of interesting stuff in tech. He's
built apps. And so he has an interesting
perspective as a business person, as
someone who knows how businesses work,
who knows how technology can impact them
to be able to take something like a
localized audience, build an expertise
and have something interesting there.
But if I was any person starting on
social media right now who didn't know
what I actually wanted to do, I would
start as a local tour guide. So for
instance, if I tomorrow could no longer
make content about marketing, I want to
grow as big as possible, I would be a
design tour guide for LA. Go from a
tasteful perspective. What should people
do in LA? I would be critiquing the
actual design and production of the
stuff that's there. Going to the
expensive shops saying, "Are these jeans
worth $2,000 going to the new place that
opened and critiquing the interiors or
saying this or that?" Or doing tasteful
person's guides to ice cream, sushi,
coffee, boba, museums, bookstores
relentlessly until I figured out what I
wanted to build on top of that because I
would get an audience of people that
live there and people that are traveling
there interested in that niche. and the
algorithm is excellent at showing that
to people. And so for those of you that
don't know where you want to build, that
is 100% the place that I would start.
And this ties really well into why
hospitality content goes so well
currently. I'm going to break down two
of my favorite accounts in hospitality
in the video formats that any expert can
use here in a sec. But first, if you
work in marketing or run content for a
brand, then this free report from
HubSpot is actually one you need to
read. It's called the 2026 state of
marketing report, and it breaks down
where marketing is actually headed right
now. specifically, how to scale with AI
without turning into a content farm, and
how to build real brand trust when
everyone's fighting for the same
attention. Inside the report, they cover
three big shifts. One, brand point of
view is becoming a real growth engine,
similar to what I'm talking about here
with personalities. As AI floods the
market with content, brands with a clear
perspective are standing out, and ones
without a clear perspective are getting
buried. And the report shows which
branding investments are actually
delivering ROI right now and examples of
what that perspective means. Second, AI
is a baseline now, not the
differentiator. 81% of marketers say
this is the biggest disruption in 20
years and 80% are already using AI for
content creation. So the question isn't
whether you're using it, it's how well.
And third, humanled marketing is still
what wins trust and revenue. The data
shows that audiences reward brands that
feel real and authentic that are
actually helpful, not just automated and
optimized. And we see this play out on
social every day. And my favorite part
is the section on brand POV. It lines up
with everything I talk about on this
channel. Having a sharp, distinctive
perspective is what separates you from a
sea of AI generated noise. This report
backs it up with real data on what's
actually working. If you want to
understand the shifts happening in
marketing right now and make smarter
decisions about where to put your
energy, you can get this report for free
at the link in the description. And
thank you so much to HubSpot for
sponsoring this video. All right, so I
want to call out one of my personal
favorite accounts right now, which is
first class jerk. Uh Adam Love is his
name on Tik Tok. And he is a travel and
hospitality content creator. Why I like
his content so much is that he doesn't
just play one note. He does multiple
things that interest me and engage me
around the niche of travel and
hospitality in general. And one of them
is he shares news, right? Virgin just
brought back this specific thing. He's
using the carousel format to share
announcements and things that have been
happening. This is where I love
carousels. Carousels are a great content
pillar if you're doing a lot of other
types of content already. They can help
you reach your existing audience well
tap into new localized audiences and
they're easy to create. He does these
compilations of rules. He actually
intersects
them their favorite hotel location. He
will put that into videos and carousels
as well. There's a community aspect to
what he's doing. Probably my favorite
part of that is the fact that he's
seeing who follows him, engaging them
immediately, and then putting that
content on the timeline, and it makes it
feel like there's a flywheel in the
community happening there. We DM
celebrities who follow FCJ, here are
their favorite hotel stays, part five.
Shout out Bear Grills. Absolute legend.
But in addition to opinion pieces and
curation, he's building credibility by
going to these places, putting his face
in front of them. And this is a key
thing. You will see on my channel, I
review products now physically in hand
because I've talked about enough stuff
on green screen. Anyone can do that.
Anyone can make up those things. But if
you have something tactile in your hands
or you go to a real place, the way I was
going to China to talk about clothing
production back when that was something
I was really interested in, gives you a
layer of credibility that other accounts
can't have. When you look at all of the
massgenerated stuff, everyone's making
the same carousels. Everyone's copying
each other's videos. What they can't
copy is having the personality, the
resources, and the connections to
actually go show that you're in the
streets, for lack of a better term, cuz
or inside the castle in this case. Now,
he does an excellent job with that
balanced with his other content. day
four of touring the best hotels in New
York. In addition to the more timely
stuff, this is a perfect example of the
content pillar system I preach all the
time where he has multiple formats that
he repeats from news-based carousels to
curating from his audience to talking
about concepts and ideas in the niche to
actually going and doing physical tours
of places. And so there's always
something new and exciting there and you
might get reeled in with one format then
learn a lot from the others. And so
another accountant in the same niche and
uh cut 30 grad want to shout out Ryan
who does in hospitality. He does this
and I want to break down what he does
here and how that kind of leads to his
offer flow as well. So he is a
hospitality consultant. He is helping
hospitality brands. So he has a lot of
green screen takes but following a
similar formula right where he is doing
versus videos. One of my favorite
techniques where you compare two things
against each other. He's doing videos
about how things are dying and he's also
doing videos about the future. This is a
three tiered strategy. I'll break it
down again in a second for coming up
with video concepts. That is amazing.
He's also breaking down history. So, he
will go into a history of the Fairmont
hotels. Then he'll go into what their
future looks like in the next video. So,
almost like a miniseries carousels on
what trends look like. This is how you
position yourself well as an expert.
He's done an excellent job doing it. And
I like to call it for everybody. You
scroll down on his account. He's only
been doing this for a few months, but
he's been on a grind posting lots of
videos. And you'll see these. This is 60
days ago, 90 days ago, and he's getting
20 likes, couple hundred views, and he's
just yapping in front of the bookshelf.
And then he's moving into the green
screen. Still not putting up great
numbers, but he's staying consistent.
Okay, now we're starting to hit. And
then he starts getting thousands of
likes. And then that stays consistent
from there where his views and his
interest are doing really well. And the
playbook I want to call out, this isn't
about hospitality. There's plenty of
hospitality content. If you're not
already an expert, I wouldn't go back
hop into that niche. But in any other
niche you're talking about, if you're in
design, if you're in creativity, if
you're in marketing, if you're in legal,
you're in accounting, whatever it is,
when you're setting yourself up as a
personal brand, this is the formula to
work at versus content. Comparing one
thing versus another. Old school versus
new school, cheap versus luxury, gap
versus acrruel, comparison beats
explanation almost every time. Number
two is history. Like those deep dives
and graphic gaps I presented before go
into interesting things in the niche.
I'm doing a video like this in like two
weeks about truffles. I'm giving the
whole history of how truffles turn
synthetic, China's production of
truffles, how the impacted truffle
supply chain, and why that means that
most people have never actually really
tasted truffle. It's a history video,
right? You're giving context. You're
getting people in by showing them what
you're passionate about. You can do this
in any niche. Inerson review, you'll
notice Ryan's reviewing spots in
Toronto. He's going to hotels where he
lives and giving feedback. You know,
Toronto is not the most glamorous
market, right? It doesn't matter where
you are, but where can you show that
expertise in person? What can you have
in hand is a crucial differentiator as
more and more people make review and and
content where they're giving opinion.
How can you tactically show that you
really do it? And then there's the
future. Ryan's killer at this. He's
always putting out what is this future
of this type of hospitality? What is the
future of this hotel group? What is the
future of bar consumption? If Gen Z is
doing X or Y, giving predictions of what
things look like is a way to establish
expertise and more importantly stimulate
conversation because people will have
opinions on it. The thing I want to add
on for anyone following this formula is
to have a relentless CTA. So you will
see Ryan in stories a lot being like,
"Hey, I'm taking on a new project of
this type or that type. I'm trying to
learn about X, so I'm looking for a
client in Y." And he's always asking for
people that are looking for help
restoring their bar, working on their
hotel. I know a lot of people who are
running this run the email funnel,
right? It's saying, "Hey, get on my
email list, join the Substack, and then
they will begin to pitch their offers
inside of there." When you're talking
about making money, get this making
money section. Now, there's really two
key angles to do this. Brand deals,
that's number one. That is a much harder
road, not what I recommend for most
people, but we'll still walk through it.
Second is creating content for other
people. Easy media money. And then the
third is having an offer. I'm going
explain what an offer is. So, first
let's talk about brand deals. The bottom
tier of where brand deals are accepted
is growing, right? 200,000 followers is
the new 50,000 followers. If you want to
get considered looking for brand deals,
you have to be pretty big now. It's cuz
there's a lot of creators that are
getting pretty big. But if you want to
circumvent that, the number one way to
do it is provide content that brands
will want to whitelist and run ads for
and also get on those brands radar. So,
for instance, I was hit up. There's a
huge Airwong collab launching this week.
It's function and air1. They hit me up.
Function did because I've already made
content about air1 smoothies. And
they've seen, oh, successful content
about an air1 smoothie launch. That's
someone we should work with. When I
bought my human scale chair, human scale
was like, "Hey, we'd love to run an ad
on this content." Same thing that
happened when I reviewed the board, the
game for my kids stuff. They hit me up
being like, "Hey, let's make another
version of this we can run as an ad."
You have to already be making content
and be on the radar for this. If you
make a lot of content about Adobe
Illustrator, guess who's going to be
looking at getting an Adobe sponsorship?
Cuz those brands, look at those people
first. at one of the makeup brands I
work with. That is the requirement. They
have to have posted about that brand
organically prior or they don't
understand it enough and they're a big
enough brand where that's feasible. So,
it's the number one easiest way to get
on the radar to do that. You have to be
doing that kind of review and overview
and showcase videos before you're
getting paid for it. And you'll see a
lot of those brands begin to hit you up
and all of a sudden you have an asset or
two that does well. You do a couple
cheap at first, those ads start running.
It becomes a flywheel because the more
ads you do, the more showcases you have,
the more they come in. Brand deals is a
hard game as one of the biggest
certainly the biggest in my niche doing
that. It is an absolute grind. You have
to post a lot of content. It's actually
hard to make good content for the brands
as well. There's a lot of factors to
consider, but obviously there's great
money at the end of it. Number two, this
is the best one, is being able to use
that to be a creator for brands in your
niche. When I was on tour the other
week, I had a lot of people who had made
that exact jump. There's a woman who had
made content on medical devices who got
hired by medical device firm to be their
creator. I am constantly hit up by
brands who are looking for creators,
especially in intellectual niches. And
if you are marketing creators who are
looking for that kind of stuff, DM me on
Instagram.
>> The hard part about this is there's no
real aggregation for it. It's not like
there's a platform you can go on. Brands
know how to ask. Creators know how to
show themselves, but everyone wants it.
And so with that, that's one of the
things that you have to put out there on
your email list or on your stories or on
your CTA like, hey, looking for a brand
or two, just like Ryan saying, looking
for a hospital hospitality client or
two. You need to make the ask, hey, I'm
looking for a brand or two where I can
make content for you on your feed.
putting that out on stories, mentioning
it inside some of the content that you
do, putting it in your newsletter.
That's a worthwhile call to action to
have. And what most creative people miss
is they just never ask for the sale and
then wonder why they don't get it.
Should run that back. Every creative
person should just run that back. And I
want you to glaze over that point. And
the third, we're going to talk about
offers. So, first, what is an offer? If
you're a creative person who's who says,
"Oh, I'm a designer. I saw all types of
design. This this is for you." Most
people do not know how to package and
sell their expertise. And so, what they
do is they say, "I'm a consultant for X
or Y, or I'm a designer. I'm a
videographer. I'm an editor. That's not
what people want to buy. They don't want
to buy a big default thing. Is way
easier to say, I sell X. I do brand
sprints where I will develop a brand for
you within 14 days. And every offer has
to be based on one of the principles of
sales, which is, are you selling speed?
Is it going to be faster than the
competition? Are you selling price? Is
going to be cheaper than the
competition? Or are you selling skill?
Am I better than the competition? And
you can't have all three. You need to
choose at least one you're going to
market on. I'm going to give you the
best brand identity possible on the same
timeline as everyone else. I'm going to
give you a brand identity in two weeks
and it's going to be solid. That's an
amazing value proposition. Then look at
what people are actually buying, right?
If you are a designing carousels for
social media like we talked about,
that's a niche people are buying in.
Right now, you need to decide what is
that offer that I have. I I help hotels
do X and Y in a workshop and actually
package that offer. And every single
expert, you're either looking for one of
two things. You want to move up in your
career at some point and leverage your
social media to move up in your career.
We'll talk about that in a minute. Or
you are selling some type of
consultation or service and you should
package that, not have that be be
default. Now, how to make this good? At
least you have alignment with your
niche. I know a couple creators who sell
something totally different. There's a
lot of creators have video editing
services, right? That's a a thing that
tons of people market and they upsell
people from the Philippines. But if your
content is about restaurants, it has a
little bit of alignment. You could be
like social media editing for
restaurants, but it's like not quite
there. You need actual alignment. Ryan
has alignment. He makes content about
hospitality in the future of hospitality
and he will help bars, hotels, and
restaurants who are trying to change
their trajectory. So, offer alignment is
crucial to match to the content that you
have. If you are selling content about
AI graphic design but you have
photography services again it's not
aligned then specificity get to I am
selling you a specific thing you have
this package of these assets right I no
longer do consultation I just do
programs but before it was like I will
give you creative strategy for your
campaign or for your social content and
you will get the ideas and the briefs
and all the connections needed to
execute them and that was the offer and
then what I also see is most people need
two tiers if you are selling a higher
ticket thing or an expensive thing you
should give people away to try with a
$1,000 hey we do a workshop again
something cheaper or something smaller
that can get people in the door that
then you can then use to validate if
they're the right client to have for
something larger. That is the 120 second
version of what offers are and what that
offer stack matters. That's how every
expert needs to think about what they
sell. And if you make content, you don't
know what to sell from it because it's a
niche that doesn't have alignment with
something you can sell. You probably
have a a gap there. You need to think
about what am I really doing on social
media? Why am I making content like
this? And then think about do I need a
new account or a new approach that
allows me to align an offer I can
deliver with the content I'm making
that's popular. Next, we're going to get
into the two biggest traps that are
happening right now. Probably three, two
and a half. We're talk about the three
levels of making content for a personal
brand in 26. We'll wrap it up. So, the
traps you need to avoid. First is the
sameness trap. You will see now someone
makes a popular format. People hop on
it. They make the exact same thing
extremely quick and you can pull up
views that way. But, as you'll notice,
there's a lot of people that knock off
the product versus brand content I do.
There are 11 people I have a list who
have made multiple versions of this
video. One of them at least asked and
had a conversation about it and were
friendly and so that was fun. Some
tagged me a few times, great, whatever.
But one thing that's noticed about
basically all of them is that they don't
get the same level of sponsorship or
flow that I do because at the end of the
day, it's someone else's idea. People
don't want the second person on the
idea. They want the originator of the
idea. Now, if you have your own ideas to
supplement that, that's a different
thing. And people may want to check in
and clock into that. But you are not
going to get to the monetization as well
from someone else's thing. And so
instead of copying, look at how do you
put your unique spin on any of these?
And it's really not that hard. But with
that sameness trap comes everyone being
like, how can I do this with AI? Can I
use claw to write my scripts? Can I just
put their content in chatbt and make a
new version of it? Can I automate these
carousels with X or Y? If you are
flooding spam onto the timeline, the
only money you get, if you get any money
at all, is going to be money that goes
away quick because everyone else who
wants a cheap and easy version is doing
the same thing and that gets commodified
first and commodified the fastest. It's
why you don't see nearly any people that
are actually using AI generated content
to have any form of success beyond maybe
driving some leads to a SAS product. And
as more and more of it rises, the only
thing that stands out is what I
mentioned before, personality,
connection with the audience. The last
one is the high production trap. I know
a lot of people that are in this right
now because high production content had
a huge moment in 2025. We're talking
about social shows, all those like
vignettes of different carousels that
were popping. Everyone's making
beautiful looking films. Brands are show
all these things off. But now when you
actually watch people scroll and consume
that content, you begin to realize it
was exciting at the start. People really
like it. They find it funny. They'd
engage with it. They go to the brand.
Now it's noise. Now, there's so many
high production brands doing their
version of that that it doesn't perform
as well. And if it does put up the likes
and views, you're not getting that
click-through and that connection. It's
basically looking at like, okay, they're
watching Hulu and they never get to the
ad. They never click through and go to
the call to action. And there's a lot of
people who specialize in that who are
struggling right now cuz they're like,
these things that we're launching don't
work. When they do work, we're not
getting the results and the sales that
come on the other end. And it's funny
cuz I remember when Adam Oseri from
Instagram mentioned this and he was
like, "Hey, we've seen in AI generated
content. It's actually easier for us to
call out real generated content and is
AI and actually believe it's going to
lead to lowerfi content overall or more
natural candid conversations." I
remember at the time being like, I don't
really know if that's right necessarily.
And then now I'm like, oh, he was
actually 100% right. Where whatever you
were doing to form that personal
connection is the only thing that
matters and everything else is this wide
expansive noise. We're going to end with
the three levels of personal brand here.
The first that everyone watching this
should do is create to escape. And there
are tons of people doing this. When I
launched my video, I think it was the
art of the personal brand maybe four or
five months ago. I've never had as many
people DM me within a few months saying
I started to make content and were
successful. It was 50 plus. A lot of
them have really popping accounts. It
was kind of crazy to see. If you've not
watched that, go back and watch that
video if you need exact road map. You
don't have the tools you have from this.
But that video is about creating to
escape. Once you start doing it and you
get your first couple thousand followers
and you now it's a skill that you have.
You never have to worry about where
you're going to work again. You are
going to be able to when you need to
turn it on and put your foot down is
going to get to level two in a second.
You can
>> you can do it.
>> You now have the power cuz you began to
build an audience and you have the skill
set that whenever you need to turn it
on, you can. That's where we're going to
go to for level two is turning it on. If
you are actually selling something right
now and you want to generate business
right now or if you're at level one
where you created and you're at a
current job, you didn't really have a
goal but now you're like, "Oh I
lost my job." Or, "You know what? I'm
tired of this." Hey, I want to take a
change. Then you put the foot on the gas
and you have the ability to because you
started. You can generate affinity for
your service. You can generate leads.
You can tell people you're open for
employment. You can put it down. That's
level two of content. You're doing it
with a reason. I encourage everyone to
get into level one. Everyone thinks
they're like, "Oh, there's so many
creators. How come there be room for
more?" We're still battling against the
worst news media ever. Terrible
television experiences. There's more
consumption happening here and there's
only more to go. And you don't need a
bunch. You need a couple thousand
followers and the ability to know you
have a video that can get 20,000 50,000
views. And then you have that ability
again whenever you want to turn on and
be like, I need leads for my consulting
business. I want to find a new job. I'm
going to X place and I want to meet
people. All these objectives you have in
your life, it is a tool to achieve those
objectives. And it is the biggest
superpower you can tap into in our
modern time. And level three, if you
want to scale that, you want to go
beyond this. Okay, you got your first
10, 20,000 followers or you got a couple
hundred thousand followers and it's kind
of scaling but you don't have that
affinity. You're like, okay, people like
the content, but it's not doing anything
for me. That's all about personality.
People have to get to know you. They
have to like and love you. There needs
to be story lines and plot lines and
things that come with that. And that's
not for everybody. It totally doesn't
have to be. But that's the third level
if you want to get to there. So, quick
housekeeping. I'm doing another
community call. It's going to be this
Sunday where we're just going to be live
workshopping. I'm going be teaching a
bunch about creative strategy. You can
find that in the description down below.
We don't have another new cut 30 until
March. You can get on the wait list for
that on the link below as well if you
want to do short form content with
people over 30 days. and we have our
state of content report where we break
down all the trends and stuff in the
written version. I'm going to link down
there below. There are a whole bunch uh
of things happening. We're going to keep
these community calls going every month.
I love chatting with y'all. You have
questions, you're trying to decide what
kind of content to make. You want to
know what you would want to yap about.
Comment your niche, comment what you
have down below. We can workshop some.
Once they'll start to get to like 500
comments, I usually give up. I try to
hit as many as I can getting into it.
So, if you have that, drop them below
and I will get to them. Thank you'all so
much for watching.