we need to get to the bottom of what is
going on because Big Brand marketing Big
Brand branding has gotten bad it is
either feast or famine in this video
we're going to talk about the new
Rebrand of jaguar or Jaguar however you
prefer to pronounce it key cultural
topics like is Jaguar brat break down by
contrast brands that are evolving in a
good way look at the attention getting
industrial complex of 2024 2025 talk
about the strategies brands should be
considering when they're going into
approaching a new look and feel and talk
about the contrast of nostalgia and the
future that we're trapped in when we
have these type of conversations ever
been interested in marketing and
rebrands or passionate about cars and
the future and looks of where they're
going or just want to understand why
Marketing in general has often gotten so
bad we're going to hit all that inside
this video but first this is the
scenario that we're in this is the video
released by Jaguar create exuberant live
Vivid delete
ordinary break molds copy nothing I am
never going to get that 30 seconds of my
life back so this accompan this logo
change of Jaguar it's much more simple
streamlined interface as our friends at
Outlander point out this is a common
theme of brands that have continually
Blended over time because they think
that's what consumers want or makes it
easier to do their logo applications Etc
but this video at approached by Jaguar
has the internet in an up and over a few
things one is the complete tone defa
nature of this ad right this is a
perfect example of when you go to an ad
agency and ask what does gen Z want and
it's all these unique personas it's
unknown you know this entire ad could be
Ai and I'd be like all right I believe
it yeah unique looks bright
personalities whatever this is what a
lot of agencies and Executives think
that people want they want Blanding they
want future forward bright colors and
fruit when I had my worst marketing
video I talked about how Coca-Cola
spiced have like giant fruit in their
attempt to attract gen Z but they are
operating in a parallel universe from
reality this is a set of agencies who
are now 7 months late to the brat Trend
who are asking can we make Jaguar brat
here's what this Zeitgeist looks like
this is someone saying hey people don't
like Tesla because Elon Musk Tesla is
the vehicle of conservatives let's
become the anti-tesla let's be as
flamboyant as we can and with that
moving into a marketing sphere that
actually markets to no one because the
people who are in that zone appreciate
well done and sophisticated things as
much as the people that don't and so you
end up in an attention grab that only
gets attention because of the negativity
presented upon but then they follow up
with the vehicle they were unveiling
this on the 2nd of December and then
this has been the look and feel that
they've seen driving around in camo this
is where this conversation gets
interesting I like everyone on the
internet think that that AB was
absolutely terrible we'll get to the
Rebrand and the core of it in the second
and cuz I actually like some of that I
am very intrigued by the look and feel
of this I also very intrigued by the
look and feel of this photo and I do
feel like even if this is one of the
worst videos ever if a Hypes of this
much attention if there is a sick
vehicle at the end of it that people go
that is outrageous or that is something
I want to drive then the attention and
eyeballs that come from all this
negativity on the internet will actually
have served them well in having people
really looking at what is going to come
from this release was that their
intention probably not if it was they're
certainly playing some 4D chess that we
were not expecting but now everything
hinges on this December December 2
release of this vehicle and I do predict
that we're going to see a lot of people
do purposely bad ads having seen this
happen with Jaguar to then follow up and
say haha guess what that was a troll and
then release a new campaign or a
different looking feel because they're
seeing how the attention industrial
complex shifts to bash on this Jaguar
items so much so that it creates a
moment of brand recognition unlike what
this brand has had in I don't know
decades and then I was dming with
someone who was asking me if I was going
to have an opinion about this who were
saying that they they saw a reading
where Jaguar was saying they only expect
15% of their existing customer based to
come with them on this new Journey so
they are doing a radical repositioning
and look this is obviously a good thing
Jaguar is nothing like what it used to
be it's not a car people are frequently
considering buying the best thing they
had going forward is I believe that they
were wayo cars so at least was Tech
adjacent and I think they lost that
contract to like Hyundai or somebody
they need this redo they need this
refresh a drastic change is likely a
good one I'll talk about some of those
angles coming up in the video of taking
a future forward approach versus a
nostalgic approach and now they
certainly have All Eyes Upon them for
what's going to happen but before I get
into this and an example of a good
version of this that's happening with
Porsche we're going to talk about why
bad stuff like this happen why are
agencies and big Brands so bad right now
why does stuff like that terrible North
Face campaign that we saw with like the
AI Manifesto happened to such a
legendary brand and it's because of the
death of the marketing middle class so
there's all these people right now that
should be director and VP of marketing
people between the ages of 30 and 40 who
have quickly realized if you have a
great skill set in marketing you can do
good paid marketing you are a marketing
leader you are a solid content creator
influencer manager you can make far more
money by being an entrepreneur or being
a co-founder or being a Creator then you
can at those typical jobs and that
leaves this Gap where all those people
that would normally be mentoring the
younger generation of marketers that
layer is now gone and this is a very
real thing because if you are one of
those people that has that skill set you
have a paid marketing skill set or a
Content creation skill set you are worth
an absolute ton of money significantly
more than many times anyone else in the
company but those people have gone
entrepreneurial and then the people that
are left there's plenty of them who
still say hey I want to work for
whatever reason they now get their
choice because of all these people
exiting of all the cool brand right
would you rather work for or road or
hexclad or Al or Brands doing really
cool and exciting stuff and put your
toolkit to use there would you rather be
at some stagnant agency and would you
rather be at a small agency doing cool
work or a medium-sized agency or be
going to the sais of the world where
you're not going to be doing that kind
of work and you're going to be trapped
in this system or even working in the
Jaguars where no one's going to listen
to you you're not you're going to these
places where you can still get
compensated really well and do
interesting work and this is a
significant departure from where
marketing people lived in the past and
because of this Gap you have a lot of
gen Z people who know they know better
they say I had know what's going on in
the culture hey I know how to do content
I know whatever but they have don't have
the experience or the management
expertise and don't have the coaching to
be able to communicate that to the seite
and there's this General sense of
entitlement that happens in every
younger generation where people think oh
they think they can just jump these jobs
without having to work and you have a
sea level people who can't understand
the Gen Z people don't know how to
justify the actions that are happening
don't really know what's going on on the
ground are completely disconnected from
the tiktock ification of the world we
have now who can't make solid decisions
this happens again agency level and
brand level which leads to a dir of good
decisions and a feast or fam mentality
your brand either gets it or it does not
get it it and jaguar does not get it
does that mean that they may not be
successful no you never know and a lot
of cases product heals all wounds let's
look at an example of what good car
marketing looks like so I found it
interesting that the same time we
debuted this Jaguar scenario Porsche and
Al are doing a marketing effort for a
collaboration there now this is
obviously a this is marketing right
they're using they're selling multi
thousand doll bags and jackets by
applying the Porsche Life Style to it
but they're creating beautiful looking
Vehicles the true nature of luxury both
in the product development itself and
the adjacent product development of what
Al is selling in the presentation of the
product in the styles that it
evokes this was the video that they were
debuting while we're seeing the other
Jaguar video where they're really
playing into the exact opposite we got
an old dude coral on his sheep while we
we roll through the the mountain tops in
Ireland or wherever we're at man's got
they brought the Yaks out and they are
telling a much more nostalgic familiar
story that is synonymous with
performance and synonymous with what
people are interested in and how people
spend money especially inside this core
demographic now Jaguar may have said hey
we actually can't compete with this
there's no way we're going to be able to
I don't think they're necessarily
correct but that could be a angle that
you take as you ascertain this and
luckily my man doesn't hit the Sheep
here and they're able to break safe just
a couple of
gentlemen having a
moment the Sheep part ways they continue
but this is very much the moment that is
happening right now we are in the
nostalgic era and there's so many brands
that are looking future forward when
they should be looking backwards and I
think there's only two ways you can
really approach Nostalgia or deep future
this is living in the Nostalgia era and
that's fine most of what we are is I had
uh some serious thoughts about kith and
Nike in their approach to the Olympics I
talked about in my worst marketing video
where everyone's you know trying to kind
of do some current things and kith was
literally just like you know what's in
the Z guys right now just rerun the
exact you know 80s and 90s shirts and
design that people were wearing that's
what people like CU that's what people
are into right now there's a whole world
around connection and Nostalgia that is
has not gone away is still on Trend and
still works if you are a brand with a
rich history like you have the choice to
do something forward or do something
nostalgic and if you go forward I feel
like you have to go deep forward I'll
talk about what that means but it's far
easier and what I think they should do
is go back so we look at these ad
examples here of what Jaguar
presentation used to look like and I
think if you even take some of the look
and feel of some of the vehicles and
we're to present it like that and saying
hey we are actually going to make our
line look like our line and lean into
true you know British Heritage they
really focus on the emblems and the
history they are going to be they could
do something that was particularly
relevant and when you look at this new
Dem graphic I actually think look at
this new designs I actually think this
isn't bad it's Sleek it's interesting I
really like the grill and the Jaguar
application here the monogram again
while I may prefer this original look
that we had and and I think obviously
that is tells a much more rich and
interesting story there's something that
could be played here where they are
doing a streamlined approach that when
paired with the right look in vehicle
could be interesting so I'm not
discounting the potential of this a
Rebrand just because that video is bad
that's truly what's bad this may be a
little bit more blander but it's not
horrible and the essence of what a brand
like this should be doing if they don't
know how to look forward because that
campaign they do not know how to look
forward this is literally operating
operating in a parallel universe where
they think they're going to be able to
sell a million units of electric
vehicles millions of units because
there's an anti- Elon Musk crowd and gen
Z loves this particular looking feel and
they're going to capture a new
generation and embrace the brat zeist
and all the I can just imagine the worst
deck that you've ever seen and then that
that is what was portrayed inside the
video app but what they have at their
fingertips is to running this exact same
ad capture a jaguar run all this put
cats out there put these same shots do
it all the same vintage style run these
car looks and feel backs domesticated
not declawed just run it run the same ad
looks and feels run it on social media
make them all as video just do it and by
running that selection of things they
could basically reown their core
audience make them reconsider it tap
into a youth that is actually
significantly more nostalgic than any
generation prior yearning for a time
before smartphones and before this you
know crazy internet brain rot that we're
in and is at their fingertips to execute
and any brand that has this history this
brand goes back to 1922 any brand with a
3050 year history 100y year history
should be doing this it is a winning
strategy that is almost impossible to
mess up if you do it with some intention
that's not what we saw we saw mediocre
future and I think the future if you
don't want to go into the past which I
can understand why many Brands don't cuz
it traps you there for some period of
time and then you have to go to the
Future at some point but you can't get
caught in what I'm going to call middle
future this idea that celebrating people
of all looks and feels and bright colors
and this changing nature of the world
we're in is is what people want cuz
that's not it if you're going to go into
the future I feel like you need to go
into the far future I'm pulling open the
heli AAL website an example of far
future here it is Universe section of
their website where they basically can
see every campaign and collaboration
they've ever done but this is a brand
that very much lives in a future period
who's taken the idea of form of of
portrayal and made like a future
University you can be a part of today
and I feel like brands that embody
things like this this brand does Rick
Owens does the amorphous metal this
quasi cyber look if you want to paint a
vision of the future it needs to be an
interesting and futuristic one it needs
to be technical that is the future that
people are really buying into more to
Archive faction more like what we're
seeing with heli at ail when you create
vehicles and identities for the future
that are more based around this and
doesn't not saying has to be black
silver and white but it has to be
thinking of a future that people view as
interesting and aspirational not as a
future that seems like fun and
collaborative and would appeal to genz
those are two very different things I
think people should be considering as
they go through exercise are we trapped
in Middle future or are we going deep
future and if you have Nostalgia should
we could just lean into that now anyway
December 2nd we're going to find out
what this actually looks like is the
vehicle worth everything we saw with
this campaign and can surpass it or is
just going to be another amazing brand
gradually slides down into nothing