hey what's up it's Orin thank you to
everyone who watched my design life Vlog
this week in LA and who came out to the
live on Thursday with myself and the
brand Brothers today I'm going to talk
about building a personal brand as a
creative and this doesn't mean you have
to become a full-time Creator I'm going
to say that right now I'm going to talk
about what do you do now that portfolios
are antiquate because they are they
don't tell the story well enough they're
hard to believe and understand and
people don't hunt them down to look at
so if you want to find more work both
freelance and you know and actually get
good jobs move up inside your career
develop leverage in your career here's
how you begin to put those foundations
together and I'm going to have examples
one not being a full-time Creator and
just how you build what I'm going to
call a living portfolio over time second
I'm going to talk about building your
portfolio and your work anonymously and
the reasons why you might want to do
that or not and then third I'm going to
talk about the route to becoming a
Creator if you do want to I think at a
lot of points in someone's career as a
creative you're going to really think
about it whether you're launching your
own brand it's part of it or you realize
it's going to help you get more work cuz
a lot of people are going to consider it
and I'm going to walk through video
formats that are easy and succeed in
showing your work whether you're a
Creator or not as well as Carousel
formats and content overall that will
help tell your story to people that will
hire you first I'm going to kick off
with walking through a couple content
types that I think every creative should
know how to make that are actually
relatively straightforward and we're
going to go through the concepts and a
bunch of EX examples so the first one is
this transformation video is what I call
them so or BTS so it starts with like a
couple iPhone clips from whatever you're
working on and then it ends with the
actual results so you'll see here mob
wife spired in photo shoot a couple
iPhone clips of the model and then you
have the actual action and results
second example is this direct flash
photography so they're actually talking
a little bit about technique again they
show a couple behind the scenes and they
show all the end result photos these
videos are like 6 seconds to 15 seconds
and it's the ultimate format for a
creative of any kind photographer
videographer designer whatever you want
or someone in marketing and branding who
did like the strategy or who worked on
the campaign or an agency that actually
does these or a brand who is actually
doing the campaigns or an influencer who
is doing this kind of stuff to show
their work in a way that is potentially
viral so talked about this on other
social media I'll mention it again here
Transformations are huge whether it's
unboxing or a sketch to reality to get
ready with everyone wants to follow a
journey and a narrative even if it's
just 15 seconds what helps social media
succeed and this is a perfect narrative
for creatives versus a traditional
portfolio for a few reason first it
plays to a successful social media
format people always trying to fight the
way oh I don't want to make trending
content I don't want you know I want to
be able to show my art in my way guess
what if you can show your art in a way
that actually succeeds on social media
even if it means that you just get 100
more likes and you typically do you are
now showcasing not just your ability to
make your art or your skill set but you
are showcasing that you can actually do
it in a way that makes sense on social
media that is a massive signaler to
people that want to hire you and
agencies that want to work with you or
potential people that you know are going
to retain your work that you know what
you're doing in the context of where
every single thing that they're working
on likely lives which is in some way
related to content the second thing I
love about this format is you do not
have to have Perfection I've talked to
too many creatives who are working super
hard on their behance portfolio or their
webs site that it just never gets done
and this is literally a couple iPhone
shots that happen from whenever you're
on a shoot or a campaign or making
something and if you're not doing
something exciting like this like
working on a campaign it can literally
be like Say You're Just designing and
you're at your desk like show the behind
the scenes of like you're pouring a
coffee you're banging your head against
the table you're rocking back and forth
you're playing with some pixels whatever
that is like find a couple little funny
things that you can do whether they're
real or they're contrived and then lead
into the work and then when you show the
work you're only showing a handful of
Clips or a handful of photos you can
just cherry-pick some of the things that
look good and it's not some big
portfolio piece the Perfection it you
know the elusive Perfection doesn't have
to exist you can just ship it couple
iPhone Clips couple of the things that
you like from the shoot that you feel
represent whatever you're doing right
and it is done and the expectation on
the other end of it is not Perfection
and this I feel really helps people
actually ship this type of content
actually make their portfolio and then
consistently add to it we'll talk about
that in a future section um versus just
kind of like having it dwell or be
continually outdated so every single
time you're working on something like
this you should try to capture one of
these moments and post one of these
moments and I think a big thing too
people get caught up on is well what do
I do depending on my position like okay
if you're a junior designer or you were
like the art director on this or you
worked on the brief or whatever you can
still run the content just to explain to
people in the caption what you actually
did and this is a huge one where you're
like hey this is a shoot that I art
directed this is a shoot that I did the
copyrighting on this is a shoot where I
was a grip it doesn't matter you are as
long as you are honest about your
participation and especially for design
work where you can very obviously be
like hey I did the wire frames or you
know guess what I did the final color
correction whatever that is Tag the
other people people that are involved if
if they're down or not but like there is
a uh the ability to Showcase that and
just tell your role in it and that's a
big part about building it this as a
portfolio or something exists on your
social media is explaining your
involvement and being able to tag along
on something cool that you worked on now
the second format I'm going to call out
is called the creative Carousel this is
a great way to go about social media
that works in your regular life they
work super well on Tik Tok and they work
super well on Instagram and if you put
them all into a PDF they also can work
pretty good on this is the idea of
taking a handful of photos Andor photos
or videos that you would normally do
like as a photo dump everyone's seen on
Instagram but just telling a story more
related to your Arc and your work and
your career this is a great one um I
it's 9x6 would succeed a lot more 4x5
like standard cor Carousel format um so
you know doing this vertical versus
doing horizontal but she has her own
trademark design style that she's
placing on top of this second clip is a
video showing something that she's
working on doesn't have to be as nice or
artfully directed as this but again with
her little brand kit she's not doing too
much on this starts to add like a some
more of a brand Cake She's got some
actual pretty sophisticated stuff on
some of these the other stuff she does
but it's just four slides that are
showing her work in a branded style and
so if you are in any Creative Marketing
branding design videography you know Etc
illustration whatever it is you need to
have your little kit of the things that
you think are good that actually
represent you as someone who knows what
they're doing and this is a great way to
do it where literally it's like couple
color combos couple font sets little
iconography and illustrations and that's
the kind of stuff everyone knows that
they can kind of pull together and you
should do something that's up to your
standard that you can do on your social
media another great example where of
basically taking the normal stuff
happening in your life and then placing
it within this kind of designed context
so literally she's just placed an
outline on herself and she's put some
text in and around this but it does
really well 6,000 likes on this and I
found this on my explore page and I
immediately was like how do I do the Bro
version of this like I'm going to put
this text around in Old English we're
going to have the glow look different
whatever like you begin to think about
what can I apply my style to like my
individual like brand kit to something
that you know a format that works for
others and then she has kind of like a
collage style similar fonts that kind of
stuff where she's showing her life in
that context but it's like a designed
life and I think this is kind of a more
personal example and applying any level
of intention to that for what you do
that's copyrighting what is or just
adding that brand kit to it immediately
sells yourself better and if you look
back on how you want to show your
portfolio this is the things I worked on
in March this is the best my favorite
things of the last quarter hey I went to
this trade show whatever it is showing
it in that perspective begins to build
your work p portfolio as a creative
online amazing example I love where
literally applying some typography some
like light canva or photoshop uh to the
beginning of a carousel the rest of it's
like a normal Carousel of those photos
but you immediately get this designed
element and like developing your
trademark style like that to add to your
kind of personal content is an excellent
way to show yourself off as someone who
cares and is intentional about branding
and marketing another excellent example
this is just a work showcase and this is
again another reason I love this so much
is this is a portfolio except it doesn't
have these standards and requirements of
like a perfect everything that's be
presented aesthetically with everything
tagged and called out she's just showing
her favorite work from this year and you
can go do the same thing and you start
to remind yourself oh I can capture
Clips I can bring some stuff on the
computer and show the PDF coming
together you know I can what what do I
have on my phone bring that together
every one of these clips is like 1
second Max and she's just showing the
work and guess what what you have show
it you don't have it you don't and you
can tell that story and because these
formats do really well you know you may
end up with 46,000 likes that she has
even if you have 469 you're beginning to
do things in a format that move well on
the internet and no matter what your
portfolio is of you can still engage in
that style like virality isn't the goal
here the goal here is beginning to
establish your narrative as a creative
online and so some of the tricks that
she's using on this like this is all
done in cap cut um I ran about cap cut
some other parts of this video but
literally like that tap onto the screen
is like a great visual trick if you have
a physical object uh she's doing some
things with key frames where they zoom
in that's all done in capcut What's
called the key Fram go just YouTube
capcut Key frames it's super easy and
like that little Zoom there also a key
frame those are like just little visual
tricks to make this comic content more
compelling another example the straight
showcase so it's just literally this
girl sitting there saying here's this
website and then she Scrolls through the
website now a couple things that make
this great the manicured hand helps a
couple little punchin and outs and then
she's like styled but you sitting there
to begin and like doesn't matter who you
are doesn't matter what you look like
pick a good-looking outfit pick a fun
environment either one of those or both
of those things and you are setting
yourself up as a hook as a creative for
that basically one to two second shot to
start so literally I will copy what she
does put yourself in a in an outfit that
you're proud of and take some time in it
pick a place that you think looks pretty
cool and just have that shot like taking
a sip of a drink just because doing an
action is always more natural than not
doing an action having a drink is a
perfect one pick your favorite beverage
tag the company they may even work with
you and then just get into this
portfolio so she's like scrolling on a
on a laptop like it can be that simple
and the last piece we going to talk
about is curation if you don't want to
show like a bunch of your own work start
to curate the things others do and so
Hans was in our cut 30 cohort was like
social media program I run blew up off
it and he's huge now um started at zero
he was in there whenever that was like 6
months ago he's bigger than me at this
point and he's just doing these
creations of like here's trees you
should add to your house he has a
intentionally designed style and it's
the beginning to think about him as an
interior designer showing his thought
process of like what that work looks
like another good example a completely
different Niche and I I show this
example just to show you like it doesn't
matter what your Niche it doesn't matter
what you do if you do anything visual or
interesting this church Graphics like
right you're like is there a church
graphic cottage industry on Instagram
like yes there is there IS300 people
that like this graphic designer showing
off his church graphics and he's
literally curating best Church Graphics
of the week I don't think he did all
these uh see this translation I think
he's just curating them okay he made he
made these Graphics he's putting them
together into a collage style and he's
presenting his beginning and end of it
this is a perfect like work example of
doing that of curating those things and
putting his own unique spin on it and
saying here's how I want to present my
work like in this Carousel form so as we
go into this next section where I talk
about different ways to put yourself
online whether you want to fully become
a Creator whether you want to like take
the step-by-step portfolio development
approach which everyone should do or you
want to kind of be like an anonymous
Creator those are the three options
these are like video and Carousel
references for post types that you
should use to achieve that if you don't
know the tools to start is literally cap
cut and canva will get you to like 90%
of the things that you see here so why
would you want to make content and why
would you put your portfolio out there
the first thing is social media is
distribution one of the things that
designers and creatives suffer a lot
from is getting people to see their work
because there's a huge disparity from
people that actually need that work and
knowing where to find I get both sides
of the equation of my I have dozens of
people hit me up every week looking for
designers and art directors and like
people of a certain Talent OR caliber or
a certain price point I also get H up by
tons of designers who are trying to find
better and more work not a lot of them
like intersect in the way you I'd like
them to and I don't spend a lot of time
like trying to compare everyone in a
spreadsheet maybe I'll make a tool for
that or something soon but it is really
interesting to see the disparity that's
there and I know that too like I'm
hunting for great techpack designers all
the time hard to find and I know a lot
of designers especially good Western
designers are not necessarily on like
upwork or some of these platforms that
you can h creatives easily so we a
social media content helps solve that
disparity in distribution and even if
you don't build a big following at a
base level just with your network this
is really important to understand
getting the Instagram of everyone that
you come across or getting the LinkedIn
that they come across and just following
up and following and then having your
work on there even if it doesn't get
mega views or you post all the time is
the foundation of allowing your
portfolio to move and a quick example of
this so I've been working on muscle goo
which is a product I'm doing with Colin
landforce that we used to do and sell on
Amazon back in the day and now we're
taking in and relaunching it to sell
here we needed the designer to do the
packaging revamp and I wanted to use
someone who had like a different looking
feel than my style design and so I had
been to Expo West which is a trade show
about natural foods organic foods and
there was an IT bag at the show
basically it was a swag bag that
everyone was lining up to get and I put
it on Instagram and someone hit me up
like hey I designed that bag and I went
to her portfolio we struck a bit of a
conversation I was like hey we actually
have this design project do you want to
do it because her visual style that I
could see there and the couple things
she had really matched what we were
looking for inside this product and now
she designed this new package that you
can see but that happens because of
putting your work out there online then
also finding people talking about your
work if you do do it and actually
interacting but the second thing that
social media builds is leverage and this
point is like absolutely massively
important to hear I remember when I
started on Tik Tok I did not expect Tik
Tok to go well I was learning Tik Tok to
learn it as a marketing executive I
wanted to be better at my job by
understanding social media but then I
started to get a lot of views 10,000
followers 20,000 followers when I got to
50,000 followers people I were working
with were talking about it people would
start to see me people recognized it it
became a thing and all of a sudden when
you're in meetings and you have 50,000
Tik Tok followers and you're in a
marketing meeting your opinion begins to
matter way more because you're actually
doing when I got 100,000 Instagram
followers and now I'm at like 500k up
across platforms like every meeting
changed meetings when I was in with
major retailers changed where it's like
hey guess what do you know how the
social strategy works like look at my
engagement versus the engagement of your
entire channel has millions of followers
and all of a sudden those conversations
begin to revolve around you and so I've
had a lot of comments about if you know
what to do from a creative standpoint
but your marketing director doesn't or
people won't listen as an executive
they'll listen to hell of a lot more
when you have success and their account
doesn't and they're like why do you have
success and our account doesn't or when
you're like hey look listen to me cuz I
actually do this and I actually get
results and it's not going to be the
Cure All end all but it certainly helps
get your voice heard and all it takes is
the time and dedication of creating and
it will reward you for the rest of your
career so we're going to hop into three
approaches to building that the first
approach is you're not want to become a
Creator you want to do a gradual
approach to it a living portfolio but
what this is is it's a foundation if you
ever want to go all in on social media
you're already there and it's something
that you're going to be able to build
upon and be a to network upon will serve
you for the rest of your life I based
this Theory and this whole program based
on what I wish I because I had a big
social media account when I was younger
on on X and I gave it up because it was
like some of the content was like more
risque a cuz I was like out partying a
lot and like it was really funny and
humor focused and I was like as I became
a more serious professional I was like
this doesn't represent me correctly and
I'm just going to move away now in
hindsight it doesn't really matter I
should have just ran with it because it
had a huge following to start with I
could have used it as a basis to move
onward and on that other note I was also
building personal brands for other
people so I was running an email list
for my uh boss and then partner in a
business at the time and we built his
email list his LinkedIn up pretty large
by just regularly publishing the things
he was working on and he has like a 27
30,000 person email list from us doing
that regularly at these projects and
establishing him that is super valuable
for him but I woke up one day and was
like oh I should have just been building
that for me right and I'm happy I did it
because I learned how to do it we've
done businesses together but if I had
been building my small version the
entire time and regularly communicating
with them all of these projects I'm
doing now would go faster I'd have more
work more opportunity make more sales
and the things I do and no matter where
you're at in your career cuz I had this
Epiphany at like 36 you know uh but
whether you are 21 30 45 the next 10
years of your life can revolve around
building up email and social media and
it can be gradual and we're going to
walk through second we're going to talk
about being anonymous online which if
you are in a job where they really don't
want you talking about it or you think
it's going to reflect badly on you you
still want to be a participant in the
social media economy you should go
Anonymous and is easier and cooler in a
lot of circumstances than you might
think and third I'm going to talk about
becoming a Creator which is obviously
something I do a pretty expansive
program on separately than this but I'll
hit the very creative Focus version on
this and like what it takes to show up
every day and make content and like what
the rewards are for something like that
and where you get started so this is the
foundation of a living portfolio so what
you're going to think about and your
task I'm going lay it out here then talk
about the pie first you're going to put
out one piece of content every month and
then you're going to put out one email
every single quarter let's break that
down a little bit further so what I mean
by one piece of content a month I mean
on multiple social media networks I'd
particularly choose Instagram and
Linkedin at least but you might as well
um also throw in like X and Tik Tok or
whatever it is if you're making it if
it's a video and we'll talk about the
types of content a minute but the reason
I say LinkedIn and Instagram is cuz
that's where you can actually interact
with people as you're going to go put
out this content your precursor is you
need to start with relationships if you
are on a shoot if you are working with
people if you meet people online or be
people in real life your homework your
task every single time is to ask them
their Instagram handle make sure you
have their name and you are going to
connect with them on LinkedIn and
Instagram you're going to do it every
single time and is takes you two minutes
is extremely good use of social time it
allows you to stay connected to them and
then those people are going to be the
foundation of your audience because this
living portfolio is not about growing to
10,000 followers or 100,000 followers is
about an audience of 10 this is my
concept if you meet 100 people in a year
50 people in a year 40 people in and you
have that relationship there and that
Stacks up two years 3 years in 10 of
those people are going to be decision
makers of some kind who could employ
your work I guarantee you and if you are
posting that work on there all that
matters is that they see it doesn't
matter if it get distribution anything
else matters of those people who are
going to make a decision about employing
someone who does what you do if you are
somewhat top of mind and this this is a
extremely useful content concept to wrap
your head around you need to focus on
those 10 people and so what do you do
you start getting these people in you're
just making friends with them you're
doing your normal life once a month
share your work the formats that I just
discussed about the transformation of a
behind the scenes to reality the format
of the creative Carousel or the growth
content those three types of content I
broke down one a month once a month is
completely achievable for anybody that
means if it takes you 10 days to make
this content cuz it's so hard you could
do it because you have a month or you
can say hey I'm going to have that one
evening or whatever it is where I craft
this one thing and it's low pressure I
have to do all the time doesn't matter
if it gets four likes turn likes off on
it doesn't matter put it out there
because let's look at one year from now
you have 12 of those now on your profile
on your portfolio can be sprinkled in
with your personal content or it can
just be this and so if someone anyone
meets you now because you're going to be
getting people's handles and whatnot and
they go to your profile they know what
you do and they have examples of it and
like I talked about in the growth
content section
if you're not good at it if you're new
to it they're going to see you growing
and learning and trying to establish
that and that have its own benefits a
year from now there will be a 12 thing
portfolio on social media in a format
that may work and may get you more
attention but that shows people that you
are on the internet that you are
somewhat Savvy to putting this together
and they can actually interact with find
easily and share this and all that is
super crucial to how hiring Works
nowadays now we're going to talk about
email your call to action on all these
is going to be to join your email list
you are going to set up with convertkit
because it is free up to 10,000 subs or
beehive I believe is also free up to
some amount of Subs they are both great
platforms they both have their ups and
downs but they are free to set up you're
going to set up your convert kit or your
beehive if you really want I could do a
video like walking through it but it's
not that hard and you going to put a
link to sign up for the landing page if
your name is John it's going to be
John's newsletter Julie's newsletter if
you have to come up with a brand you can
you can make it cool if you want but
literally just like put your thing and
literally just put like updates about my
career life project and interest
and you just want to get again any
number of people on this whenever you do
something you say hey you want to follow
along on this stuff link to my emails in
my profile and you're going to start to
see you get five people you get 50
people over the course of two years
you're going to get 50 people 100 people
on that list yes might even get more if
you put out something really cool and
that is the foundation of your quarterly
update your quarterly update is almost
an exercise in thought you can take your
three posts that you've made right you
made one a month you now have three
things to talk about your quarterly
update you go there and you reflect on
them here's here's what I did here's
what I think I'd do better here's what I
think I did great whatever that format
ends up being some kind of breakdown of
like here's the thing I did here's what
I want to do better in the future here's
what I liked about it whatever and then
a couple things you're interested in are
following along it can be that simple
right like you're writing to a friend
shoot out that email people will see the
three things and you are beginning to
now communicate with a community of
people that understand your work that
are following your journey they're going
to expect to regularly hear from you but
you're not emailing them so much that
it's annoying we'll talk in the Creator
section about growing and building this
and whatnot people AR unsubscribing from
getting an email from you once a quarter
who you've met right like if they are it
doesn't really matter it's not a huge
volume and you're now learning to
describe talk about and share the
stories you're working on on two
platforms that make a huge difference
and they form the foundation if you ever
want to lean in you're not starting from
zero you have 10 email subscribers four
email subscribers doesn't matter if it's
your mom and two of your best friends
one of them is anonymous whatever it is
you are now have a foundation where you
are not going from 0o to one on social
media or email you are already at one
and you are growing and this is a super
critical thing that I would just highly
recommend doing and that really is the
gradual breakdown one post a month one
email a quarter you do this and do this
for a year you have a foundation you do
it for four years you kind of have a
massive Foundation you got 48 things in
your portfolio you've sent out uh
whatever that is over the course of four
years 16 emails you're now communicating
and building up a serious Rapport and
this is the foundation of a creative
career in the minimum I feel like you
should be doing now let's talk about
going Anonymous there's a number of
reasons you might want to go Anonymous
you don't want friends and family to
know you're not proud of your work it's
okay happen you have a job that you
don't feel like would like you to be on
social media okay whatever or you just
find one a way to get started and and
just need to figure it out great going
Anonymous should be cool come up with a
studio name you know Studio Mescal
whatever it is something weird something
fun something that has like a theme or a
ring to it and build an identity around
it as a creative make a logo learn a
little bit of design have a fun tagline
get a visual theme this is your
opportunity to flex as a creative
because it is just for you it's purely
for you and for social media and now you
put it online you can do one of two
things you can follow the portfolio
thing I mentioned before try to put
something new every month or you can try
to be a Creator on it but either way
you're going to show your work you're
going to show your work in a faceless
manner or you're going to create work
just to do this and really it's about
creating a portfolio just for yourself
if you're a sneaker designer design 12
sneakers under your fake Studio M call
brand and be putting them out there and
showing the process showing the
transformation from sketch to a sample
showing the transformation from sketch
to illustrator from your notebook to
your iPad whatever it is but you can
show off whatever that thing is you're
doing under the guise of a completely
creative Endeavor that doesn't evolve
showing your face you can make it as
cool or as provocative as you want and
then someday when you're fired from the
job you're really worried about that
you're like a I want them to see my
social media or when you say hey my work
is actually good enough I want to start
sharing it you assign your face to it
and now you've basically pre-built an
audience you can begin layering yourself
into and introduce yourself and be like
hey I'm John I now run the studio meds
call account you know this is uh this
has been my work for the last couple
years I'm going to start talking about
it in this way you start doing green
screen videos or whatever there is no
excuse have to do one of these things a
lot of people's excuse for not being a
Creator is it's too much do your kind of
living portfolio a lot of people's
excuse for not doing living portfolio is
I don't want put my face out there I'm
not proud of my work great go Anonymous
you have to start this is all the
leverage you're going to get and all the
distribution you're going to get is
going to come from doing stuff like this
if you don't do it you have no power in
the current system that we're at people
aren't going to listen to you as much as
they would if you have social media you
are going to be at the whim of applying
to jobs on like indeed and Linkedin and
stuff like that and like with competing
against hundreds of other people versus
working from the Network that you
started that now knows that you are
putting yourself out there doing a thing
like Empower yourself to make these
moves and the most important thing from
a personal level and going back to
things I wish I'd done I wish I had a
catalog of everything I designed from
when I was in college through my first
jobs through the marketing stuff I
worked on through this if I had just put
up a portfolio once a month the thing I
was most proud of I would love right now
in my late 30s to look back on that and
be able to look at that Journey just
from a personal level say I never gotten
a job off it or anything is kind of
amazing like I look at I got some burel
books up here like some just
retrospectives he just kept all this
stuff it's amazing to look at as a as a
an outsider I'd love to be able to say
hey I have you know I have thousands of
fans for lack of a better term if I put
out that for free as a PDF I'm sure a
lot of people would be curious what that
Arc looks like right so think about it
even for yourself this is an amazing way
to document your creative life and I
would highly recommend now there is
becoming a Creator and I run a whole
program on this I try not to sell hard
in these videos but I have this thing
called cup 30 where in 30 days we teach
you how to do green screen videos and
find pillars and you Workshop in our
slack and whatever if you do want to do
something something like that with an
accountability group you can join it
it's $500 for for the month if you like
a student or you're new to some of this
don't do anything that I sell you learn
just follow the stuff I say in the
YouTubes I'm not trying to ever sell
anything to you if you are like in a
career and you're making some money and
you want to get better I build things
for you and I will 100% be working with
other people to make whatever you're
doing better you can run those programs
but I say all that and I bring it up to
say that we've now run God 7 800 people
through that program we've had a lot of
creators come out of it of all of all
styles and a bunch of them are just
basically building their portfolio as
creatives or finding work through that
and so we've learned a lot about what
works and doesn't I'm going to bring up
by my boy Brady here designed by Brady
he did a great job just cracked 10K
recently and he's just followed popular
formats for design and helped curate
fonts that he likes helped show off
things he's designed developed a bit of
a personality and he just kept going
that's what I'm going to say here is
your goal if you really want to be a
Creator is to start creating video a day
is the goal you can't do video a day
three a week you try to do less than
that stick to the gradual portfolio
thing you can do three a week you can do
one a day when I started I was doing
more than one a day and now I still do
one a day and you are literally just
going to follow these formats of
curating things that you like that's
bucket one documenting things that you
do that's bucket two and then developing
opinions and ideas that's bucket three
your job on the Internet is to find
formats and to find things that work for
you that you can easily create to all to
do so all the creating that 99% of us do
is done in cap cut and then all the kind
of edited graphics and carousels and
stuff are typically done in canva or you
can do it in in Adobe and also figma
whatever your weapon of choice is for
tools but camo is probably the easiest
if you haven't done this kind of thing
cap cut has a couple features which are
key one is effects go to effects you can
find green screen green screen has green
screen photo and Green Screen Video if
you've seen any of my Tik toks or
Instagrams most of what I do is talk on
green screen put an image up behind me
that's 9 by6 I make all of them in coma
just pop Graphics in there and resize
them and then you literally can go
graphic to graphic and talk to them when
you've talked over one you go hit the
effects button again hit green screen
again and you put up another image and
you're talking over your second image
and you can make a video talking about
those is the easiest method to go talk
about things that you do or work online
doesn't need you to have a fancy setup
or a fancy camera it's all on the iPhone
use a wired headphone Apple headphones
mic is a great one to get started with
you don't want to spend any money or you
can use like a road mini mic I think
that's what I typically use like but
your goal is to make three of those a
week at least in perpetuity doing one of
those things cury what do I mean by that
find things that you like and share them
five grils that you have for for Brands
your favorite AFF Leisure fonts that you
use hacks for video techniques eight
design you should know whatever it is
curate find things that are out there in
the world put your spin on it and
explain why you like them as topic
category one do it in carousels you can
do it in video Whatever It Is carel 2 is
documentation we talked a lot about this
same thing as a gradual portfolio things
you do show the before and the after or
talk about what you did and what you
like to do better you're basically
developing your portfolio live a fun way
to do this and get a lot of views is to
tie into pop culture be like Nike
released this blank blank blank here's
how I would put my spin on it if I was
designing it or like I redesigned the
Buick Enclave whatever it is like take
something that's happening popular
culture and put your spin as a creative
on it I filmed a spec ad I made a i
redesigned this poster I did whatever
it's a very good way to leverage
attention on something that's already
popular but put your spin on it and
third is ideas and opinions this is a
lot of what I do online where you can
basically say cool I'm going to come
with a concept whether it's like a
tactic a strategy tactic for marketing
or it's just a way you think life should
be different or change or or hey this
thing is good or this thing is bad and
why but putting yourself out there
developing opinions and reason this is
big is because so few people have
opinions nowadays they just do what
everyone else says and does if you
develop an opinion you can objectively
say I think the Dior Stone Island collab
is good because X I think the
UnderArmour Baga collab is bad because
why you being able to say that online
developing the conviction and the
authority to be able to follow through
on that and believe it and writing like
that is an amazing exercise for
creatives begin to think uh objectively
about what is good and bad their sense
of taste what they like and they don't
and begin to refine yourself it's almost
just as important for you and your work
to be able to develop that conviction to
have an opinion online or to share an
idea that's original online than it is
to just get the views but you're going
to do those three things and you're
going to put those videos out you're
going to learn cap cut and literally
YouTube capcut tutorials I learned cap
cut by youtubing cap cut tutorial I took
Jimmy Farley's course you heard Jimmy
Farley from creators Corner making all
those kids rich on Tik Tok shop I bought
his $150 whatever and I got all the
basics and I got all the advanced stuff
from YouTube and it could literally be
that that simple but you can just track
down use cap cut green screen effect is
going to be the easiest way to start um
and any of these other formats I've
shown where you can like film a couple
clips and put put them together this is
the way you go make your content and
I've broken down some of those carels
and formats earlier in this video all
right I hope you found that valuable um
as you can probably tell if you're
watching a lot of my content I'm
splitting up my weeks so in the middle
of the week I'm doing Vlogs I'm talking
a lot more about my brand and what I'm
building during that and just also
showing aot a lot like lifestyle and
things that are a little more fun
interactive they're shorter please tune
in on that especially if you're
interested to see like how I'm building
what I'm building um those are the
videos I have the most fun with and I'm
excited for you to watch them so those
are going to be every Wednesday or
Thursday and then we are live every
Friday now myself Ashwin Jordan Rogers
Bea Williams I love the live format I
love live Q&A and feedback that people
get to watch us talk about what's
happening during the week and so you can
find that on YouTube here every Friday
morning I think it's 9:00 a.m. Pacific
time we are streaming and then the
recordings are up after it's a super fun
time if you like branding and marketing
and want like-minded people to chat with
it about and to hear us kind of talk
about any topics that you bring up we're
here to hit it uh drop any topics you
want to hear us say or work with in the
comments here and I appreciate yall
watching so much