all right today we're going to talk
about brand strategy if you are a
creative or have some creative skill set
your early in your career and you want
to learn how to advance into management
make more money and develop the skills
and toolkit to freelance you need brand
strategy if you are in the middle of
your career or at the end of your career
and you're starting to realize hey I
don't quite have the full toolkit to get
where I want to go or I want to someday
be more entrepreneurial or I want to
have something that differentiates me
you need brand strategy and what I've
noticed for the people that follow me on
this platform is you are either younger
and pretty Savvy and you're trying to
learn or you're older and you're pretty
Savvy you're on YouTube and you're on
Tik Tok and reals and you're trying to
figure out those missing pieces and this
is the exact toolkit that will separate
that I'm going to talk a little bit
about how I discovered brand strategy
I'm going to go a bit into the cardinal
rule you need to have to differentiate
yourself as a branding person and
creative that you either have it and you
know how to do it or you don't and we'll
talk about developing the toolkit for it
we're going to go into the foundations
of strategy developing a perspective for
your brand your project Etc we're going
to talk about turning perspectives into
themes that can apply to campaigns and
projects individual things you do we're
going to talk about how you do examples
and kind of document and present things
to make them make sense and we're going
talk about how strategy and tactics play
a part in making ideas actionable inside
Brands then we're going to talk about
building your toolkit and like a
feedback loop to actually get good at
strategy over time and throughout I'll
sprinkle in a decent amount about how
you can approach this either
entrepreneurially or with the idea of
like making better choices to get you
somewhere in your career or making money
freelance if you noticed this week I
dropped my first Vlog and I'm going be
doing that once a week and tell a little
bit more of like here's what I'm doing
here's the things I'm working on but
these videos that I do every Sunday I'm
treating them essentially like summer
school for people that want to be
excellent at branding or their brand
that I want to give you a toolkit in
every video that you walk out with and
you go oh I have something I can use now
I can refer back to this I can make some
docs from it and this is going to help
me get where I want to go so let's do it
so first off I was a designer first ER
is IA and then in New York primarily
graphic design I stumbled into doing
things with a more luxury Bend one of
the first big thorough projects I had
was for a night club that was a super
luxury oriented gold flakes in the
drinks Ultra exclusive uh I was just as
likely to spend the night there and T
pay would be than Justin Bieber Lindsay
Lohan broke up with her Samantha Ronson
there there was a whole world revolving
around this luxury feel that was very
important to keep up I did the logos I
did the menus I did the website I did
all the flyers I really worked with the
owner who became a good friend of mine a
mentor to me over time uh into like what
it takes to conjure that level of
experience but that was a designer doing
what I was told from briefs and ideas
given to me by somebody I didn't make
much money as a designer in that era
where I started to make real money was
when I applied strategy to design that's
why I became a creative director at an
agency and then when I began to make
real real money corporate world was when
I was able to take that into branding
and sales and be not just like a young
person who can both design and do some
Basic Marketing tactics but someone who
could say here's a strategy idea for
what we should do for holiday or for
this product launch and then over time I
began to accumulate more money because I
could do strategy on the side that's
something where it's like hey I actually
need to go spend 40 hours designing
something I can have a network I can
work with existing team and I can help
them craft a strategy now it's you
becoming entrepreneurial where strategy
is a huge part of everyday life to today
where I kind of I have a strategy
understanding tactically of marketing
and I understand the internet and social
media so I'm in a constant flow of very
well-paid Consulting specifically to do
that and this could be you but what's
the most important skill set I'm
starting here with this image in this
video I'm going show a bunch of examples
of content here to help prove some
points so why are we watching a video of
women's wear being dropped up and down
I'm doing this to talk to you about
perspective there are marketers that are
good and there's marketers that are bad
and one thing that all the marketers
that are good have in common is the
ability to put themselves in their
customer shoes and recognize when they
are not their customer my first
experience is this when I was working in
the outdoors market and the customer I
was selling to was a very wealthy Hunter
as a young relatively Metropolitan guy
who's spending my free money on like
cameras and trying to go to ultra I did
not know anything about what those
people wanted but the ability to
submerge myself into what they do was a
huge differentiator in being able to
sell to them and this is a skill set
that you need to pick up and it starts
just with acknowledging it acknowledging
I am not my Target demographic and in
some cases you might be it's going to be
perfect and you are trying to sell the
people just like you but for the vast
majority of projects you are not the
person you're selling to and here's why
this is really important and here's why
I bring up these video ideas is because
on the internet everything is content
everything is being sold through content
it's being given to us on algorithms in
my algorithm that I see personally as
Orin guy into design and luxury goods
and life in Southern California is not
showing me this but it is showing the
Target customer for a brand consult I'm
working on this exact video and many
more like it and so for me to be
successful at understanding an audience
I understand the people in it if a bunch
of the audience follows Victoria Paris
it's worth it for me to understand why
Victor Victoria Paris is popular the
kind of content she makes and how her
influence Works to them and this is just
an example because I work on a bunch of
female focused Brands a lot mainly
because there's a whole strategy
component for these brands that seems to
be underserved from a very tactical
standpoint there's amazing creative for
them but there's a connecting of the
dots that I seem to have stumbled into a
nisse shop but the same goes for luxury
Brands Outdoors Brands Southern Brands
Wellness Brands whatever it is just
understanding your Target demographic
it's putting them in their shoes and
asking what would they do so as a
strategist that is your job to ask a Who
is the customer of this brand and then B
who do we want the customer to be cuz
sometimes those might be different every
project starts with that who is the
customer and is the current customer or
the customer that we want and then you
need to decide am I marketing the
current customer or I marketing the
customer we want is it a vent diagram
that's also a circle or are we doing
both and then you need to actually
submerge yourself into what that person
sees and wants and how they're sold and
in particular content that impacts them
brand strategy today is like 90% based
on content which there's G be a lot of
people that watch that and there go like
oh my God this it's 1,00% true
everything is content all the stuff I'm
presenting in brand strategy is links to
content because guess what brands do
paid media and the paid media has
content from the center and every agency
and every person running paid media
wants more content to run in the ads the
brands are running organic content and
trying to grow on there by making
content themselves they are giving
product to influencers who make content
and they're putting out advertisements
in other verticals that are often
content in the form of ads there's
almost nothing that they are doing that
does not involve the quality of content
from Center so this is actually a gift
for you because it is easier than ever
to put yourself in another customer
shoes the first thing you do is you're
going to start burner accounts on
Instagram and Tik Tok and x and you are
going to follow and only engage with on
those accounts things in the niche
you're looking for so for instance if
you are looking at a women's wear
accessories brand you're going to go
follow influencers and women's wear
accessories and the brands that do it
and the easy way to do this Tik Tok
makes this mad easy because say I'm
diving into road the road customer I can
go search Road and I immediately see
these are popular people post Road I
haven't heard of any of these people
only one of them is from the road
account if I want to go understand who
the customer the road is appealing to
I'm going to go click through 1002 200 I
mean some serious volume of these I'm
going to follow all of them and I'm
going to interact with that content I'm
not going to interact with anything else
your entire job when you scroll those
feeds and you intentionally put time to
scroll those feeds is to understand this
customer this placement and you on that
account bookmark all the stuff that is
going to be relevant now you have a
whole path you can go look on for each
demographic you do so I have hella
account so many accounts that have
second phones because I have an account
where I'm looking purely at outdoors I
have an account where I'm looking purely
at luxury I have an account where I'm
really trying to get Gen X male like
understand what that looks like we have
accounts just for weird [ __ ] we have
accounts for different types of like
female focused Brands and then you can
begin to then have your bookmarks all
organized and look into it so if you
basically make these burner accounts
plus you do intentional scrolling which
to me is like take 15 minutes once
you've done your following whatever it
is three times a week and scroll with
the purpose of bookmarking something
that is effective or interesting idea or
a theme you see a bunch of you are
collecting a catalog that serves as your
perspective base and then you can have
your traditional toolkit customer
toolkit which is just putting together a
sheet being like my customer is a you
know I have an avatar presenting I have
a customer I call her Ava she is a 34
year-old woman she loves to like here's
where she shops here's the websites that
she goes to here's what her social media
looks like with some examples of people
like that like here's her rough
disposable income here's what she
prioritizes begin to walk through what
their life looks like in and around that
that that exercise just beginning to
craft that is great but also you know
what's awesome is basing that around
real people on social media and what's
nice is you start searching through some
of this find people that are doing
videos about it have like 4,000 views
that aren't influencers have an equal
match of influencers to real people
you'll start to see customer reviews and
you can tell what's kind of promoted or
not now you're beginning to build a real
base and the deeper you go the better
your strategy is going to be first chunk
of career advice if you are working at a
job and you are trying to uplevel in
that job do this for that brand and I
don't care what you do you're a
videographer you're a photographer
whatever you are you're in marketing
you're in branding you're in sales
you're in whatever if you go understand
your customer Avatar and have a bunch of
examples for it and then continually
bring it up in the right circumstance
when you're going through a strategy or
talking about ideas or execution being
like hey I actually have these three
things that you know I've seen from this
customer avatar from our competitor or
like these three links are doing really
well in our Niche right now you just
like start to slide that stuff into
emails and slacks and like be a person
that has that and you are immediately
going to become infinitely more valuable
and people are going to notice it and
you keep pushing it you have to be your
own Champion but you're being your own
Champion not like hey look at me I have
all this great stuff just by putting
more inputs out there and that is a
significant differentiator in getting
you where you want to go and then when
you actually do end up in an interview
or pushing for a position and you go and
be like look I'm your blank blank
designer or I'm your great videographer
your excellent marketing manager I want
to be your director and you know what I
do better than anybody else that's going
to come in for this position I
understand our customer look at this
here's 40 Links of the type of
influencers that appeal to our customer
here's all of our ugc categorized here's
what I think is good and bad about it
here's ideas that our competitors are
doing that I've organized into slots if
you come with a strategic perspective
like that into an interview to move up
people are going to like hey want you to
be working on it and B be impressed the
only thing you have to worry about is
then being threatened and those are that
kind of stuff that works itself out
anyway because you're going to end up
leaving scenarios where people who are
above you are threatened by your success
so now we're going to talk about turning
a perspective into a theme everything in
brand strategy is typically going to be
based on themes and so I'm going to use
this theme Here you see all these this
luggage videos that are coming out so if
I'm scrolling through this is something
I'm was literally doing on a project
scrolling through videos of like know
women's wear accessories and I'm seeing
a lot of like this travel theme I'm like
all right cool this is all just the same
produ presented in luggage but a cool
viral format for Content but then I'm
also noticing this Carousel that popped
off where very similar theme a lot of
things going on it's all kind of travel
related you know but is obviously
presenting luxury goods then I'm seeing
this type of content where these kind of
collages are really doing well I'm
starting to think okay well there's a
lot like Scenic photos and things in
here like lifestyle as well and then it
kind of clicks okay I've not started to
see a bunch of this the theme I think
that we should embrace for whatever
we're working on is travel so what do I
mean by theme and what does that go from
there so why how do I use a theme so the
things that you work on that need
strategy usually fall into a couple
buckets one we're going to make new ads
got to make new ads we need to basically
give a brief to whoever is going to make
the ads the second thing is we need to
make new content for our page for our
whatever we need to find new ideas to
make that content third we need other
people to make content we need to find
influencers or employee influencers and
they need to make content or we're
gifting out products to our customers
and that needs that or we're making
email campaigns to update our automation
or we're doing a website all those
things do better with themes they do
better with an idea or a campaign like
your traditional advertising campaign or
Equinox being like you know uh oh you're
going to bring Equinox up they're
they're a good example they had like
yearly campaigns for a minute like
commit to something was like it was a
theme it was a textu theme that they
brought up that would be used
overarching over time in a bunch of
different stuff and you see they use it
in like a bunch of different Graphics
Etc Equinox made me do it another one
more straight brand War law are most
recent one that like these kind of very
VIs Al sexual undertones but the commit
to something campaign is one of the the
more prolific but basically they have
this kind of conceptual theme that they
would then run through advertisements
and things for a while and you can see
how those will naturally expand but so
if I notice this travel theme now it's a
question of like what do I do with so
you develop a theme for your campaigns
and usually you're going to develop like
two or three to kind of pitch to people
be like hey for whatever it is we're
doing we're going to I want to have this
travel Focus or I want to have this
other campaigns more focused on this I
do a lot of this in notion docs and um
so like uh one I worked on recently we
were kind of positioning something that
was more like like a coet theme like
some kind of like if you haven't seen
all the things that have like bows and
these kind of very ornate pieces but
done in a slightly minimalist manner we
had a couple visual ideas in one and in
brief kind of you'll have a few visual
ideas where you're presenting a theme
for the campaign and strategies about
putting those themes forward and having
examples of them and so I would take
literally all these videos that I've
shown here and I'd be like hey here's
some examples of strategic content that
kind of has this travel theme and it's a
question of what do you do with it so
once you kind of have that theme idea
and you say here's an idea here's why I
think our customer will like it here's a
couple examples of interesting content
themes and styles I'm seeing on the
internet around it then it comes into
the conversation of okay what do you
actually do with it so I would say for
instance if you're seeding influencer
product so you're sending out a hundred
of whatever product to your company
every month to influencer you could say
we should add a strategy layer to that
maybe it's not doing good enough as it
is so you can say hey we're going to do
a campaign 90 days everything we send
out to those influencers we want them to
create content with a travel theme that
is a strategy application that could be
just as easy as hey we're running a
bunch of ads 50% of the new ads we do we
want to have a travel theme you
basically take your campaign put it into
the Json content that attaches to it and
then you start to get into how you do it
but for in this influencer case what I
would is I'd actually collect these
examples and be like hey we want you to
incorporate our product the whole theme
of the campaigns you're doing is travel
you can interpret that as you made we'd
like that to be a through line we want
you to use luggage inside your videos we
want you to be going places when you use
our product you know if you want to be
talking about it or integrating it in
the things you do have it have this idea
of going from one place to the other and
so you can give whoever you're working
with whe they're making ads or they're
creative or they're editing a video or
they're coming up a copy you give them
this Steam and you give them some ideas
and how they work through it then you
give them a toolkit about how to make it
good so here's an example of that for
strategy one of the reasons like
scrolling and stuff is great so POV is
interesting so videos that say POV POV
it's summer and you're picking her up to
get ice cream every day that's what this
artist did and you can have same as like
I have a series on my on my valuable one
I think um where I had like POV the plan
is starting to come together or
something like that um yeah POV the
vision is coming together right but all
it is is just a hook an idea for how you
connect a bunch of imagery that comes
after
and so for instance when I look at you
know obviously this content is doing
just fine without necessarily my help
but if I was doing this from a branded
perspective and asking influencers to
make you know content like this having
it be like POV girls trip or whatever it
is and then the theme of your campaign
is girls trip and you're using that in
your copy you're using it everywhere all
of a sudden you're beginning to put a
through line into what you're creating
and when you're asking influencers to do
that people are going you'll start to
see the more people post it if you have
50 people actually engage with the thing
in the campaign it has like a magic
effect online it becomes a thing that
other people people adopt because
they're seeing it to start happen all of
a sudden you're having like a bigger
impact outside from what you've already
kind of paid for or done you're begin to
have a cultural impact and that's the
kind of foundation of strategy is it
gets people talking beyond what you pay
to execute but what else can you do in a
toolkit so for instance a great thing
that I love to do going back to this
first example is take a couple you see a
couple themes of something happening in
content like this is happening right now
these videos are popping right now and a
little like maybe a couple weeks ago
these kind of videos where we're popping
to just just kind of obviously they just
flip the video and you'll start to see
like when you see a couple of a format
run cross your your screen you're going
to be like oh this is a thing and then
you can kind start looking to be like
how long has this been a thing but
either way give a couple pieces like
this like these hanging upside down or
the drop you saw or even something like
this we looked at before put a couple
clumps of examples together in the brief
that you're giving to a creative teams
or influencers and if you basically say
here's some ideas that we see are doing
well online right now you can use as a
basis for your content and then you
actually give them some tutorials go say
here's how you do that in cap cut or go
find million tutorials for how to do all
this stuff on reals and Tik Tok just go
find someone doing it and all of a
sudden if you get an influencer brief or
a brief your ad creative or your photo
team and it's like here's this visual
idea here's some examples of that visual
idea performing well organically online
here's a tutorial of how to actually do
some of that right there now You' have
completed the loop you are coming up of
the strategy and helping other people
implement it you are now probably the
most useful person working onside one of
these projects because you have the
ability to say here's how we make it
better and they have the ability to give
people the toolkit to do it and so if
you just focus on doing that on any of
these projects you do especially if
you're enabling others and the big part
about strategy is maybe you're doing
strategy you're than doing the final
application on yourself maybe you're
enabling others but either way you're
about making it better so if you're the
videographer a designer in this point
you're hunting down all these for
yourself so you can go I'm going to have
a theme for this I'm going to execute it
I'm going to use a new visual idea it's
going to work and then you can use this
basis and that's equally as powerful of
a concept if you want to just be a
better creative but then if you really
want to move up in a career or you get
into making money you're going to be
doing this as part of a larger team and
then when you start to take it to the
next level you're going to have done
this multiple times on M multiple
projects you're going to develop a
portfolio of this you're going to see
what works and doesn't you're going to
say I send people the examples but they
never actually do that so then you're
going to have to think about how am I
briefing this or how am I communicating
I need to do more of that or you're
going to say hey I we I put these ideas
in here but when they actually did them
they didn't perform maybe it was just
something that only worked at the time
but you're going to start to say this
idea of okay I need to communicate these
ideas better or maybe to this
demographic I communicate this
differently or hey the trends move way
faster by the time I actually get them
out I you know Trend stuff doesn't work
for me whatever that is feedback it look
at every time you do a strategy
postmortem what worked and what didn't
and the key columns to have within that
are does it not work because I didn't
communicate it well enough or stay on
top of the people well enough to execute
it or did it not work because the idea
didn't and there's a lot of times that
falls in the First Column and it's not
your fault and it's okay don't get
attached to it don't live and die by it
literally have the checkbox and say this
didn't work but I don't think it was my
bad but note what can I improve to make
sure that it works next time then you
have the ideas where you to say this
this doesn't work or this does and then
after 10 projects 15 projects 100
projects you've got a toolkit this is
your brand strategy toolkit you know you
can go drop the bomb when you need
something to work you know you have some
things that are like might work in this
circumstance you have some things you're
dying to try but like now you're working
with like a full deck as a strategist
and the reason I think this is a thing
worth bringing up and talking a lot
about is I feel like so many of these
creative roles are going to now be
replaced to some extent by like people
able to do it cheaper overseas some
functions of AI Etc your ability to
think critically about it and apply a
critical toolkit in your customer shoes
is something that like every person who
really wants to succeed is going to have
to do and what's nice is if you do this
a few times you put together that kit
that kit can literally be like here's a
theme with a mood board all right and
I'll show you one right here there's an
exact one that we were just pitching out
we like cool here's a big image that's a
thematic what we're doing with this
campaign here's a mood board I'm linking
to like this is just a screenshot of a u
from the cosmos mood board we made of
all the examples and references visually
we're looking at going into this project
here's things that kind of entice us and
we're interested in visually and I'll
make this public on Cosmos you can go SC
scroll scroll through it as well like
here's some of the visual inspiration we
have here's some brands that are doing
some stuff like this in in the right way
or that are kind of an example of this
look that we're going for so you can see
the content that they make and kind of
how that's going and then I'll go into
like amuse for it pick somebody who is
embodying this kind of theme that we're
going through and it's a good example
that we'd say if we're looking for our
perfect person to be like an embodiment
of this would be this person list out
some of the imagery we're looking at
opens the door to what that means like
can kind of talk a bit through like what
the angle means we're talking about like
this is an example of like a brief for
this this isn't the craziest thing
doesn't take you years to put together
but it's a simple effective format that
basically presents a strategy when you
get a whole bunch of these even if you
only get a handful your first two or
three that you've done when you actually
go to tell someone why should you hire
me you go here's my process when I come
up with I come up with a theme like this
and it's based in reality in the
customer Persona and then we go execute
a campaign your ability to say that
versus 90% of Freelancers that are
competing for something is like such a
leg up and if you do the kind of stuff I
do like I'm basically showing this in
public right now there will be brands
that will hit me because of this YouTube
video they'll be like I need that if you
begin to document here's how I look at
it or here's the theme or whatever it is
you're beginning to build that portfolio
and I'm going to do a whole separate
video on like starting to build your
personal brand not like becoming a
full-time Creator or anything like that
but like building your modern portfolio
is one of the ones I'm about to hit in
this in this series here I know I say
all the time these videos I have these
videos coming I do like write out a
bunch of them I have a million ideas but
that's one I think is really critical
but you developed this over time and all
of a sudden your Pinterest your Cosmos
are filled with a bunch of these
archetypes and links these campaign
ideas and you have some results of what
worked and what didn't and you're
thinking in your customer shoes you are
now a strategist you can use that job
and that toolkit and it will be able to
make you money it will allow you to rise
up be able to manage others and be a
crucial part of a team that may not be
the person actually executing the work
inside some of these organizations it's
going to allow you to think being a
manager being a director being a VP is
usually a combination of of three things
one is your ability to actually get
results out of other people and
communicate with other people two is
your ability to have strategy and impact
and three is the way you communicate
upwards and communicate to other parts
of the org in a way that makes them feel
good about your efficiency that's
probably a whole separate conversation
too but this is one of those key three
components and if you combin it with
even one of the other two you are a fit
for management which will make you much
more money and then last if you just
want to make a good work if you just
want to be making better work for what
you do you can take this angle with
yourself anyway that is my quick and
dirty guide to Brand strategy there is
obviously significantly more Nuance in
100 layers you can do but if you want to
do the minimum viable product that is
going to allow you to create interesting
better stuff and you're ble to Churn it
cuz a lot of what we're doing today in
today's world is about just [ __ ]
moving there's just so much content to
make so many campaigns to do and
everyone is behind in terms of the
velocity and volume they should have and
you can just knock out this type of
thing you can just hammer it you can be
doing this every week and you can be a
major part of why your brand is moving
fast and all these people were talking
about brand strategy is these these 400
items or we got to go in this checklist
or do these user interviews or whatever
you can be like yeah you know what but
what I'm doing actually works and see
social results and the feedback loop is
super quick so we're going to that
because I can run 10 of them in the
speed you can run that one process
anyway a bit of a rabbit hole appreciate
you watching if you have questions on
this stuff you want to hit more in this
series let me know appreciate you
watching as always I will be back with a
vlog in the middle of the week and
another one of these next Sunday plus up