I'm the active CEO of a 2500 person
global agency. I am the copywriter. With
all due respect to every CMO in the
world, I have four active massive
companies. I'm busier. And if I can do
it, you can do it. I am the human being,
me, me, me, who has built the largest,
most significant independent global
agency from scratch in the last 15
years. That's me.
>> So, I'm super excited that in this
week's YouTube, we are sitting down with
the one and only Gary Veaynerchuk. And
this isn't your average Gary Vee
interview you may have seen all over the
internet. We don't talk as much about
Gary Vee, the personal brander. We talk
about Gary Veaynerchuk, the businessman,
the agency owner who works with Vayner
Media, when one of the largest agencies
in the world on social strategy, on
brand strategy. And so Clayton and I,
who runs my hyper newsletter with me, we
got to sit down with him at night at
Khan, the advertising film festival. We
are literally fountain side with people
going by saying hi to him. But to
basically chop it up and have a moment
to talk about the advertising world,
executives making content, brands
understanding content, AI's role in the
future of content, how he stays current,
his team, and the changing nature of
everything in this industry. So without
further ado, we're going to get right
into it. I think you guys are going to
like this conversation. Let's lock in.
[Music]
So we are here at KN with one of the
most inspiring people for content and
creative. I know inspired a lot of what
I do myself, Mr. Gary Vee.
>> Thank you brother.
>> But we want to talk a bit about what we
do inside Hyper about the brand strategy
side of this. What people are thinking,
how creators work in the creator
economy. We're just going to get into a
bunch of questions and just see if we
can get some interesting answers, spark
some conversation.
>> I'm looking forward to it. So the first
one I want to talk about, one of the one
of the things we were talking about
going into this week was this idea that
also a big beauty retailer, they've
started putting a bounty on creator
content from their employees. They
started to say, "Hey, we want to
actually engage this Gen Z that is doing
so much creation." I'm curious like you
run a big company, you work for all
these big companies. How can they start
to mobilize this creator generation?
>> Full disclosure, I don't know if you
guys know this. Spayer Media works very
closely with Alta. You know, I mean,
look, I think content coming from
anywhere, whether it's an AI prompt
engineering, whether it's a kid in their
basement in Amsterdam that's a
16-year-old girl that just has it,
whether it's agencies, whether it's your
employees, whether it's your interns.
I'm agnostic and I think that every
brand in the world should be looking to
drive down its cost of creative and
really understand how to make creative
at scale that is relevant to as many
different consumer segmentation as
possible. I think we will see a huge
movement of more organizations
empowering and enlisting their employees
especially retail where a lot of those
employees on the floor actually know
their [ __ ] QSRs like just the employees
at restaurants. So I think it's a very
good idea and I think you will see more
and more of it.
>> We obviously have jinzy and younger
people who have grown up in the social
first era and live and breathe that very
much not the case from many executives
or CMOs who are in more corporate
positions, right? They didn't grow up
making content in a native way.
>> No.
>> What are the things that you're telling
them in rooms and meetings every day
that helps them create a mindset shift
for this new wave? One of the things
that has built Veayner, I think if you
surveyed this industry, like why did
Vayner get so big? I think people would
overly give Gary Vee credit and underly
give Gary Vaynerchuk credit if that
makes sense. Right? What do I do as Gary
Vaynerchuk? I sit in business meetings
for hours and break down actual black
and white details of how, you know, when
a single Tik Tok gets 40 million views,
you sell the living [ __ ] out of a
product. And you know, there's not a
single commercial on earth that can make
that claim. So, I think we have business
meetings. I also think that most CMOs
don't know how it works. Like, they're
not practitioners. The thing that makes
my company dangerous is I'm the active
CEO of a 2500 person global agency and I
I me and I'm going to show you this. You
guys will find this interesting. I me I
me writing the copy
>> 32 minutes ago
>> of my post. Me, I am the copywriter. And
more CMOs need to be like at that level.
Even if it's just to make that first
video that can get to 5,000 views is a
challenge. Like understand the hook.
>> With all due respect to every CMO in the
world, I have four active massive
companies. I'm busier and if I can do
it, you can do it. They just don't think
it's important. So, you know, I think I
explain to them the black and white. I
show them the truth. And it comes from a
business lens, not a let's win a can
lion, not a it got a million
impressions. Well, what does that mean?
A million impressions when you spend
media ads on Facebook could mean
nothing. You spent enough money to get a
million views on Facebook on a piece of
[ __ ] piece of creative on Facebook,
beloved social media, and it won't do
anything.
>> It's understanding why organic social
matters as a creative validator. It's
understanding what to do with that piece
of creative when it works. How do you
convert it into Substack or an email or
how do you spend $5 million in media to
amplify it if you're a Fortune50
company? like I'm really in it and I
show them how it could actually drive
their business and that works.
>> And so knowing that you're this deep,
you know, uh, and we're thinking about
this a lot as people who are growing
personalities as you look at younger up
and cominging agencies who are saying,
"Hey, we're already ahead of the curve."
Like what keeps you up at night? What
are the things that you're really
thinking about being like, "How do I
orient my business to be in front of
it?" The only thing I'm concerned about
is what AI is going to do in the short
term that mitigates or commoditizes
things that we have advantages of. In
the long term, I'm not worried about it
because I'm a real businessman and I'm
already way ahead on live social
shopping production capabilities for the
biggest brands in the world. Check. I'm
already very ahead of fashion and
collectibles as marketing. meaning like
I I really see fashion LTO's and
collaborations and I see collectible
integration into products as a major
marketing thing that's not being talked
about here. I'm already very advanced on
>> Thank you guys. I'm already very
advanced on experiential events as
production days for creative. So I'm
already attacking virtual influencers.
I'm like very advanced. Uh AI, search
engine optimiz like I'm playing for 2030
right now. But I have to be aware that
some of the things that Boehner
dominates the world on social creative
at scale better than everybody else and
what that all means has the potential to
be commoditized.
>> What are the things that you think with
respect to AI on the brand side brand
should be or good examples of AI
applications that brands are using right
now in the dayto-day. We're still in
this moment where it feels like a lot of
brands are hesitant to make any moves
cuz everyone's always sort of waiting
for someone else to be like who's going
to like have this first good use case or
this first case study. We saw the the
the Glance AI stuff earlier today with
with with you know live shopping and
it's like what brands are putting those
things to use right now? I think I think
E.L.F. Cosmetics is doing a nice job.
And to be honest with you, after that,
I'm not sure cuz I just One of the weird
things with me is I don't really pay a
lot of I don't know a much about what's
going on here. I only care about the
consumer. Like I don't need inspiration
from Delta or Reebok or Coca-Cola. That
to your point and I'm empathetic for
everybody who's watching. I'm empathetic
that brands need someone to do it for
them to be like, "Oh shit." Okay. But
the truth is like especially with
characters like yourselves starting to
emerge, there's this new crop of people
that are covering the industry that are
not adage, that are not adequat. And you
[ __ ] are going to give them
examples every day. Like I'm bored by
the concept of like I have to show you
an example of another old brand doing it
right. When I talk to my clients, I'm
like, can we please be the people that
do it? Like you know, uh some of my
creative team is very excited. We work
on Pinesol. Pines's crushing Tik Tok
right now. Have you seen it?
>> Yeah. So, like watching some of my
traditional creatives who I'm bringing
along like I don't know if you guys can
see these goosebumps like two very
meaningful meetings today with ECDs in
my company who I brought over from Droga
and Mischief and Wid and those kind of
places and they're like [ __ ] man four
people today in the randomness we're
like Pine Soul. I'm like that's my work.
I'm like [ __ ] you've been in
this business for 30 years and no one's
ever said anything about your work but
this you know what I mean you guys know.
>> So it's all this stuff this jargon I'm
spitting right now. But that's in
general. This is uh this is our first
time at Kent.
>> We're coming out from that other
perspective. Hey, we're talking about
Tik Tok shop and scaled affiliate and
we're talking about all these things all
day, the creator economy and hearing
what the topics are seems to be kind of
a big shift even how the brands
activate. And so I'd be curious if you
were
>> advising obviously there's agencies and
there's actual brands looking for
dollars. Anyone at Canon wants to do an
amazing job with actually presenting
their brand, doing doing an exhibit,
doing an activation, doing a presence,
like what should they focus on?
>> You're not wasting money on dumb [ __ ]
that nobody gives a [ __ ] about. Like
what the [ __ ] is that billboard?
>> Show them, bro. Thank you. Like not that
one. That one I'm okay with a little.
That one right there. Like what is that?
Like on a like on the top of like I
don't know. Like I will bet my [ __ ]
life that that QR code gets click like
clicked less than 10 times this whole
week, you know? Like like I don't know,
man. Like honestly spend more time like
actually being with people. Like look at
what I'm doing. I would choose to do
this with you guys over like an
interview with the like I don't know a
traditional media thing. It's just
contemporary understanding. I think if
you want to stand out here, I think you
try to be very clever. You try not to
waste money on dumb [ __ ] and you try to
bring value. Even the Vayner prep, like
these Vayner things, we're helping
people get around because we know
logistics are hard here. That's a good
idea,
>> right? Like like
>> actual experience a consumer enjoy.
>> Yeah. like like the Vayner Express is
literally helping people get around this
town and like people are like thank you
like that's good you know like and so
we're thinking about those things.
>> It is funny what you bring up around the
traditional media I think about a lot
cuz when you actually present numbers to
people they're like how many views do
you have a month how many subscribers
you have and it's like larger than many
legacy media in the space and people
just don't understand what
>> you guys also because of the nature of
what you do have the potential to make
one social media post that will get more
awareness than anything a traditional
play will do for a month.
>> Yeah. My last question to wrap things up
maybe more on like the personal side.
You you've been in Vayner business for
how many years now? Like how long?
>> Uh we launched in May of 2009. Okay.
>> So 15 almost 16 16 years.
>> Yeah. I mean you have firmly been
preaching the gospel of social first
content the way before so many brands
are ahead of time. Like you've been a
huge inspiration for me early in my own
creator journey as well. But for you
looking back, like if if you were to go
back and tell yourself a string of
things uh as advice to younger Gary,
like what would those things be knowing
what you know now?
>> The same advice I just gave you guys
like, "Hey, you remember when you wrote
that $200,000 check into Facebook? Make
it 600,000 and borrow money cuz you're
going to make you're going to make $13
million for every 50,000 bucks." You
know, I I think what I would do is cuz
I've been so uncomfortably historically
correct, I think that I would just ask
myself to squeeze more of the orange.
Like, I was right. Like, I'm comfortable
saying that the world thought it was a
cucumber and I thought the world was an
orange. And I went to that orange and I
squeezed it and I really [ __ ]
squeezed it. But the truth is, you'll
know this if you've ever squeezed an
orange for fresh juice. There's more to
squeeze. And even I could have made more
content, could have been more loud,
could have traveled. There was a lot of
meetings I didn't go to. Like I saw
Spotify early. Like all I had to do was
DM Daniel Ek get to Sweden. Like like I
left an enormous amount of opportunity
on the table in 16 years out of sheer
like not being 11 out of 10 in every
turn and every moment because no human
can. I've been pretty [ __ ] 11 out of
10 with content, which is why I am who I
am. I might be the only human here, but
but in in business development, in
business opportunities, you know, I
think this is like interesting to say
here, I've never really said it like the
way I'm about to say. I've said versions
of it, but like I am the human being, me
me who has built the largest, most
significant independent global agency
from scratch in the last 15 years.
That's me. And that's cool. Like that's
a nice accomplishment.
>> Well, it's amazing for the rest of us to
see like here's all these institutions,
here's all these people. How could you
possibly be? It's like, hey, guess this
guy did it. You just pulled it out of
the universe by attrition, ideas,
>> being right, operationalized, being an
actual businessman and not just a
blowhard. I'm not a provocator. I'm
actually an executor of truth of today.
For you guys, I'm the only one that
makes sense. For a lot of these [ __ ]
I'm the only one that doesn't make
sense. For the two guys behind the
camera now shaking their head, it's me.
>> That truth hurts.
>> For for 60 year olds who like believe in
a world of yesterday, it's not me. my
big goal at 49 years old. I can still
chop it up with y'all. In fact, I can
chop it up probably deeper than y'all.
Especially if I'm doing that with you
guys, then I'm still in it. The question
for me becomes is like when will I not
be that guy? When will I sit with you
too? Like will be will there be anything
where I sit here and I feel like [ __ ]
these kids know a lot more than me. I
prefer to never
>> live so maybe a while. Yeah. Yeah.
>> You know, but but I mean, you know what
I mean? Like the next thing like like to
me I'm still in that place where like
I'm just going to be more curious and
deeper and and I'm going to keep trying
to build, you know? I'm going to keep
trying to build and I want to still be
that guy. I want to be that guy as long
as I possibly can because I want to be
the person that people like yourselves,
other winners look up to. And I want to
be that good cuz that means that I'm
still in it. I'm still that guy. And I
feel like I'm lucky I'm not in sports.
It's not like where your body breaks
down and you can't. And I think for the
Kobes and the LeBron and and the Jordans
and the Bradies and the Federers, their
body had to break down eventually. I'm
in business and that won't happen and I
want to see how far I can take it.
>> Super inspiring to watch. Thank you for
all that you do.
>> Thanks for having me, man.
>> Thank you guys. Continued success.
Really, I really like what you guys are
doing and like this space needs more
characters like you. So, I'm like I
really wanted to support and do this.
>> We really appreciate it.
>> On the side, man, I just wanted to say
too like I know you obviously here
because of Tyler and Nick. Like Tyler
and Nick are the [ __ ] It's like
the people that you build and just I I
see this too with other people at the
company. Like
>> it's really important for you guys to
watch that.
>> You know, that goes to another thing
that people don't understand why I was
able to do it. It's that and it's
putting those it's putting him and Nick
spending real time to know who they are
and put them in a position that actually
can [ __ ] impact like there are no
Nicks and Tylers in other organizations.
People that care to [ __ ] put on like
that doesn't exist. Yeah. So, I think I
hope you guys see that and as you
continue to build your empires, you
think about little different moves that
are different like that's made up what
Nick and Tyler do. It's made up. Go in
the world and bring value to the [ __ ]
next crew. Like,
>> oh, we are we're looking. It's funny.
It's only the only blueprint we have.
It's amazing the final frontier.
>> 100%. Especially with an AI world.
>> Thank you.
>> All right. Big thank you to Gary for
coming on. If y'all don't know, Clayton
and I who are in this video, we run a
brand strategy newsletter called Hyper.
It is free weekly and we cover cutting
edge of strategy from affiliate,
creative direction, ads, etc. for
brands, both small and large. I'm going
to link that down below cuz this is just
an excerpt from the full Gary interview.
We're going to put the full transcript
inside the newsletter this week. I know
I haven't done frequently done guests,
so if you like this, please let me know.
And I can easily get other creative
directors and art directors. I can get
experts in things like meta ads, or I
can get more high-profile people like
Gary. If that's content that y'all want
to check out, please let me know and we
can tailor some future videos around it.
As always, appreciate y'all watching. I
will be back in the next two weeks with
videos on heritage maximalism and that
aesthetic style of brands like 1803
Bully and Burberry and a video on dark
marketing and some of the gray area
tactics that a lot of people don't talk
about, but you see happen all the time.
As always, appreciate y'all watching and
I'll be back next week.
[Music]