Marketing has been changing completely
and no one is talking about it. We
actually live in an era where marketing
is almost like a sport. More people know
and understand marketing than ever.
Mostly because of the internet and
content around it for the last few
years. Also, this comes with an increase
in like small business acumen because of
things like Shark Tank and all the gurus
we know and love. But a lot of the
trends that are happening are really
hard to put in the snippet. And a lot of
the people that make content about this
stuff don't really live it. And if they
do, aren't on the cutting edge. they're
too far removed or they're too
impersonal brands or selling courses or
their niche. In this video, I'm going to
walk through the actual trends and
extremely important concepts that are
not being talked about almost anywhere
on the internet. We're going to talk
about visual world building, product
marketing, 10x creative directors, how
mainstream AI ads have gone, the
clipping era, brand trips, event
rollouts, and global rollouts, the rise
of indie brands on social, and how
bigger marketing institutions are
beginning to get better now. why we need
to stay on the edge. There'll be
campaign examples for all of these. I
want this to be both fun to follow and
educational if you work in the space.
And I promise you there is no marketing
content like this on the internet. Let's
lock in. So, first I want to talk about
the app Aura and this concept of world
building. You've heard this a lot. A lot
of marketing people have co-opted this
term, but the Aura app is basically a
running app. You can showcase your run
with custom graphics and a lot of
graphics they curate themselves. What
Zach has done is using AI mostly has
taken pieces of internet culture of all
kinds and rapidly implements them into
the app. People really want to share
Aura and share this absolutely
constantly whenever they do their runs.
They make it so much more likely to
share their workouts. But each piece is
basically a piece of in internet
ephemera for lack of a better term where
Zach will grab all of these pieces of
culture from the Drake fonts to adding
like Call of Duty killreak graphics
building his own quotes and lore even
recurring characters and things they've
talked about to form the story around
his app. And what is particularly
interesting about this is this app was
basically born on X where he said he
built it in public from his initial
concept to prototypes to graphics to
beta to launch. Then he brought it over
to Instagram and then people began
sharing it and multiplying it. People
sharing this app that people have not
seen before with all these graphics and
things that look familiar and now
characters and through lines and ideas
that he's pushing through. This gives
this new visual building which is kind
of completely different than any roll
out or thing that we've seen before in
software. But it reminds me a lot of
this podcast called the technology
brothers podcast tbn if you have not
heard of this. So they rolled out with a
very strong visual feel. The podcast
hosts were in suits. They were in a more
formal environment. They were reading
tweets printed off on paper. It felt
more professional, more real, more put
together than what we'd seen prior. It
evolved into a live show that mirrors
almost exactly what would be on a major
news network. But they've now built
their brand world by basically having
snippets again just like a news site
that lives within the things like a new
profile pick for a former open AI
executive or the world's largest
longrange aircraft being delivered.
Engineers becoming a girl dad. They are
using a visual universe of the way they
present themselves, the graphics of how
they present their episodes to the
promotions that move out around it to
treat the content and the brand of their
content like a modern news network to
position against kind of more
traditional technology podcasts and
allin and antiquated stuff like that and
tell an interesting visually dynamic
story. And what's important here for all
marketers to recognize is the playbook
has very much changed about how much
media you can turn out, how constant you
can keep the conversation and the
network effects that happen when people
believe in it and have a toolkit they
can adopt. Much like we see things like
Wimbledon or the US Open or people
dropping thousands of pieces of content
are understanding fundamentally of
velocity in marketing, how much can get
covered, how much content you can put
out. TVPN is live for hours every single
day and they evolve to there from a
podcast within months and what you
should be covering and the role of what
media looks like. And I bring up this
media role because it's important for
brands too. More and more now you see
brands hiring for media roles, whether
that's coaching employees to make
content, ghostwriting for the founders,
or opening up whole media arms. A16Z is
a whole media arm coming together
because they're realizing that a lot of
lifestyle journalism and a lot of
industry coverage people want to listen
to no longer comes from journalism.
There's a stark divide between wanting
to read that the terribleness of the UX
on those sites and the unqualified
nature of most of the people that write
for those publications versus having
that happen by people that actually
operate in it with a more
straightforward relationship of a brand
gives you good content, maybe you'll
want to buy their products. you actually
know the motivations there versus
darker, more complicated motivations
that come from the traditional
journalist ecosystem. And this goes for
marketing the same way. People much
rather consume things from the marketing
creator ecosystem. People curating those
news sources because ad week or ad age
seems brutally out of touch. They can't
even make their own good content. Why
would you listen to them about what
content is? and knowing the people that
they cover most often in agencies or the
same people sponsoring these events or
that and no idea what the real economics
or implications of the relationship look
like. But along with world building, we
are in the product as marketing era. So
Skiims released this head wrap. They had
Anthony Hopkins relive his Silence of
the Lambs character as part of its
debut. And this is an example of
something that maybe they'll sell a
bunch of units. Maybe this will be a
success. I don't think so. I doubt this
will even work. but it is purely
marketing inside the product roadmap.
This has worked for a while. You would
see brands release concept products or
release products that were more meant
for virality. But now people that were
on it early, this is now built in. This
is in the product development meetings.
This is in the release schedule. They're
years into it. It's become adopted.
That's an important concept to consider
because the product development cycle
takes time. It took time to actually
activate on this as a strategy. So
someone's a couple cycles ahead. They're
already so much better at it than
others. And mainstream companies get it
too. This is Progresso. They made real
soup drops. That's purely a marketing
stone. This is purely marketing, but
they made them. They're real and people
could buy them. And this now happens in
the mainstream. For instance, this
Gustaf Westman IKEA collaboration
featured this meatball tray that again,
you may have, you're rarely going to
use, is there for virality. There's been
more conversation around this meatball
tray than the collaboration itself. And
that drives then demand for the
collaboration. That's always been the
point of these viral items is to drive
conversation about the topic to then get
people to go consume more normal stuff
cuz they don't really need a meatball
tray. But while they looked at the page,
maybe they saw something they actually
do need. This concept has gone from cool
idea to built into serious companies.
IKEA, SKIMS, Progresso is in their road
map. This is cemented. So this is
something that if you have a serious
brand should be certainly thinking about
and in the midst of. And the key thing
to solve is how do the marketing teams
and product teams work together to find
theQs, get ahead, develop the viral
item, make it both interesting enough
and functional enough they may want to
actually work for your customer,
forecast it, act on it, and make it a
recurring part of what you build
together. And this is one thing I want
to call out. You do not have a social
media team member working with your
product team. We're in the packaging
meetings. You need people that
understand how things move online
because those little changes, those
tweaks, the color schemes, the
postability of anything makes a massive
difference in 2025. One of the related
concepts I want to talk about is this
idea of the 10x creative director. I
talk a lot to people about why Skims is
on top cuz everyone will assume it's the
Kardashians and certainly that's part of
it, but they also have an example of
what I call a 10x creative director. And
this is Nadia Lee Cohen. She's probably
a 100x creative director. That's a
separate cop topic, but basically this
idea that whoever's taking the photos
and the videos is good enough to propel
the brand into culture. And she's a
perfect example of this. Her shooting
the Cavali Skiims campaign is the
difference between me being okay and it
being innately viral. You can tell from
every image it's one of her images.
Medium format film look is crushing it.
She has her trademarks. They care about
the presentation. She is doing this at a
level of pure excellence from her
involvement and the added her social
media and her million followers and her
cult around what she's put together is a
massive multiplier for that brand.
That's not for everybody and I want to
talk about that. I want to talk about
the level below this because there's a
whole generation mostly women who are
propelling these modern brands forward
by thinking like this. So, you've heard
me talk a lot about David Bar. This
woman Sarah is the creative director
there. You're like creative director of
a protein bar. Like what does that even
mean? Why would they need that? But
David is an extremely aesthetically
driven brand, right? That gold wrapper
reminds you of a power bar from back in
the day, but has that Greek refinement
to it, playing into all the aesthetic
tropes that we know and just makes it
seem immediately appealing. They got
aesthetics from the start. They're also
leaning into conceptual marketing.
Product is marketing. They launched COD.
This has been talked about to death, but
to give you a quick recap, they launched
basically a fish bar with the emphasis
that we care so much about protein and
the macro content of these products that
we make that we're going to give you the
highest source, basically a stunt that
they put out. They prove that the only
thing is as protein dense as eating a
David bar is a literal brick of cod that
you could actually purchase. But the
campaign to release that was
immaculately creative directed by this
woman and her associated crew. But it
presented the brand with the autist
triggering silverware, a creative
directed look and feel and an actual
campaign with the roll out for a CPG
brand that traditionally would do
absolutely nothing like this. It's like
a fashion roll out and then continue to
actually complete a set of aesthetic
imagery that really tells the brand
story in a compelling and unique way.
What she is doing for this brand from an
aesthetic and a campaign angle, even in
just these two things we're talking
about in this brand's arc as a new
brand, is a 10x multiplier on how it
will be regarded in space over time if
it continues. And the same goes for
people inside the beauty worlds. This
woman works with a ton of beauty
campaigns and basically is responsible
for kind of artful and interesting
teaser and campaign content. She has her
own trademark style, these kind of
compilations of images and behind the
scenes and art coming together. But I
have seen her do campaigns for like a
dozen major beauty brands, all of whom
are kind of competitive with each other,
but they don't care as long as they can
get their hands on some of her work to
actually promote what they're working
on. This is House Labs next to Flur,
next to Salt and Stone, next to Dior
Beauty, next to Fenty Skin, next to
Nars, next to Road. All of those brands
compete with each other. Salt and Stone
a little bit on the side. This is really
good content. I'm not saying it's
ultraviral, but it is good artful brand
building creative content that she has a
knack for. It's good another ad asset
you can be testing inside the campaign.
But people who have this skill set, I
show her and all the brands she's doing
because that shows you the demand for
creative level content has any level of
resonance. Again, none of this is even
ultraviral or even semi viral. It is
bass hits that are good, but they are
brand builders by the nature of the
visuals and who they appeal to and why.
And the fact that she's behind it. So,
you have an if you know, you know aspect
as well. And there's a whole cottage
industry of these people out there that
can be multipliers for brands, musical
artists. I believe I found Sandy cuz she
was doing art direction for K-pop groups
that were standing out, but then all of
a sudden she's doing this like
sexualized doll supreme campaign. There
are people out here who can move the
visual zeitgeist. They are in extremely
high demand. They're often shooting a
lot of these things themselves or at
least know the access to the crews to be
able to do it. And they are pulling the
strings of the tasteful angles inside of
social media. And with the exception of
Naughty Lee Cohen there, none of those
are household names. All right, so as
many of you know, I launched a new
domain the other week. I bought creative
director.net and I put together a
landing page in Framer and gave you a
bit of a tutorial about how I chose the
template and how quick it was for me to
put it together. But I want to highlight
a new feature Framer has released that
makes editing websites super easy for
you or your team. So if you are on any
live framer site the way I am on here,
you'll notice this little edit button on
the left. So you can actually just click
edit and this is the live site. As long
as I'm logged in in Framer on this live
site, I can edit any of the stuff you
see here. So you'll see I can roll over
any of the sections it allows me to
change. And so I'm going to update this
cuz I am going to do my next webinar on
October 22nd. So, I'm just going to go
in here and literally change it to
October 22nd. And here, I click this
image. I could change the type. I can
swap it out. Same thing here. Even with
the form, I could change my form ID with
ConvertKit. All without even going into
an editor. And I click finish editing
and it is just live. So, if you are a
designer who is making sites that your
clients are going to update, you now
have an easy way to tutorial them having
to do it without even having to touch an
editor. Or if you have a team and you've
been editing your own site and you want
to update it with a VA or have someone
who's not as design savvy do it, you can
lock this in here. And it's just one of
the many reasons why I love to choose
Framer for portfolio sites and business
sites. So an interesting time to be in
the web design ecosystem with all these
tools coming out. You can learn more
about Framer and get started with the
link that I have in the description.
Let's get back to it. But moving over
into the AI ad world, you don't hear me
talk a ton about AI on this channel. I
think a lot of its applications people
spend waste a lot of time pursuing. But
the one that has been the most dramatic
is what happened specifically with this
guy PJ PJ Asuro um who I've talked to
super nice guy super talented he's
working on a campaign on a project I
have at work but he created this Koshi
campaign. Now obviously you will see
things like sports betting and gambling
and stuff be on the fringes of adoption
of a lot of marketing but they created
these basically like almost hype reel
marketing style videos where they were
able to use AI for all the clips and
kind of create these otherworldly
appealing campaigns. But Khi did it.
They put this together in two days. It
is on television. It went viral and
shows you that the fringe conversation
that creatives are having about oh AI or
not AI or does the consumer like it or
should we allow these tools? Those
conversation is already over. The
watershed has already broken. This is
already more popular than almost any
creative asset created by purely a human
by an artist has been replaced by one ad
for a AG1 competitor done by a handful
of people in days. And so it's hard to
present the implications of that or even
just participate in the argument.
Participating in that argument is a
waste of time. The result is already
here. It is already epic and resisting
it is feudal. Instead, what you need to
be doing is understanding how you can
effectively use something like that to
tell your story. To say, maybe I I don't
want to worry about consistent
characters or this or that. I want to be
able to take ideas from a brain and
generate them extremely fast in a
compelling way to tell stories that
invoke emotion in a way that make
content travel. But moving back one
notch, touching on David one more time,
they're an example of what I call a USP
to Tik Tok shop pipeline. Tik Tok shop
is still vastly misunderstood. I've
spent an ungodly amount of time the last
6 months trying to convince some of the
brands I work with to go further in on
this is a hard conversation is a thing
people do not understand is not native
to a lot of folks. Retail is terrified
of it. So if you're also in retail they
don't want to be competing against it is
complicated and misunderstood. But if
you have a strong USP unique selling
proposition the things that sell your
product. Tik Tok shop is a heavyweight
battering ram to get your brand into the
world. David being a perfect example
ultimate example of a USP. Their macros
is better than any macro in any protein
bar you can possibly buy. We get more
protein for less calories with very
little sugar. That is the requirements.
Every single person who buys protein
bars looks at that goes, "Does it taste
okay?" And that is the vetting process.
And they have won that battle
scientifically. And that allows them to
hammer Tik Tok shop ads cuz the best Tik
Tok shop ads go unique selling
proposition. Hammer it in and then add a
couple vehicles on that. This deal is
leaving soon. Is this worth the money?
Here's the results from doing X and Y. a
lot of proven viral factors, but it all
comes down to are their rock solid USPs.
Now, other protein bars have noticed
this. One that I like and I'm a consumer
of called Prima have basically been
like, "Hey, we are positioning very
different than David." David's like,
"You're going to get all these macros."
Prima's like, "You're going to get all
natural. No seed oils, no weird stuff.
This is like purely beef tallow and
honey and all that. You want something
that is completely unprocessed. This
tastes good." And the macros are I and I
respect it. Do I wish it had 90% less
sugar and I'd deal with the taste with
that? Yes. But I get the American
palette. Peanut butter cup Doritos
sausage curved panini and let's crack a
cabaret egg over the whole thing.
>> But they are have a USP for that. You
want a all natural thing that's
positioned against this other popular
thing and all these other brands in the
market. You can read every ingredient
and understand what it is. That's a rock
solid USP for Tik Tok shop and they're
blowing up from it. If you're in this
algorithm, you've probably seen sour
berry puff and someone else saying, "You
know what? Do you not care about any of
that [ __ ] and you just want something
that tastes completely outrageous and
disgusting and it gets the job done?
Here's sour berry puff." Right? But it's
just worth noting if you have USPs,
actual unique selling points to the
product, the scalability of that on Tik
Tok shop and the ability to say I give
an affiliate a percent, I give them 20%,
30%, whatever it is of a sale and that's
all that I give and I send out product.
I have an economic model that means that
whenever the posts are made about it, I
pay off that commission. I fulfill the
order and I still make any amount of
money. Any amount of money is a win and
the I can get as much of that out of the
ecosystem as I desire. That is a
mathematically driven business scaling
system with which the economics are
intrinsically better than just purely
running ads and having to force more
creative into it. Plus, with GMV Max and
things like that in Tik Tok shop, you
can steamroll. You can add fuel to the
fire, push a lot more of those ads out
there to actually boost that on your own
as well and build a machine these brands
are actively doing. What I love most
about it is you can explain it to the
finance team as a quantifiable machine
is a perfect merger of operations,
marketing, product, and finance from
which like giant companies can be born.
Fired up, not going to lie.
>> Just do it.
>> Moving over to the dark web and [ __ ] and
clipping our boy TJR. So, first, if you
are not familiar with the concept of
clipping, this has gone pretty
mainstream now. Most of you who are
consumers of content get it. But it's
this idea that people are being paid on
a platform called [ __ ] which is a
facilitator of paying people for things
on the internet and absolute legends in
their own right. That's a separate
video, but basically a person or a brand
can set up a [ __ ] give access to a big
library of footage and say, "Clip this
footage into like basically ming
clipping edit this footage into things
that will perform on the internet within
these parameters." Some people have no
parameters. Do whatever you want. Make
it as risque as you'd like it to be.
Some people have more brand standards
and we will pay you a bounty by its
performance. So basically we've now
moved from having to quantify views for
sales before views being worth
something. We will pay you x amount of
dollars per thousand views of things you
click from this. Good editors sometimes
get put on hiring and they move out of
the WAP ecosystem entirely and you just
pay them to actually work for you.
That's what a lot of gurus have and
they'll have a team of assistant like
other people that supplement that within
the WAP or it's all done through there.
They'll be bounty say, "Oh, you know
what? This brand has a good content
library and they're paying $8 per
thousand views or whatever it's pretty
high." And they will move around to find
the right balance of can I make the
content go and am I getting paid enough
for it. And this came to the forefront
because of TJR, trading course seller,
influencer, bought a $3.5 million
hypercar and crossed over into the
mainstream. He went to Mterrey Car Week
where a lot of the other rich car people
are, was featured in a lot of content,
and got people like my lawyer being
like, "Do you know this kid?" cuz it's
on his Tik Tok timeline crossing over
because of the cost of the car. When you
access TJR, you see the car, you see the
first video, you are pulled into the TJR
clipping ecosystem. Tik Tok recognizes
this and they show you 14,000 other
accounts of TJR doing all kinds of stuff
and then you see a BRZ video, then
you're in the Bre algorithm and all of a
sudden you are lost in the clipping
nature of Tik Tok and for the first
time, many people have seen this before
with other personalities. if you're a
younger consumer. But if you're an older
consumer, the hypercar was the first
entry point into this world for a lot of
people on TikTok. And this is still
something brands don't have figured out,
right? Their libraries aren't compelling
enough to actually clip. They don't know
who bounties are. They don't know how to
recruit. They're not putting this
together. That is where the alpha is. I
every single day as a person with a
pretty large personal brand on the
internet regret I am not going harder
clipping, but there's like two or three
things that are higher priority in the
list I have to get done. I will not let
myself get shiny object syndrome with
[ __ ] for any any longer. it. I will get
there when I get there. But it is a
thing I think about absolutely
constantly. But this is something that
again is quantified now the value of
making your content move. There is an
active basically market for that on the
internet and one that you can
participate in with an infrastructure
that is on the fringe and that's only
going to get more mainstream because it
is literally driving big business. And
moving on into a totally different
world. Let's talk about brand trips. I
like to call this one from Graza. This
is an influencer on the Graza trip. If
you know Graza, they make olive oil.
What are they doing? Doing brand trips
to the US Open with hand me the fork
participating. Shout out hand me the
fork. But again, to the point how the
algorithms work. If you follow an
influencer on a trip and they're
interacting with a brand, it begins to
show you other people that are on that
same trip and shows you that brand
again. The algorithms are good at
piecing those things together. So when
you get a lot of influencers or people
in one place and also you attach it to a
thing that has its own algorithm and its
own things being generated like the US
Open, all of a sudden you get a content
opportunity and the interesting nature
of the content. Is there a competition?
or what's happening inside of it. Is
there any virality there? Multiply by
the event, multiply by the people that
are there gives you a total available
viral moment that you can have. And
Graza seems to be going very in on the
event strategy. They're following this
up with a Graza verse one day only
tasting experience to celebrate their
glass bottles with a surrealist dinner
party and art show, which I'm sure will
be a social optimized experience in
itself. But related, this is now a brand
highlight technique, right? Hotel lobby
candles did this. They basically got
influencers on a PJ, not even a PJ, like
on basically a small plane that
resembles a private jet to the Hamptons
and they invited a bunch of influencers
in and on that trip. They had a bunch of
branded stuff inside of it. And they got
a ton of content and coverage because
you know what happens when you invite
influencers on a private jet? They shoot
a ton of content and want to show it off
as much as they can. And they follow
this up with a boat trip and a bunch of
other stuff for this weekend thing.
Look, this is a candle brand. But you
then you look at, oh, how hard is it for
a candle brand to stand out? How many
candle brands there are out there? You
have to be doing something interesting.
So, they put together whatever this
excursion cost, let's say it cost
$90,000 to do everything. And this was a
private jet from New York to the
Hampton, so it's like a 15-minute
flight. Probably wasn't even that
expensive for that portion of it, but
they had this whole trip and experience
planned out. Multiplied their influencer
efforts 10fold by putting it inside of
this context. And at the same time, we
had a similar thing happen with Water
Boy. Water Boy did a brand trip, invited
a bunch of their customers, invited a
bunch of influencers, and then got a lot
of conversation around their brand.
Their social media manager was getting
flack. They were getting flack as an
electrolytes or recovery brand cuz
everyone was hung over. The trip didn't
quite do so well. But all of a sudden, a
million more people than normally would
have thought about knew about Water Boy.
And this is because of the viral
multiplier of these brand trips. People
like, "Oh, no one wants to see
influencers doing this anymore." Great.
Yeah, they probably want to see
influencers and customers. But you know
what? If it's entertaining, they're
going to watch it. And it works cuz
again, the multiplier of virality, I
can't speak to this enough. If you have
a brand and a good social media or you
are an influencer with a good social
media and you begin to multiply that by
six or eight collaborators that are
frequent and you interact with each
other's algorithms, the crossover and
how that works is like a radical
positive. It works extremely well in
generating more interest for the halo.
And then again, you cross that over with
summer in the Hamptons, the US Open,
other cultural events with their own
algorithms. It is a shockingly powerful
tool that's kind of hard to describe.
Cozy Earth did this with what was called
the Bedrock Challenge. They made up
their own challenge. They invited
influencers. They made a ton of content.
My god, this has 530,000
likes and 105,000 shares. And again, all
these people you see here have their own
social followings. This is not one
video. This is one of 100 videos that's
on their account about it. By
participating in a piece of culture in a
moment in putting TV on that has more
impact than any ad ever could. I don't
know how much this cost them. Let's say
this was $150,000 effort. They have paid
this to back. There's no $150,000 ad
campaign you could run that was as
effective as the Bedrock challenge. And
because I've been kind of going over
time here, I'm going to jump to one of
the last ones I had on my list. And this
is the rise of the independent brand and
their story in particular. Bad ombres, a
brand who I love on social media. They
tell their story. Hank quit his job to
start a frozen bean and cheese burrito
company. And they tell that through
vlogs, they tell it on carousels. They
tell it again and again. They
participate in collaborations. And they
have succeeded and got a 100,000
follower business that sells out of
burritos all the time by telling their
story on social media in in a completely
organic fashion by mastering what people
want to see and narrative and putting it
out there with basically nothing else
behind it. But they're not the only
ones. This is a storytelling trend that
continues. I want to call it Nitro Bar
is another example often used. Coffee
shop that uses the personalities they
have and ideabased storytelling. How
we're going to make this drink. How we'd
make a drink if Lana Del Rey came to our
store. using conceptual engaging content
to put themselves on the map with social
media is lowfi. It is narrative driven.
They show the drinks, they talk about
the drinks, they talk about concepts.
She store of Beverly Hills, another one,
shout out my boy Greg who works with
them where they literally show customer
interactions inside the store with what
cheese they're buying and then talk
through the cheeses and cutting the
cheeses and things in the store of all
just high-end cheese. They are just
telling a myriad of stories of everyday
life inside there, filming customer
interaction after customer interaction.
But his everyday life on iPhone of the
personalities in the business that
stands out better than any corporate
account that is spending god knows what
with social agencies and traditional
agencies to try and do something with
their marketing that can be done with
one to two people on their phone. So
anyway, it's just really important to
understand where these things are at,
how powerful these strategies are. All
the things that I've outlined here are
multipliers that if you just continue to
work by their existing playbook, you are
just going to be left behind. It fires
me up to talk about this cuz I go and
I'm like, man, the more I talk through
it, like I'm in conversations where I'm
trying to convince people to do some of
these things or I'm in conversations
where we're actually pedaling the metal
on some of them and all I want to do is
just go hammer it and I'm going to take
30 minutes out of my night to go talk to
you about it to try and get other people
fired up about it. But this is this is
happening in real time. If you have the
ability to take advantage of it, you can
be ahead of the game. The things they're
telling you to focus on, the things that
you're at, your agency is telling you to
do, whoever you've paid, what your
school is at, it's antiquated. It's
[ __ ] bad. They do not understand. You
can live in this world of like complete
abundance of creative concepts, creative
execution, and the power of social
media. And I highly encourage you to.
Anyway, thank y'all so much for watching
and letting me be fired up about this.
Until next time.
[Music]