mood boarding is an art and a science
being good at it will change the way you
visually communicate and help you be the
best creative you can be this video is
everything I've learned in 15 years of
mood boarding on all kinds of projects
and I'm going to show you the exact
boards I use I'm going to cover mood
boarding for photo shoots even if it's
just your own personal photos and you
want to elevate them it's like a crazy
useful strategy boot boarding for
Branding and design projects Bove
boarding for big creative campaigns that
are multimedia working with color and
exactly how I mood board right now for
my brand for lack of a better way to
kick this off let's cook let's start
with a really important thing and that's
Cosmos and Pinterest are the salvation
for your social media scrolling habit
leads me to the first section here I'm
going to talk about pinest versus Cosmos
versus Arena uh and then more tactical
apps that are Quasi mood boarding like
Millan Noe and how I use CA and then a
bit of the board infrastructure to get
you started if you've never done this or
to get you a little more intentional if
you do do it and you have this like
whole mess of things so first off
there's Pinterest and the beauty of
Pinterest is the algorithm that they
have what it shows you so I'm scrolling
through my feed and is all stuff that is
hyper relevant to me and what I've
searched and when you click on anything
they show you a bunch of other hyper
relevant stuff down below is full of ads
is what it is I really wish there was
like a pro where I could pay to get the
ads away there may be I haven't actually
looked at it but probably the most
useful part of this app why it is so
good and still the kind of just giant
inside this move boarding space is this
find some ideas for this board tab so
you start putting some images together
so I've got a bunch of bags in here from
like a bag project and you can click
this and they are giving you based on
the images you put in your board just a
grip more that are actually very good
and very relevant and there is no
platform with as much Acumen in the
algorithm is that of the mood boarding
apps and so it's why it's still the best
it's why it's the easiest to kind of
navigate and use on your phone and just
a great solution overall if you have to
pay for it great way to start then we
have Cosmos so Cosmos is smaller much
more curated I think they curate this
home feed themselves uh the people
present on it are much more particular
and you just have this really good base
of imagery start from that is like
extremely captivating and now this is
the app now that I open on my phone and
scroll more often they also have a great
phone plugin that allows you to save
reals and Tik toks and things like that
into your boards which is a cool little
infrastructure uh when you get nuanced
one of my favorite things about Cosmos
is the ability to search by color so you
can go enter a color code into here
we'll get to this when I hit some color
color theory later and you can pop in a
specific color and see things with that
uh and these are lenses that become
really useful as you get into tactics
and then we have Arena AR . na this is
the best collection of resources on the
internet because tons of real art
directors creative directors
photographers brand people use Arena
every day and so the actual stuff in
there when you go click around and find
boards and find inspiration is just like
10x is good if you are like really
trying to do some Cutting Edge
Innovative stuff all of the best
resources are in here all of the best
creative items algorithm isn't as good
as Pinterest search capabilities and
some of the things you actually do
within it aren't as good as cosmos but
when you actually comes down to I want
to find the most interesting stuff that
is most relevant to real work that is
like actually good in the creative space
arena is the answer and other apps I'll
show you like the way I use uh Kaa and
milanote are more for organizing photos
and things you already have they don't
have a curational component and know
focus on the curational apps for them so
if you don't know how to mood board or
you're trying to better mood board one
of the key things I have to make my
scrolling relevant is you have boards
that are in buckets so this one is Avant
guard packaging I do a lot of work in
packaging uh I I like packaging that is
strange off the beat path I make content
about it so I have a board where I just
just save examples of things like that
and you need to find those things and
what you work on what are those
recurring themes that come up that you
always want to make sure that you have a
board for and you're consistently saving
things to same thing for I work on a lot
of brand photography projects I'm always
saving references that I like to a
specific photo board as well at use for
inspiration these are just high level
macr level boards to work from it's also
worth like having a brand for your brand
or for a brand board per project that
you're working on allows you to save Ino
on one place that way when you're
scrolling you're saving things
intentionally which to me just kind of
gets you thinking in that mode of how do
I find more how do I Explore More what
references that are relevant to a
project kind of hones your creative
thinking you know something that's
actually tactic now I'm talk about mood
boarding for color so color isn't just a
great tool to be able to search by color
is like a super nuanced thing when you
talk about a color for a brand or even
colors for a campaign or season or when
you're choosing colors like will your
hex codes convert well enough into
something that's printed like how do
these colors actually perform in the
world and I do a lot of like color
consults where someone will bring me in
just two talk about color on a brand
project or Rebrand or a campaign I know
that sounds crazy but then by put it in
context I believe Nike has like a
relatively large team I think it's like
30 or 50 people that work only on color
that like having someone that you call
to do like a couple dedicated sessions
on color like isn't that crazy and one
of the things we do on almost all of
these um is we will make a board in
Cosmos searching those color Cod codes
and begin to see what comes up and begin
to see how the colors play together so
as you can tell from the way this board
looks we're kind of going from these
like darker and lighter sand Grays to
you know kind of more typical sky blue
and playing a bit with how they interact
cuz you start with your ideas of what
those colors look like then you see like
in principle you go okay maybe this much
more saturated blue like is actually
going to be like more interesting or
maybe we want to be able to introduce
like a light to dark blue gradient
capturing things within that color and
putting on a board and organizing it a
bit by like like this one's very much
like dark to light to some references
that we may eliminate and you begin to
kind of organize it and piece it around
you kind of have a look at how t Ally
color is shown another great example of
this from a from like a Rebrand one is
we wanted to go with this blue and cream
for a Rebrand it's like heavy blue like
with a cream what does that look like
we're getting to find a bunch of
resources that like kind of allow you to
begin to get an idea and picture when
you're showing the brand to be like hey
here's some angles of how this could go
this is what happens if it goes more
white this is what happens if it looks
more cream you know uh here's here's a
bit of angles if it was just purely the
blue you can begin to put those thoughts
together to communicate them and that's
a lot about what this is about like I
look at a mood board like a conversation
you're putting on things here that you
want to talk through or walk through to
get basically sign off on and if you are
if you can use it to get everyone on the
same page cuz you know I would walk
through this on a client project and we'
be like okay this blue is too bright we
never use with black eliminated from the
board okay every instance of white and
blue we never want to go straight white
we're going eliminate all the whites we
only want to show the creams and then we
start to get into this and be like okay
actually we should add blacket as a
brand color that's complimentary but
only use it with the cream you're having
this conversation and you're adding and
eliminating to the board as you go to be
able to then craft a thing where you say
hey when we need to have a color
reference tool you know we're going to
go back to this and all something like
this on here be like hey actually we
should subdue the blue more we want to
have this other different vibe you may
end up going in a whole another you know
conversation around it but this is there
to kind of talk through and work through
and you'll find that people with
creative minds work really well in the
scenario of adding a few things to it
changing the order using it as a
conversational tool versus just talking
it out or trying to go through that on
Zoom without any reference and this ties
into boards for actual projects so two
types of mood boards when you're going
into branding and design projects you're
doing client work there are Vibe mood
boards and there are tactical mood and
I've been in this uh this kick lately
where we've been doing lots of smaller
mood boards as opposed to like a couple
big ones where we'll say hey there's a
specific Vibe board and then we'll have
a typography board a layout board a
product photography board a lifestyle
photography um this is very mirrored in
um van the the agency that I work with
as creative residents that's like very
much like their creative director has
been taking their boards in a very
similar Direction where they'll have
these kind of like overall brand like
like brand Vibe boards then they will
have these very kind of tactical and
they'll do it all all in figma and I
think this is a good way to have that
conversation is because then you're
really going like Choice by choice and
you can bring it all into one kind of
overall structure but these are the kind
of ways to think about putting visual
references together and you don't want
to ignore the vibe part entirely because
you really need to have that like
overall idea of what is the feeling that
you're going for and you don't want to
not have the Tactical component because
then you're not actually getting Buy in
or finding like a angle on anything that
you're booring so for instance uh
working on a logo project now and
putting a lot of inspiration together
and one of the first things we did was
we kind of took these ideas he like
heavily word marked it's a it's a
two-word logo that we're working on and
we wanted to have the you know these
these kind of styles where we kind of
took this and then again eliminated it
down like with the stakeholders in the
project like down to one thing but
there's nothing else on this there's no
Vibes no anything this is purely like
we're deciding on a logo here's how we
board versus a Vibe board like this
where we are purely going for like a
brand archetype of like what are we
looking for for um this is on a brand
Consulting project I was working on
where we're trying to basically find a
brand that doesn't have a like really
strong personality out there and be like
all right can we lean in one of these
directions and we're really thinking of
it through through Vibe and this is just
a good like overall a charter of like
this is the feeling that we want to
embody and you combine something like
that with those individual logo boards
Etc you're beginning to build a real
brand experience this is the kind of
stuff that like makes a difference in
having a good unified strategy something
to look back to and whiteboards are
important and so then you have the
scenario where you want to look at all
these things in one place and creating
like a tactical workspace for attacking
a number of things so this is a good
example of one that I worked really
extensively on where this is in millin
note M note is awesome for a certain
type of like visual creative where you
want to be able to take notes and and
write things down you also want to be
able to have visual references and like
have it all in one place I'm actually
moving a bunch of this workflow that we
were doing in here into CA right now and
I'll show you that when I get to my
brand boards uh because there's like the
way you navigate images and stuff around
in here and drag and drop things is
actually a little bit easier in Kaa for
like everyone to interact with whereas
this is like a little more designer
focused and people do this kind of thing
in figma as well if your whole team's in
there but the general idea is you get
one big whiteboard area and work it down
so here's how this particular board
works for like an overarching campaign
where we have designers in here we have
social media teams in here we have
people actually creating the content in
here and we have project management and
so literally there's task lists running
down this side who's doing what
checkboxes that kind of thing there's
briefs they're beginning to come
together like inside this note and then
we'll see things like here's a be bit of
like what merchandise and things are
looking like here's concepts for you
this there's like a sports team theme
and we're talking about like fictional
sponsors for them here's some kind of
ideas and references for that like
here's how pulling some of the color
schemes together and then it gets into
lifestyle photo references and how we
want to do it in like hero shops but
there should always be other people in
it we don't want just one one person we
want to have this implied motion we want
to talk about using these spotlights we
want to do type treatments like this
you'll see all these little mini boards
with just a handful of references so
it's really tactical pop up in here all
the way down to how do we want to
actually lay out the graphics with the
graphic team afterwards to what is the
actual set look like that we're going to
be shooting on for some of these these
shoots where we're using kind of these
big steel walls all the way over to
here's here's actual social inspiration
for the launches of the shoe like here's
a bunch of these ideas that we want to
go find our own version of and then we
have notes and scripts and things that
come together there some graphics that
show kind of the graphic style of
overlays we want on the screen this is
all happening inside one millon note and
this is a blessing for visual people to
be able to like look at things like this
and talk through things like this and
have those direct Inspirations and be
able to see oh this is how this ties in
the social media campaign oh what if we
took one of these things from over here
and put it over there oh you guys are
using that for the set for the photo
shoot let's use that inside of the
social media video when you actually end
up working with like a 10 or 12 person
squad on something or you're bringing in
outside folks like stuff like this is
just inherently super super useful I
think this app is like $8 or something
that's a brief interview that like I
like many of you out there am addicted
to buying creative SAS tools like I
don't really need and uh a big part of
like condensing I'm condensing so much
workflow into canva right now um it's a
lot because of that like especially as I
grow the team that works on on my stuff
you know like I make content I have a
brand I have freelance projects uh and
me is an extension there's designers
that work for me fulltime there's a VA
that works for me full-time I have
Freelancers I bring in on a lot of
projects I have Partners I work with
these things on when we start to get
five or six seats on this it's not like
oh I'm paying $30 for Creative Cloud and
$20 for this $8 for that all a you're
like ah now this is all hundreds and so
um we're bringing a ton of it into canva
because I'll show you the whiteboarding
function stuff in there later and one of
the things um at the canva conference
that uh that I was at and this is not I
do paid partnership content with canva
but this is like a non-related
endorsement they had all this stuff
where they were like they announcing the
ability to turn like their whiteboards
into like documents and reports and it
was stuff that I was just like oh my God
like I've needed like this is just going
to Save hours of my life and like of my
team's time and so we been migrating a
bunch over there and I'll show you a bit
of that on here but if you are working
as a brand strategist or a project
manager or a creative director or an art
director and you're the kind of person
that brings this together for the team
and you're like hey I'm going to put all
these notes in here let's get this fol
and you're actually organizing this as
part of the job that you have you are
like an IND dispensible person and
you're able to create some of these on
some projects and bring that into how
you pitched for work and be like hey
this is how I organize it this is what
this looks like again you're setting
yourself up for success by being the
kind of person that operates like this
and I'm not going to act like this is
the most sophisticated there's Brands
out there and incredible art directors
creators who are crushing any of my
workflows but I'm the one here talking
to you right now and I'm giving you more
sauce than they will so now let's look
at a brand board so this is my brand
board for the first valuable collection
and it has everything from like I have
my vibe boards I have down here so like
specifically like what is this like look
and feel that we are going for as a
brand we have like kind of two dualities
of that that that we're talking about
that's always present it's always there
then we have the actual line like what
are we producing that's going into
production this is this is the reference
so we know what we have there same thing
here little things we're working on like
I'm working on custom Hardware um for
some of these items we'll we'll
reference down there all of the
iconography that we have as a brand that
we are working from all sitting in one
place and then you're going into
applications like we're working on hats
here's some the Hat application working
on shoes here's some of the shoe
application working on bags here's a bit
of the bag application and you can start
to see how these come together reference
bag photo bag mockup that I put together
bag reference of what I want to look
like from Pinterest more flat kind of
mockups of what I'm looking at for like
back and bottom and stuff for a variant
all the way over to like individual
items that are that are being worked
through all the way on the side to color
references that we're kind of pulling
some colors and looks from and the
legend of color patented color schemes
uh this dude here who I had a pleasure
to meet while I was in in London um but
it's just goated his stuff is on it's so
funny I'll walk in like and probably
eight of the 10 like scw Weare projects
I've worked on like his stuff is on the
mood board which is funny so I want to
give him his flowers here and he's also
on my mood board so this is a good
example of like a big working board for
a brand and this was the one around our
first collection um now we have a much
bigger board as we go like multi
collection and look there are definitely
people that keep their boards more
organized than mine I know when I'm
looking at a board what I'm looking at
and if I'm working with people as you
see on that um on the more like
cyberpunk board that you showed like
everything's much more labeled U but I'm
working myself I know I pop this board
open we haven't even talked about it yet
but it's just like okay like I have my
brand references here on the left I have
the colorways down here on the bottom I
have my materials references down here
in the corner I have what I'm actually
where we're at from in working is in the
middle the future is here on the right
my art Direction hasn't even really
started yet so if you can kind of
visually see that but if you're working
with people like labeling all these
sections and walking through it becomes
becomes more helpful so this is the
board for the shoes Z you may have seen
these behind me at some point in here
but these are the first valuable
sneakers that I'm doing and uh we
actually made some adjustments which you
can actually see here in the board but
for instance these are now going to be a
color that match is the so is all going
to be one color I love the shadow effect
of this but unless I go open molds for a
custom so which is like $800 a size
which I'm not going to do for the till
uh I make sure that these sell well
they're painting them and it's just not
clean uh so I'm going with like with a
single color but to do these and to do
this effectively like the most simple
version of that board is what's
happening here so some of these brand
Vibes we have really taking a lot of
inso from these like' 70s car
exploitation movies sauce long story all
the way to a bit of like what we're
looking at for materials coming up where
it's like all right cool I'm trying to
do this like color on color like puffy
items just you get some leather and
stuff we're looking at you know we we're
trying to get lace sizing to match this
obviously anyone's doing a chunky is
kind of looked at a Muska at some point
you know um again let we look at like
what colors we are where we pulling
something from this is for like a future
reference we have some references down
there I have where we're at today this
is what's coming off the factory line
like the photos from sent for me
straight from the xiaomi phone um to my
inbox that's all happening here then we
have the status of like what we asked
for so basically this was the last
version of the tech we sent them still
have that bottom sole we're getting
ready to La we were adding insoles here
was the insole design here's the changes
that we were doing we're having them put
this put this logo on here uh we were
having them add foam thickness from this
first sample that you can see over here
all the way down to to this of like what
do we want here's examples of that
padding this is a good time to look at
like what you send to factories for this
kind of stuff so for instance like
what's an example of laces we want I was
basically like hey can you get laces
that look like any of these three laces
even this I'm like hey here's we want
you to do this mesh we want you to have
this logo in here we want to look you
know similar SAR to how this looks we
want you to pad we want you to pad more
like how these are giving people
examples and like a simple reference is
a great way to communicate especially
when you're you're going overseas uh and
then we're going into colorways like I'm
like all right cool we're looking at
what does the future look like here and
a sample this one it didn't quite look
right they couldn't match the blues and
the pinks like color becomes super hard
when you get into into materials
especially with colors nuances these
really comes down where you can get um
versus like hey this is where we're like
ending up for our first one you know and
more and like more simpler schemes we
can match to a bit of like what the
future looks like there which I'll keep
relatively H that's just like a simple
like byproduct Board of like what that
looks like so you go all the way from
the beginning mood boarding that we had
of like hey I'm actually creating a Vibe
or I'm just capturing stuff for
photography all the way to like what you
do for an actual product but now I'm
going to talk about the one that's
probably the most relevant to anybody
like even if you're just a creative or
you're just a Creator or you're an
influencer or you just shoot photos of
yourself or social media your friends or
you're all the way up to orchestrating
Brand shoots like mood boarding photo
and video shoots but mostly photo shoots
is like super crucial between making it
good and making it be average I'm a huge
proponent something I tell people all
the time um You' heard me say it on like
The Sweat Equity podcast set of than
videos like you see one thing one
intentional thing can set anything apart
right like so I'm looking at doing some
some content for uh the sex valuable
release where like it's I'm doing the
same content everyone else does I'm in a
white background Studio but uh talking
about the garments but we added one
thing that's completely different than
anyone else has ever done and also cuz
that one thing it cost me $500 to rent
it and will add a huge Dynamic element
to that it will be inherently more viral
and just thinking about that through
everything you do and mood boarding
helps that process so there are five
buckets and an extra to think about when
you are mood boarding photo phot shoots
if you are really into it you can make a
board for each but I'd recommend making
one board and just incorporating all of
them in there so you can talk through
with your photographer the first thing
is setting where are you going to shoot
so for instance if we were going to
shoot in my house or a friend's house I
would go get some pictures of this area
and this couch and put them on the board
so we know then I'd also get some
pictures of other couch shots like this
one and put them on the board if you're
using a white Studio get some pictures
of the studios you see how high the
ceilings are even if it's just the
images pull from their website whatever
and then get other white Studio imagery
that starts to be like all right well
how do we make this look the way we want
what's the difference between it showing
up with this lighting or that lighting
so setting is one to always capture and
even if you're going to do if you're
going to shoot you know um extr
photography like you're just be we just
going to go out in wherever we are
downtown Houston we're going to shoot I
would reference that too and be like I
would go on the streets you're going to
go on and be like all right cool like
what does the light look like like all
right do we want to have poles on there
kind use a vehicle like beginning to
think through what do those Shoots look
like um like these guys are just at a
gas station but like getting that idea
like hey we can shoot there's light here
is important to get for the setting
especially if you're inviting a
photographer to somewhere that they
haven't shot before give them these
refence makes your it's going to make
your shoe go better guaranteed then we
have action you don't want to just stand
there in photo shoots it is awkward if
you are inherently extremely
good-looking maybe you can get away with
it but people are always wondering what
am I supposed to be doing working is a
great one to work around right like
Jerry Lorenzo at his Studio doing work
is much more compelling than him
standing there looking at the camera
this man is taking a photo also a
compelling way to stand up what can
someone do what single thing can you add
that someone is doing that makes the
photo Sho look good eating is a really
easy one always compelling naturally
holding something holding flowers is
another great one I've seen a lot of
reaching and grabbing something
obviously this is a unique perspective
for that man's out here playing chess
and action ties really well into angle
so for instance you could talk about a
chess shoot there's a lot different
chess like action plus angle begins to
make interesting right this is much
different than if he was sitting down
playing chess in a more traditional view
same thing same thing with a car shoot
like okay I'm going to be in the seat
next to you and you're going to be
looking like that you begin to start to
be put these items together of like all
right well we know he want him to be in
the car he's going to be in the car
chilling but then the difference is my
shooting from the back seat to the front
seat side to side you begin to say how
do I create a mood around that another
example of angle just like being Ultra
crucial to make a photo ultimately
interesting that is relatively basic
they brought the ladder out or the stick
or whatever then we have lighting and
lighting is abely crucial to begin to
communicate to your photographer what
you want to do you don't need to know
how they do it you just need to be like
oh they're using you know this means to
be a high flash this me to be a strobe
or whatever this is we need a constant
light source you just need to show them
the visual look that you want from light
and then they should be responsible for
understanding how to complete it there's
a very big difference between like like
flash photography or like something
inherently complicated like this a very
specific like even in studio but like
has a really specific light all the way
to like a full Studio lit
environment to a flash photography to
something that actually like this looks
like a simple photo but was probably
really complex to light but giving them
those references of like here's what
we're going to do here's some of the
light style that we want if be bright or
dark or whatever it is that is down
giving the photography a photographer a
tool kit to be like all right I'm going
need this gear I need to be do to that I
can plan this in advance and they're
making that stuff up on the spot or
there isn't a concrete plan or they're
calling with a plan that's different
than the vision you have in your head
this is how creative stuff doesn't get
to the area where people want it to
whereas giving a creative something like
this as a starting point and letting
them cook on top of it be like oh what
about this and look at this interesting
thing because their references that
they've built on are going to be just as
good if not better and they're going to
be able to bring that together and
you're going be able to make something
awesome and then we can always talk
about especially if you don't have a big
budget for the photo shoot what what are
we going to do an edit like what comes
after this like all right cool like
we're actually going to make all these
we're going to you try to attempt
something like this or you know we're
going to collage what are things you're
going to do and post that might make it
interesting it's something else to
consider specific color correction it's
always worth having a conversation on
the edit expectations and think about
what you can do to make it just a little
bit different right like this is four
photos in one but it's more impactful
than any single photo and then the last
thing that isn't like in the core five I
like to think about all the time is
behind the scenes so a good example like
they're doing a photo shoot here they're
capturing a bunch of behind the scenes
to be able to use this kind of video um
like in design sessions like they're
able to note that they want to have a
lot of these video clips being captured
like while they're doing whatever
session they're doing then we're going
to talk about new project with the
absolute goats of this where look this
is just a shot list making sure they
capture BTS Like of the photo shoot for
a really basic version of this and so
this is just like okay making sure we
get a bunch of these shots but you'll
also see the doing conceptual behind the
scenes too where like they thought of
this idea beforehand and they're
actually saying hey cool we're going to
do like a little uh we're going to do a
real where we're actually going to show
everyone at the photo shoot off like one
by one was some personality like this
was scripted beforehand same thing like
like a funny item too they can capture
in BDS and then this which is like a
much more conceptual like okay someone
with a gimbal planned out every part of
this like they're going into it being
like this BTS for reals is actually more
important than the shoot itself and
they're coming at it tactically from
that with a bunch of examples and uh
this is nude project who are like
honestly like the goats of social media
brand content right now for like a like
just being able to turn out tons of
really fun stuff that like takes a
decent amount of production but like
it's just no matter what catchy in a
like very Universal way like they're
doing a great job and so I know that may
be a little bit more than you bargain
for just in like a video about mood
boarding but like it covers the whole
Gambit where I'm trying to make it like
tactically useful too about why do these
things exist and like how do you use
them and what's worth like the reference
points and it really starts with just
creating your own boards and scrolling
them and using some Tik Tok time to be
Pinterest time or Cosmos time whatever
it is of just being like all right cool
like I'm going to have my photo
references together or even the
bookmarks on Instagram for those kind of
things like I'm a heavy Instagram
bookmarker I have folders for it and the
one pro tip that I will end with is
taking time to review your bookmarks and
your pins is like massively crucial I uh
on Sunday nights I take like 45 minutes
I have it booked in my calendar um you
can do it anyti during the week or
whatever it is but having that like 30
45 where you're just like I go through
bookmarks now I decide what I do with
them do I delete it is it belong in a
folder should it go on a mood board for
a project is it cool the way it is is
there any action I can take just having
dedicated time for that so you don't
just never look at it again help you
stay organized to put this together and
as a creative a professional creative
especially like being the person who has
a ton of organized references is like a
thing that basically helps you continue
to get work forever and makes you just
that much more effective because so many
creative people just can't put
themselves in that box um or just refuse
to when it really is like especially
nowadays A differentiator in like
actually being able to perform anyway
any questions about the process things
like that please let me know in the
comments um and hopefully draw some
value thank you so much