Today we are going to talk about the
cursed opportunity of LinkedIn, the
business network. In this video, we're
going to talk about do you really need
to become LinkedIn famous? What does it
actually take to do so and does it
actually matter for a brand? We'll hit
the state of LinkedIn, the AI slop, the
never- ending outreach, the massive
video uptick that happened on the
platform last year, people that stand
out and how brands build something that
stand out on the platform, which there's
a absolute ton of value in. We'll get
there. We'll talk about LinkedIn for
creators because some of the results on
there have made me kind of think twice
about my strategy. We'll talk about a
bit of how the actual network works when
you're creating on there and then how
you develop a cadence that works and a
lens that works if you want to post on
the platform. Let's lock in. So let's
start with LinkedIn on the surface. When
you log into there, you get this
immediate level of cringe that none of
the other social networks will ever give
you. While at the same time posting on
there has a higher level of angst than
anywhere else you can post because it is
professional, because bosses are on
there, because co-workers are on there
because there's expectation. And so what
you do see is a lot of dril. You'll see
posts someone can you know announcing a
or making some note or news about their
industry and then you'll have these AI
responses which has grown increasingly
popular on there where people will just
hit a button and we'll have some generic
response that recaps it to you. It's
truly a bad experience to engage in.
When you combine that with the
relentless outreach in your inbox from
sales reps at wherever who are trying to
get on a call to sell their software
that does whatever that just makes it so
a lot of people just don't want to log
in. That is the negative. And that
negative means a lot of people look at
that social network as one that should
not be a part of their strategy. But I'm
here to say that it is quite the
opposite. But it is completely different
than how you engage in any other of
these networks. If you want to lock in,
actually make money on the network and
advance your career on the network, you
have to think of it in its own vacuum.
So when we talk about opportunity, the
first thing that comes up is what's
happened with video on LinkedIn. So
there's now a dedicated videos tab.
Also, when you play videos, it pops into
a dedicated videos feed you can scroll
through. You'll notice when you view
videos on mobile on there is a whole
little designed interface which is very
attractive. It makes you want to watch
these. And if you do post videos on
there, you've probably noticed that a
lot of them get absolutely massive
impressions. I want to clear up this
impression statistic because a lot of
people will la it and be like, "Hey, I'm
getting hundreds of thousands of
impressions, millions of impressions on
LinkedIn." But what does that actually
mean? So on certain social networks,
impressions are measured differently.
LinkedIn introduced their video module.
You'll see this on desktop especially be
a carousel of about three or videos that
are going across and it is natural when
you scroll through there's a constant
flow of those multiple carousels. If
your video is seen on one of those
carousels whether it plays or not it is
an impression for that video and because
those are now constantly throughout
everyone's feed. If you do post video
and it happens to be then featured
inside those carousels, you get an
absolute ton of impressions. But very
few people click through in videos on
that feed. And if they do they click
one, there's multiple videos and so it
leads to a much higher number than the
actual number of people looking at it.
So plays as always is a much better
metric to actually measure. Now plays
are no joke on LinkedIn and you actually
can get a lot of interesting and quality
traffic on that, but it operates in a
different universe than it does on
Instagram etc. It's not as inherently
sharable. People aren't sharing LinkedIn
videos back and forth with each other
the way that you see that on Instagram
or Tik Tok. People are viewing it.
People are consuming it oftentimes at
work. People will feel like they're
doing work when they browse LinkedIn as
opposed to when they're browsing other
networks. So you get this consumption
that fits a little bit differently, but
it's still an excellent tool for
awareness and for personality building,
just in a different way. I'm going to
talk about LinkedIn first as a creator
and then as a brand. So I was not super
active on LinkedIn and posting videos on
LinkedIn, even though I make business
content, right? All my short form video
is about marketing, about branding,
about trends, about consumer products.
Actually fits very well on LinkedIn. And
at one point, I began cross-osting on
there. That's gone pretty well, but it
hasn't like brought in major brand
deals. It hasn't gotten me a bunch of
work. People don't buy a lot of anything
that I'm selling particularly on there.
I'll get some like add-ons to existing
brand deals to also post on LinkedIn for
like a low amount like whatever. It's
not like a hugely incremental. What has
happened is the tying in of the dots
where people that are in professional
settings have seen my content on
Instagram or Tik Tok aren't comfortable
DMing me about work on there. Just
straight up. I there just if you and if
it does honestly my DMs I can barely
respond to like a fraction of them.
There's so many requests in the
different inboxes whatever it is if you
don't follow you. But on LinkedIn, I've
noticed significantly more of the actual
people that will sponsor my videos, who
want to work with me on consults, who
want to join whatever program are more
than comfortable reaching out on
LinkedIn and also they can reach out in
the connection request and send that
note. And so you basically get this
bottom of funnel traffic of people that
have seen you on these other social
platforms, but who then finish the deal
inside LinkedIn or who find that other
connection or get brought up again and
again say, "Hey, I'm going to send this,
but it's coming from my work account
versus like my personal Instagram."
There's actually a huge needle mover
that I cannot recommend enough that if
you are a creator operating in that
world, posting your content and growing
on there sheerely to just take advantage
of some of these closing aspects that
come from that is something to hugely be
aware of. Let's talk about LinkedIn from
a brand perspective and how that works.
And I'm going to use two examples for
this, both friends of mine who have used
LinkedIn for one for the brand he works
for, one for a brand other guy founded
to actual like great success and in two
very different strategies. So, first I
want to talk about my friend Matt from a
brand called Chlorophyll Water.
Chlorophyll Water is a brand that I
worked with him when it launched. We
built out SEO for it, some of the
strategies, some initial web stuff. Matt
is someone I used to work for back in
the day before we started this water
brand. And he has now gone on to like
great success. Sprouts and Whole Foods
and the the water has carried
everywhere. It's a wonderful product.
But since the beginning on LinkedIn and
with all social strategy to be honest,
he has been pretty savvy in some unique
ways. But he has cheerleaded on LinkedIn
from the beginning. And cheerleading is
an important word where Matt posts all
the time. He posts every time they're
into a new store. Every time he does a
store visit, he is posting that product.
Hey, Corell Water is now in this yoga
studio. It's now in Awan. Hey, I stopped
by and dropped off five at this charity
event today. And his posting of those
milestones, you look at his LinkedIn
from the outside perspective, especially
at the start, it got like a couple
likes. It was not like getting massive
traction or anything like that. Uh, now
I think it does significantly better,
but him just sharing those stories and
the ripple effects of that and then
tagging the buyers he saw or tagging the
places he went has been a massive like
B2B positive. I remember I was at the
natural natural expo West or Expo West
that's out here. It's like a natural
foods expo. We were there together a
year or two ago and we're walking
through and there are so many people
that see him who know him from LinkedIn
but also know the accounts he's in. He
will meet with this buyer, this person
and be like, "Oh, I saw that you're in
blank and blank. Oh, I saw that you got
this account." the B2B effects that
don't matter. Doesn't matter how many
likes you get, you can get zero likes.
If you are building your network and
you're connecting with people on there,
if you're tagging with people that work
in legitimate roles, like buying at
whatever store, you're tagging in on
these chains, the way that LinkedIn
works and shows content means that other
people in that industry are going to be
aware and are going to find out. And him
just relentlessly posting multiple times
a week, every single business goal and
telling that story has probably led to
an exponential increase in the retail
success of his brand. And I've got to
tout him for having that strategy and
sticking to it. And I also wanted to say
like that is a blueprint for especially
if you are in retail or you're building
B2B connections to share that brand
story as a founder. And again, this
isn't video content. This isn't high
produced content. It's just him writing
updates and sharing a few photos and
doing it absolutely constantly over the
course of years. And this is an
important strategy to note because
branded content on there, posting from a
brand like doesn't do particularly well.
You post from the brand account, it
doesn't really go anywhere. There are a
couple exceptions to that. We'll talk
about that strategy in a second. But
before that, I want to talk about my
friend Steve. When I was running
marketing at Gailb Blaster, Steve had
run marketing prior and then moved over
to launch the new product that gel
blaster product called Nexus. It's like
an experience center and he is a
relentless LinkedIn poster likes which
I've never seen before in my life. But I
also got to see the huge benefits that
come with that because what Steve does
is particularly interesting. I think
applies to almost all brand categories
is he's not the founder. He's not
posting founder content. He's a
representative of the brand. He works
for the brand and he is telling the
brand story on LinkedIn and he's doing
it in multiple ways. Any cool piece of
content related to the brand, Steve is
posting it on his LinkedIn. If we post a
cool video on Instagram, he's ripping it
and it's on there. He would be putting
stuff out before we'd even cross post it
at places. Like he was on it. Anything
cool influencer deals, influencer kind,
hey, we just did blank and blank with
blank and blank here. It's on here. This
YouTube video just went live or someone
talks about blank. This review is here.
Anything that the brand does, new
location, new store, photos, the street
team posted on their personal Instagram.
This guy had it curated as putting out
on LinkedIn. The power of this was huge
because he was also a relentless
networker on there. anyone in the toy
industry, which is his background, he
had sent that request to, right? And
then he had been trying to meet up with
them at trade shows. He remembers
people's names. He is constantly adding
to that network. But when we would go to
shows with Steve, people knew Steve
before they even knew the brand. They
knew about the stories that Steve told
and about brand lore in a way that if
even if you were on our email list or
follow our social media, you probably
wouldn't keep up with. And he had been
able to maintain an industry reputation
around the brand by sharing consumer
content, not just business content, of
just telling, "Hey, here's what we're
doing. I'm proud of it. and I'm going to
relentlessly tell that story as an
advocate of it while connecting with
people in my industry. And if you are a
brand owner or work in marketing at a
brand, no matter what, you need a person
who is doing the Steve role there who is
saying because it's not just about
business content on LinkedIn, right? I
feel it's about consumer content. If you
have a kids brand, you say, "Hey, my
customer isn't on LinkedIn." Yeah, they
are. Parents are on there. And guess
what? If you constantly post your cool
consumer content, your influencer brand
deals, your collabs, your new email
strategy, whatever it is, people are
going to notice it in your industry and
the buyers and the B2B relationships you
want. And there's a lot of casual
consumers who again they may not click
through and purchase but the awareness
is there as well. All right. So I'm
going to walk through some new features
that Art List has put inside their
platform that I think every marketing
person and content creator should be
thinking about as they begin to
understand the landscape of what's
changing around us. They now have these
AI image and video generation tools
where you're able to generate images and
then generate video from images. So
you'll see here they have a bunch of
styles listed out from more realistic
stuff to things that are very good
information. But these are excellent
tools to be able to fill in B-roll and
create interesting story. Of course, I
used just this prompt, drift cars racing
in the desert. It generated this
image. Now, I'm able to animate from
there. So, I click animate button. When
I click the animate button, it gives me
a video prompt that's already written
out that I can then edit to actually
tell it what shots we want it to do, how
we actually want the video to go. And
you'll see in the video here, it's kind
of panning around as this car moves,
generated from the image that I made.
You can see much the experiments I have
inside my account with different things
happening. This is another one where we
generated a fume bottle and actually
created the video of it spinning around
it with a really kind of simple video
prompt. And so you can see this is
everything from scenic like I generated
the shot of Hawaii and then generated
kind of a drone video that probably on
top of it animating drawings like you
see here with this cityscape cartoon.
There's just a ton of options you're
able to do inside the platform. Now just
fill in any footage you might need to
help tell a compelling story. And this
is, I think, a really important time to
be talking about this kind of stuff for
creatives because you're beginning to
notice that the limitations of
production budgets just continue to
decrease. We're just in this very
shifting world where it really is the
creativity of the ideas and then the
distribution and organization of the
team that are like really going to be
what separates interesting, creative,
and creative that works kind of from
what doesn't and less and less like, oh,
we can't afford to hire this tool or
that. And you're like watching this kind
of change under our feet like as we
create, right? So anyway, you can check
this out inside Artlist at artlist.io.
Uh, and I'm stoked to see anything you
might create. A final example I'll bring
up on this is the Portland Leather team.
The Portland Leather CEO does an
excellent job of founder content that
actually performs at a high level, gets
a ton of likes, gets a ton of
engagement, telling that story, walking
through the business anecdotes, and
sharing the cool things that they do
along the way. And I think that versus
trying to emphasize your brand page,
build anything is just saying, "Hey, we
have all this content, things that we
are doing. We should be sharing that,
building personalities around it and
combining the sharing of that story and
all those things with the networking
that comes natural to LinkedIn. And that
brings us to actually a bit of what
success looks like on the network and
what you can actually do with brand
account because LinkedIn is a social
network and a very social network. The
more you are connecting with people, the
more you have an actual conversation,
the more you comment and engage, the
better you do, the better your content
does and the better you get real life
benefit from it. And LinkedIn tells you
this. They have expectations for how
much you interact on the platform. So
before you even start posting any
content, be that person who is making
three to five genuine comments every
week on people's stuff that's on there,
who's actually weighing in with non AI
responses on things, who's connecting
with people and then going into their
content and looking at it and who's
having actual conversations on there.
And then when you begin posting content
along with that and engaging with it,
you will notice there's a much better
effect. But how social you are on
LinkedIn in terms of how many people
you're connecting with that are actually
relevant that want to connect with you
and how many real conversations you're
having on there is a big variable to how
successful your content can become. This
ties into how brand accounts work
because it's actually interesting. If
you post on your account and you tag a
brand and you are one of the admins, you
have the option to notify people at your
company that you posted. And also, if
people at your company like an update
that you mentioned that tags their
company and you listed as working at
their company, the algorithm likes that,
too. Which means that a cohesive
strategy of people from the company
posting about the company and sharing
updates, tagging it, and other people
interacting with it actually can push
you pretty far in the algorithm. And
you'll notice whether it's planned or
unplanned. A lot of the companies that
do well on there is because there's a
high engagement level between their team
members and the actual content that
they're producing as a brand. And this
is a important thing to note and
incorporate into your strategy. If you
have a brand account, you want to
succeed on there. But if you want to
start contributing there and you make
content already or you don't, there's
two things I think are particularly
important. The first is developing a
cadence. Most people are inhibited by
posting content. They don't want to do
it. They're afraid to start out. If they
do start out, they post once and they
stop. This is the thing that you
absolutely must not do. And I'll break
down some ideas to make this easy for
you, too. The first thing you do is get
a cadence. I recommend that especially
for creatives and marketing people. Post
once a month is a great start or once a
week even is a great start, but get this
lower cadence. It doesn't have to be
daily. Everyone always has these like
high expectations. That's great. You
want to become a creator and influencer,
you kind of have to do that. But if you
are just trying to set up your basis on
the platform, let's start with monthly.
Say, hey, once a month I'm going to post
about my work and what I do on LinkedIn.
And if I miss a month, then you know I'm
putting some major penalty together. But
if that every month you go, I'm going to
share one project that I worked on at
work that I had a contribution to. Or if
that project is posted by the brand, I'm
then going to share and be like, hey, it
was a pleasure to work on blank and
blank. I did X and Y. Here's what I
learned. Here's where I took
inspiration. Where you are big upping
things that happened at the brand. So
it's not like you're building some
separate identity. You're sharing what
you worked on specifically and showing
off your role for others to see. And
you're providing some experience for
people to look into and be like, "Oh,
that's what a junior art director at
Amazon does or whatever your role is."
But establishing that cadence and
sticking to it at the end of a year,
you've now posted 12 things that show
what you do. Whenever a potential
employer goes there, it's there. You
begin to see some resonance. You have a
contribution. Now, if you can do that
weekly, even better. But how you do it
weekly is you have your contribution
item. Maybe that's once a month. And
then you begin to have what else you can
share, right? And so a big thing there
is what's happening in the world, right?
Can you what is happening in your
industry, in your niche? If you are
again, if you're in art direction,
what's happening in current art
direction or cool campaigns that happen?
If you're in the cosmetics industry,
like what new releases or anything
happen? being able to talk about those.
And to do that, you need a lens. This is
a really important concept for posting
on LinkedIn, really anywhere. A lens is
just a way with which you look at things
that happen in your industry. And to
give you some examples, if you have an
art direction lens, so anytime anyone
releases a campaign, you're just going
to talk about the art direction. I love
the composition of this, the way they
use these this color pattern. Oh, they
use this lighting structure. Whatever it
is, same thing. a photographers's lens,
a copywriter's lens, a salesperson's
lens, a meta ads lens, whatever it is,
you're gonna say from my perspective,
I'm going to analyze this thing and I'm
going to talk about my expertise in
relation to that thing. So, Road
launches a new campaign. Hey, this new
road campaign launched. I looked at
their two meta ads and this is the ones
I think are the best and this is why
they did it well. Right? That is a lens
that you get to apply and every person
has a lens. Accountants have lenses.
Analysts have lenses. Videographers have
a lens. You all have to have your
perspective of how something happens.
So, if you want to then say, "Okay, I
have my projects I'm working on. I talk
about those. There's some cheerleading
you can do, just promoting your brand,
whatever. And then, hey, I'm going to
take my lens on things that are
happening in the world, and I post that
like once a week. You are then
developing a rapport for things that are
happening. You're not making it purely
about you, and you're expanding things
that are in your industry. And if
anyone's like, oh, you're posting on
LinkedIn now, which is what everyone's
worried about. You're like, yeah, I'm
sharing the things I'm learning in my
industry. I'm trying to connect with
more people so I can better be better at
my job and better promote the brand that
I work for. And very few people are
going to have any problem with that. But
if you are looking for that initial
cadence of like, hey, where do I start?
do that exact thing we just mentioned.
What was my contribution? How can I
share something with my lens? And do
that while being social on it and you're
beginning your LinkedIn journey. To
recap, if you're a creator, I feel like
you have to get on there for bottom of
funnel and be crossosting your content
and just have people be aware they're
there because you're going to get more
business inquiries that way. If you're a
brand, you need to find those
cheerleaders and if there's no one
around to do it, then it's probably you
and be posting your consumer content on
there on your personal page like as much
as possible, too, because that
storytelling of all the things you're
doing is important and reaches
consumers. And if you are just an
employee looking to better use that
platform and connect, then I would be
sharing within those two frameworks I
provided. If you want to take it more
seriously and learn how to make video
and stuff for it, the cut 30 info as
always is below, which is the 30-day
kind of boot camp I do for short form
video and carousels and whatnot where we
do cover a lot of LinkedIn, but this
isn't like a long sales letter for that.
But it is a network where I say there's
no need to go to say I'm become LinkedIn
famous. But it is a key part of personal
marketing and of brand marketing.
Especially if you end up selling B2B or
especially if you are trying to rise
from a junior to more senior position or
you in a senior position and want to
make sure you know what your options are
for the future. You should,000% being
taken advantage of. Thank you so much
for watching. If you have any questions
about LinkedIn below or you want to just
drop your URL to connect,
[Music]