In this video, we're going to talk about
Nike and their awkward current state,
Adidas and their cultural comeback, and
the marketing around the World Cup. A
lot on soccer, a little bit on
basketball, but most importantly, the
state of the world as cultural titans
and smaller brands battle it out around
the sporting zeitgeist. And look, I
remember crystal clearly the moment my
older brothers showed me this, the Nike
All-Stars versus Devils ad. Nike
entering the arena into soccer marketing
in the most major of ways, right?
Creating ads nothing like we'd ever seen
before. Pure cinema, drawing the
absolute best out of the sport,
marketing at its highest level. And when
I was growing up, it seemed like they
were on a run that would be completely
unstoppable. I had branded posters
hanging in my room. When they dropped an
ad, it was a discussion point. You
assumed the great athlete would be a
Nike athlete. And this was their soccer
strategy. Sign Brazilian athletes, make
cinematic ads, and establish cultural
urgency in the United States and
globally around a sport they didn't have
deep roots in. Adidas was rooted, and
they were counter-positioning. And in
their time, they dropped incredible ad
after incredible ad. This one, World Cup
1998 Brazil at the airport, equally as
important viewing, right? In a
completely different flavor and way. All
fun and skill and expertise and stardom,
while being distinctly Nike. Simple,
fun. But perhaps my favorite ad is one
that I bring up all the time when
talking to brands now, when we talk
about cinematic content, right? You see
now, streetwear brands, athletic brands,
they're all doing real cinema. They're
all putting together lookbooks, making
their own movies, their own shows. And
this Nike first-person POV directed by
Guy Ritchie ad, that puts you in the
position of this player in this
situation, inside Arsenal, was not just
unique at the time, but is incredible
for anyone who wants to immerse
themselves inside a brand world. A truly
masterful piece of advertising. But fast
forward to today, that's not where
Nike's at. That's not what's happening
in the culture. For most people, it's
synonymous with mediocre. The shoes are
okay. You wouldn't ever buy the clothes.
Millennials have strong feelings about
the brand. They grew up with it. They
have hope for it. I have hope for it.
But, the reality of it with the consumer
is something different. And to
understand it, we should go away from
soccer and into basketball, where they
have one of the hottest athletes of the
moment. If you look at the shoes they
have, this is the shoe they have for
Victor Wembanyama right now. They're
simply bad. I had a moment with my son
when Luka was traded to the Lakers from
the Mavericks, when he was asking, "Does
he have shoes?" He's aware of the idea
of the shoes and Jordan shoes. And I
remember distinctly showing him the Luka
shoes in all the styles and being like,
"Yeah, I'm cool, bro." And I'm trying to
put that in perspective of people that
grew up in the era I did, where it would
just be like them taking an L or doing
that just seems not even comprehensible.
But, this is it. Look at the Jordan Luka
3. Like, look at this. Who is wearing
this? How is this aspirational? How does
one of the top athletes in one of the
biggest markets get represented by Nike
for something like this? And it's not
just one athlete or two athletes.
Everyone on the Jordan roster, everyone
on the Nike roster, perhaps best
exemplified by the honestly complacent
trash of the Devin Booker shoe, trying
to badly reinvent what came before it in
a really unique market with a unique
player who could have done so much more.
One of the only players with a decent
shoe and presentation, Ja Morant. But,
even then, they had to go through a sea
of whack shoe after whack shoe to get to
anything interesting and respectable.
And to the point now, when you go on to
the football cleats section of this, and
you scroll through these now, there is
very little here, if anything, that
you'd want to wear, that you'd be
excited about. And I find this
interesting that this is where this
brand is at, when we are in one of the
most interesting times in design,
possibly ever, where there is so much
talent, there is so much high quality,
and they choose again and again to put
out stuff that is mediocre at best. So,
what happened? I'm going to talk for a
bit about how jerseys began to take over
culture and how that began to actually
take share away from these big brands
used to sell you athletics. We'll talk a
bit about campaigns and relevancy in the
modern era. The brands that are taking
this share and the unique things that
they're doing. And then go into the
marketing behind the World Cup and why
this is such an important and pivotal
moment for both Nike and Adidas on the
trajectories they're going, one up and
one down. So, the cultural cache of
sportswear is at an absolute all-time
high and the soccer jersey perhaps most
exemplifies that. Brands like House of
Errors that I'm wearing right now took
that fandom that used to be expressed
through like a Nike garment and made it
simply more interesting. And that became
a major trend. It's gone all the way
down into brands like PacSun. And you'll
see lots of brands that are actually
passionate about the jersey use it
pretty extensively inside what they're
doing. KidSuper is another example I
frequently point to where the founder is
passionate about soccer and you see it
again and again as a motif inside the
clothes that they put out. But all of
this, this embracing of this used to be
traditionally focused on these major
athletic brands. But now the symbol
isn't the jersey of the player itself.
It's it as a fashion concept. And that's
an arena that Nike doesn't play in at
all. And it's not like other brands
haven't noticed. One of my favorite
stories of the last few years is Umbro's
taking a more fashion-forward approach
with the line they've done with Slam
Jam, right? And they came out and they
launched it in 2025 with this chainmail
jersey, right? Which is the perfect
example of the abstraction we have of
these artifacts we have around sports we
want to purchase, we want to remember,
we want to represent us and what can be
done with a vision around that. And when
you look at these you go, "Okay, this
creative director working on this gets
taken by Umbro but not Nike." And you
can see this brand was able to get life
breathed back into it by making really
interesting sportswear. And if you just
go through the Slam Jam collections,
there is more interesting things
happening here than across the entire
Nike site. And I say this to highlight
that it is a talent war that we are in
right now. We have more independent
talent than ever, better designers, more
creative directors, the ability to
sample and test more things, more
inspiration, more people working
together. But since the Virgil Abloh
era, none of that has landed at Nike.
And, at the same time, you have the
Fanatics world, right? The world of
cheap jerseys. My only Fanatics anecdote
is that's one of the most despised
brands by generations, right? You have I
remember at a I was at a Super Bowl
party recently, back in Feb, kids had
angry Fanatics stories, and adults had
angry Fanatics stories for they'd gotten
a bad quality or not arrived on time, or
they'd been disappointed. There's been
this cheapening of the official
merchandise significantly by how bad of
a brand that is, and how much they've
tarnished the fan experience, that it
dirties the brands in the middle, and
it's made people go to more of these
independent people that obviously care
about it. Well, at the same time, we've
seen the teams themselves actually
flourishing by embracing design. In
Italy, multiple clubs are doing just an
exceptional job. The merchandise
performs and is more widely known than
the teams and their actual games. And,
they're putting out better stuff at
better prices than a lot of the actual
brands. And, both of these have done an
excellent job with their releases. And,
perhaps most interestingly, the campaign
has changed. All those big ads that I
showed you before were done by the same
ad agencies that are still working on
Nike campaigns. We still see the the
last bastion of the millennial like big
catchy tagline, the key moment ad. They
still operate in this more antiquated
way, and what's happening is you are
seeing the internet build around it
faster. And, a great example is
this young guy, Asher Hyde, who after
Wemby's games against OKC the other day,
released just mock-ups, right? It's just
nano banana mock-ups. So, these ads are
ruthlessly viral, hundreds of millions
of views. Where he's able to deploy a
concept based on the nun iconography,
the the nuns that are at the Spurs game
at the Spurs games. But, even that, just
showcasing the size, showcasing him
against other athletes, the creativity
happens at a faster speed, and done
better by independents than these brands
are able to do with their own IP cuz
they won't adapt their systems. They're
locked in with these ad agencies that
are antiquated, with these processes
that are super behind. Those are the
people that are desperately trying to
catch up by watching the kind of videos
and stuff we have on our channel and
realizing they can't act like that.
There's too much of a change. And you
end up in this sea shift of brands that
can act and brands that can't. But in
the meantime, the campaigns are executed
specifically by others. The
personalities become the stars more than
the brands behind them. How do we end up
with a better Ja Morant ad from an AI
creator, no matter how cursed you think
that may be, than what we got with they
got more interaction than anything the
actual brand put out. Then we enter that
relevancy moment, too, with those
athletes. Shohei Ohtani is with New
Balance. Cooper Flag is with New
Balance. Anthony Edwards is with Adidas.
There's more competition than ever,
faster speed to move. And we have a
company with incredible IP that is
behind the ball constantly. Before we
dive into the state of marketing, why
the World Cup is so important, and
what's happening as we speak, as we
think about the soccer jersey as a pop
culture item, as something fashion
brands interpret, something where the
elements are broken down and recreated
and shared, where these lookbooks are
looked at aspirationally from these
teams and these releases, where brands
are even creating fictional teams that
play with materials, the things I talked
about. So last year I worked on some
concepts around this for some brand
merchandise. And I pulled together
dozens of like vintage jersey designs,
art direction mood boards, and visual
campaigns with football themes as part
of the process, as well as a bunch of
factories to make them. We ended up
going with an alternative direction,
this luxury collection you may have seen
last summer. But I wanted to find a way
to present this here and share much of
those resources. It's more than just a
mood board or a link. So I went to
Perplexity computer and created a
microsite from scratch so you can get
here for free. It's a design resource, a
factory resource. And so you see it has
38 campaigns, 100 jerseys, 16
manufacturers, mood boards, all live on
this site with links you can use as a
resource. If you ever wondered how it
works to put something like this
together, you can build that inside of
Perplexity computer. They have access to
multiple different models for different
functions. It can do deep research with
one, it can compose copy with another,
generate graphics, write design, code,
and deploy all in one interface you see
here. So I gave computer the initial
links and resources that I pulled. And I
asked it to pull a lot more. And I could
determine if I want to add or reject
them. And then I asked it to build a
complete browsable site with these
different sections for mobile and
desktop that I could present here as a
design resource. In about 20 minutes, we
went from concept to site, and you can
see me asking it to change different
specific things in here to go validate
images and previews. I could just do
this all inside the Perplexity computer
interface. If you've ever wanted any
design inspiration around this niche now
or for the future, you can check out the
build in the description, and you'll
find the template and prompts I used
that you could use for compiling your
own resources or building micro sites
with Perplexity computer. All the links
are in the description. I hope you find
it super useful, and thank you so much
to Perplexity for sponsoring this video.
Before we get into this year's World
Cup, I want to talk about running as an
example of what's happening right now.
Why this is such an important era to
think about. So, we have so many of
these brands. If you look at like why is
Nike no longer the champion of running?
Why are they not associated with
running? Why do they even own like a
fraction of the subculture the way they
used to? You look at how specific these
brands have gotten, right? So, you have
Satisfy, and Satisfy is here collabing
with Adidas. You have Minted New York
dropping running shoes with Saucony and
incredible gear. You have District
Vision, and all of these are niched in,
right? District Vision owns like the
wellness end of it, and they do it with
New Balance. Satisfy has more of like
the Ed Hardy Affliction vibe, granted a
little higher end cuz they're French.
Minted is fiercely independent and
personality driven. Bandit owns the
underdog and the concept. They launched
that unsponsored project, went directly
at something that felt very Nike,
saying, "Hey, we're going to give these
athletes, these underdogs, a chance."
Tracksmith has collegiate. The casual
user, these are just wanting to have a
shoe that looks good on just took all of
that, especially in like the more
suburban demographic. Hoka has the
trails. There is no subculture that
Nike's able to own, and the world is
splintering into these subcultures. And
so, every one of these categories is up
for grabs. Part of when I originally
started this channel, I was giving away
lots of factory links and how to build
brand items because that opportunity is
so large cuz every one of those big
conglomerates is operating behind the
ball. You are able to get market share
from them, and it's not just D2C
anymore. It's not just getting it
online. You see more and more of these
people opening up stores. Tracksmith has
so many stores and doing run clubs in
all these regions. I was in Tokyo, I
wandered by a Bandit store in Tokyo. You
have the a scale that these brands are
able to operate at and this certain a
certain amount of speed is just
extremely encouraging. When you look at
the soccer landscape, this is where
Adidas' advantage shows the most
clearly. Adidas owns roughly 40% of the
global football boot market and with
their actual kit deals, their
relationships are extremely deep. They
basically dominate that segment. And in
2025, they announced home kits for 22
nations simultaneously. They've
splintered down as well. More and more
smaller collabs, more and more regional.
And each one of those 22 kits that they
announced had its own design background,
its own lore, its own campaign. That's
what it means to operate in this modern
landscape if you are one of those bigger
brands is to use your scale to operate
lots of smaller campaigns the way the
internet works in niches, in
regionality, in algorithms. For the 2026
World Cup, Adidas has 13 nations
including Mexico and Argentina. Then
Nike has 12, two of them being the host
countries, which is why this lines up to
be one of the more competitive moments
of this. And this comes at a peak
moment, right? Adidas has been football
adjacent fashion culture in a much
stronger way than Nike. The Samba, the
Gazelle, the Copa, those are all also
related to the football world in a way
that any of Nike's dominance is more
SBs, basketball. Their newfound growth
and success is attached to a cultural
memory of the game in a way Nike's never
really was. And so globally, Nike's
market share is set to decline. Not a
huge amount, but a minor amount. And
Adidas's set to rise small amount as
well. But this World Cup is particularly
important because this is Nike's
backyard. US and Canada. And with them
set to own the host countries, you see
Adidas came in with the strongest
campaign possible from the start. So
before Nike was even able to announce
what they're doing with their campaigns,
we got Timothy Chalamet at the peak of
his moments, Messi, Bad Bunny in a film
that was for the first time something,
you know, watched at the breakfast table
with my family. Something on the par of
what we saw in those Nike examples we
had originally. And now whatever Nike
does, as good as it is and bringing out
that star power, is secondary to what
they rolled out. I think this we're
talking about how this actually works.
Why is this such an important moment?
How brands that are both actually
involved and involved on the side can
like hijack these big moments like the
World Cup. So, FIFA does like a billion,
1.1 billion in sponsorships from this
2026 World Cup. Adidas pays for the
tournament rights, Visa pays, Coca-Cola
pays. Coca-Cola's been paying since
1976. So, these are the official
partners. Their logos appear on the
broadcast, corner flags, the match
balls. They've bought the real estate
around this. But, that's not always the
brand that walks away with the actual
cultural resonance from the event. That
just sets you up to make sure you have
some guaranteed impressions. So, in 2010
in South Africa, Adidas is the big FIFA
sponsor, same way they are this year.
And Nike is not an official sponsor,
they never are. So, they launched a film
then with Kobe Bryant, Ronaldo, Federer
that went ultra viral especially for
that time, like 7 million views or
something. And they ended up with a
Nielsen tracked buzz of 30.2% of the
brand conversation around the World Cup
and Adidas only had 14 even though they
weren't the official sponsor. And they
did that for maybe 10, 25 million on the
campaign versus the hundreds of millions
Adidas spent to sponsor the whole thing.
Because there is so much attention and
conversation around the few monocultural
moments that we have left. So, why a
Super Bowl ad is still worth the money
for a lot of brands. It's so hard to get
that many targeted eyeballs at one time
that have the ability to potentially
spur a bigger conversation. Now, this
isn't always just the big brands like
this, right? So, in 2014 in Brazil,
Beats by Dre had a moment. They weren't
a sponsor, they're not even a sports
brand. And they actually just been
banned by FIFA. Players could not wear
those headphones because Sony was the
official sponsor. So, Beats launched a
film during the pregame. LeBron, Nicki
Minaj, Lil Wayne. Doesn't even mention
the World Cup. Gets 23 million views and
the same rating system basically shows
that Beats has more of an association
with the World Cup than Sony, the actual
sponsor. Like, this is the virality move
that we play in. They also sent custom
Beats in team colors to all the top
squads in the tournament and players
kept wearing them despite the ban
because they were hot. And then, when
Germany won the final, they gave the
players 24-karat gold headphones
delivered by Naomi Campbell, right? This
is someone going for the jugular in a
cultural moment. This is why as we lead
up to this, there's so much brand
planning that goes into it. Because
these official sponsorships only buy you
access to the surface, right? The moment
itself is just about who can direct
human attention. That's done through
careful planning and thought and timing.
Just like we saw with the Adidas. The
Adidas fired early knowing they could
get ahead of the conversation,
potentially be the first to dominate.
Anything Nike does now is in response to
Adidas. Now, maybe they can blow it out
of the water, but because it came out so
strong, anything similar is another
bunch of star power. Looks like a copy.
They're preemptively getting ahead
knowing their competitor is down bad.
Because guess what? Judging by Nike's
recent track record, they probably don't
have anything sick lined up. It's
probably okay. And so the playbook for
this, if you're actually looking at
implementing this as a brand, because
this goes to any event, goes to any new
thing. If you want to think about how do
you hijack something? The Boston
Marathon if you're a running company.
You see Band-Aid do this a grip,
CrossFit Games, anything. They need
three things. Two are relationships with
the principals, not just sponsoring the
event, it's about who is in there that
you are able to work with to get
attention. The actual players, the
actual competitors, the actual people
involved with the event. Because working
with them outside of it can be just as
impactful and likely cheaper. And it's
about having territory that the other
people can't claim. Beats isn't
competing for the ad that's on during
the actual World Cup, they're competing
for the tunnel or what people are
wearing there. And then you want to
create something that's worth sharing on
its own terms, right? This Timothy
Chalamet Adidas ad isn't just exciting
because it's the World Cup. Again, it
doesn't even mention the World Cup. It's
interesting on its own. It's a short
film, it's funny, it's creative, it has
a lot of star power whether or not it's
attached to the World Cup. It's worth
sharing. And that's the mistake of just
putting all the same creative or
launching another ad or focusing direct
on this is there's bigger ramifications
now in terms of what virality can make.
And right now in 2026, brands are
expecting to double the social
engagement in 2022. We're in a different
world now. It's far more social, far
more shareable. The ability to say we're
going to put out a campaign, we're going
to get the conversation going, we're
going to seed it with clippers, we're
going to get into response, we're going
to know that there's an algorithm
building around it and act on it is
crucial. You may have seen a video I put
out a while back about Coachella. Why do
so many brands spend so much money on
Coachella? Cuz there's a Coachella
algorithm. You consume some content
about Coachella, just like the Olympics.
And I put out videos around this. They
did great. I had a video about Olympics.
I had a video about Coachella. Because
so many people are watching and viewing
that content, whether it's a hate watch
or a like watch, they show them more and
more of it. The algorithms know this.
They respond to it. They put it inside
your feed. They test it to a lot more
people. This happens at every big event.
And this becomes an opportunity to
hijack that, to sponsor a couple people
to go, to release a jersey, to do X or Y
collection related to it, to basically
catch the tail of that algorithm to get
more views than you normally would. This
is such an outsized opportunity for
small brands who understand social
media. I absolutely have to call it out.
It's the same exact thing for creators
as well. And all this goes back to big
agencies aren't able to understand and
leverage it, although they are getting
better. Big brands have a hard time
moving into this. This is the time of
the smaller people who can come around
and move against the culture in
different ways. And so, I'm going to end
with what would I think Nike had to do
to get back on track. So, the first
thing I think would be would be retire
the SNKRS app. Sneaker culture,
hypebeast culture is probably the
biggest negative implication and
association with Nike now. So many
people have used the SNKRS app and just
never gotten the stuff they actually
want. So, the consumer now has a
negative association with one of those
top apps. Got to crush that. That has to
go. And then when they do release this,
do things like the limited, it has to
just have more production. It doesn't
have to be unlimited, but if someone
wants something, you have to be able to
let them get it. You will not be able to
get the kids excited. You will not be
able to get the collaboration scaled,
even know what works and what the depth
is without more availability. You have
to be anti-reseller culture. There are
no people besides maybe crypto people
who are looked down upon more than
sneaker resellers, sneaker flipper. You
have to remove that association. You You
have to actively work against that as
that brand. You need to position that
that is something they are never going
to be able to support again. That you
should be able to get whatever you want
from the brand at its own price. Resets
with this new population who have such a
negative association with these brand
experiences. And with that comes the
exiting of the C-suite, right? No one
now responsible for marketing, for
design, or for product, and thus no one
in the operations around that should be
allowed to stay there. Needs to be a
complete house clean. Same thing with
the agencies. Every old agency has to
go. None of them operate inside this
world that we're in now. And does that
mean more coordination, more campaigns,
more failures, whatever? Yes, but
there's no way you can keep winning with
the same agency that you had 25 years
ago. They do not have the juice to
function in the modern era. I know I go
to these I do these workshops at these
major brands at Fortune 500s inside the
household names. We talk about their
marketing. We go through it. They know
who they have can't respond. They know
they're behind. Most people just don't
do anything about it. But with a brand
where that lifestyle and the marketing
is everything, you have to do something
about it. Then fanatical focus on new
silhouettes and actually incubating
design talent that stays with the brand,
actually documents what's happening and
shares it. Cannot be the closed vault.
It has to be a story that Nike is
telling with its designers, with its
athletes, all in one like amazing
internet canvas that could be better
entertainment than any other brand has.
Then they need to care far more for the
women's market. Beyond a few collabs and
Skims, a handful of athletes, it feels
like an afterthought, a design
afterthought, and it's lost its purchase
power with that demographic. But it's a
complicated market there now with a lot
of movement between those brands, the
Lulus, the Allos, etc. That potentially
with some focus could get brought back.
And lastly, to bring voices to social
media. They need not just their Marcus
Milionis, dozens of them. Unique people
with perspectives inside the company or
building their own brands or building
subsections there that are able to
actually share with passion that story
to greater level. And frankly, I don't
think they'll be able to do it. I think
we'll see one of the great American
brands get continually hacked and
chipped away at into obscurity. It will
remember what it was and it will be more
Kmart and TJ Maxx than anything else.
And I hope that I'm wrong, but there's
nothing that I've seen that would
suggest it will go a different way. If
you're passionate about these kinds of
topics, doing another creative direction
webinar coming up here in a week or two.
I will link down here where we run them
basically like a community call where I
talk a little bit and do a training,
then we all go through questions and
Q&A, actually just workshop the things
that are going on. So if you want to
connect with other people that you're
excited about this with and just get
deeper into these topics and actually do
some work shopping and talk about it.
We'd love to have you there as well.
We'll be documenting a lot more
marketing around what actually happens
during the World Cup so you can find
that on short form. I appreciate y'all
so much for watching.