[Music]
oh
all right so this is my first day in
Wang Joo Fresh Off The 16-hour flight
from LA to Hong Kong to here and we went
right into fabric hunting we went to
zanga which is one of the if not the
largest fabric Market in the world and
then we went and visited juang which is
like a super large fabric provider who
specializes in color and it was just one
of those days right 16-hour flight from
LA right into the action we hunted
fabric all day long we visited tons of
different vendors and I'm going to break
that whole experience down why we're
visiting Fabric and what that means how
actually manufacturing Fabric and
washing works when you're in somewhere
like China juang and color and what they
do why that's so interesting and just
exploring one of the most fascinating
places on Earth let's hit
it so just all these shops all up and
down these blocks is just fabric fabric
fabric all the clothes in here are just
for a display they not actually clothes
you can buy they're just there to show
off the fabric you can get distracted by
like a good ass garments literally as
far as the eye can see is through we're
walking it's just fabric tore after
fabric
tore you e it or you
[Applause]
[Music]
out all right one of the largest fabric
markets in the world we're hunting for
accessories on the bottom floor I'm
hunting for some interesting fabrics for
jackets uh up on the middle but whenever
you go send somebody to a factory for a
reference or you want to find something
similar what they do is they send people
to these to go to go hunt it down so
we're here hitting some of it
ourselves all right so here in the flesh
with the 600 R&B mul
Fe and about 3,000 minimum on the actual
amount of buttons or zippers we want to
make but literally we're picking from
the
references
Kenzo
Chrome that equ out to like 100 120
bucks and M fee 3,000 minimum price will
varies on there but say it's 10 15 cents
and you're cooking and that's zippers
buttons whatever it
is game it's hard to it's hard to
properly qualify scale at this place cuz
like every direction you see there's
just more and it's just level after
level of whatever it is you could
humanly desire all right so we're
here we got the
flannel flannel and powder Bender a
bunch of
towels things of that
nature everything has a little bit of
texture everything's real
solid you can
see it's kind of work even this I might
run this is like an
overshirt but we go stall to stall here
you get their card you get their info so
have have them send it to crease we can
stack them all in one place you know and
you work from
there all right so this spot has a bunch
of the performance Fabrics that they're
in there but we're getting a couple
meters of a bunch of them uh to make
some samples of see how they hold up if
they have the same strength as the
garments they're referencing all right
so what am I actually doing here in
China so I'm here for two things for my
valuables brand I'm trying to get most
of next year figured out from a material
perspective and then also I have some
client projects who are looking for
specific materials for things that
they're making so let's talk a bit about
what material and fabric means and why
so when you hire someone to make your
stuff whether you hire them in turkey or
you hire them in China or wherever it
ends up being to make it they have to
get their material from somewhere
there's two types of Manufacturers we'll
talk about large manufacturers and small
man small manufacturers handle cutting
sewing finishing and then finding all
the stuff that you need so when you
retain a small manufacturer to make
stuff for you and you need garment for
whatever hoodie it is they're going to
go find that material and buy it from
somebody then they're actually going to
cut it and sew it and they're probably
going to take it to a third party to
wash it if you have a wash like this
hoodie here and then to print on it in
some cases they may do one or both of
those things in house to some capacity
and you get to larger manufacturers
might do some of that in-house as well
they often don't do everything a lot of
them don't make their own fabric if not
most of them and you also don't
necessarily want them all to be doing it
in one place I'll talk about this a
little later when we get to to juang who
we visited quick context on this juang
makes tons and tons of fabric one of the
biggest fabric providers in the world
one of the best at it and when they
provide you fabric based on the fabric
they give you wash house recommend so
they say hey if you get this Terry use
these wash houses if you get this cotton
blend use these wash houses because they
know that certain people do certain
things better and then also they have
options for that hey you can do highq
use these people if you be able to go
low mq use these people so when you're
getting something manufactured is an
amalgamation of all these things so you
just go look up manufacturer on Alibaba
and you hire them to do something
they're going to go get the fabric for
you they're going to go cut and sew it
they're going to go screen print it
through somebody else Etc and and your
job as someone who is making stuff is to
make sure that that goes as good as you
want it to so my manufacturer Cree group
who I'm here with they've crushed some
things right the t-shirts that we have
are amazing the hats that we have are
amazing they got all the materials I
looked for I specified really certain
materials in reference but hoodie wise
we haven't gotten to exactly where I
want to go yet and so we're going to go
hunt down that fabric and work together
as a team to get there and then we have
these more complex garments we're doing
these mechanics jackets and a few other
items where I really want to find the
most interesting materials and so I
don't have a vision I can explain to
them like here's this Tech pack gave me
this thing it's more like hey let's go
hunt and that's a really fun experience
to be able to do as a brand owner is go
hunt down interesting things you can
find yourself so when you do this we
explore all these stalls they all have
different types of fabric and this is
literally like an an absolutely enormous
Megaplex of fabric and they have
everything from you know everything you
can imagine and they have Imports like
we had one whole section it was just
stuff from Italy and Japan and when you
find stuff that you like there's a
certain quantity you can buy so you
looked at all that stuff we were looking
at that was like very Stone
islandyas like a very specialty fabric
from a very specific people but then you
go to someone like who does a shirt
fabric they actually do one of the new
valuable shirts that shirt fabric is
excellent there you can just buy the
default colors and options they have by
the roll sorry it was APM and this
literally fabric I like I can go get any
of these Colors by the roll a roll is
like 80 to 100 m so much less that you
can get as a minimum this is why you see
these fabric books go along because a
lot of these fabric books mean something
is default you have to go get it made
versus if I want to get my own color in
that fabric then it has to be much
higher quantity you go get that's why
you go work through the fabric and
depending on the quality of that it's
going to be anywhere from like 250 for
like a 180 GSM like lower weight fabric
all the way up to like 6 seven eight
bucks for really nice fabric per meter
and so that's where a lot of mqs come
from is how much fabric you can buy Etc
as well as what your manufacturer
actually wants to do and then you have
wash houses and nailing washes you get
the fabric your manufacturer is able to
cut sew execute the actual garment that
you want to make and then you want to
make sure it has a wash and it has any
like the acuts on it that you want it's
a whole another set of factories you
want to make sure great and so we're
going to visit on this trip I'll
document in a separate video the person
who does like the screen printing and
stuff here we have a super precise great
team for that and we're going to some
wash
houses but basically it today we
accumulated tons and tons and tons of
references and we had even more shipped
to the Cru group facility and we're
going to go we're going to put it all on
boards we're going to say we're using
this for that here's what this cost is
compare it look at those options bring
samples to the wash houses and talk to
them about it and be able to figure out
a plan for everything want want to do
with the fabric options we have and then
use that to build out like ideally like
at least 12 months worth of so next up
visiting ju Fang we can talk a lot about
what they do which is super fascinating
in its own way appreciate yall
watching Tom we've been sent to easily
four or five alternate locations but now
I think we're I think we're here we're
following
her and we'll see what we actually get
[Music]
to place is a you got 420 with that wash
on it you can see the colors and pick it
up that's not that's the the closest to
what I think we're were going for
yeah yeah it's like it's almost like
sued this that's nice
[Music]
[Applause]
too yeah everyone thinks so you they
they got offices and like dank shacks
and stuff this is this is not it we got
the full get the full Tech experience
this is this is industrial CH this is
prer CH it but it is funny they will
call out specific colors you can see the
fear of
God the Balenciaga and these are all
just in stock this is where the blue
this is where the Blues from the te's
that I've been showing I've been wearing
all the blues come from from here all
right so in this spot they specialize in
getting all the color right so along
here you see all these Brands Paul Smith
Pals Palm Angels Rens zakai Etc they
have massive vaults where they basically
gotten all their products they have them
all sitting in here and they're matching
the colors they have huge color
libraries so if you actually want to go
get a color something about the panone
it's about kind of matching what happens
you can go from this collection from
Supreme this from that purse this from
whatever and they give you the like the
whole nine all happening in the building
and then they have all their different
Fabrics Etc that you can pull from all
right so they actually have like a full
like a full color palette that break
down the pant tones here they got the
move boards they put together and you
can actually literally shop the
individual Fabrics they got right
here and so just inside the room you can
basically pick any of pick any of these
colors that they have they have a whole
bunch of these sets so right now I'm
going to pop this next
one but again we're going to roll it
straight down the whole
board and boom got the options here with
all the various kind of fabric that
comes in and if you do like the fabric
but don't want that pallette they got
the full listing on there and so this we
had much like this first knit we have
we're going to do a pant matching the
knit and we're going to do the zip up
and another and so we're going to use
this fabric from us so we're going to
pull we'll pull a card from that and uh
we'll see if we find a color that
matches what we were looking for and
what their Wash House recommendations
are all right so if I look exhausted
it's because I am exhausted we are
wandering the streets of Wang Joo hidden
meeting to meeting it takes a lot out of
you out here for a couple reasons the
first is there's like 11 things
happening at once people are ripping by
on scooters hauling things everything's
beeping people are going in all
directions it's for all intens of
purposes like extremely chaotic there
also is like no texting or driving laws
you'll basically see people on mopeds
like scrolling through their version of
Tik Tok just like ripping uh so you have
to have your eyes going at all times
plus the jet lag plus it's like 97° out
and it seems like everything takes like
three times as long as it should but
that's all part of it we're having fun I
am just definitely drained I want to
talk about ju Fang which we just showed
and what they do so that is a fabric
only company you see all these places
I'm posting videos of that have all
these garments those garments are just
to show off the fabric and what it can
do those aren't actually garments you
can purchase or like get tech pcks for
or anything like that this is you know
they purely use that to market the
fabric juang is a massive fabric provid
so they had five showrooms just in this
city we went to like three figuring out
where our actual meeting was our meeting
ended up being at their like HQ sales HQ
which is like for all intento purposes
looks like an SF tech company on the
side like we like a in their cafeteria
super nice spot and they do like major
major business in a few ways and I'll
break down so they are color specialist
color catchers is their so they have
this huge Archive of all these garments
from like loue Gucci Rick Owens
represent Palace Supreme like anyone you
could think of that's like permeated the
culture they have a library of basically
every color that they've used that has
any level of popularity they have it and
they have a Swatch for it and why this
is important is that you may have
experienced if you try to get something
you send a panone color that's not
actually the color you get like with
fabric and you can't find something very
close to it and so they are basically
being like hey we can actually get you
to any of and there's two sides to that
business one is they have all their own
color seasonality so the same way like
wgsn does color reports if you've seen
that or Pantone does color reports juang
does color reports and they have their
season what they think is going to be
hot they have all these multiple mood
boards and themes they are constantly
rotating them and they have a pretty
solid pulse on what people are actually
ordering based on obviously the data
they're getting from theol sale market
so they actually in my opinion probably
have a closer tie to the pulse than
people who are simply like interpreting
the trends cuz they can actually look at
the sales data what's being made right
now and you can get that super easily
and they are carrying stock of a bunch
of those Fabric in a bunch of their
default Fabrics but then if you want to
like that will come relatively quick
right you can go get that sent to your
facility you know fast days but then if
you want to go get one of the colors
from their vault then that's like a
couple week process but you can get
anything and you can get any of those
colors they have default available or
you can get any colors in their vault in
this wide range of fabrics they have
that cover like all these different
shirts one of the valuable shirts is is
a juang shirt and they have continual
like new Fabrics are getting added so
they have this kind of wide option of it
and so it's all like your Basics right
this is hoodies every kind of weight of
hoodies you can imagine shirts every
weight weight basic shirt they have some
like light knits but pretty solid set
they that blends as well as as as 100%
cotton but this is the backbone behind
just a huge amount of brand are getting
Fabrics through them whether they know
it or not whether they're manufacturers
just grabbing it or whether they're
actually participating in the process it
was really cool to see um to see how
they do it to look at what colors they
think are coming up as we start doing
our color story for next year and to
work through some of the needs we have
on different projects with what they
have available and then now know if we
ever want to get any color of anything
in the world we can go hunted down
inside that
[Music]
bul I'm going to wrap up with a bit of
the logistics of getting to wongo so we
left La at 1:00 a.m. on Thursday night/
Friday morning and then we arrived
Saturday at about 9:00 a.m. it's a 14
hour flight from LAX to Hong Kong and
then it's like a 40-minute flight after
your layover Etc from Hong Kong to W I
actually really like that flight and
leing in the middle of the night for a
few reasons one is if you sleep at any
point you sleep at the beginning of that
flight which is going to be late night
your time or you sleep at the end of
that flight you're coming in in the
morning and so you've already kind of
had your rest you're coming into a fresh
day versus leaving midday you'd be all
combobulated and then you miss basically
Miss immigration like there was no one
at the immigration we got off in U in
wongo which during the day can be like
hours so benefit to that flight we're on
cath Pacific which is uh super nice I'm
definitely too old and Too Tall uh to be
riding comy plus so we were hitting that
business more expensive but you're
making the most of those days and be at
least somewhat fresh uh cuz I can only
imagine with how exhausted I am now if I
had that you know been trying to make it
work the entire time but to go to China
to do this you you could try to go as a
tourist but I got a business Visa you
get a business Visa by invite from a
business partner and so your
manufacturer or manufacturer you work
with can give you a letter that
basically has their information that
they're inviting you there and they use
the I to the consulate leave your
passport and they come back and you you
have a Visa as long as it's like a legit
filled out letter and you fill out the
application all right you can get a
business Visa that's valid for 10 it's
easier than people think you have to ask
your manufacturer for this letter
they've probably given a bunch of these
letters before uh it's relatively common
and China's pretty open for business to
be able to do that so it's pretty
straightforward process once you have
them and then logistically like I'm
going with my manufacturing group right
so the owner of the factory we going
with I tagged along and he was he needed
to go out there I was like hey let's
plan this together so I had someone to
go out with go with the art director I
work with on a bunch of these uh the
shoots who works with them's done some
of the directed some of the shops we've
done in China and then we have then the
people that run the factory on the
ground who have a solid English who are
running around with us and you'll see in
bun of these videos and I mean this
would be like extremely hard without
that like you could do it you can go to
all these same places and navigate it
but having someone that speaks the
language is like is incredibly useful uh
and also like hard to get DD which is
like their Uber and all that like all
the apps and everything is like just
it's way more complicated if you don't
have someone there to run you around but
what's nice is like most of the
manufacturers are super well out there
even when we go to Jen the guys from
Petra were like happy to help with one
anything we need going there so I I it
is it's worth taking the time to figure
out that facilitation in my opinion to
be able to like make the most of when
you're on a trip like this but I feel
like this was definitely enough content
for one video just going to the Fabric
Mart and going to juang this is just day
one I don't think we'll do a video every
day but uh we're headed to leather
tomorrow um which will be part of if not
a a whole video I'm just talking about
sourcing leather and working through
that um as I Look to get some leather
for some new bags and then we have days
at the showrooms at the screen printers
of the wash houses seeing new factories
going to Footwear um I think we're going
to try and be doing some e-commerce
shots while I'm here photo shoots
happening I'm going to document as much
as I humanly can and we will we will get
into it appreciate youall watching if
you have questions about any things
you're seeing any stuff that's happening
uh please let me know in the comments
I'll try to address in one of the future
Vlogs and as always thanks for watching