this is the Deep geek industrial complex
and we're going to talk about what that
really means today we are going to talk
about products as art and the brand
teenage engineering as a perfect example
of it we are in the Aesthetics economy
basically every single thing that we buy
or purchase there's opportunity to make
a more beautiful version of it or to
geek out for a really specific Niche and
this is something that brand teage
engineering whether you've heard of them
or not has done an excellent job of in
this video I'm going to walk through
their storytelling and why it's so good
I'm going to talk about the speaker that
I bought from them and what makes it
special we going to talk about their
medieval sampler night core and this
whole world of Aesthetics and how people
get into it and how to play Trends into
your products then we're going to talk
about aesthetic objects in general I'm
going to dive a little bit deep into the
fitness Niche now that we've seen
companies like Seline release weights
and a whole cottage industry of just
making things slightly more beautiful
and then I'm going to talk about some of
my favorite new brands who are doing
things in that same space but overall
it's a conversation around how
everything in our homes and our lives is
becoming more artistic why that's a good
thing and what it means for our future
let's kick off with teenage engineering
as you can see on their website here a
lot of the things that they make are
musical equipment or related to music
pop over into the product section they
have this popular field recorder they
have popular synthesizers they have
Samplers but they've also dove into some
other items like actual desk sets Etc
what you'll notice is things like this
field recorder that you see here this is
as simple as any kind of audio recorder
but they've gone above and beyond to
make it particularly beautiful that
right blend of of deer ROMs and bang and
olivon with their own kind of signature
style and they charge a premium for
these things versus anything you would
see that would be in the same vein of
what's actually available from a product
perspective from the actual features
that you're buying for this look and
feel that takes us to this first point
of this world that we exist in today
where anything that's on the background
behind me or on the desk sitting beside
you whether you're in real life or on
social media is kind of an opportunity
to stand out if something catches
someone's eye for another second or two
that can make their video perform better
if you have something very interesting
on a desk at work it's a talking point
with others these different collections
of products and brands that we purchase
kind of form our inherent experience as
people and how people see us and how we
perceive ourselves and feel about the
environments that we're in and as we've
grown more conscious of this with social
media and seeing all these beautiful
interiors and all these beautiful things
we can get we think about our purchase
decisions differently while at the same
time the direct to consumer economy has
meant that we have the ability to
purchase things that honestly cost the
same price sometimes as things that have
been around for a long time where you're
buying a certain brand value to be able
to kind of pick things that are more
into our personal aesthetic and our
personal visual sense of self and this
brand is a perfect example they've zoned
in on what I'll call the Deep geek
demographic so in everything from these
field desks that you see here to the
toys that they offer to all that audio
equipment they're looking at a certain
type of person who is into the Vintage
the design perspective and the
Aesthetics is willing to pay a premium
and for many people look at this and go
why would this be $300 or $400 more than
the normal thing I can buy they'll
understand that that demographic of
folks who loves it and looks at it as a
hobby chooses to purchase those things
not just for their function but because
it's an important moment for them it's
an art piece for them to build their
style and their collection around and
they're proud of that purchase choice I
could have gotten any number of speakers
but because I love T engineering's
design aesthetic and because I've been
into the ideas of the brand the way they
create things and want to own a piece of
that experience it became Natural Choice
for me to pay a bit of a premium to have
something like this and I also
appreciate all the minor things and
features they build in for people that
really care one of my favorite things
about this speaker is it actually has
like a rewind function where it records
a certain amount of the things that
played through it whether it's Bluetooth
from my phone or whatever it is and I
can actually just turn that back and hit
it anytime I want so if I'm out and
about in a different place I can simply
replay things that have happened before
and does that with a little visual cue
of the actual rewind happening on top of
the speaker and the little things like
that just provide a slight experience
that I as a deep geek of my own
appreciate but what separates this brand
isn't just the interesting look and feel
of the products it's the storytelling
around it so I'm not going to translate
the German you see here on this website
but this sequencer and sampler launch is
as Immaculate told storytelling from the
presentation of the product visually to
the craftwork style visuals that we see
here the Dos sequencer time the Dos
sequencer tagline they're tying into
that whole experience you've seen of
German techno of the history of this
Nishan industry and presenting a
complete visual story that goes with it
videos that tie into it and adding this
whole element and dimension of the
product that you simply don't see on
much musical equipment or from many
brands in general so they are treating
the product as art not just from its
visual design but also from the story
they tell around it from The Branding
and the marketing there is a
presentation and thought to that
campaign that is unlike any that you're
seeing inside that space at all perhaps
one of my favorites that ties into a
trend that I've seen a lot recently and
have done a viral video on recently as
well it's called Nightcore is this
medieval sampler so basically they took
a normal musical sampler and made it D
and dcoded they added on a whole number
of these medieval buttons to it and they
presented it in a very Majestic fashion
they brought The Druids out for the
videos so as I pop this video on screen
here you see the entire look and feel
and style that they're going for as they
present this product and this is the
kind of marketing That You Don't See in
your typical objects or interior items
or even audio items release where
they're taking an entire visual world
something that's very on Trend now and
then mer applying that to the niche that
they're in which happens to be audio
equipment and this kind of Storytelling
is all about creating an object
aesthetic that ties to a visual idea and
so Nightcore is an interesting visual
idea one that we're seeing a lot of
where there are cloaks and gauntlets and
armor even when I was at complex con
this last week there was a brand there
that had their mannequins like in full
armor there you're seeing chain mail
jerseys for people like Umbro that I
talked about in my viral Pro products
video If you start to see these
subcultures coming about online you have
the ability to take a product like they
have and lean all the way into it they
did that with their fonts and the
application on the product itself and
they did that with their marketing of
and this whole idea of deep geek is the
idea of taking those people that are
really into one idea or one concept or
one looking feel and creating something
super specific for them and there are
hundreds of these Cottage core coet any
number of these kind of Aesthetics you
can dive into one of my favorite ones if
you really want to go down the rabbit
hole is this Aesthetics Wiki that I'm
pulling up here this Aesthetics .
fandom.com where you can literally go by
decade and go through what all the kind
of Aesthetics that are popular are and
there's just a whole Archive of just
like lists a toz of every possible
aesthetic that you could think of from
ether Punk to Baby core to a Christian
girl Autumn whatever it ends up being
you can actually click in and get ideas
for things that may Inspire some of your
products or some of your designs that
has a subculture somewhere that's built
into it and obviously the more authentic
you can rise out of these the better but
designers and creatives finding some of
this visual inspiration understanding
what resonates and then building that
into your references is a really
important thing to think about but let's
double click for a second on this
aesthetic objects idea about everything
in our homes or everything in our
offices and our lives becoming slightly
better looking and this is really about
the design and attention economy right
where more and more people now are
design educated and the concepts are
easier to get as you begin to spend more
time on YouTube as you see more
beautiful things and now people with
Creative Visions have an easier time
than never actually producing those
because of the affordability and
availability of whether it's factories
or molds or production methods that
small companies just simply didn't have
access to in like the pre- Alibaba era
and that combination of design skill
sets appreciation of creativity and
Aesthetics on social media and
availability of production means that
almost anyone can create anything I've
done all these videos on websites like
Petra where you can go and find 10
Ceramics factories around the world and
produce something or make your own thing
in Marble whatever is it was just
something that if you had those ideas
before being able to go find your 3D
artist online that's going to be able to
help you actually create the thing to
produce and find that factory would be
super hard and now exists and you have
the ability to do it direct to Consumer
at price points that are competitive and
the category that's the most funny to me
and one of the reasons I think we'll
we'll dive deep into it here is the
actual Fitness economy around this so
this whole idea of a luxury home gym so
Seline you noted fashion house released
a whole aesthetic line of luxury weights
and Pilatus equipment and it ties to
their demographic right A lot of people
that do afford and buy Seline have a
beautiful home they're looking at how do
they kind of create in a different
category something that people are worth
paying a premium for but it's just funny
seeing this idea of a Seline kettle bell
it's actually beautiful and looks very
functional as opposed to some of these
other kettle bells you'll see from
different brands trying to do Luxury
weights where you wonder if they're
usable at all and you'll see they're
applying all these trappings of luxury
design Astic so something that does not
need it whatsoever but if someone's
looking at putting together a beautiful
beautiful home or they're looking at
putting together a beautiful space they
have an unlimited budget then they're
begin to look at those options where
there's an aesthetic standout and
there's companies that based their whole
existence around this like this company
pent who I think really sell for the
majority of their to like Hotel gyms
yacht gyms inside existing apartment
complexes they make all these super
aesthetic weight sets they have this
kind of Restoration Hardware looking
Feel Again have they're a little more
focused on actually being very
functional as well as having that look
but you can go say by this $99,500 gym
equipment set for a luxury hotel that
may actually care about what that
presentation looks like or want someone
to share the gym on social media versus
people sheerly buying the product for
the product reason and this is this
concept taken to its farthest point
right where you're taking something who
function is exactly the same as an
extremely affordable version and marking
that price up to the full top of the
luxury price points that's where I like
to really show things that highlight the
contrast where because I do feel like
this is a category where there's almost
like no reason to buy things at this
rate this ties to all fit right so this
company Nord has this has a treadmill
that's $7,300 called the Spring boach
like all made out of wood where if you
do want to go purchase a piece of
equipment that is also an art piece if
you're going to have that sitting in
your house when you do buy a expensive
treadmill having something that matches
the aesthetic maybe worth that couple
extra thousand dollars for you versus
always trying to hide it away or being
like oh man I don't want anyone to go
into that room because we have this like
massive piece of equipment there this
helps solve that issue and there's now a
cottage economy of Brands out there that
can take advantage of this inside
whatever world that they want they want
to so I have over here a little bit off
screen a Roco fridge is a vintage style
fridge has a really unique look and feel
they also have some like Tech functions
to it I don't really use it for the tech
functions I have it mostly for
Aesthetics but I said hey if I'm going
to have a garage fridge in a place where
I film and make content I want it to be
a beautiful one and so you can kind of
see here on their website the look that
they have but it basically becomes the
hey what premium are you willing to pay
for that thing slightly above what you
would have for like a regular existing
item and I'm going to bring up my friend
Brandon's brand blanked where he's doing
a very similar thing where he has
developed an aesthetic for his brand of
Steel of wood of kind of geometry and
said hey I'm going to take completely
normal everyday objects I'm going to
take things like a tray like a lamp like
a folder like the thing I'm going to use
on my desk I'm going to apply a kind of
brutalist geometric aesthetic to it with
his own feel he's going to document the
process of doing that he's a young
designer and create a whole brand and
identity around both the design of the
objects and the presentation of them and
you'll see he has this kind of Apple
meets Brun meets like slight future
Studio look that is very uniquely his
own with the colors that are his own as
well he's storytelling that and he's
basically moving through his design
journey of someone who appreciates these
things who's creating their own things
and showcasing that online and over time
that's going to mature and become
something completely interesting and
unique and why I like to highlight this
is because there there's two ways to
think about it to we'll end this video
with the first is how do I think about
this as a creative or someone who wants
to make something and the second is how
do I think about this as a consumer and
should I partake in these items so if
you are a creative I encourage you to
think about things like this the way
Brandon has like what is your aesthetic
what is your look what defines it if you
were to have one person using that or
dressed in it like who would it be what
how what are the kind of the visual
toolkit you have you can create all your
things around if you've seen some of my
brand and items I have this very
Americana feel to the beginning of them
or if I was to create any existing
household item how could I apply that
same like old vintage car aesthetic how
could I use those lines or put an eagle
on it or have it kind of have this kind
of worn feel but that inherently feels
right would be part of my aesthetic
whereas Brandon is obviously more
brutalist more steel I encourage you to
think about what world you want to build
T engineering is building this like
apple plus geek identity World they have
right where it's like we have this we
taken Tech and vintage to its its peak
and now we're adding in subcultures like
medieval and I want to think about that
exercise and actually make something you
have to roll out a whole brand the way
that the Brandon's done you can take
that one item and say I want to take one
normal item in my life I want to
designed it to match this unique
aesthetic I have and I want to see what
kind of world I can build from there and
then how can I within whatever budget or
constraints I have tell a really
interesting story and then as a consumer
think about intentionally about the
items you buy what price points are you
paying for is it worth a premium to find
someone who's trying to tell an
interesting visual story that appeals to
you and then what interesting stories
aren't being told inside your
demographic if you're someone that's
really into coet and you don't have a
great option for a bedside table or a
lamp or whatever it is is that an idea
that maybe you want to bring into the
world and you can begin to look at at
what are the impactful visual things in
my life what is going to help my real
pop out on Instagram or make my house
like have something really ties a room
together these are the opportunities we
now have to think about those decisions
and what actually matters to us and
what's worth the money but always have
that in the back of your head if
something doesn't exist and you love it
and you think a bunch of others would
love it is that a business you can start
an item you can create or a story that
you can tell so appreciate y'all
watching and talking through me through
this video this idea of products as art
this kind of interesting world that
we're in appreciate any likes any
subscribes I'll see you in the next
video