all right so today we are going to be
ranking luxury Brands by their social
media it's going to be completely
arbitrary based on things that I like
and think are good as an expert in the
luxury social media and creative
direction space basically I could do
what I want because it is my YouTube
channel but this is a super interesting
topic to talk about and one that I talk
about a lot because I am the creative
and residents at Van group we make
luxury websites and online presences for
people like Tiffany's Jacob and Co Road
Etc and within that role I do things
like put together our luxury online
report which is a trend report about
what free brands are doing on the
internet that was you know cited in
business of fashion kind of a claimed
around that we put out earlier this year
we'll link that down here in the profile
and I also work on a ton of brands from
a luxury standpoint so I've sold kind of
artisan high-end things and Outdoors and
Sporting Goods for a long long time and
then now consult with whether it's major
retail chains major brands on their
actual social strategy and product
strategy all right to kick off we are
going to talk about luxury experiences
and luxury hotels in particular I'm
going to Zone in on the Ritz and the
Ritz Carlton and talk about some that
don't do as well you know we weren't
going to get into fashion right from the
start have to get a little more
interesting so luxury experiences are
really interesting how do you convey a
place within content how as a historic
brand you can't stand out so we'll start
with the Four Seasons who do basically
what most hotels do they have some
really nice reels sh the most beautiful
locations that they have in a this very
like highly produced format that
honestly don't do very well like 50
60,000 views one incredible one might
get 560 or like a million but there is
no storytelling here it is just purely
like travel content has not adapted to
what's actually happening in the world
they slightly better able to do you know
some stuff where they're like obviously
they're bring in like a celebrity chef
like that kind of thing but again even
this isn't good content is aesthetically
beautiful content that doesn't
inherently have any purpose which is why
it doesn't work and I'm going to put
this down here for the four seasons in
the bottom quadrant of of how I think
these brands are ranked I do not think
this is good and you come over here and
to Tik Tok they're at least trying some
different content formats and getting a
little more experimental stitching some
influencers Etc but it is a pretty
limited selection of content at best
where it tells you that they're risky
not trying or taking this seriously as a
magnet and let's contrast this a bit
with some other channels so now here we
have the Ritz Carlton so they were for a
long time doing typical content very
similar to The Four Seasons they would
have you know sometimes they'd have like
a vignette meet the faces of their
people but mostly it was just the same
beautiful typical Instagram content but
then recently with their new merch
collab they did some things that were a
little bit different so they collab with
this brand late checkout to do a
merchandise collection late checkout is
very like quasi rowing Blazers peral I
think it's a win for them to be able to
get a collab with someone like Ritz
Carlton Ritz Carlton sees a like
affluent Millennial demographic that
kind of fits into their General brand
perception and says cool like we can
lean into this quasi Wes Anderson quasi
ivy league aesthetic and put something
together and they launched a campaign
well on social media for a brand of this
size so they have aous famous actor
anchoring this he posts as a collab with
the brand in the Ritz Carlton and he
does this twice you'll notice it's one
of his only posts but major views on
each of these 2.2 and 1.7 million which
is the power of having an anchor
influencer in these campaigns which is
why if you do have luxury Brands and
larger Brands using those people
effectively in something like this and
making sure they're contracted to post
but then being able to see the Ripple
effects of that like he kicks off a
series for them is impactful so in this
collaboration they have basically a mini
movie that's on YouTube and about a late
checkout scenario with a number of
actors featuring The Brand and the
merchandise throughout it that you see
has those collab posts but then also has
its time just separate purely on the
Ritz Carlton account and they're able to
kind of tell their story they're doing
it in this kind of idea of TV shows
social media you've seen me talk about
and they're also employing carousels and
things also showing off the merchandise
but with the through story line This is
inherently way more interesting than
anything else that the Ritz Carlton has
done and takes them in that interesting
Direction and some of these like this
post isn't doing that great and I think
what you see here is all the right
Concepts but they're still figuring out
execution there are a couple brands that
have done the TV show right like as far
as social TV show in luxury so Alexis
Batar is the one that comes to mind
where they spent a lot of time over time
instead of like a short film broken into
five chunks they've done episodic series
with these characters that they have
where each part of an episode they've
done probably a hundred or plus of these
episodes at once they've established
fictional characters in The Format and
they've brought in real life people like
this is La Roes in here as as like as
the guest of this in luxury crossing
over into this series that they've built
and I feel like that's where something
like the Ritz could go with this and be
doing better with the posts if each
single one was telling like a real
narrative story versus just a little few
excerpts but it's for what they're doing
is excellent and headed completely in
the right direction and it get
inherently more interesting than what we
saw at the Four Seasons so I'm going to
put this up here and culture to the B+
category headed to the right place let's
pop over to the rits on Tik Tok who are
again doing way more of an approach and
a try for this than that we're seeing
from The Four Seasons they're doing the
same stuff showing off the you know the
beautiful things but they're also doing
some more sharable formats right like
this Carousel of You Know Places to make
memories not saying it's amazing but
they're they're trying some things they
have a little bit of a theme inside what
they're doing for their locations versus
having a just be footage which which I
like but then they are presenting some
of their luxury experiences as art which
I love the art of Mixology in Tokyo
where they're basically saying here's
what a luxury experience looks like when
you go to this hotel here's how we make
you a cocktail presented and shown
really well in classic kind of Tik Tock
format and they've done this in a couple
a couple ways obviously did this the
shoot in Tokyo they to Showcase Tokyo a
couple times but basically every little
thing that you would see in the hotel
they're presenting in this very well
done experience that people want to
watch people love content like this ties
to the brand is extremely luxury and
makes you want to go visit and
experience it so those vignettes I think
are some of the most compelling pieces
of content that they have for the brand
and they should really lean into this
the art of because they have every
location in their portfolio to work with
with different Artisan things happening
so they're showing that and everything
from afternoon tea Etc so people ask how
do you do Luxury content on social
social media if you are an experience
like showing the experience and showing
it in context and taking care into the
craft of it is a is a winning formula
especially if people can lose themselves
in it for a few moments So speaking of
that and again I'll put this Ritz
Carlton overall and this kind of B+ on
social category we have the Ritz London
this is an example of what I would give
an A so single location Ritz Carlton and
Ritz are different ownership and they
are doing an excellent job showcasing
with a couple different formats so one I
think they do an illustration every
month or every every week or something
like that and they document some fun
little content the interplay of Art and
luxury is something we'll talk about a
lot in this video but then they are
creating characters of the people that
work at the hotel so as opposed to like
the television series RIT where they're
bringing in actors and things to do it
they have a lot of characters there so
this is their tea Master xando he talks
about the Tea you can tell he's
passionate about it he cares about it he
really knows about it he's worked there
for a long time it's presented in the
luxury setting of The Ritz itself and
they have an awesome set of videos where
you can learn about tea and you can
really learn about the ethos of the
people that are there I think is an
excellent content series and they're
doing the same things in several ways so
this is the actual manager of the Ritz
telling a story about how the crep
Suzette came about while he actually
Cooks them tableside and so you get the
combination of a story being told this
Immaculate setting the actual recipe of
how this is made and just like a luxury
showcase all in all personality based I
think is really top tier luxury
experience content and the other thing
that they're doing is well call almost
like parasite luxury is is wrong term
but basically they're saying if you're
in your feed and you see these posts you
get pulled into the world of the rits
for a brief moment of someone serving
you cheese of getting served a morning
breakfast they're basically putting
these little moments that you would
experience in the hotel like into your
feed from a first-person perspective
very casually in a way that makes you
get lost in them momentarily and want to
enjoy them and I think this is a a big
part of why people have continued to
follow their account they've gotten a
lot more than some of these other luxury
chains is you begin to feel that
personality between the people you're
able to lose yourself in a little moment
there and they have these formats that
really embody luxury and personality in
the best way for an experien to
standpoint I will be giving the Ritz and
a all right now we're going to dive over
into the world of luxury fashion we're
going to kick off talking about Burber
their Tik Tok in particular got quite
the notoriety and put out some very
interesting content they took a
luxurious art approach to content by
saying hey we're going to use some of
the brand iconography we're going to use
some of the things that are happening
with our products to create truly
interesting more artistic Expressions
that we put online that has done very
well for them in terms of getting
attention we're looking at these videos
of 14 million views 3 million views Etc
um they're again purely presented from
an artistic perspective done by a team
that obviously cares a lot about making
incredible content and who just done
just an amazing job but what gets
complicated about something like this is
where that goes over time based on where
the brand is over time so if you want to
represent you know get brand awareness
for berbery in general to associate
berbery with a culture of art as luxury
then they are doing a great job I think
I've gotten a lot of awareness on the
brand they also gone through a pretty
major Rebrand and you've seen some my
other content you know I'm a big fan of
the actual look and feel of this new
logo of the general idea of it but and
am not a fan of kind of what the
execution of product has looked like
with this over time and so that's where
this gets interesting right where this
is a a video that deserves its 10.2
million views that we have on here but
it's not leading to an experience that
gives the consumer the ability to buy as
represented in kind of berbery sales for
a fair few reasons and so if we go back
through this again 10 10 million views
this bag does not have the potential to
be an IT bag does not have that
popularity level it does not for all
intensive purposes look great sorry to
go full fashion critic here but that's
where we are they are presenting all
this artistic work for things that are
at best okay and this is something has
much more potential than the previous
bag but what happens when you have a bit
of a product crisis which is why I feel
like they right now where you have these
items that you know get some views but
like are people shelling out 2K for this
like particular Burberry tracksuit in
that look like no they're not and if
they are it has to be made into a
cultural item and it has to on so
there's this combination of finding the
actual product resonance they need to do
and then even no matter what if they do
have products that are out there really
showing why they belong into a luxury
wardrobe and a luxury staple so this
content again all incredible social
media team do an absolutely excellent
job of securing views and positive
association with the brand but notice
that they stopped recently now they're
moving into this kind of content which
they've got some vignettes in here it's
a little more real it's a little more
focused on some of their celebrity
Partners feels a little more Instagram
but it doesn't really have any weight to
it like obviously it's not built to
perform and get a bunch of views they're
showing the clothing in a light where
it's kind it's almost hard to understand
and appreciate it that was actually
pretty pretty decent but these ones for
instance I do not think are and you'll
see you know they're getting these views
on these videos but they're doing things
even on Instagram like this is not a
format that is going to do well for you
like on on Instagram it's a it's a
cheating format right where you're
saying hey cool I'm going put it out for
a couple seconds and try to get a bunch
of repeat views when in reality like you
need to be doing better to Showcase it
so I feel like what brands like this
were at a complicated Point are missing
is that you can't just flash the product
anymore they've made good enough content
over enough time the brand resonance is
there but the product resonance isn't
and the answer to that isn't flashing
the product on screen a few times with
the logo and the answer isn't even
necessarily showing it like on the
runway the answer is how do I actually
wear and incorporate this into my life
how does this become part of my wardrobe
stop presenting the objects as art start
telling the story of how you style it
how you incorporate it and seeing people
that actually resonate and not purely
celebrities helping do that so right now
I would give the brand approach they
started with and they really built them
up on social I would give an a excellent
work across the board where we are
ending up at now and how social Works in
context of where the brand is positioned
currently I think we're headed to the C
that's fine they by no means the worse
we're going to talk about Seline here
Seline doing an atrocious job on social
media for a brand that I really respect
and enjoy so first on Tik Tok two videos
maybe they deleted the older ones Etc
but they are basically you two black and
white videos that make no sense in
context don't have any reason to exist
we'll get to Tik Tok strategy in a
minute and then we have what's happening
on Instagram where they're just living
in 2017 they're posting single photos I
actually don't even mind this branded
area around the photo uh I actually
think they could do really well with
like that as a format of like a video or
the way that plays into like doing a
Carousel and an intelligent way like
that could potentially work but all of
these images here like are not
particularly exciting they're all
presented in single image format as
opposed to in in reels or anything else
we got four reels here and obviously the
one reel that they did do which I don't
know if this is actually with the ratio
that might be real but obviously like
the real that they did do smashed in
black and white not setting themselves
up for huge success but you also know
the look look at the views they do get
when they get that versus is they're
getting less likes than like most
influencers like on these photos they're
presenting all the right subject matter
this is a super interesting interior why
is it this a carousel of all these it
would perform way better on social same
thing with like okay we can't take these
experiences and make them a video with
some sort of guide or tour or a quote
and then even with the products the
difference between where berbery and
Seline are at currently is Selen has
products that resonate and are
interesting and are potentially viral
right the Seline weights have been going
viral recently they are in the tennis
conversation they have these really
interesting looks that like are are
controversial enough to at least be
conversation starting and then plenty of
like classic items but they're not being
presented in a way that makes sense on
social media whatsoever and they may not
care with where they're at as a brand
but I think at this point in time it's
worth noting how powerful this conduit
can be for a brand if chosen to be
approached right so quick notes on if we
were creative directing this what would
we be doing better it's like I would
share these same experiences we'
literally just be sharing them on
vertical video and same thing with these
products like can we showcase these
products with some like interesting
influencers actually using them in like
a creative way versus just popping them
down on whites and be doing like a lot
more of that but keep keep these same
environments keep the same products take
even these same environments and these
same photos and pop them into carousels
and literally just format all the same
things you're doing in a way that is
designed to work better on social media
then for Tik Tok I get it some Brands
don't want to be on Tik Tok I think that
is a bad decision is what it is but say
you didn't want to make any new content
or think about formats or do things like
Gucci who about to break down in a
second what you should do here is use
your archives all these luxury brands
have a Heritage they have history they
have old logos they have old designs
they have old they have previous
collection archives they have
interesting facilities they have
interesting people on Tik Tok especially
if you're saying hey this is not the
audience for us it's too young it's too
whatever go educate them as to why show
them the San archives show them the San
history pull out a couple interesting
people from the brand and have them act
as Representatives similar to what we
saw in the luxury experiences segment of
this video and actually tell that story
for them and not doing that is a
honestly just a massive waste of money
not just in the short term from
attention but from the long term in
terms of educating a new generation on
the history of your luxury house now
they do have a new director of art I
believe Michael Ryder who is coming so
maybe this will all hop over into his
world and perview but I certainly hope
that there's a change CU right now I
give this an F SEL I love you if you
want me to host like a tennis or workout
series for you guys we can pump some
social media content out just bang the
line now let's go into one of the best
in class with Gucci so I like when
looking at Gucci overall is the balance
of what they do on these on their
different platforms one thing I'll noce
they do a lot of vignettes of celebs Etc
but they pick the right ones and they
put them in the right outfits there's
that combin of if you are going to use
celebrity making sure they're set up for
success as as you go about doing this
they are on a Relentless stream of reals
all the time they're specifically
aesthetic for Instagram they're built as
basically Gucci Instagram ads for lack
of a better term and they're presenting
all of these excellently in a format
that's meant for Instagram and why I say
that format that's meant for Instagram
and they're doing all kinds of content
is we're going to talk about how they
separate out their Tik Tok and how
different that is here in in a second
and so they are basically just using
every single thing that they do as a
like an Instagram campaign right they're
presenting their storyline they're doing
all the typical things that you'd expect
and they're doing tons of reals they are
just focused on pumping out content
there was just a lot of Gucci content
happening at once I think doing an
excellent job with it but I really want
to focus in on their Tik Tok because
they're not just crossposting those same
things there in fact there's very little
content overlap between the two which
shows me inherently they understand
about the strategy of what's going on
here we're not merely crossposting back
and forth and when you do see it on
there they are telling stories right
they are presenting things inside of Tik
Tok formats that they know people like
to use and share they're doing more
interesting and viral approaches of
stuff that does not make it onto
Instagram and they are leveraging
personalities these may not have a ton
of views but the fact that they have an
actual like they have like celebrities
and influencers interviewing each other
and like talking around like on camera
in a more candid section giving some
room to experiment is I think in is
important to be a part of the cultural
conversation and look again may only
have 76,000 views being able to have
some of these characters and presence
and show some of that personality in a
more candid way it's okay if it doesn't
have that level of views I think it's
interesting that they're attempting
those things and doing them and
establishing personalities that look
right for the brand and even in their
more candid stuff they are doing it in a
wonderful Gucci way that is very tailor
built for Tik Tok I also enjoy that
they've worked to bring Tik Tok
influencers into the fold as part of the
Tik Tok conversation which something I
feel every brand should do your normal
celebrities May resonate on here but
they don't resonate nearly as much as
when you actually put Tik Tok characters
to work like within the Gucci ecos
System case in point having Nara
involved in what they're doing for
fashion week and at Gucci's level is a
proper proper level of involvement for
for brand inclusion there and I will say
if you are a brand a fashion forward
brand looking for inspiration in this
and how to work in this one of the
better accounts to look at and how they
incorporate influence and how they
incorporate culture is is Australia's in
Gia and so I want to call this one now
because again they're experimenting a
lot a lot of their stuff is only going
to get 10,000 views Etc but they're
throwing those shots at the wall and
then seeing the potential of them
hitting and so like this one hit on in
stagram and on Tik Tok but they're
pulling into the zeist they're using a
phrase along with things that are
collected from their lookbook in a way
that kind of resonates with culture and
you look at the backup of this campaign
they shot there's like a there's easily
15 videos in here from that campaign
that's all shots on goal that's how to
treat you're looking at a campaign like
how do we get footage to compliment
these ideas and that other one worked
but this one didn't and that's totally
fine to be able to put those out there
parents need to realize that but then
also like this is a famous she's like a
famous Tik Tok influencer she's playing
the campaign in a completely different
character that she is inside her
influencing and they're picking those
right people her and I believe her
boyfriend that are doing this where he
like cooks for her inside this and then
putting that same concept in a different
environment tied into as like a tangent
to their existing campaign is like
really really smart World building but
it's about finding these people right
okay he's got a million he's feeding her
food in the campaign that is a great
person to have in the middle of your
model and conversation because he
obviously is inundated with super fans
and then is able to like understand the
role of being like a fashionable item
and Brands like like Gia and a smaller
label G and G pronounce it are playing
in like a slightly different field right
because they can access people that are
kind of bubbling versus like the full
extent of someone like Nara who's much
bigger but those are the people to look
to for to as in terms of how you can
actually leverage brand celebrity and
conversation and bring people out of
their element into your campaign and
utilize the way Tik Tok Works to like
bring a visual world to light that
includes what's happening in Tik Tok and
Tik Tok culture itself so overall I will
give Gucci say an AA minus for how they
are coming across on social and we'll
dive into a few more Brands here and for
this last section I'm going to talk
about b a grab bag of all kinds of
Brands I find interesting and we're
going to start with the furniture
category cartel's designer Furniture why
I want to focus on them is is they have
uh obviously known and beautiful form
factors and things that I think could
potentially resonate all these things
you see here are cartel products these
are super standout well-known designer
items like obviously this lamp is is
super iconic you've seen the different
cartel stools you you've seen things
like this Bookworm obviously this and
you'll notice when they just do the
basic literally just do the least of
showing this iconic form factor standard
text the video isn't even good and it
gets views but they've basically given
up on that right you see stuff now it's
basically reposted Instagrams from a few
months ago they're kind like
International and odd at best and you go
over into Instagram and you're seeing
kind of these these vignettes similar to
what we saw in the hotel world of of a
nice setup has the brand on it I think
they have a brand logo is one of the few
you can actually get away with like
having your logo on there in a nice way
but okay just beautiful areas in
vignettes that is the kind of story of
the their brand is telling on there and
then basically show the product like a
handful of times within there this is
the kind of thing where if they were
doing this like a little more savy and
the Instagram is significantly better
than the Tik Tok like they could be
going off on this every single day by
showing those products like in context
and it doesn't have to be this huge
fancy context where a lot of Brands like
don't quite understand but the following
to views ratio on this is like okay but
that same thing could be going on on Tik
Tok and just absolutely destroying it
but they're not even merged like they're
not even sharing the same things
nonetheless attempting to show these
unique items in different ways and
perspectives and what I like to think
about this is like how easy this is to
do like this is a company that's been
around for 75 years hundreds of
thousands of followers stores the whole
nine I want to bring over Brandon from
blank he's got 70,000 followers on this
though he himself is like 200k but he is
making like relatively straightforward
explainer videos obviously take a ton of
time and intention to make kind of
thought out but he is one guy working
with a 3D editor who is making this
really nice content getting just as many
views as you're seeing onside a lot of
the cartel stuff 400k 164 191 showcasing
these items that are are you know like
attempting to be in that same ranges as
cartell is making beautiful stuff and
this is something that one person with
some effort while in addition to running
a brand can execute and then this guy I
know been working with him on a bunch of
the the 3D stuff again he has a person
that he is you know he's paying to work
with build these these worlds with
Brandon he has the brand account he's
promoting these on but like that is the
barrier this is what I like to kind of
highlight is that if you have items that
look amazing similar to the way the
cartels are if you are building a brand
you want to build luxury yourself inside
that that furniture space you can get
more attention on social media than
these Brands who are going to spend more
money on it and more time on it and get
less views on it all you need is designs
that are even just moderately as good
and you need to post them on social
media frequently and it is just a
massive leg up and so I will give cartel
let's say a a b here on Instagram and
then a e on Tik Tok speaking of brands
that are kind of lost in their identi
they want to talk about offwhite
offwhite just sold it's obviously been
in a hard place if you've seen any of
the stuff recently like I think what
they've done from a fragrance
perspective is interesting I think their
store Interiors are are super
interesting I even think some of the
content they've done has been decent but
the the clothes have just not been we we
are not in the right space I don't know
how we got here with those the
collections have not been received well
and they're getting like okay views on
Instagram and they still managed to get
some attention but it hasn't quite hit
and then same thing with you know Tik
Tok it's like almost a complete give up
right like none of this stuff matches
it's purely a cross poost this is an
interesting one to talk about because of
the ethos of the brand and its founder
where I feel like they have this
opportunity to lean into the other side
of like spotlighting up up and cominging
artists and designers being wide open
and completely open the way Virgil was
and how things we were building and like
what they used and the tech packs and
the designs and the ability to show this
other side of designer and luxury and
fashion life in a way that no one else
can that I would be super heavily
leaning into if I was that brand I I
want to talk about bonak arguably the
best in execution on on Tik Tok and
social media although of a complicated
brand but products lend itself
supernaturally to being experimental and
making experimental content just like
how berbery did they have more avangard
versions of these experimental reals and
Tik toks they are tying into that idea
of art as luxury but going farther
deeper into it as like a more avangard
expression but this is like amazing
content right you want to watch this and
finish this until the end to see exactly
what happens the production value is
hard and complicated it is super well
done very interesting work across the
board that gets attention and then
builds the brand lore in the way that
they want it to and while still
showcasing the product and the
difference between this and what we saw
in Berber is because people actually buy
got those who at this point but like
people actually do buy and support Baga
as the brand and then see these items
and want these items and the virality
has something to do with it but there is
a constant flow and direct flow of these
items being featured on their social to
people going and engaging with bonak and
then they do a great job like we saw
with Gucci of not putting the same
content across both networks there is
some featured but they do a lot more on
Instagram post a lot more there and have
a lot more conversational I think they
could do actually do more on both
networks but not like they need to I
think they're they're gaining the
attention that they want through the
strategy they have but I don't really
want to talk about either those I want
to talk about their YouTube because they
are one of the brands who is using
YouTube extremely well which is rare for
a lot of these Brands right and YouTube
extremely well for a brand isn't getting
hundreds of thousands of views each
video it's it it's taking interesting
shots and telling interesting stories
and so for instance here like the
ability to like take a look at these
Mech Gala they make a gor gorgeous video
complete with like sound design of how
they built together this look um that
was very particular that came out as the
look came out you know features
celebrity in there and it's short and
rewatchable in an interesting way and
they continue to do these little
breakdowns of like individual people and
vignettes of how one thing is made a
look at the background of a particular
gown using their brand ambassadors to
actually like go do something
interesting like actually talk through
the closet and like look at their bags
or do whatever like it's a everything
has a concept cep they're trying things
out it doesn't have to be going for
virality but it's also not telling some
boring story and you actually see if you
go through these they have campaign
after campaign and thought after thought
that's going into this like from a long
form perspective in a way that's
interesting that utilizes personality
that utilizes the storytelling of craft
that becomes genuinely interesting and
so I want to commend them on their use
on YouTube as well so I have a ton more
Brands I'd love to go through from a
luxury standpoint I have like a massive
list here I don't want this video to be
two hours if you like this please
comment other brands you'd like me to
talk about and I will drop into it but I
do have like Ferrari Rolex Tiffany's
Hermes Shamus cardier and a few others
that I'm prepped for for like a
follow-up video so and other categories
too the way we talked about experiences
or hotels would love to know which ones
you're interested in and what categories
you're interested in for social
breakdowns but I hope you found this is
interesting to watch as I did like
exploring it and thinking about it
critically so there there'll be more of
these coming soon again I do shorter
versions and breakdowns of this on Tik
Tok and Instagram so you can follow me
on the same handle there but we will be
back soon with another one of these
based on these other ideas if this one
does as well so thank you so much for
watching like subscribe all the usual
thank you