These are books every creative should
read. I broke them into categories. We
have things like oral histories for
context. We have books about making
money, books about fashion, books about
world building, marketing, just business
in general. We cover the whole gambit.
We'll see how many we get through in the
video. And we're going to talk a lot
about life along the way. If you have
any wrecks that I didn't cover here,
please drop them in the comments so
people can see and add them to the list.
And I note all of these in the
description. I will put all of these in
my email newsletter. I'll link it down
in the description so you can get links
to all of them. Let's lock in. So, first
of all, why these books? I see a lot of
lists that say you should read like the
creative way or like a lot of Seth Goden
books. Uh, and I really well, I think
reading in general is positive. There's
a lot of books I think don't actually
make a big difference or aren't
necessarily teaching you to think the
right way as a modern creative. And so,
I tried to pick a list of things I feel
really will help shape your mind for the
kind of decisions you have to make like
in the modern world. And so for some
context, I grew up, my parents are
teachers and so I grew up in a house
that is like covered in books on every
surface. Uh my house is like that as
well. So this is just a fraction of the
books. For all the ones I picked, there
are a dozen that did not cut it. There's
no coffee table books or anything. This
is all for like serious reading. But
let's start with kind of branding,
marketing, design, and then we're going
to go into a bit of like how to think.
So this book, Like Art, if you can get
your hands on it, it's actually harder
to get nowadays. uh by Glenn O'Brien who
is a a noted advertiser and he wrote a
column in a periodical called Art Forum
and he basically takes a look a a
sophisticated nuance look at the world
of selling things and treats it kind of
like the ridiculous beast that it is
similar to how I do a lot of these
videos where I will talk about how
ridiculous it is for like Xbrand to go
on a brand trip or this positioning or
that like he did this uh in critique
format for years and he did it in a
classic era of marketing and advertising
where the copy really mattered and where
everything was kind of changing and
infomercials were happening at the same
time and it's really one of the best
glimpses into like advertising thought
that you can buy. Similarly, another one
that's like a period of the time I feel
a lot of brands should read is emotion
by design. This is from the former CMO
of Nike who breaks down some of the uh
more leftrain like big brand concept
things that they actually work through
putting a brand like that together. But
getting into the ones I think are really
really interesting is this book
Capslock. You've seen me recommend
before. It's super dense. This is the
kind of book that you will go pick up
like do 10 pages once a week. But
basically it looks at graphic design's
impact on capitalism like what we
designed from currency to credit cards
to modern UX to what's the difference
between design and advertising and
especially when you get to the middle of
this book he talks about like tourism
and like the selling of cities through
design about design versus advertising.
Talks about you know sales and crashes.
It is probably one of the most thorough
comprehensive looks at the power of how
we graphically present the world and how
everything around us is designed to sell
us on a concept or a thing. And it's
probably the most impactful book I've
read in terms of the lens with which I
view the world. And that's really, I
think, what creatives are trying to
establish when they're reading, right?
Is that we all scroll these same
algorithms and no matter how nuanced or
interesting we think we are, we're being
shown a lot of the same content. We're
also listening to a lot of the same
creatives. like I can count on my hands
on on here uh how many like big
marketing and branding accounts there
are most of us are friends we're we're
in group chats we're sharing a lot of
the similar stuff and so even the lens
we present is while unique comparative
to like what you might see versus
traditional media is just one factor I
think a lot of uh reading these more
foundational books helps you build your
own lens how you look at things like how
you can define it and that's what I'm
doing with my own reading I didn't bring
out any of the books I'm reading right
now it's probably a separate video but
I'm reading things specifically to learn
learn how to critically think cuz that
helps my work as a strategist. But this
one is highly recommended. Don't let
like the density of the first chunks of
this get you down. Literally skip
through this book. Like open up any
section of page and you're going to find
some really interesting nugget is an
excellent excellent tone to have on
hand. But related, this is an
interesting one. This is meaning at
work. Uh so a mentor gave this to me
when I was really struggling with
something I think a lot of creatives
deal with, right? And that is you want
to do all these creative aspirational
things but then you have to have a job
and sometimes you are good at your job
and don't want to lean into it. You want
to give up that part of yourself. That's
where I was when I was given this book
is I had stopped having a more creative
life. I've been a musical artist in a
previous life. I had done a ton of
graphic design work uh right after that.
I was really leaning into kind of a
really creative era. Thought I was going
to have a really creative life. I kind
of had fallen out in love with it and I
started to realize I was very good at
marketing like the number side of
marketing providing sales qualified
leads setting up funnels. I just got an
Eloqua certified like automation and I
was like I I don't want to love this. I
want to love the creative side of
things. It's part of my identity. But
then this book uh basically helps you
establish context of like the role work
plays in our life and like letting it
define us or not and like finding
meaning in that in the human journey. I
think it's something that we all
struggle with especially now in the like
quasi work from home or hybrid era. I
think we're more crucially aware of the
difference between work and not than
ever and whether we love it or not. And
this book is just gives you a way to
digest that I think is really important.
But moving over into more context
setting. So one of the things I
typically recommend for almost every
creative is to look more at like oral
histories and compendiums of periods of
time. So one of the perfect examples of
this is this book powerhouse. So this is
a oral history of CIA. If you're not
familiar with oral histories, they will
basically go interview like 50 people
from a time period and have them tell
the story through their own words of all
these things that happened. And these
people will put together these sprawling
comprehensive versions on this. There's
a famous one about SNL. But this one
about CIA. So CA was basically the the
talent management agency, creative
artist agency that changed the way
Hollywood functioned. And I bring up
that one. I also bring up this one. Um,
these guys have all the fun, which is
basically oral history of ESPN and ESPN
changing television and changing the way
cable worked and basically bullying
everyone around because they had sports
and then all the egos and personalities
that were born out of that. And the fact
they did all this from Bristol,
Connecticut, this kind of middle or
nowhere location. These two books are
particularly fascinating for the modern
era. If you're a creative, if you're a
creator, if you're a journalist, if you
participate in new media, because these
were turning points. This book describes
a turning point in how artists were
managed, how Hollywood actors pursued
their careers and how this like that
generation of talent work. This
generation of talent is being actively
replaced. It's almost complete with the
influencer generation. Everything that
happened in this book with things
getting replaced is happening now in a
new era. It's a fascinating way to think
about it. And it's the same exact thing
with ESPN. It's basically we're seeing
the opposite. We're seeing ESPN's like
gradual end, right? We now have UFC is
going to CBS. There's all these
streaming services, Amazon, all these
different deals, cable, cost, cord
cutting. This was the history of the
last chapter of when this happened. Now
we're going through the new version. So
this context becomes really, really
interesting and useful. And I love just
diving into those worlds. You have all
this knowledge of how media and
personality and things we deal with now
like existed in the previous generation
that we just didn't experience. So
similar to that, I feel like journalism
is at its lowest state like it's ever
been. All of the talent goes and does
their own writing, right? and is mostly
better off on their own. Most of the
stuff we see online and written up is
like slop or serving some way greater
agenda that doesn't have the consumer in
mind. I feel like the pinnacle of
journalism, the last pinnacle was was
Grantland and they have a uh a histories
of all the best articles written in
there. This is number seven. I have like
three or four of these floating around,
but this is just a great look at if you
have only consumed journalism with a
bunch of pop-ups and these like shady
ulterior motives, these writers that
make $200 an article or this like holier
than thou like Atlantic stuff or
Substack writers consuming this where
it's like truly well-written stuff by
people that are passionate and care
about fandom and a lot of it's about
sports cuz Grant Land was sportscentric,
but it goes over into culture as well.
Gives you a taste of like what real kind
of storytelling was like and immerses
you in in all these moments. That's what
I like where you then get this
perspective that um you know it's like
watching like a deep dive YouTube etc.
but you're doing it kind of in written
form and these are great. And last one
here for anyone that is uh lost in
politics which is a lot of creatives. I
actually read this during the first
Trump presidency because um my wife,
myself, a lot of people around us don't
talk about politics on this channel.
We're having a hard time like a lot of
people are. You read all these
sensationalist headlines all the time.
You're like oh my god the world is
falling. And it was like year two of
that and like co and everything. And at
some point I was like this is like like
is this right? you begin to kind of
question the reality, the nature of
things around you. And I had gone to
this book. This is a Hunter Thompson
book. Everyone knows from Fear and
Loathing in Las Vegas. We wrote a lot of
uh interesting books and this is Fear
and Loathing on the campaign trail 72.
And so he is actually following a far
different election, McGovern, this like
' 70s Nixon adjacent era and writing in
his kind of trademark like overdone
style. But what this book really showed
me and put into perspective was just
like how crazy that politics and the way
people write about politics and
interpret it and the way the US has been
for so long that like where we're at now
is just no different than anything was
in the '7s. It was just as bad. People
were just as hyped up about it. It was
just as divided just in a very different
way. And then seeing someone interpret
that. The difference though is that it
was interpreted with a level of nuance
and writing that is just missing from
our political spectrum right now. Right?
It's like Fox News or CNN and MSNBC and
it's far one way or far the other and
any of the takes on any side or in the
middle just lack that kind of acumen and
nuance to make people want to read them.
Right? You browse that headline, you go,
"Oh my god." And then you kind of move
on. Whereas he wrote like really
compellingly about his feelings and how
this interpret this over overlapped with
the world that he was in. I think it's
if you are too deep in the political
spectrum, this is a good perspective
book for you. But now zipping over into
mind state, an important one here.
You've heard me talk about this book
before, The War of Art. This is Steven
Presfield's book. The basic symbol of
this is that if you don't do the things
you want to, creatives deal with this
all the time, right? You aren't
completing the work you want to make.
You procrastinate all the time. You
wonder why can't I get these things
done? I was living this before I read
this book. And this book basically takes
all that and turns it into a concept.
this thing called the resistance that
gives your enemy a common name and
defines it and tells you how to fight
against it to get things done. So, I
read this uh I was working. I was a VP
of marketing. I was about to have my son
and I was realizing like I just couldn't
do anything with my free time, right?
You don't have a ton of free time when
you're an executive like at a company.
But like in my free time, my wife and I
like went to happy hour. We went out to
drinks with our friends. We played video
games. We saw every movie. We lived by
an Alamo Draft House. We were in Austin.
We literally watched every movie that
came through there. And I was kept being
like this just isn't it's I'm not doing
what I want to do with my time. as
enjoyable as all those things are. And I
was like, why? Why can't I? Because
there's no limitation. It wasn't like
I'm being forced to go out or forced to
do anything. Most of it was my idea. And
I realized it was myself kind of holding
me back. But I don't want you to just
read this book. I want you to read other
Steven Presfield books. So this is why
this book becomes really interesting is
he wrote this basically a self-help book
for creatives. But he is a best-selling
author in a different way. This is Gates
of Fire. This is a great one to do. This
is the book that 300 is roughly based
on. This guy who is at the top of his
craft, incredible author writing
historical fiction, dealt so deeply with
procrastination, with his career, with
his artistic vision while banging out
absolute masterpieces. The context of
this, I feel like, is really important
cuz usually you read self-help books
from people that like aren't in the work
like this. And I think it's a really
good duality. And I also think uh not to
get controversial here, but I feel like
for a lot of young men, you are innately
biologically drawn to stories about war
and sports and competition, reading a
lot of historical fiction about great
people who tried to conquer the world
and failed and like those moments of
greatness and like the the strength of
mind, etc. in the historical fiction
context, uh I think it's just like good
for your brain. Anyway, so another one I
used to uh I used to keep a stack of
these on my desk. I I was president of
this company. Uh we owned a series of
stores here in Southern California and
some operations in a few states. Had
about 200 people working for me at the
time. A lot of retail employees. I would
keep a stack of this book called The
Obstacle Was the Way on my desk for
whenever anyone complained. Basically,
we had a culture of um of not
complaining, a culture of like doing the
most. It was had its ups and downs. I'll
put it that way. But for every one of
the decisions we were dealing with at
that time, we were in a extremely
competitive industry. The answer to all
of them was the obstacle is the way. And
this is a really useful thing for every
creative to get through their brains. a
thing you don't want to do like, "Oh my
god, I don't want to get on the phone. I
I'll do anything with my business except
to get on the phone with clients. I
don't want to sell or oh, I'll do I I
don't want to put my face on video."
Another good one. You have there's these
objections people have. I'll do anything
but that. And what this book will teach
you is that like the answer every time
you feel that way, every single time
you're like, I'll do anything but that.
The answer to your seeking is to do that
thing. It's a crucial mindset shift. The
important thing for this with me was
sales. So, as I mentioned earlier in in
my career, I'd gotten really into like
providing leads in the sales process. I
knew I was really good at it. I could
quantify it and ways to generate it,
understood how doing that through ads
and email and cold and all these things,
but I didn't want to sell myself. I
didn't want to sit on the round robin
with the sales team. I thought I'm
basically better than a salesperson. And
the answer was I'm not. And also once I
started getting in the mix of that and
started selling when we had a period
when we had a like a call center and I
was running a team for a call center and
a different business to this business
where I was managing the sales team, I
was hitting a bunch of the outbound and
outreach myself. I was trying to put up
numbers on the board with the team. That
was just something I never would have
done without that obstacle as the way
being like, you know, the answer to me
being a better sales leader and a better
leader in companies is to sell. And it's
a skill I've gained that's been useful
for the rest of my life. And uh wouldn't
have it without this book. So this is a
really useful one. Similar uh there's
this book, it's called The Courage to Be
Disliked. Uh I remember my boy James,
shout out James, we were arguing about
something or in some kind of argument
and he made a joke about me reading this
book and genuinely not worrying about
being disliked cuz I was probably being
a dick. But I've taken this book
extremely to heart, right? I um do not
care in circumstances unless it's being
done for a cruel reason. If it's being
done for a reason that is achieving an
objective, I don't care about anyone's
feelings. I don't want to do anything to
hurt people's feelings specifically to
do that. That's kind of the line. But
this understanding that to be good at a
lot of things, you have to be okay with
not being liked all the time, especially
to be a good manager, a good boss, or to
push people around you to like reach
greatness, you're not going to be liked.
And the more as soon as you accept that,
and especially if you're a creator in
this world, right? Like I got people
I'll I'll say that like you know this
one mattress is bad and people will be
threatening to kill me in the DMs
because I didn't like their mattress,
right? Like you it's not for the faint
of heart. This is a good book to work
through that I think is really valuable
for a lot of people if you consider
yourself a people pleaser to kind of get
up and do something about it. The last
kind of mind state book is this book the
4-hour work week by Tim Ferrris. This is
not a good book to read if you're trying
to achieve the objective. You will not
work a 4-hour work week after reading
this book. It's not good at that. But
what it is good at is about like
designing things that scale, outsourcing
things, understanding the nuance of like
how business is done. If you want to
start like a one or two person small
business and build something on the side
or build a lifestyle around something
and begin to like quantify the time you
spend and where it goes, it is like
still an extremely valuable look at
that. I just wouldn't expect to achieve
the objective at the end of it. If you
have a vision in your head but need help
creating it, let me introduce you to the
new Adobe Firefly boards now in G. So, I
know a lot of you who watch my videos
are into using materials and the design
of objects, not just graphic design. So,
I'm going to show examples for both
things of some of the new age workflows
that Firefly allows. So, first, you can
add multiple images like you see on the
screen here. And then you can use this
remix prompt to create multiple
variations of those objects together.
So, I did this and came out with these
two that I like to literally just take
this thatch pattern and apply it to this
chair. And this is great to add a design
to a mockup to visualize things in
different materials. You can also create
pretty great collateral for reference as
well. So for instance, I took this one
and I did a generate video. You can
actually select your model in here. So
you can select from the Firefly video
model which is commercial safe and they
have a bunch of popular models you can
choose from. But my prompt was an orbit
shot wrapping around the chair smoothly
and slowly. And from there we generated
this video that you see here where I'm
actually just taking one of these
mockups and bringing it to life. But
another function I know my graphic
designers will love is if I click edit
in here in a board, I can click the edit
text in image that is in beta and it is
going to find all the text inside my
image and I'm able to go I can select
any of the text that was in here
including this one that was behind my
head. And I'm going to go pirates
instead of social and is going to match
the font and update it even without
having any of the original file. And
there are tons of really fun uses for
that that I know all my designers will
think of. And you can easily sync things
you create from this into Adobe Express
or other Creative Cloud apps. So, if you
want to experiment bringing your ideas
to life and try out a bunch of these
other features, you can learn more about
Adobe Firefly at the link in the
description. And thank you so much to
Adobe for sponsoring this video. All
right, so we're going to get into
fashion and then we're going to get into
making money. So, for my fashion heads,
first is this House of Errors book. I
love books like this because it tells
the story of the brand like in photos
and videos from its inception. From like
guy trying to get clothes done or making
his own stuff to like paying Instagram
archive pages to post it so he gets his
first sales to messing stuff up to
overordering to not having collections
work to being like a powerhouse brand
which they are now. also while making
good clothes. Like there's a lot of
brands that could talk about this, but
like House of Ears makes interesting,
complicated stuff while still being like
rud streetear. And uh and he's very
candid and obviously whenever when
someone's writing their own story,
they're going to tell it like through
their lens. So you have to take
everything with a grain of salt. But
this is a 5 years of this brand, one to
five years, an extremely realistic arc
of someone with like a couple hundred
like scrging through to making a like
significant brand. And I would just
highly recommend that as like a real
thing versus a YouTube being like make
100k on your first drop. like this is a
far better look at that. I think he
includes it. This came free with an
order. So if you buy from them, they may
just show up. Uh then related this atlas
of modern clothing. I don't know how
readily available this is online. I got
this at Premier Vision um a show in
Paris. But basically this book goes
through every type of clothing like like
the safari jacket for instance and it
calls out all the things on it like
these are epolettes, these are patch
pockets. This is a you know standard
flat collar. This is what's called the
called the belt. These are what
materials people typically use for it.
And so if you're looking for
nomenclature in your like design
journey, you're like, I really want to
know what these different things are,
like level one, oh that's a fly
fastening, that's a Prussian collar,
that's a point collar, it gives you that
vernacular to talk to your designers, to
talk to your manufacturers and like know
what things are. Even just to know, oh
that's a great coat versus that's a slip
dress. You begin to get this full
context. It's like useful having some of
these compendiums um just to get those
terms because there's not like a lot of
content that works through that online
and it's useful to have like the
reference books on that. So there's
there's other books like this. Um, but
this is a good starter. Related to that
is this book, Textileedia. They walk
through just tons of different fabrics
like this is chino, this is cavalry
twill. Here's what it's commonly used
for. They compare fabrics to each other
for different things. Talks about
different structures of it. Even talks
about like different printing styles and
techniques and like fixing steps and how
dying works and you can actually get a
kind of comprehensive look at stuff.
Especially this back half if you're like
the stages of dying, types of dyes,
tanning methods. This is the difference
for most people between like
understanding what you're making versus
just like sending mood board picks and
like hoping for the best is to like
really learn using books like this and
then taking the info you get from those
things and like going to your
manufacturers or going to Wangjo and
like getting in the mix. Uh it's super
helpful. Switching over to to making
money. I know a lot of creatives are
afraid of money-making and business
books. They don't want to read them.
They're not like tasteful, lack of a
better term. But really what they need,
the most important thing for most of
those people is to be reading more books
about making money. So, the first people
are going to hate me for saying this,
but the $100 million offers by Alex
Feroszi changed my life, will probably
change yours. And the reason this book
is important is it teaches you how to
structure what you sell. So, a lot of
creatives want to do freelance work. You
want to design, you want to do creative
direction, doing social media
management, you make websites, whatever.
You sell the freelance thing or you just
sell the fact that you're available for
whatever. This book teaches you how to
package that into a viable thing people
want to get and repeat that allows you
to sell an offer versus just a regular
service. and he basically has ran
through every piece of sales psychology
from guarantees to extras to whatever
that actually get people to buy things.
And if you just take this book and he
you can follow everything and probably
destroy it. But even if you follow like
half of it, you're going to sell better
than 90% of creatives. And it's just a
really useful book. I have this is like
the third copy I've gotten cuz I've
given them away. But there's a reason
why he is so popular and that's because
he started by giving like extreme value
and this is an extremely valuable book.
Similarly, if you are a creator and
you're trying to get brand deals, but
also this applies for basically
everything. Same thing for creative
work. This book, Sponsor Magnet by uh by
Justin, former C30 grad. Justin, shout
out the gang. He teaches you how to get
brand sponsorships, how to reach out to
them, how to prepare yourself for them.
This book is an excellent example. He
goes through scenarios and sales and
basically that like art of selling
yourself. If you don't have a manager,
if you're just trying to think through
more of how do I get money from my
online audience? Excellent one. Related
on the business side, ones I think are
are especially useful for creatives.
Becoming Trader Joe's. This is a
business we all know, we all appreciate,
but every decision made at Trader Joe's
happens for like a critical reason. From
the packaging design to the pricing
structure to the way the stores are laid
out to their compensation. This is an
immaculately thought through business
from a positioning perspective that has
honed in to win through a culture of
that. And I think a lot of marketers
would do really well to to read this. By
contrast, uh this book, Super Pumped, is
about Uber. I think this book was meant
as a cautionary tale. This book was uh
basically a story of how Travis Colonic
was a wild and dangerous person and ran
this company into kind of insanity
through his ego. But at the same time,
there's a lot of people that I know that
basically treated this less like a
cautionary tale and more like a manual.
I would argue that this whole new
generation of startups like the Cluly
era like that are more like you know
what we could just do that you know and
and kind of act like pull a lot from
this and that's why I think it's
interesting context because you look at
this being like okay if I did this with
slightly less ego this is kind of the
blueprint for aggressively building
something and so it's just an
interesting character study to kind of
look at things being done not always the
right way and it's a really well-ritten
kind of very fun read. I'm gonna zip
through a few of the business ones here
real quick and then we're going to get
into world building to uh to wrap this
up. So, couple key concepts. You may not
even have to necessarily read these. You
could cliffnotes a lot of these.
Exponential organizations is important
because it basically all this describes
is the concept of a business that grows
radically more than the sum of its
parts. It has the ability to scale
beyond the active nature of people
working. So, it's not like, hey, I add
two employees, I get another $100,000 in
revenue. It's this idea that a hockey
stick can explode out at any point. That
concept, the concept of of being
exponential and a bit of how you get
there and if a business can be like that
is just worth understanding. But this is
like a cliffnotes version of this book.
Do the audio chat GPT whatever. Made to
stick. This is a book about messaging.
This is a book about when you launch a
product or you launch a thing it having
positioning and angle and messaging that
to work to get people to care about
ideas. If you are a marketer or you're
trying to position something or you or
you are a product developer, you need to
be able to communicate from the start.
you're making something different and
know how to position it and actually
communicate that out to make people
work. This is the bible for that. I will
say that these two books and then the
two I'm about to uh about to show here
were all recommended to me by CEOs.
These were all given to me by CEOs at
companies I worked at. They were like
this is the most important book in my
life. You'll notice a lot of CEOs will
do that. Much like I gave the obstacles
the way to everyone that worked for me
cuz that was a really important and
impactful thing for that organization.
CEOs will do this and they'll give you
these books that are really impactful to
them. And these were two of those from
two guys who uh I don't necessarily like
but I respect similar EOS attraction.
This is from people who I both like and
respect who gave me this absolute
savages. So EOS is a function with which
running businesses more than 10 people
is a really really powerful framework.
And you'll notice especially creative
people they don't realize that okay I
can grow my business. I have a 20 person
agency now or a 30 person clothing brand
whatever it is. And you don't realize
they're like oh there's structures that
exist that are built really well that I
can just run my company on. And EOS is
the one that uh I am the biggest fan of.
It has these really powerful concepts
about how to set goals and how to
communicate things between an executive
leadership team and will make
organizations really functional above 10
people. But ending out in world
building, this is an important one. Um
like reading fiction cuz I think we are
we are a very non-fiction culture now. A
lot of business books, a lot of what's
happening in the world, even historical
fiction. I think it's important to like
understand the world around you a bit.
So a few of those you can read that are
more just for fun. These two, Zerville
and the Aderall Diaries are these like
very American fiction books of like like
previous gens of America and like the
human emotion and people going through
them that I think are are good to think
about. How would you write or interpret
the life that you're going through now
or went through over the last few years
in a way like this? It's an interesting
way to like set up a world for a modern
brand. Similarly, Cormick McCarthy this
book Blood Meridian this is a dark book
just forewarning you but it's based in
the Texas Mexico border in the 1850s and
it's written in he's submersing you
immediately in this gritty world from
the way that it's written to the actions
that are happening every decision around
this like submerges you inside this this
life and uh and you've noticed how
easily someone does that with words and
story I think it's really impactful to
think about how you can apply like kind
of those same principles to building
your world and you start to read Cormick
McCarthy's like full canon obviously a
lot of really famous novels and you
begin to see he puts his whole work
inside of that kind of same presentation
in a really interesting way. If you do
any work with China, the three body
problems is a Chinese science fiction
book translated into English. But it
shows the kind of key differential
between uh every science fiction book
that's western and science fiction books
that are eastern. Western science
fiction books have like a protagonist
and a hero and someone that works
against it. In this book, the uh the
people are the hero. It's just a good,
it showcases to you just a way of
thinking, especially if you've read a
lot of Western science fiction. Begins
to show you just a bit of like the pure
difference of places in the world and
the way they think. This book is like a
conduit to that. I have many more in
these piles, but I know we've already
gone on here for a decent amount of
time, but um if you are trying to find a
way to read, I like to highly encourage
it. I used to read a book a week when I
was younger. Was preocial media being
kind of what it was. I tried to do that
now and I probably realistically read
more like one a month. Sometimes we get
up to two. Typically the best way that
I'm able to do that is like 30 minutes
before sleep. I will try to be off all
devices, no screens, and then get some
reading time in and that works out
really well. But I'm currently reading
it's gray mirror and this is a book
about uh the way to think and it
positions a lot of uh common liberal
perceptions of the past and prevents uh
presents counterpoints to them. This is
a really interesting type of book uh for
me to read right now is I really enjoy
like contrarian approaches and how
people position contrarian statements
because it teaches me how to think. It
teaches me how to position things in
work. And I'm not saying I agree with
the positions. This book has a lot of uh
pretty out there positions, but the way
with which they argue, the way with
which they talk, how they present the
alternatives, and the way people's minds
work and approach it is just a really
fascinating thing. And that's where the
books that I have been really into
recently are all for me about like
shaping the way I think and approach
problems because frankly, I feel that is
like the last piece of nuance we have
left here when uh ChatBT and Claude are
like telling us the answers to the
majority of things. and all the creators
just like copy each other for lack of a
better term. Being able to have like
your own schools of of of position or
critical thinking like how can I
approach this problem? How would I look
at this from a contrarian perspective?
Like what principle of like psychology
can I use here? And you it'll allow you
to function in an era where people are
just thinking dumber than ever. Um but
that is my kind of current obsession.
But anyway, if you have other
recommendations, please drop them below.
I think a lot of people would love to
dive into all the different books that
people recommend here. Like I mentioned,
I will put links to all of these in the
newsletter that will be linked down
below. And as always, I appreciate y'all
watching.
[Music]