content is on easy mode if you're
willing to put in the work and you
actually do the things that work on the
networks this goes for a brand and this
goes for personalities and so we're
going to talk about that here today
we're going to go through the state of
brand content and what I think is going
to be different in 2025 and how you can
act on it then we're going to go through
the state of the creative professional
if you're a person that wants to make
content particularly if you have any
background in entrepreneurship
creativity marketing branding Etc we're
going to talk about what can work for
you then we're going to go through the
algorithms their state how I feel they
work and what you can do make sure
you're taking maximum Advantage then
we're going to talk through the secret
which is a concept of a format this is
the one thing everyone needs to develop
it's something that I've been working on
a lot over this year that once you see
broken down and explained it will make
almost everything about why social media
content Works make sense let's lock in
so for Brands the key things we're going
to talk about are Concepts and
personality number one scaled accounts
and multiple accounts functioning
together number two Community number
three the power of briefs number four
and speed is number five to kick it off
concepts are King well you'll notice
about the brands that are breaking out
on social media right now is they are
have something specific about their
content it's not just here's my products
or here's what we do they have something
interesting and specific that they're
talking about or doing that makes their
content stand out from the rest we're
going to go through a few examples
you'll also notice for the most part
these brands are Creator Le it doesn't
mean they're Creator founded but there
are personalities that are on camera
that Define the Brand's presence we'll
go through a couple examples of this too
cuz it's often who you wouldn't expect
and then third they're all doing both
carousels and they're doing reals this
is in particular on Instagram we'll talk
about Tik Tok as well but they are
finding a balance between these two
working formats because they reach and
appeal to different people and feed into
each other in their success so what do I
mean by content with a concept so to
kickoff as an example of what I mean by
ideas we're going to start with BK
coffee shop and the content that they
have here so you'll notice that they
have a recurring series with the Creator
who's one of the partners in it and
other creators that come in and out
where they present a avanguard Black
Mirror version of a coffee shop
experience people come in they have
these filmed title overlays they film it
like a little series and they give these
ridiculous Concepts that come up and
these will be collaboration post between
the Creator who started it the actual
account of the brand itself and the
creators that come in as you can see as
you dive in there's a who's who of
people you may recognize from the
internet who are coming in and making
these guest appearances all with
relatively the same look and feel of
production it's beginning to establish
this as more of a TV show The they're
trying to be more of a parks and wreck
or something of that nature than they
are trying to be a typical brand account
now now before anyone kind of cries out
at oh this would be so expensive this
would be so much to do when you really
look at this they have the same two
camera angles they have a bunch of
guests they have a relatively simple
editing style you could spend a lot of
money making something like this or you
could do it pretty straightforward at
the end of the day with a two camera
setup even a One camera setup if it's
filmed with lines that's particularly
nice and someone that knows what they're
doing and actors that rehearse this is
easier than you think the concept is the
thing that puts it together and once you
get into a rhythm of executing it the
first time the second time getting good
at it you can continue to hit it
especially if it's doing well on the
algorithm gives you the incentive to
continue to execute these and because
the actual videos are doing well now you
get people that want to be guests inside
of them I love this example because it's
not your average it's not a fashion
brand or someone with a huge budget is a
Creator who has a coffee shop who's
looking at an out of the box way to
position their content as television and
have it stand out on Feed in a similar
way I want to look at gaun so I love
this travel series they have I'm going
to do an art Direction video in a few
weeks we'll dive into it a little bit
deeper but they have this these Concepts
they have recurring one is postcards
from different places where they're
filming these little vignettes of people
that get a lot a lot of views and looks
if you go through their page they have
multiple of these Concepts checking in
for the holidays where they're filming
like inside of a hotel scenario and
they're putting together uh little
vignettes that show that uh they are
doing their best to create a bunch of
different scenarios and test what works
and then continue them in different ways
but they're also balancing that with
near constant carousels of the product
right all the typical things you'd
expect from a fashion brand presented
artfully and nicely in simple carousels
next to each other to balance out these
brand building more viral items with
really straightforward things that
actually show off what they're selling
and the balance they have in this
account of trying conceptual things of
trying them multiple times to make sure
they work of tweaking them and adjusting
them while at the same time having
really sales oriented straightforward
content right next to it is a really
smart approach I feel like for brands
that want to approach this and make sure
they have performance dialed as well but
you may say hey those are high budget
those are required you have real cameras
people people on set scripting all that
kind of stuff and you'd be right there
has at least some level of production
value but that doesn't mean that that's
the only answer when I talk about the
algorithms a little bit later I'm going
to note that Instagram is moving higher
production value but there are still
tons of lower production things that
work and on Tik Tok lower production is
still King and so to call this out I'm
going to look at Santa Cruz medicinals
is a legendary account I'm pulling out
their Instagram they're bigger and more
prolific on on Tik Tok but this is the
creator the founder becoming a
personality and treating every single
moment like they're a like an going
narrative about his life they have all
these things going on inside their
content where they'll have rented houses
they have competitions with other
creator houses they're doing challenges
they're getting people into shape inside
this environment they have a cast of
characters he's doing constant skits and
it's all super simple super low
production done on iPhone but they have
created The Narrative around their brand
he is showing up every day doing things
like calling out Lunchables or creating
X challenge or Y challenge or bringing
people into it sharing it with podcast
clips and is a Relentless stream of
content around the founder that just
breaks out of the box because it's
treating it far more like you're
watching a reality show about him or he
also happens to be talking to the camera
a lot of the time than it is anything
else and the last brand I'm going to
bring up is duts and I want to bring
this up because I talked to a lot of
Brands outside of the fashion space I
know a lot of you watching this are
potentially in there because I make a
lot of content about it so we see all
the cool content ahead of time right
because things happen there but one of
the biggest Trends I think are going to
be happening for all brands in 2025 is
way more humor content so D shoots has a
constant stream of skits they have two
creators that are in almost every video
and the founder makes some appearances
as well it's a male and a female Creator
so there's a dynamic between the two of
them that often happens and there's also
they have their own individual
characters and is a constant stream of
funny videos that gets tons of views
they're always wearing the clothes from
the brand inside the videos sometime the
clothes are also at the center of them
like you can see here like you with
these these loafers but every video is
conceptual every video is funny and they
release them absolutely constantly they
also have a pretty Advanced strategy of
putting different accounts for these
when they open different locations I'll
talk about scaled accounts in a second
but using this humor aspect is another
one where this is the creativity right
again over the production they've added
production onto this as they become more
successful with it but at its core it's
two people engaging with each other
acting out funny scenarios where
creativity is King there's no fancy
cameras it's iPhone all the time and you
can see the intention that's put into it
and how well it's done for the brand so
let's talk about scaled accounts one
thing you'll notice is that there's
multiple accounts now representing
Brands you'll see the account has a
brand a Founder will have a brand an
employee will have a brand there'll be a
behind the scenes account once you
figure out content I wouldn't start
multiple until you know what you're
doing but once you figure it out you
start to realize content is actually
pretty easy to produce there's multiple
angles and multiple Styles and the more
stories you tell the better it is what
you can do and so again I wouldn't
recommend it until you have at least one
figured out but beginning to put those
different pieces in place and say we're
going to have one regionally because
Regional content works really well on
the algorithm or we're going to be able
to have our content you know told by
multiple voices or different we have
employees that to create content we want
to get on an account or we want to have
a secret account whatever it is start
thinking about that strategy and so one
key thing to remember especially if you
work at a company is that it's no longer
your company's voice representing you on
social media it's the combination of
your company your customers and your
team members and that overlap that
happens right there is how you can have
something special happen because all of
them should be a part of telling the
Brand Story and we'll get to this in a
future video but one of the key things
that's driving a lot of this is the
briefing process I'll probably do just a
dedicated creative briefs video at one
point but all of this does well because
people are creat creating repeatable
outlines and formats that work and are
able to share them with others and get
others involved and execute a lot of it
without having to be in the middle of it
at all times if there's one skill that
is valuable going into 2025 it's being
the person that can creative brief my
timeline is filled with people looking
for Creative strategist and creative
director jobs and that is because
finding people who can actually
communicate that consistently follow up
have nuance and report on it is tough
this is a new scenario it's hard to have
those proof of actually made from work
to do that and that's what we're seeing
so much demand for now and what helps
things like this scale so moving on from
Brands we're going to talk about people
and what makes people stand out on
social media now if you're trying to
create your own presence as a
professional and then I'll dive into the
state of the individual algorithms so
first I will start out that social media
is the portfolio now there is no more
hey I'm going to go to this website to
look at X or Y you are discovered and
understood on social and the key reason
of that is because the core work at it
on its own often doesn't matter as much
anymore how the work performs in context
AKA how it moves on social media becomes
even more important and this goes for
everything from copyrighting to to
photography to actual content creation
to any marketing campaign you might have
so much of it goes back to that that
putting it in the social media context
becomes Ultra important most skills lead
back to content brands are sold by
content that goes from everything from
services to physical locations to
products and then money and passion are
both generated through content so I'm
going to talk through a few formats that
you can use to make content for yourself
that are impactful now that will
actually make a difference if you're
trying to look for What should I do to
actually start participating in that
that's going to work so the first is
what I call the creative Carousel this
is one from someone who's in Cut 30
recently who again I like to highlight
this one because it's not beautiful his
typography is not amazing it's cut off
on several slides but it's still got
2300 likes or whatever it is cuz he's
literally just using the carousel format
to tell his exact story and people are
interested in his story and this is a
really key thing to think about and I
want to encourage and I'll start again
with this one that doesn't look
beautiful but tells a cool story as a
great example of putting multiple slides
together with text on top of them to
tell a story people want to hear is one
of the easiest ways to make content if
you don't want to put your face on it
another example for a brand this is a
conceptual carousel right I want this
idea of a creative Carousel you can tell
a story this is one where they're just
presenting photos artfully but it's
creative right it's not just these
photos here it's gum tree has their
notifications silenced is like a key
call out of this right where they're
able to actually show and explain
something that's going on and put it
into a creative way another one I like
to call out so Katie just has these
carousels where she's basically telling
her story about running what she's
eating what she's learning and she's
just putting text in cool patterns
around this and some of this you could
scribble on your iPad some of this you
could use text wrap tools and in
Photoshop or similar to do but she is
basically presenting her life Artful so
when I call out creative Carousel I
really mean creative I mean there needs
to be interesting things that are
happening to help tie it together but
it's an amazing vehicle to Showcase your
life and whatever it is that you do and
are interested in and should be kind of
the backbone of how you're thinking
about personal content strategy and the
same goes not just on Instagram but Tik
Tok weights carels even higher than ever
literally as of to higher than ever and
it has now they have another dedicated
feed just for photos and if you are on
threads which I know not a lot of people
are one thing that is bubbling on there
I think will bubble other places is
you're seeing these people do these like
day nine of using threads as a as a
photographic Journal where they're
really playing with like text styles on
things and like how text overlays I
think we're we obviously see a decent
amount of this on Instagram already this
is another style if you can learn to do
that and document your life and
participate in it it's a great way to
look at making content right now so
besides creative carousels another idea
is actually curation right where I don't
think you can go there and just read the
news and say Here's what's happening in
marke or here's four things you can
learn about accounting or whatever it is
now you need to take it a step further
and so this curation one this is from
yaah another cut 30 grad one of my
friends where he's put together a bunch
of slides where he's just obviously
there's much of known brands in here but
it's talking about what he thinks is
interesting about them with a common
theme it's another aggregation piece you
should look at for personality creative
carousels and then curation and curation
can be via Carousel or via video and
then the third is this IDE is the idea
of ideas so this is a format that I've
used a ton where I would basically say
hey if I was creative directing X I
would do y this woman has uh is using a
a similar format to great effect right
now and has grown a lot of followers and
is making some really cool content but
what you'll notice about this is it has
some inherent virality because of its
controversy so she is basically
presenting if I was going to make a
brand I'd do it like this awesome
Showcase of your skill set if you are
doing anything if you are an accountant
if you are a photographer if you're a
strategist if you're a copywriter
basically saying hey if I was you know
uh like one I did maybe like nine months
ago or six months ago was if I was Skull
Candy I'd do collaborations like this
right and you should be able to present
yourself in that context is an anchor
and a hook that works really well it
gives you a challenge and makes good
content about it but she's upping in a
notch because you know people are here
for the comments right when you look at
what is one of the things that helps
content succeed the most it is the
comments on it because dwell time goes
longer and watch time goes longer when
people are scrolling through the
comments to see what other people say
and so she has a lot of controversy
around these videos because she
generates all the images she uses from
them in ai ai is still no matter how
much people start using it reviled on
the internet in terms of image
generation because it's replacing
creative jobs Etc won't go too deep on
that in this video but you will see a
constant you know 22,000 likes on
someone just hating on her use of AI
right but it doesn't matter that Sparks
the conversation it get her ideas in
front of more people it has an innate
virality to it because of the
controversy and that's something else to
think about but this idea format is
wonderful and I would encourage you to
put yourself in the shoes of what you
would do for a company or scenario and
apply your expertise to it as a key
content format to stand out with
personal brand and you don't have to do
that with just long content uh someone
who I think does it well with short
content and lower production value
content is uh is this Creator and she
does predictions right um they're
usually iPhone there usually a little
less put together but she would
literally say here's what I think is
going to happen with this company or
this brand or the Kardashians or I think
this app should be created or why
doesn't this exist it's 90% of her
content right now she's doing 31 days of
predictions like for the holidays which
is smart and I think she did it last
year too but again she's just putting
her ideas out there in like relatively
low production with some text on it and
if you are the kind of person that has
ideas or you kind person wants to show
that off this is a great format with
which to do it and the and I think again
reading the news or saying this thing
happened or breaking it down into a
Playbook is moving away in 2025 real
ideas people can resonate with and think
is what people want to follow and the
last topic I will talk about is creating
art like creating actual things people
find interesting You Can Have Art in any
way like from this design Creator who
then kind of created the toy to someone
showing off their photography but doing
it in a super Artful way if you want to
show off something creative that you do
you need to present something like
really Artful and unique I couldn't find
the original creator for this this is
taken from a a style of a of a creator
that got really popular he was doing
like this was his thing where he put his
his hand with whatever on it behind him
cropped and that got super popular then
a lot of people jumped on on the trend
it started by one person who's basically
I'm making carousels like this and
literally it was like a nicely lit shot
of a hand nicely shot of a person one
cop behind the other really fun format
and so this is the kind of world we
exist in right where if you you are
creating like find some standout look
and feel way and then continue to create
it and eventually might get adopted
whole scale but you're going to get the
followers and attention in the meantime
all right so now we are going to talk
about the algorithms and how to look at
that into the new year this is really
tactical information to really think
about how content moves and why so first
is the Instagram algorithm probably more
important than ever as a looming Tik Tok
band in the US comes up but you will
notice that content on there is
upgrading more and more High visual
content movie level production content
great looking content on Pro Camera is
succeeding and I would be leaning into
that if this is your primary platform
and I be doing what I showed earlier and
creating a 50/50 mix of carousels and
reals you have to be good at both I feel
like to really stand out in the New Year
if you are excellent at one that will
always work but I think it's really
worth testing doing both and one thing
to note about Instagram's algorithm is
they have what I call like a almost like
a mass algorithm they can put you in a
bucket they basically say do you like
marketing do you like cars do you like
female fitness do you like men's fitness
do you like fashion they take these big
buckets and put you in an algorithm of
the bucket you're in the marketing
algorithm the design algorithm you can
be in a few at a time but that's how
they look at these big macro algorithms
which is why creators can blow up and do
really well because if you start to
dominate inside one thing you get shown
to anyone that's in that algorithm
that's how I view Instagram and Tik Tok
is not that right Tik Tok is very
specific it will give you exact creators
you like and show you a ton of them it
will give you exact niches you like you
really like you know dark anime but only
from the 9s period got it you like
conspiracy theories but only this type
of conspiracy theory they're on it they
will give you really exact versions of
the things that you're into and that's
worth thinking about as you create
because Instagram needs to know where to
put you and if there isn't an algorithm
for what you're doing and is throwing
you somebody somewhere else then you're
not going to succeed whereas in Tik Tok
you can make the nichest content you
want and you may not get a ton of views
from it but it will be the people that
are actually interested in that subject
provided you're making something that
can kind of Point them in the right
direction has good captions and
descriptions Etc but Tik Tok is more
than ever now different than Instagram
it is iPhone content it is BAS level
content very little pro quality content
succeeds on there it is lots of photos
it is lots of skill it is lots of people
participating and talking candidly and I
do feel like this is now the time where
if you don't have content kind of like
the Santa Cruz Medicals gu showed where
it can kind of cross over to both and
his lowf you need a specific strategy
for Tik Tok and the only people that are
able to get away with this high-end
content are big brands with established
followings who are doing that kind of
thing and after that comes YouTube and
YouTube is just mainstream content when
it comes to shorts it shows the shorts
to everybody if you want someone to
really succeed in there it has to have
massive mainstream appeal it is barely
an algorithm in terms of what it gives
you it's very light on that if you you
want to have huge success on there it
needs to be something that anyone of any
age or level would love and like which
is why you see so few people blow up on
it who don't have Mass Appeal content
and niches are really hard to build
there and so is personality and then we
have LinkedIn LinkedIn is boosting
Impressions right now you'll see massive
impression numbers because there's a
little module on the screen that has a
Carousel and anytime someone Scrolls by
that module which they'll scroll by a
dozen times whenever they're in a
session then they get an impression on a
video whether the video plays or not so
you'll see you're getting huge
Impressions on LinkedIn but not actually
many views but LinkedIn video is great
they're pushing it more than ever I'd
highly recommend creating on there but
it needs to be a balance with other
content it's a lot of filler there's a
lot of people that really interact with
it it's a good thing because everyone on
there is obviously more qualified more
professional it's good if you're
building a business but I feel like it
needs to be anchored with another
strategy and what does rud do really
good on LinkedIn is approaching it as a
team LinkedIn rewards companies whose
people comment on each other's stuff
gives you the option as an employee of a
company to notify people at your company
when you tag them that the post has gone
live there's a lot of little features
like that that it actually helps if you
work in LinkedIn as a team and I'm going
to talk about two things and we're going
to wrap up so the first is developing a
format this is the most important
crucial secret to making content succeed
is you'll notice that almost everybody
who really blows up has a couple things
in common they are doing a thing is
number one so for instance Nara Smith is
cooking food from scratch in every
single video is why she's one of the
biggest Tik tokers if not the biggest
Tik tocker my boy Thor is chopping wood
every single video he's related he is
chopping wood while he gives you life
advice or flirts with the camera
whatever it is Ken amazing fashion
account is sitting at this same table
with the graphics in the same style
giving you this information his is the
least of like I'm doing a thing but he's
explaining it to you like in this very
similar look but they will be doing an
item that they complete this action
every time and I think that's crucial I
think you there's account with that one
girl who eats a ribeye every day and
talks right she's completing an action
while she does it and that's crucial if
you can add that into your content that
you are doing a thing and it's the same
thing every time that is a very useful
thing to Anchor content inside of and a
crucial thing that helps people stand
out second is they are set up the same
almost every time their sets don't
really change they have a unique looking
feel like Nara is always wearing Couture
Thor always has a unique axe or a crazy
piece of wood or whatever it is but they
have set themselves up you'll notice
their framing is almost the same exactly
so people when they scroll by they know
this is unique content of this person
they recognize it immediately and that
means they stay and dwell if they like
it so we now have they're doing a thing
and they're presenting it with the same
visual format and then they package it
the same way right the same titles the
same textt in the same places there's
consistency in The Branding of it look
at the shift Fashion Group they make
content we taking apart clothes all the
time and it's it's a little technical
right it's not like the most exciting
content but people that are interested
in are really interested in it but they
package it the same the shots are the
same each time the text in the title
cars is the same each time and there's a
hundred examples of this right you'll
find that someone doing a thing
completing an action cutting open
clothes baking a cake whatever it is
combined with the same Framing and
formatting adding on to value or
entertainment whichever you're getting
from it is just a key part of finding
success so I highly encourage people who
are stalled in their content to think
about how do I adopt this format when I
created it we have another cut 30
kicking off is January 7th cut 3.co if
you want to join us for that I will
always disclaimer that that if you are
like a student or you are new in your
career whatever please just take the
free content and roll with it when I
sell or package anything I do it for
people that are at a certain place in
their career or a certain place in their
Journey where they have the resources to
spend on it if you are again a student
or a junior person I do not want your
money from anything if you are a
professional you're really about
buildings you know your brand content or
whatever it is then uh I make solutions
for you and you can hit me at cut 30.com
drop any questions you have around
content I'm going do a follow-up video
to this coming here in a few few weeks
and appreciate you watching
[Music]