the most in demand position in marketing
today is the creative strategist this
job is a bit of a hybrid between
traditional creative director art
director and a social media manager
influencer manager creative strategists
are responsible for ideating ideas for
Content owned organic content for
influencer Content affiliate content
actually briefing that content to get
executed and then feedbacking it with
the people they work with so it's
actually good but the secret behind
being an amazing creative strategist
really comes down to making a great
brief we're going to go through the
format of a great brief with a bunch of
content examples this is really rooted
in the content of like what this
differentiators are we're going to go
through building an Insight toolkit
which is about how to make content that
works I'm going to share some exact
examples then we're going to go through
the psychology of content Hooks and
break some videos down and then drop
some homework about how to get started
if you're trying to do this for the
first time so if you ever want to make
your brand content pop off on social
media your content pop off be able to
scale things of the job you work at or
just be ultra equipped for where media
is going this is the video for you let's
lock so let's talk about the foundation
of what's covered inside a creative
brief and a brief is a document that's
given to someone who has to go create
content and I'm going to have this
Reformation example up cuz we're going
to get into some insights around this in
a second like all of these pieces of
content I'm pulling up started with a
brief everything from Cosmetics to
Fashion to memes so what's actually on
the well the first thing is the hook and
the hook of a piece of content is the
first visual that you see this guy on
the subway in his shoes the first thing
that you read the text on screen can
Asher outrun the train in his Mack X2
and the first audio you hear what does
someone say or what music is there that
is your hook the Hook's job is to get
someone to stop more on that later the
second portion of the brief is the idea
what are all the references so for
instance if I was trying to make a
similar piece of content this would be
the reference that was in there you're
going to put the basics of what the
video and the third thing and the core
basically all art direction is the
Insight let's talk about insights for a
second and content insights what do we
even mean by insight and insight is a
reason someone watching it is going to
care and this is what's missing this is
good content versus bad content at its
core is does it hook someone to actually
watch them is there a reason for them to
be engaged versus just selling whatever
we're going to sell or just putting some
mindless stuff out there so what do we
mean by that let's talk about your
Insight toolkit if you are a creative
strategist you're going to have a couple
core ideas you're able to go back to
that you know resonate with consumers
I'll give some examples when your Audi
shops at ref ref being Reformation they
are duplicating a shot from the sance TV
show they are using text from the
severance TV show the Audi concept this
is a part of the Insight toolkit it's a
cultural Insight everyone is watching
this is what I refer to it as so there's
a common shared cultural moment the last
of the finale of Game of Thrones
Everyone's Watching Severance or talking
about Severance if enough of your
audience is participating in a thing the
Super Bowl they're paying attention to
Island they watch the dualingo owl
die there's a cultural thing that's
happening that you can participate in
that is a cultural Insight so they chose
to put out this video cuz they went does
our audience resonate with Severance do
they understand what this is can we tap
into that great that is a cultural
Insight that's at the root of the brief
for a video like this then we have
what's called a shared experience inside
this is one I love to use so breaking in
new jeans right that's something
everyone deals with it's a complicated
thing there's a funny video made about
it but this here POV you said you're 5
minutes away this is a normal video
right she's just doing a makeup routine
video it's sped up but they put that
shared experience of oh man this
person's coming and I'm not ready right
that is a thing that everyone
understands everyone has been through
and that's a part of the toolkit right
how do you take whatever idea or content
you want to make I want to make a makeup
video how do I create a shared
experience Insight around it something
we've all gone through you could do the
opposite of this video If I Was
brainstorming for something similar it
would be like POV you said you'd be
there at 4:00 there's a clock it says
4:15 you're doing the makeup or whatever
uh like there's a certain types of those
things they're just recurring things we
all have met with and that's a useful
thing to have in your tool kit another
Insight type is cost or barrier to entry
so how to fake an eye lift right so this
is basically positioning that oh I don't
actually want to get an ey lift but I
want to look like I have an eye lift or
I couldn't afford an ey lift and I want
to have one and cosmetics is a great
Niche to look at this stuffing so they
usually on the edge so there's this
Insight that people want to have this
look might not potentially actually want
to go do the thing that takes it there
and they're going to recreate that that
is an Insight at the core of this piece
of content and there's aspiration this
is one of my videos aspiration is a
great one we saying hey like this is a
lifestyle thing POV you swore off the
curse Millennial pan Brands and only buy
copper and steel kitchen autron from a
trusted Source in Paris so I'm using a
combination of shared experience people
have had bad Millennial pan brand
experiences that's something shared
within my demographic people would love
the idea that they could actually go
shop and be buying copper pans in like a
location in Paris or something asp
insirational I'm tying those two things
together on a video that got 12,000
likes just a reminder as you watch this
those only know me from YouTube um I do
really well on short form content I live
inside this both for myself and for
Brands thus my ability to casually talk
to you about this right here while
having 12,000 likes on something but
your job in Creative strategy when you
have the brief is to go through okay the
hook how are we going to stop things
what's the core idea of the video and
then what's the Insight what is the
thing that's going to tie people in is
an aspiration factor is there a cost
factor I can get this effect by doing X
is there a shared experience something
that they're relating to is there a
cultural factor that oh we're buying
into this is there a problem solve this
is one it's one of the most typical ones
right are we saying hey this is
something people deal with that we're
helping solve and there's also just pure
entertainment humor things like but
getting a bank of different Insight
types and then applying them to your
briefs is the difference between making
okay content and making great content I
want to Zone in on that here we're going
to go through the rest of the brief
process I'm talk about some about how
you actually become good at some of so
one of the other things in every brief
is formats does this need to be 9 x 16 1
by one Etc and I want to call out
formats because one thing that uh when I
go into companies and I'm working on
creative strategy I bring up all the
time is that if you have a good idea you
have a good concept you have something
you want to get across and you've made a
video brief for it you also can probably
make a carousel brief and you can also
probably make what we call a onot brief
let me break that concept down so this
is my boy uh he runs a vintage account
called Game Day Grails noted cut 30 grad
and he is making a video about The Cult
of the lawsuit logo this is a moment in
time but he did this video popular video
of his about a unique piece of vintage
Weare but since this video did well this
is a pretty uh good performing video for
him on his account this same exact video
with the the same exact hook the cult of
the lawsuit logo could probably function
just as well as a carousel where that is
the hook the cult for the lawsuit logo
you're showing this thing that sports
fans really know and you walk through
the history this happened blank this
happened blank here's a couple items
that reflect it end of Carousel but you
can tell that same story visually in six
Graphics then same thing with a onot if
he was doing the same thing if like he's
uh mimicking that Meme where someone's
standing in the corner and there's a
party or whatever it is or like he's
standing there's a bunch of people
around him and he's like I bet they
don't even know I'm in a lawsuit logo
you know windbreaker whatever it is
there's an approach you could have to
take this same idea and make it a
oneshot video a 6sec text over screen
clip that's something I encourage people
who are briefing to think about because
one of the foundations of good creative
strategies how do you achieve scale
that's the issue you have right some
people are good at making individual
briefs but the problem is there's so
many assets that actually need to get
made if you in the middle of a real
performing growing brand doing you're
starting to go over 5 mil to the 10 mil
Plus or getting an even bigger brand you
need so many ads so many social posts
you're seeding so many influencers
you're doing ugc you probably have
multiple Tik Tok and Instagram accounts
there is a scale element that makes a
good creative strategist where a lot of
us can sit down and really work through
it and create a good brief but can you
create 10 of those a day can you scale
that across x amount of creators and
languages and regions that's what makes
an exper but one of the biggest things I
like to think about is if I had one good
idea all right let's do this in multiple
formats that's also a carousel idea I
get to brief to the designer it's a
onshot idea I get to the ugc creators
we're going to do that same idea in
Spanish like you can begin to think
about scale some other key Parts you
have variance do you want to actually
have to have different uh Beginnings or
endings to the video so you can test
them talk a bit about that in strategy
here in a minute and then your call to
action what's the point what do you want
people to get across at the end I'm
going to walk a bit through a template
of this and we're going to get into some
strategy and then some specific examples
I'm going to break down really into hook
strategy as well so this is forplay who
have agreed to sponsor this video you
can find a link about them in the
description forplay is where I keep all
my references for brand content
basically allows you to save any ads or
organic ads inside of this platform they
have a dashboard where I can scroll
through tons of product they have this
discovery function where I can see what
other people are liking and saving and
all the kind different content I can go
find any brand is a great source to be
able to hunt through ads but they also
have briefs briefs built in the platform
I'm going show you an example of a test
brief so quick example here you will see
brand profiles so if you're working on
multiple Brands and your strategies you
can put it up there inspiration so I can
go grab this from my existing videos and
attach inspiration into here some
bookmarked I go look and view and say
I'm going to add this to the brief that
will help you now I have my reference in
here and details description stuff we
talked about size and aspect ratio
formats duration what platform that's
going on products we want to make sure
included music if you want to add a loom
all that goes in here you can put
details in it's actually little AI
script generation thing here story
boards if you have them you'll know
especially when you're working with
influencers a lot of the time there will
actually be some story boards that will
go in there especially if you want to
map out a hook you can add different
scenes to it and all this is savable and
most importantly duplicable inside of
here so I can go to my briefs down here
where you see test brief I can share it
real quick and most importantly sharable
I can take these and I can actually go
send it to people to participate in in
one place with the links I have from all
my swipe files but we're going to talk
about hooks I'm actually going to go
into uh one of the boards I've made on
here for this video and then we're going
to go with some strategy and some
homework so just like we had insights up
there earlier we talked about how having
a consumer Insight can help make a great
brief so can Hooks and the combination
of both of them together is where you
become a weapon so what do I mean by
Hooks so just like you have a toolkit
for insights you need a toolkit for
Hooks and funny I was talking to my
friend Jason um Jason sweat he's another
Creator and we were talking at uh the
shopi dent event I didn't New York the
other week and he was talking about when
he started making content he was an art
director at Amazon at the time how the
biggest insight for him was he was like
oh my God I'm making these ads but like
I need to think like a content creator
when I'm also doing these ads I need to
hook people in the same way it's all the
same psychology and this is something I
think everyone needs to get across one
of the real reasons it's important to
like really be a content creator or
think like a content creator when you're
doing this is that every one of these ad
assets every organic asset you know if
you're a contractor you know the hook is
the most important thing and then these
strategies are going to tie into every
single thing you do from television
campaigns to print campaigns to he so
there's a couple different types of
hooks I want to call out so this video
from H I'm training a little differently
let's R this train he is racing a
train so this is a challenge hook you
are going to wait to see like there's
set up a challenge and you're going to
wait till then see what the result is
man is going to race train in Hocus that
is the hook that is going to get you to
stop and watch the video if you are
interested in seeing a challenge
complete one style of hook let me of
what's called negative hooks this is one
here worst sellers in store another one
down here our fat burner does not work
doesn't work and you'll notice these are
not like big standout high production
videos they're talk he's talking about
his product these people are talking
about products they sell in stores this
thing doesn't work this is my worst
seller just putting that negative
interaction in there negative content
just does better these aren't negative
videos he's explaining in the worst
sellers video how to actually make
videos sorry how to why people should be
buying this product as their wor so
another hook strategy is the unveil like
you see here where she's actually
bringing out like unrolling something
people wait to see what is about to be
unrolled what we call displacement where
at that first shot in the video you were
looking at someone pulling pancakes out
of a refrigerator refrigerator with
jewelry in it you begin to wonder what's
happening that's a behind the scenes
video there's drama midday squares the
kings of this we're being extorted exed
with pornography like extremely strong
hook they're basically taking reality TV
and bringing it in drama is another one
curiosity one of my favorites Lana Del
Walks Like Lana Del walks in the coffee
shop what are you going to make her is
like one of those like oh I wouldn't
normally watch a coffee recipe video but
this is weird adrenaline is a great hook
this is a classic from 2J where he leaps
in his full
outfit down below all those are hook
tactics and so just like you built your
Insight Bank of why would people watch
this video you should build your hook
Bank of what are tactics can I do a
challenge can I do adrenaline can I do
drama can I do displacement can I do
curiosity you are going to build your
bank so as a strategist you have your
insights Bank you have your hooks Bank
much like You' seen me in Prior videos
pull up my art Direction boards and go
like here's all these different art
Direction ideas I have with a couple
examples you can build that same exact
thing out and even here like in foreplay
like I I uh and this is like my test
account I do for these videos but you
could very easily like have a different
board for each of those hook styles with
your references on so we're going to
talk about some strategy and then we're
going to get into some homework so on
strategy one of the most important
things to think about is you need to
really think like a Creator and ideally
be a Creator even if you're not a big
YouTuber a big instagrammer having gone
through the P like the process of this
will make you way more useful within it
and so why do I say that a few things
the first is there's all these little
strategy components that make you better
than other people that come from being a
Creator the first is stuff like related
video I haven't made YouTube for that
long I put a lot of brand videos on
YouTube forever I didn't really
understand the related video thing
between shorts and long form which where
basically you can attach a short form
video to a long form video so it's like
easy to click through and that's like a
really powerful tool and a lot of Brands
don't even know that it exists they
don't even know you can attach the two
of those that's like an Insight you get
from being a Creator same thing with
other things you have in the strategy
trial reels like right now you can bang
out variations of videos and trial reels
if a video does well so something that I
have a lot of Brands doing is we'll make
a video a high performing video we'll go
test a bunch of similar versions of it
and just throw it up in trial reels I'll
throw up five or six versions of a
banger video and trial reels and we'll
only show them to nonf followers of our
accounts and you can actually scale a
bunch of creative organic that way it's
like a cheat code I would not know that
if I was not running trial reels on my
account many chat same thing this is
where you comment a word and you get a
DM on Tik Tok or Instagram whatever that
is a tool that you have when you are
talking to influencers as a strategy
tool if you understand understand how it
works you can ask them to do if I was a
software influencer if I was a software
creative strategist asking for software
influencer I'd be asking for that all
the time because you just guaranteeing a
DM call to action you can have some
measurability ility that's harder to get
from a Lincoln bio but knowing all those
things are little Parts you have in your
strategic toolkit that make you better
than another creative strategist but if
you have many chat in your tool kit
you're like I know when I ask a certain
Creator I can do a comment call to
action and that maybe we have to charge
a little bit more or whatever we should
work that into the brief same thing with
hey I want seven variations of that of
this creative that we're doing
internally so I can run them as trial
ads as trial reels that is an advantage
you now have over every other creative
strategist who does not know that
another amazing one people don't do
enough is Recreation like this
Reformation campaign I use Reformation
as an example all the times cuz they're
unhinged want to know what their email
list to see what I mean let me show you
so Reformation did this whole campaign
where they took viral videos from
existing creators had them remake the
viral video some on their account and
some on the actual creators account
again just in a Reformation outfit this
is like a genius thing I always wonder
why more people don't do I've had this
happen to me once I've done I do two
sponsor videos a week on short form I've
had one person ever be like hey can you
just make this video with our product in
it it was a wallet video um and they
were smart they're like hey this thing
went viral it'll probably go viral again
it did it did like the first one did
500k the second remake did 281 or
something that is an amazing technique
to have when you were going out to
influencers if you understand how to
properly integrate your product and if
you are comfortable with something of
hey I just want to show people wearing
this amazing dress whatever it is part
of the things you have in your toolkit
so your homework you want to enter
deeper in this world of creative
strategy is one thing I always talk
about is Shifting your consumption of
content from I'm scrolling to I'm
intentionally consuming intentionally
scrolling I want you to set a 20 minute
30 minute calendar for yourself could be
a night could be wherever where you're
going to intentionally scroll on Tik Tok
and reals start a new account if you
want use your existing account whatever
but your job is you're going to come up
with hook ideas way I was talking about
challenges or drama or whatever you're
going to say okay I want to bookmark in
a folder start a four playboard
different hook types and I also want to
have insights I'm going to think about
what other insights besides the one I
outlined here are examples of those that
are relevant to what you work on or of
your own insights begin to build that
toolkit and you'll notice in a half hour
even a half hour a week of intentionally
scrolling versus just scrolling being
like I'm going to save 10 hooks I'm
going to get X examples of insights
whatever it is you are going to begin to
build a toolkit that will turn you into
a weapon when it comes to creative
strategy so anyway way try to load this
video up with value because I think this
is actually a really important you know
you can jump career steps if you are
good at this and also like I mentioned I
know a lot of brands that need people
like this there's all these hiring stuff
on Twitter that comes out around this
kind of skill set uh and so I think it's
a useful thing overall please drop any
questions you have below and thank y'all
so much for watching