In this video, we're going to cover
everything you could ever desire to know
about advertising in the modern era. I
shot some of this direct from the Can
Lions Advertising Festival in France and
picked up the rest here in my studio. We
have some special guests. But the goal
here is if you're ever going to run an
ad in a modern world, whether it's for a
brand, for a services business, whether
it's for yourself, if you want this in
your toolkit as a marketer, we're going
to cover it all. We're going to talk
about positioning a brand to succeed
inside of advertising. We're going to
talk about the concept of hooks and why
it actually matters in ads just as much
as content. We're going to cover
emotion, persuasion, and psychology and
review 10 psychology tactics that are
going to help you convert in your
marketing. We're going to go through
digital ad types. My friend Lucas from
Dark Room is actually going to walk
through all the different types of
digital ads and keywords. Everything
from Amazon to Instagram to Google. You
get an idea of the full toolkit you have
to play with. We're going to talk a bit
about traditional advertising and its
place in the modern world, types of ads
that work, and I'm actually going to go
through a bunch of different ad types
you should be running for every business
or at least considering. We're going to
talk about direct response and making
money in the traditional sales side of
advertising and then end a little bit on
landing pages, funnels, and the things
that actually make your ads work on the
other end. This is going to be the
longest video that I have ever made. I
want you to view this as a resource you
can come back to whenever you're get get
to advertising for your business. And I
want you to think of this and everything
I put in here as you are building your
toolkit. You are going to take some of
the ideas I put out there, some of the
strategies, the networks, the
psychology, and find the things that you
feel like resonate with either your
customer or your style and then list
those things out and build a toolkit. I
will have a full guide with all of this
available for download in the
description for free. So, if you want
text versions as well as some templates
for these, that is all going to be
there. This is going to be a great one.
It's going to hit the money-making side
of marketing versus just the creative
side I talk so often about. If you're
ready to do it, let's lock in.
[Music]
So, why should you listen to me about
advertising? I'm a former designer who
worked my way through to director and
eventually to CMO. I've overseen nine
figures in metas-pend and work on these
platforms with client brands and my own
every day. You'll hear a lot of these
anecdotes around the way and I'm out
here at CAM with my friends at Dark
Room, a serious performance agency who's
worked with Lollipop, Saws, lots of
household brands and up andcoming CPG.
And we're doing this event here at CAM
with everyone from CMOs to entrepreneurs
who are really in the weeds now talking
about these conversations and the real
data behind them every day. And that
leads us to positioning. I didn't
position myself as a commentator or as
an employee or a billion-dollar
entrepreneur, but as an operator who
lives this true expertise that's not
removed from the battle and it's
surrounded by other experts to help
shape a worldview you can learn from.
So, you probably heard the word
positioning, but what does it really
mean? Positioning starts with product is
reinforced by marketing and is about the
association your product and your brand
has inside the consumer's mind which is
a choice on your behalf and how you
create the product design the product
and how you advertise it. So a good
example is a brand like Volvo who is
associated with safety. They are
positioning themselves as a safe family
vehicle where you are basically buying
peace of mind. And the first type of
positioning that I'm going to talk about
is category creation. This is when you
create something completely new to
position yourself as a unique offering
on the market. So a good example is an
Aura ring where there had been rest
optimization and some of these other
things that existed with smartwatches or
devices but they positioned it inside of
a new form factor focused on achieving
that optimization in your life without
interfering with the rest of what's
going on. And then someone like AG1
where vegetables have been around
forever even some greens company but
they basically created a ritual around
getting what you need for your body in a
new way in a new form factor. And that
leads us really quickly to the second
type of positioning which is called
position against. This means you're
positioning against a leader or an enemy
inside of an existing category to say we
are better in a different way. I love
using that AG1 example for someone new
because there's a new company Grunts
that has come out by positioning
basically against AG1 saying you are
doing this thing that's healthy for you
but it tastes bad and it's a weird
experience. Like why are we still doing
this way? Let's give it to you the way
that you will enjoy having in a gummy.
And also that means it's not just for
adults, it's for kids. they are
positioning against an existing industry
incumbent. You look at the same thing
with you look at a local bookstores
trying to position against Amazon.
You're not buying from this
conglomerate. You're buying from your
local neighborhood bookstore. We just
happen to have an online store or a
classic Apple positioning itself against
PC with this kind of line of ads that
was made very famous where they're
saying this is a PC and associating it
with this like older antiquated type of
person and I'm a Mac. I'm this new
person so many more people want to be.
And another type of positioning is
really highlighting a difference in your
product through choice of words. I call
this smart positioning because it
happens so much with the word smart. So
for instance, we had phones and then we
had smartphones. So someone created that
idea of if you have this phone that's
not smart, it is therefore dumb. It was
a positioning choice. I've used this
multiple times inside my own career. One
of the first projects I worked on using
something like this was in the defense
industry. And then we did another one
inside of uh the consumer drones where
basically we put chips and a set of and
apps associated with initial camera
drones and positioned as a smart drone
against dumb drones that couldn't do
some of the functionality that we had.
This is in the same way you see a brand
like eightle be like hey here's a
traditional mattress. Well it's really a
dumb mattress because we have all this
technology and all these things that
enable you to have this modern
experience. Call that smart positioning.
That leads us to value positioning. This
is positioning based on cost. This is
one of the easiest types of positions to
make where you say, I'm going to look at
what everything costs in a market and
I'm going to say how much cheaper do I
have to be for consumers to always pick
that if they are price conscious. This
is a harder and harder way to position
because it gives you less room for
advertising spend to secure customers,
but it also gives you a high likelihood
when they see it. You have a higher
chance of conversion just at a lower
margin. As we've gone through time in
the world with Amazon brands and brands
online and timu that costbased
positioning has basically been eroded by
overseas brands by duplicate goods in a
way that makes it really hard for a lot
of entrepreneurs to succeed with cost
positioning but it's still worth
understanding. Then we have niche
positioning. This is around positioning
around subcultures. Whether that's
around language, areas of demographics,
backgrounds, races, size, anything where
you say this is built by us for us. That
becomes a type of positioning that makes
someone feel like they want to buy
because of a more associative instinct
that feels like this is something that
was created for me. I'm supporting my
people. And then we're going to go to
counterculture positioning. This is
where you say there's a whole existing
category, but we're going to make
something alternative. We're going to
make something extreme. Liquid death is
a great example where the B there used
to be a lot of Evian, a lot of Dani on
the shelves and you say something with
this is a pure lifestyle, heavy metal.
Usually it's that kind of extreme
aesthetic. You put that right next to
it. There's a certain buyer that goes,
I'm extreme. Like I want this like
alternative. Like I'm different. And
they'll go towards that. And this is an
excellent, especially with Gen X who all
believe that they're unique and
beautiful snowflakes and they make their
own taste is an excellent way to market
to them. We've seen this in everything
from coffee with people like Black Rifle
to water cafes and restaurants. And then
we have generational positioning saying
we're going to take a product or
category and position it towards a
certain age. I'll bring this up in
cosmetics. There's a company called
Jones Road that positions itself a
little bit older. They become an
accessible point for older women to feel
excited about getting into makeup and
cosmetics. And that's reflected in the
model choices they use in their
advertising, some of the copy and the
way they put things together. And it's
not exclusive, it's just focus. Same
thing with lower younger positioning,
the way you've seen uh a brand like Half
Magic come in and say this would really
appeal to a younger demographic. Again,
it's not excluding the older, but it has
a lot of the trappings of something that
would make someone younger be excited by
it. And positioning is important to
start with because this impacts the lens
you approach in your advertising. Your
positioning is the core of what every
campaign starts with. You're positioning
generationally by a niche subculture, a
counterculture, or based on price.
That's going to be one of the first
things you consider when you go to make
a great ad. And now I want to get one
thing out of the way before we keep
rolling through this. I want to talk
about AI. Really, this is a conversation
about tools and mediums. Inevitably,
whenever I do one of these videos,
people like, "What is AI going to do
this? What does AI mean?" And we talk
about that. Let's talk about ad formats.
To make good ads, there are formats you
choose from to go advertise. Let's break
those down. So, the first is a designer
making an ad. This is someone saying,
"Hey, let's take some existing product
photography. Let's put some copy with it
and let's design a asset, whether that's
for digital or to get printed out or put
on a billboard that is a designed ad.
It's an ad type that you can make." Now,
in our modern world, as we get into more
video friendly stuff, we also have in
addition to those like static designed
ads, we'll have 3D ads. things like
you've seen like you're actually
animating a 3D of a product into a scene
or you're doing just an animation or a
2D or a cartoon style video. It's called
a 3D and animated ad. So we enter into
video whether it's on television, a
video billboard on your actual video in
a short form. That is a format you can
choose for an ad. Then we have produced
video like video that you can do on a
shoot or video that's being done like
for a campaign with actual people inside
of it. And then we have this new
incumbent the last few years UGC video
which is getting user generated content.
That's getting actual normal human
beings to do a video promoting a product
as if they were just a normal person, a
consumer giving a review. It's basically
a more candid style. So we sort of
stacked up these different types of ads.
There's another one I love to call out
called ugly ads where people are saying,
"Hey, we actually we want to take that
design. We're still going to design it,
but it's going to be a post-it note.
It's going to be a screenshot of the
notes app. We're going to make these
really simple ads." Another good
category for this. And then AI is just a
segment of this. Now, there are AI video
ads. Veo 3 has really enabled this where
you can create a lot of B-roll and
scenarios completely animated without
having to do a produced shoot. But the
core of that ad and what makes it
function is almost exactly the same as
what a produced ad is. One of the only
differences is now you have an open
creative world where you could show
something hyperrealistic of real people
engaging in the product or if you wanted
that ad narrated by a panda bear or a
Spartan inside a horse, whatever it is,
you're able to execute on that creative
vision. And then same thing with design.
AI design might be useful from some
variations now, but isn't designing full
ads to the standard with which they'll
perform. But it can basically be a tool
in the toolkit of those designing to add
background images to get variations and
layouts. And that's where this all fits
inside the framework. When you go to
design your ad campaigns and look at
what tools do I have in my toolkit,
knowing that you have designed ads, you
have animated ads, you have actually
produced video and photo shoots, you
have UGC and content from other folks,
and then you have some of the AI
components you can plug into. It gives
you a full breadth of toolkit that you
can say this is the different ways I can
approach putting together assets for a
campaign. This video is sponsored by
Framer. Framer is an awesome platform
for creating websites. I especially want
to call this out for creatives who are
trying to build your own portfolio site
or build a site for your agency or
business because they have an amazing
combination of things. It really appeals
to design and aesthetic oriented people.
Why I like this is this is the simplest
platform where I can actually make
complicated beautiful things versus a
lot of platforms where you get templates
that are mediocre or you have to really
go all out with complex code to do it.
We're in the era of the enabled
designer, the enabled creative. You can
do so much now with the combination of
tools available to you and framework is
just a great example of how you can in
less time than ever make truly gorgeous
websites. And showing some examples of
these templates here. So this is
Fabrica. I'm actually looking at redoing
my website in this exact theme right
now. Beauty of Frame is that these are
templates that have all these little
things. The way that the scroll is, the
way everything loads, the parallax, the
edges, the corners, the video integrated
your site out of the box can look like
this. Like that is an amazing advantage.
And all these are available. I think
these are like uh some are $79, some are
$99. Here's another one, another agency
one. I love especially in a mobile first
world where everyone's consuming on
their phones. Things that work on cards
like this I think is a great way to do
it cuz you can really visualize how
those cards change when they go down
into mobile. Finally, I want to talk
about this workshop thing that they
have. I'll do I'll do like a deeper dive
on this in a future video, but this is
basically an AI for advanced components.
So, basically, uh, one of the reasons
that I've really shifted over workflow
into framer is because if I want
something like a number counter or an
analog clock or a text scrambler or any
of the things shown here, I can
literally type into the workshop what I
want and it will create something like
right there in front of you. It's
actually magic. And especially for
simple visual elements that you don't
want to take the time to design or
figure out or kind of develop something
custom for. There's so much of that from
these like slider examples, counters, a
lot of these little things you can do on
web that help you actually make a
creative vision. The fact that you can
like type those in and get something
that's very relevant to what you're
trying to create is is amazing. So, if
you haven't heard of Framer before, if
you're looking for a new website
platform, uh definitely check it out at
the link I have below in this
description. I appreciate Framer for
sponsoring this video. We're going to do
more content with them and some
tutorials on what I'm working on with
them and things you can do there. But
check out them and their templates if
you want to kind of guarantee you have a
beautiful design driven site you can
create interesting things on that does
everything you need out of the box. They
are an awesome platform to learn. Let's
go. But no matter what you choose, we
need to have a conversation around
hooks. What do I mean by hooks? There's
basically two types of content and
advertisements right now. Advertisements
are almost always what we call an
interrupt. This means that someone is
doing something else and your
advertising interrupts them versus a
choose to watch. YouTube, for instance,
is a choose to watch. When you clicked
on this video, you saw my thumbnail, you
saw my title, and you chose to watch it
versus what's next to it. It did not
interrupt your feed the way an Instagram
video when you swipe up comes up next,
then have to reel you in based on you
seeing it. Those are two extremely
different experiences. But now, if I
have an ad placement in this video,
which we probably do, it's going to
interrupt what I am talking about unless
I found a really amazing way to
integrate it to make it feel natural,
which I will try to do. And then when
you're going into TV or you're going
into a streaming world, basically
everything is interrupt. You're
interrupting a movie or whatever it is.
And what happens there is a little
different on your phone. When you're on
a secondary device and why traditional
marketing is failing so badly is because
everyone just looks at their phone when
you're watching the NFL and they go to
that commercial, everyone just opens
their phone. When you are same thing if
you get that Amazon ad at the start of
whatever video that you're uh putting on
their streaming service, you just look
at your phone. So, not only does the ad
interrupt, but then it has to compete
with a device that is addicting in its
own way, that has better content on it.
And that's why those ads are just never
ever going to perform the way they did
10 or 15 years ago. But this is where
the hook becomes important. So, I have
whole videos where I dive in digestion
of the hooks, but really is the first 3
seconds of your video. What gets someone
to not scroll through it? Or if you're
interrupting them and no matter what it
is, how do they basically get interested
enough to watch versus like scroll away
or look at a device or click bypass as
soon as they can? And so this gives you
a extremely small window in a
combination of the first visual that
they see, the first thing that they hear
and whatever that they can read that is
on the screen to get the message across
that they need to keep going and they
need to keep watching. And you will see
this metric measured all the time and
you are meta ads manager. They have a
metric called hook rate which is the
amount of people that actually watch
beyond this. When you go into your
Instagram analytics, they're going to
show you 3 second rate is inside there.
It'll show you how many people are going
beyond 3 seconds. And you'll notice that
this is the key metric. 3 second watch
time to nonfollowers is the key metric
with which Instagram promotes your video
to people that don't already follow you
and is a huge deal. So everything that
you think about should be about 3
seconds. Now this applies in multiple
ways. It's the same thing with a
carousel or a static image. People need
to be retained on that for 3 seconds
plus for the networks to care about it
and they will judge that in the ads. And
it's also an amazing rule in more
traditional formats as well. It's like
how do I utilize you have less time when
you're looking at a banner ad, less time
when you're on a listing for Amazon. you
get a second or two seconds max. But the
same principles apply. I need to hook
in. And so an anecdote from uh the
series I did with air recently and my
friend Jason was on there. He used to be
an art director at Amazon and when he
had done cut 30 and he was saying hey
when I learned how to make content the
biggest reveal for me as an art director
here where I work on all these client
projects every day is that my god like
if I thought of everything like hooks
immediately all the assets I'm making is
better. And this was a epiphany for him
when he was explaining it to me. It was
epiphany for me as well. And because I
think it's one thing that basically
every advertiser now comes from usually
a more traditional design background.
That's how I got started there. Or a
more traditional marketing background
and they're not creators. But if you're
a creator, even if you're just in high
school making TikToks, you and your
friends dancing, you know the importance
of a hook and you know what has to
happen in those first few seconds. And
so I cannot emphasize enough that
whether you are making something for
television, whether you're making a
print ad, whether you're making a
carousel, whatever it is, that that
first 3 seconds is the number one thing
that you need to focus on. When you
review, when you go creative reviews
with teams, whatever it is, when you
review stuff back from a creator, when
you create something, the first and most
important thing to focus on is, are
people going to stop scrolling? Is this
interesting enough? And I would do the
litmus test of pull your feet up and
pull your ad up and is it that good? But
moving into making good ads from there,
let's talk about psychology and tactics.
This is one of my favorite parts of
this, something I've never talked about
in a video that I absolutely love to
because this gets into kind of the dark
arts and the nuance of marketing. So,
first let's talk psychology tactics. We
have emotion, we have persuasion, and we
have culture. These are all ways that
you can kind of manipulate people into
doing what you want with marketing, for
lack of a better term. So, what I mean
by emotion, so first is storytelling.
The idea of a hero's journey, creating
compelling copy, I highly recommend if
you have any story you're trying to
tell, anything happened to your
business, you're trying to tell, founder
story, literally go to chatbt, put the
story in and say, can you rewrite this
with a hero's journey arc? You can
Google hero's journey and you will see
it's a formula that basically all the
most popular books in history tend to
follow. Someone has a setback and they
go through an arc that redeems
themselves and there's a payoff. If you
do that, you will begin to basically
follow a formula that works for how
people want to engage with content and
stories. And then we have humor. Humor
is a super easy thing to hook with for
content, almost too easy. Why it's too
easy is because it's very hard to
finalize. One of my favorite quotes from
traditional advertising is that people
don't buy from clowns. This is a
particularly relevant quote because
that's why you see humorous creators get
a lot less brand deals rather than be a
lot less impactful when they do get them
is because at the end of the day people
will laugh. They will hook you in, but
it doesn't necessarily make you want to
buy. There's almost every other
technique that I'm going to talk through
is going to be more impactful than
humor. But if you can hook with humor
and then reinforce with some of the
other tactics we have here, you can
begin to find a unique recipe. But
that's one of the four emotional tactics
is going to be humor. The next one is
going to be fear. And fear is the most
impactful. How do I prevent this? That
is the core idea of any fear. And you
want to tap into your consumer
psychology of I want to look bad at that
big event. I'm going to go bald before I
should. I'm never going to get a husband
or a wife. I'm going to die early.
Whatever it is. Playing those up inside
of advertising is what makes often the
most successful ads is having people
prevent the end result. And the last one
and the most intangible is aspiration.
How do you make people want to be
something better than themselves? Or how
do they basically view that buying your
product buys them into a new life? After
emotion comes persuasion. What are you
going to do within your advertisement to
actually make someone take the action
that you want? So, the first item is
social proof. Basically, showing them
through reviews or testimonials, whether
that's part of the ad or the whole
thing, the success that your product has
given them. The second one is scarcity,
saying, "This isn't going to be around
for long. This deal is going to be done
in 2 weeks. This is why the drop
marketing of fashion works so well.
You're never going to be able to get
this t-shirt again." And then we have
authority. Someone that they believe in
and love is telling them to get this
thing. This is why you see Andrew Andrew
Huberman sells so many products as he's
developed all this authority with
somebody. And then we have belonging.
Someone buying something because they
want to feel like they are a part of
something greater or a part of a
community or someone understands them.
That's emotion. That's persuasion. And
persuasion in particular plays out as a
battleground on Tik Tok shop. I would
recommend going and watching top Tik Tok
shop ads because they are using the most
core fundamental human psychology to
sell there. It is always like this deal
is not going to last for long. I can't
believe they allowed us to do this or
they will leverage as hard as they can.
And social proof is built into all of
them because you'll see the comments,
you'll see the sales numbers, but they
are immediately selling. You want to
look like this and be like this. And
then last is the cultural element of
this. There is relevancy. Basically
showing that you understand the things
your consumers understand. This is a
tactic that you have. There are through
lines or the ability for you to put
different things that are going on in
the universe around you through your
content that again show you as someone
who understands the culture or is
driving the culture in a way the
consumers respect. And then aesthetic
and just the idea of how things look,
how you present them can then tell that
you are a part of something modern or
positioning yourself as more
traditional, whatever it is. It's the
most intangible suspect of this. But
that combination of what emotions are
you playing to inside of your
advertisement? How are you persuading
somebody? And then what is your kind of
relevance to them in culture is what
makes a great advertising campaign. And
so let's get into 10 tactics to
consider. Use this to build a toolkit.
Take the ones of these you like. Use
this full list that's in the guide you
can download below. And then every time
you're going to run a campaign, think
about if you can integrate some of
these. So the first is loss aversion.
This is that people fear missing out
more than they crave improvement. So
something like most brands are wasting
30% of ad spend. Like are you kind of
selling them that hook there is
something better out there. Then we have
anchoring. This is a price psychology
tactic. It's why you see three prices a
lot where someone will set a high
reference point so that their medium or
low price thing seems to be much more
reasonable. normally $1.99 now $7.99
works not because of price but because
of the comparison between the two.
There's also what's known as the decoy
effect. It's the threepric option. A
high priced anchor mid-pric best low
price that's kind of too little and
forces people to the middle. This works
in pricing pages, ad bundles, etc. Then
we have the prat fall effect or uh the
eight mile strategy and that's that
flaws create trust whereas per
perfection repels. That's about adding
honesty to ads. Like we're not the
cheapest but we're the most durable.
things like that. And from the eight
mile tactic, it's like get that stuff
out of the way before they can say it.
Get their objections handled. And
there's the idea of visual suggestion
and semiodics. How do you shape
perception through color, texture,
fonts, etc. Like using Sarah fonts and
beige tones can imply you're more
prestige, whereas high contrast neon is
stereotype, just more experimental or
youthful. This idea of familiarity bias.
Repetition builds trust. The more we see
something, the more we believe it. This
is why I often encourage brands to kind
of repeat their taglines or their main
messages again and again until they're
tired of them across every medium you
possibly can. The more you've kind of
heard that, the more it's reinforced.
And this is something that doesn't seem
to have an effect for the first year or
two years, then really begins to add up.
And then what we'll call temporal
landmines before summer hits while
supplies last. Time pressure activates
action, especially with a seasonal or
cultural reference, and it's worth
including. Then there's behavioral
mimicry. This is a really important one
for kind of the modern era where you use
UGC your influencer videos or branded
content to basically subtly mimic your
actual audience's like real lives and
how they talk and how they work. And one
of the key ways to do this is go look up
on Tik Tok shop like or just on Tik Tok
in general real customers using your
product and your category or what your
customer does. Don't look at the videos
just about your product. Look at their
other content. How do they talk? What
words do they use? What do they do? What
are their actions like? And then you do
like a POV day in the life whatever
video and you're actually doing all the
things that the consumer does and
integrating your product. That's going
to work much better. And that's that
this mimicry technique. Once you hear
about it, you're going to start
realizing how much this is used inside
content. That's an intentional choice.
And then I'm going to end with this idea
of identity is more important than
logic. People justify with logic, but
they buy with identity. You don't just
sell the what or the why. You sell who
they will become. You don't just sell
that you're going to be able to like buy
this gym set to be get more fit. You
actually don't want to necessarily be
more fit. You want to be X type of
athlete. You want to be able to complete
a CrossFit game. You want to be able to
do whatever. So really look at that end
result from a lifestyle perspective. All
right. So now I'm going to bring in my
friend Lucas. We are going to walk
through all the different types of
digital ads as much as the key
terminology that you need to know. Let's
hit it.
[Music]
All right. Like I mentioned, I am here
with Dark Room, the performance agency
that we're doing this whole event here
at K. And I want to introduce Lucas, who
is the one of the founders of Dark Room,
uh to help educate y'all exactly on the
different types of advertising,
specifically digitally, and what you
should do for your company when. Lucas,
want to give a little background about
uh your company and journey getting
here?
>> Yeah, for sure. So, we're a a digital
commerce agency. We focus exclusively on
retail media, marketplaces as like one
section, social commerce, so Tik Tok
shop, affiliate, um a lot of the stuff
we've been talking about, and then
direct to consumer and digital
advertising. I really view those things
as like three pillars to have effective
strategies for consumer businesses
today. So, retail media, which we can
dive into, social commerce, digital
media, and there's all like a bunch of
different permutations and it is kind of
complex. So, we can we can talk about
it.
>> And so, Lucas is deep in it. What kind
of clients do you work with? Uh any kind
of particular projects you want to shout
out, give people some context.
>> Yeah. So, I mean, we work with leading
consumer brands. So any mid-market
business that is in a consumer category
that's selling on TTOC, Amazon, other
marketplaces at retail, like that's our
sweet spot. We really specialize on the
businesses that are like between 5 and
$150 million in revenue. So these are
challenger brands that are growing fast
and we help hypers scale them. Um we've
worked with I mean hundreds of brands at
this point uh at this point. A couple of
my callouts though I have them right
here. Burton, Garrett Light, Necessary,
Lollipop, Dead Cool. We did a video on
DeadCool. Um, but it's really like
brands that have high consumability and
that's the traditional CPG type play
layers.
>> Perfect. And so I think uh diving a bit
into this, we talk a lot about the
content funnel and the advertising
funnel is a similar thing. You basically
want to choose to advertise for
different layers of your business in
different places. Want to give a little
breakdown of like what that funnel means
and how you think about it when you're
putting that together for a brand?
>> Yeah, I think it's really dependent like
if you're a brand owner and a founder,
you need to contextualize where you're
at in your life cycle. So, like, are you
just starting out and like your
advertising dollars are super precious?
You're probably going to be spending a
lot more money on the bottom of funnel.
You want to focus on conversion. We do
visualize the entire funnel though, just
to make things easier. This is like
marketing 101. So, you have upper
funnel, midfunnel, bottom of funnel, or
top of funnel, tofu, midfunnel, mofu,
fu. Like those are the acronyms that
people usually use in
>> definitely drop tofu in as many meetings
as you can just to you know
>> if you're not throwing acronyms out
there like are you even a marketer
that's what you need to be asking
yourself for for me it's really a
question of like what type of business
are you and like what sales channels are
you on that's going to dictate where you
should be investing advertising dollars.
The sales channels that exist from a
high level are for most CPG companies,
Amazon, DTOC, and retail. And then
within Amazon, like there are other
marketplaces that are kind of offshoot.
So you have Walmart, you have Target. I
think this is going to be a huge trend
that starts to evolve like other 3P
marketplaces, meaning the brands selling
their product.
>> Yeah. So what's the acronym 3P mean for
the people?
>> Yeah. So 3P is like I'm basically a
third party seller on Amazon. Uh they're
buying that product on Amazon, but it's
coming coming from me. It might be
facilitated through Amazon's warehouse,
but that's 3P. 1 P is uh the retailer
like Amazon or Walmart. They're buying
product directly from me in a PO. Yeah.
>> And that is housed and and it's their
inventory that they have margin on and
they get to sell.
>> And you're helping promote that through
ads on their platform.
>> Yeah. And there's a whole bunch of
nuances to how you should do one P or
3P. We could do a whole video on that.
But
>> yeah, I think we we'll stick to probably
some of the more like digital the things
people should really kind of learn and
focus on to start. Let's double click on
Amazon uh real quick. If you are looking
at the funnel and you're trying to
generate business on Amazon uh and you
don't know what any of these things are
kind of what should you start? What are
those core advertising types on Amazon?
>> Yeah. So I I think of Amazon it's like
your it's like Shopify and Google had a
baby together, right? So you can have a
branded experience on there. You have
your own Amazon storefront. Looks like a
DTOC site these days. You list all your
products on there but you benefit from
having all of the search uh query and
intent being directly on platform. So, a
platform where people buy. There is a
high conversion rate on there compared
to anything else in the world.
>> 63% of purchases start on Amazon. Um,
63% of ecom is is happening on on on
Amazon.
>> This is something I call out all the
time to brands who don't want to be on
Amazon or intimidated by Amazon. It's
like, hey, your consumer, if they're
seeing you on TikTok or Instagram, 63%
of them aren't actually going to go
search that website, right? They're
going to start searching on Amazon to
start. And if you're not present there,
what is the experience? Who's then
owning that sale? Maybe they go take the
second step, but probably not. And so,
especially as you start to get real
traffic, knowing and owning this is a
huge step of any brand journey.
>> Yeah. I think if you're a consumable,
like you need to be on Amazon full stop.
Like that's where people buy grocery.
That's where they're buying CPG,
skincare. The only product category
that's really difficult still is
apparel. But that's, you know, I speak
to Amazon and their team pretty
consistently on the emerging brand side.
They have such big internal benchmarks
for getting
>> and they started to add in like they
have a whole new luxury section with
like Oscar Dearenta. They're working
hard to try and prioritize that. And
it's always good to lean into a bit of
what the platform is prioritizing so you
get some incentives etc. Let's go into
ads. Like what are the ad types on
Amazon? If you're just getting started,
you want to do some bottle of funnel
advertising. Where does that where does
that?
>> Yeah. So, okay. So, brands that start
out, Amazon is a very robust advertising
ecosystem. So, you have your top
offunnel placements with DSP, which
we'll get to, and Amazon Marketing
Cloud. But if you're a brand that's just
starting out, you're going to be living
in the traditional uh search intent type
placements. So sponsored product
advertisement, sponsored brand,
basically indexing for users who are
searching for the type of product that
you offer or tapping into the uh the
search intent and the brand the demand
generation that you're doing off
platform. So if you're doing organic
social on Tik Tok and you're really
growing demand for your business and
people all of a sudden start searching
for your brand on Amazon, you want to be
showing up there from an organic
perspective and you probably want to be
bidding on some of those terms. That's
unfortunately just like Google. we call
it an Amazon tax, but you want to make
sure you're winning the bid and
sometimes you'll have competitors
winning on your bid if you're doing
something right off platform.
>> And so the format with which you're able
to do that is basically like you're able
to show a sponsored listing just has
your listing highlighted or there's like
banner ads that appear at the top
basically. Any kind of tips or uh things
on making sure you're like making the
most of that small real estate when you
actually get to use it. Yeah, I honestly
think like leaning into video, which is
like what we talk about on a lot of a
lot of the the the advertising formats
today, is really important. But for new
brands, I think you want to lean into
storytelling on Amazon in short form
ways. I don't mean like someone a
founder talking on screen describing the
product like we're using little clips
that are highly branded that kind of
demonstrate why you should buy, you
know,
>> you're calling out some top selling
points. You're basically doing the
basics of your positioning.
>> Yeah. I'll show you. So, for one of our
brands, saws, you know, one of the
different placements that we use. So,
this asset right here in the beginning,
it's like showing the making of a
chicken parm. Um, and it's showing the
product and how it's getting made. Like,
this would be a sponsored video ad that
you would run as a banner placement when
someone searches pasta sauce, for
instance. And this has this asset right
here has incredibly high performance.
And this is for a brand new brand to
platform. So, they're competing against
Carbone or Ryos, but we're trying to
tell our unique story through making
pasta or chicken parm or pizza product
in action. Yeah,
>> most Amazon businesses if they've been
running it for a long time, they're not
leaning into creative.
>> And that's where the opportunity is for
advertisers being like, "Hey, you're
competing against incumbents who are
kind of used to their mix. If you're
doing something new and exciting, you
get to you get to leverage."
>> That's the name of the game with all
advertising. I would just say like your
brand starting out on Amazon, you want
to be as close to the bottom of funnel
as possible. So, you're bidding on
keywords that really matter for people
who are searching for your product and
want to buy it.
>> Let's move that all the way to the top
of funnel. If I'm a big brand, I've been
doing this a little bit on Amazon. We
know it's a growth channel for us. We
want to really go generate awareness.
All right. And we're not going to get
super dive deep into attribution and
things. This video is a little more
focused on the ads themselves. But I do
want to then just kind of lean over into
one of the other segments you talked
about. Let's talk about Google and
YouTube and their properties and kind of
where they live in your funnel and what
are some of those kind of same way we
talked about DSP or like the Amazon, you
know, search ads. What's worth knowing
for young marketers out there?
>> Yeah. So, I think the traditional
playbook with DDC businesses has been
like you have your meta Google split.
Meta is demand genen and it's direct
response. You're targeting customers
through that to drive demand for your B
TOC business. And then Google is
capturing a lot of
>> intent based targeting, people that are
already moving towards either your
category or your product.
>> Yeah. And it depends on the type of
product you have. If you have something
that's super utilitarian, it's solving a
need that people have and they search
for pretty consistently. Google's going
to be your bread and butter. I have a
lot of clients that were starting out.
Most of their budget was in Google
because they're just capturing that
there's a niche. There's a rift in the
market and they're able to win the bid
and they're able to win the sale and
they're driving demand that way, too.
And there's something I like to talk
about a lot when it comes to choosing
what ad platforms to run is that you
have to decide if you're basically like
interrupting or intercepting. And so
Google is like an intercepting platform
to me. This means that someone is either
looking for your category, they're
trying to buy a knife and you are a
knife brand or they are trying to buy
your brand and you are concerned about
whether you're going to show up close
enough to that sale to be able to
intercept it organically that you then
want to spend that money on. If there is
a large amount of demand there, this is
a great platform to be able to build out
some pretty straightforward economics
and you'll kind of be able to hit some
some natural scale points. But there's
also some like non-arch there too.
There's like Pmax and things like that.
What what are your your views on those
platforms and where do they fit in that
marketing funnel?
>> Yeah, there's Pmax. You know, obviously
like Google Shopping is a huge part of
the equation. There's YouTube as well,
like talking about TopFunnel. YouTube
has been crushing it for our brands,
especially when you run the MM um and
you see some of the credit.
>> Not to be confused with MLM. We're not
running the MLM on this video. You know,
I'm sure
>> the next thing I think that's going to
be really big in the Google ecosystem as
Gemini becomes more uh established is
Genai Ads, which honestly like
>> does that exist already? I haven't tried
that.
>> It does, but let me let me show you. So,
>> and while we're going before we hit geni
ads, what's pmax?
>> So, pmax is a it's it's really similar
to advantage plus or dynamic bids on
Amazon. It's Google's AI offering to
better target audiences and please
>> with everything on their network. And
this means anyone who has Google ads
installed on their sites. This means
every advertiser that they have any
level of partnership with when you see
one of those like banner ads will search
ads on the side. Basically, you can get
you can buy those through like kind of
standard systems or you can say let
Google buy these for me through PMAX.
Correct.
>> Yeah. And Google also has a it's very
similar to Amazon DSP. They have their
their network of publishers that it's
just a very robust ecosystem. So, you're
basically tapping in and this is where
media buying is going like the platforms
are moving to a place where everything
is a lot more automated. They know who
your audience is. They know who you
should be targeting. they know what type
of ad format's going to perform best.
And so you're basically saying, "Hey, go
out and do your work and and and drive
conversions for me." And all these
platforms are saying that's where things
are going. The only caveat if you're
starting off though and you know what
bids and and what placements you should
be buying, go manual to start. We always
do this for our Amazon and Google
clients because there's no data to go
off of if you're just starting out.
>> Yeah. And also, I just have never um had
amazing experience with PMAX through and
through. I've I've spent a absolute boat
ton of money on YouTube ads that has
gone uh extremely well. But yeah, so
just putting out there with a grain of
salt. These things all exist, but
they're all particular scenarios and
some of them I think go better than
others. Let's talk about Gen AI ads. Um
I know nothing about those so curious to
hear what you have to say. Let's let's
take a step back. So Gen AI ads would
be, you know, obviously LLMs are a
really big thing today like Yeah. Chat
GBT, Gemini. Yeah, exactly. There's a
whole bunch of publishers actually and
derivatives of chat GBT that are
basically just chat bops for for certain
audiences. The thing that I'm pushing
and advising our brands on is there is
an entire AI marketing funnel where
people are discovering and buying
products that's fully insulated from all
of the traditional media that's going on
and being spent through brand marketing
and performance marketing.
>> And you'll probably I curious about this
from your perspective. Are you ever
going to see like a banner ad or you
know Yeah. inside that?
>> It's happening right now. So there's two
types of formats right now. This doesn't
exist in chat GPT yet because they're
really focused on just like building the
best experience. They have hired
advertising execs, but I think it's just
like down the road map for them. But you
have other types of LLMs and and chatbot
interfaces. There's something called
liner for students that has, you know,
tens of millions of users. And there
these
>> So if you're trying to hit 18 to 21, you
should go smash that. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Basically, so these are
the these are some of the stats. There's
two two platforms I use that I'll call
out here. I use KA for Genai uh
placements like the banner placements
and then I use context for in feed in
response type hyperlink responses which
I'll show you an example of two. They
have a ton of ad advertising inventory.
I'll give you a couple stats. 2x higher
CTR verse Google, 6x clicked conversions
verse Google, 7% average clickthrough
rate, 3x longer engagement period than
traditional search,
>> which is [ __ ] mindboggling. But what
are they charging? You know what I Is uh
is it worth it economically too?
>> Yes, let's go.
>> CPMs are great. Uh it's a CPC based
model. Well, this we're always when
you're in this, you're always looking
for like what's the alpha. I talk a lot
about Tik Tok shops. There's a massive
amount of alpha still there, but then
you're super deep on every single
channel that you could buy on.
Everyone's always being like what is
being underserved? What are people under
buying on? Cuz then the CPMs are still
low. Like I when I first started really
getting money in my life is when the
Facebook CPMs were extremely small,
right? And you're like this is an
amazing period of life. And gradually
and gradually now we're paying $3 for a
click to go to a landing page, you know?
And I think what what you're on a macro
level, what you're seeing is traditional
paid media, people just like trust it
less. You get hit with an ad on
Instagram, you're like, I don't want to
be pushed product. Same thing with
search, like you have all these you you
kind of people understand the game.
Whereas I think with LLMs, like you
trust the responses you're getting. You
trust it. It's like there,
>> but you build this rapport with it that
we're we're still it's going to be years
of unpacking that to get somewhere. So
the Gen AI ad platforms right now,
they're working really hard to make sure
that the placements they're giving are
highly contextually relevant. So if I'm
searching and I'm like, I have dry skin
and like really bad rosacea or whatever,
like
>> Sarah,
>> exactly his uh his brand partnership
right there.
>> Shout out the gods. And so with that,
how do you how do you create a good ad
for Gen AI? Like you're on the edge of
this. Any best practices? Any things to
think about if you are a marketer being
like, I don't want to mess up this
platform? I think there's a ton of alpha
here if you're just starting out because
I I listen I pitched Aloe Yoga. I just
pitched Unilever. They're like
interesting but we're just going to keep
spending in Google and Meta.
>> And that is that's the that's the alpha.
That right there is where you get your
money.
>> That's the alpha. So for some of these
platforms, the way that these are
getting administered, they're not like
really self-s served yet like fully.
It's like in those early days where it's
like an Excel sheet and you're talking
about you're saying, "Hey, these are the
audiences I want to target. These are
the exact type of needs that I have and
the platforms are going out there and
they're delivering on that. These
platforms are raising a shitload of
money though. They're raising so much in
venture. That's actually how I'm finding
out about a lot of these. The VCs are
introducing us directly. There are
certain audiences that are great. So
within context, for instance, there's a
really strong mom audience. Gaming
audience is really big. Skincare
education. We talked about
>> wrapping up Google walking into YouTube.
the success I've had on YouTube with
ads. We've done some really direct
response related stuff. We basically do
VSSLs on YouTube. I even when we were
doing toy stuff, it was literally a VSSL
which is just like a video sales letter.
It's like, hey, we're going to go walk
through the journey of like what is the
problem, agitate the problem, present
the solution, back up the solution, like
do it because you have like a full
length of video to do it. If you hook
people past those first two seconds, you
get a long time to be able to pitch them
something. That's been a format that's
been successful for me, but I know a lot
of people also optimize for really short
ads, do a whole bunch of things. Where
would you start with buying on YouTube?
Any terminology, advice, strategy?
>> I honestly think it's it's really
dependent on the product. I love YouTube
as like a It depends on the category
really, but I do like it as a top
ofunnel placement for consumer
businesses. If you have something
visual, like a product, like I I want to
be on YouTube. I like it. The targeting
capability is very robust. It's also
good to cross over to retail. We did a
very big campaign supporting a target
launch where we basically were looking
at all of our data be like, "Yo, YouTube
is the only really like attributable
thing we saw lift to." We just hammered
YouTube as like probably half of that
launch support campaign. It worked
really well.
>> And then I also think if you have
something either educational or direct
response probably like the stuff what
were the ads that you were running?
>> Yeah, we were running stuff for gelb
blaster but it was very much like we
just chose the VSSL style. We were
comparing like sizzle real style ad to
like typical product spot to we had then
we had a founder story and then we had a
VSSL and founder story and the VSSL
crushed for us on there.
>> Yeah, if you can master like traditional
long form direct response VSSL like that
format can be successful in so many
different places. I also run that on
meta with a UGC hook and then I just run
into the full infomercial or VSSL.
>> That's what all this is. Yeah. And this
that's like the trick basically I feel
like on all these platforms is like hook
whatever it doesn't matter. You can do
you can do viral hook, you can do UGC
hook, whatever it is go into this
traditional sales format as soon as you
if they're staying to watch that video
and you've you've run that like they're
going to follow that flow. That flow is
based on like consumer psychology. Yeah.
And I think there's this because of the
advent of like short form social and
meta advertising, people were like, "No,
it needs to be a 15-second ad." But like
that's just not true. If you can engage
someone and they're interested in the
video, they'll watch the entire thing
and those people will buy. And if even
if they watch the 14 seconds, but click
through, all you matters is the
clickthrough, you know, where whether
they do it at second three or second 15
or at the end of the 90, like it's just
getting them that next that next level.
Getting into Tik Tok, this is a fun one.
And Tik Tok, I will just disqualify
first of like do not like run any
polished quality ads like on Tik Tok.
There's I've seen one or two of them
work, but like it's that native feeling.
It's that exact like it would look on a
short form video. Lwood is an amazing
example of this. You are a male watching
this video, you've probably been served
Lwood ads on Tik Tok where they
literally just make it look like any
video you would see, whether it's like a
fit check or a style or it was put on.
They run them constantly. They spark all
their organic posts. It works really
well as an advertising strategy. And
then it's all just based exactly like it
is on short form where like the hook is
super important, the payoff is
important, but you're a little more
focused on the CTA in terms of the copy.
breakdown if you want to start working
on on Tik Tok ads on shop versus not on
shop. What's what's some of your your
thoughts?
>> I honestly think like Tik Tok is is an
ecosystem very similar to I honestly
think it's very similar to Amazon
>> cuz it's a search platform.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Amazon and uh Instagram together.
I think Tik Tok I mean we we talked
about this. Tik Tok is where you are
like building community and brand
especially if you're a consumer business
today. I think in some luxury categories
it's really like it's tough still.
Again, if you're consumable, if you're
if you're in beverage, if you're in
supplements, if you're in cosmetics,
like you can really hit there. We do Tik
Tok shop. We also run Tik Tok ads. I
think you know there's a couple of
different types of ad formats.
>> So we have Spark, we have GMD Max. I'll
hit Spark real quick and we talk about
GMD Max. And so Spark has where you take
an existing video. So I've done this. A
lot of people will spark my content on
there. They'll be like, "Hey, give them
an ad code. They run the ad comes from
my account, but whenever they click it
or go to view it, actually just leads to
the landing page." that can be on a Tik
Tok product. So for on Tik Tok shop, so
you can actually be going directly to
buy on the listing or that can be to a
third party landing page as an extremely
successful format. Usually it basically
caps out what I've seen is we'll run it
run it for a couple weeks installation
returns and goes. But you can really
have a very timely nature. If you're
loading in a lot of creative into Spark,
it works well. You're basically
advertising through others. But if you
want to get more robust and do something
like GMV Max, what does that look like?
>> Yeah. So GMBB Max is an ad format and
it's like basically like a type of bid
that you're running for it's for Tik Tok
shop. So with GMV Max you set an ROI
target and it takes into account your
organic sales and your rorowaz from paid
sales and it's basically kind of like
trying to optimize for what your GMV
threshold is for the entire
>> and so it brings so just across real
quick. Rowass return on ad spend GMV is
just basically the revenue value
generated
>> gross merchandise value on platform. We
use GMV for for marketplaces really. So
you're going to use it for Amazon,
you'll use it for Tik Tok shop. Tik Tok
shop though, you need to go, you know,
it's a tough thing to to operationalize.
You need volume, you need content, you
need branded content, and you need to
build community. So it is a is a
extremely the flywheel takes a lot to
get spinning. But then once it's
spinning, it is just an absolute [ __ ]
machine. But yeah, probably not the
first thing on the list where people are
going to go after if you're like
learning this for the first time. But
definitely when we look at those areas
of alpha, one of the biggest ones if
you're willing to go get that. We're
recruiting creators and we're training
creators. And then we are managing what
this you know how the creators actually
interact and we're seeing them and doing
our bundles and managing our platform.
Then we're briefing and feedbacking and
turning it into this big flywheel and
we're trying to get thousand plus videos
a month from affiliates. It's it's an
amazing place to be because all that
natural money that comes from what
they're generating with their organic
content, there's 100% alpha and just
sparking as much of that as you can
putting that and out of your organic
content into these kind of more robust
bidding campaigns and like really
building uh something unique there.
>> So when we do shop, we think about shop
management. This is like the technical
operation side of things. So that's like
your traditional Amazon ops like you
know integration, inventory management,
discounting, all the other promotions,
shop hygiene, etc. etc. Then you have
creative flywheel basically that
affiliate pipeline that you were talking
about where it's volume and it's also
making sure you're working with the
right people, ad management, spark, GMV
Max, so on and so forth. I think this is
going to become very automated in the
future. And then live shopping. I mean,
I'd honestly love to get your take on
live shopping. Like, uh I So, it's
actually interesting. So, I think we had
talked about earlier. I was actually at
like a live shopping, what's the right
word? Like, not a dungeons was a really
nice area, but like a live shopping
megaplex in LA where they actually had a
bunch of rooms. They're all selling
luxury, vintage, and they had like eight
or 10 creators on live at any time, all
on their own account selling live,
generating a lot of money. The live
shopping is one of those where like it's
definitely the fringe. It's huge in
China. It's a successful additional part
of a already existing Tik Tok strategy.
I don't think it's a strategy by itself
to launch on it and it's great for some
certain demographics. So, I think some
of the top uh live shopping experiences
right now, at least in the categories I
look at are in Spanish. There's some
alpha in in that and like who buys in
that way. And there's also this the idea
that if you host it as an event, you
build them up, you make it a recurring
thing. The way uh goalie did this really
well or you have like, hey, my holiday
promotions, we're going to cap it off
with a big live with other influencers.
We're going to bring it in. It's like
useful as a basically like a tentpole
part of a existing campaign strategy or
as something once you've already got
your shop dialed and you want to elevate
it, but it requires being live like a
lot like hours and hours. A good Tik Tok
shop live is 4 hours, 6 hours, 8 hours.
It's not like we pop on for an hour and
try to sell. I don't think the America
is going to be like a full copy paste of
like what's going on in China in terms
of how live manifests and and grows. But
I was uh on the phone with you know one
of the head of Tik Tok shop in in hair
care and you know they're doing a
million-dollar GMV live sessions over 4
hours now. So that's that's great. You
know it's proof of concept. It's
working. Um and I think it's going to be
a big part of the equation. I'm curious
though in your world in creative in
creators and the creator economy. Like
there's like so many different there's
like a spectrum here, right? It's like
you've got hosts who are doing live and
they're like almost sales people and
then you have like pure creators.
>> Well and it's interesting. I've I go
live on Tik Tok. Tik Tok, one of the
alpha points as a creator is if you have
a video ripping on Tik Tok and you go
live, it pumps that video. So, I went
live Friday at the airport. I had this
product versus brand headphones video
ripping. It was at like 600K. By the
time I got off the live, like 35 minutes
later, it was like 750. Like, they will
rip your ripping video to promote the
fact you're live because it has that
circle on it. So, that's like a bit of
creator alpha. And then also, you get
people to approach you as hosts. So,
I've had that a few times. I was
actually talking to that bag company
just cuz I'm curious. I was like, "Hey,
can I do a 4-hour live? What kind of
sales would I generate?"
>> I could you could sell so much. Uh, and
so but I think we're going to try and
give that a shot and be like just out of
pure curiosity. And I'm like cool. I
would 100% look at if there's a brand I
believe in or we can have some fun with
it like be a host because you'll notice
like these lives that went really well
for goalies like Kevin Hart shows up and
like people are doing skits and I feel
like if we had all the personalities
that were in this house and we were all
live right now and like had the big
bingo wheel and like people were were
taking shots every time you did a
thousand. We could sell a lot of product
and have a good time.
>> You need a producer.
>> I couldn't switch products. I was trying
to move the thing. It was just too
frustrating. I was like
>> that's that's what we're doing. I plan I
think we're going to do HQ in New York
live stream studios multiple of them
close to Tik Tok shop HQ and we'll just
continue to reskin those studios for
different brands bring different people
in but I do think for creators like
there's a lot of different ways to
monetize now like you could go and get
good at direct response sales and sales
psychology and you could be a host for
skincare and you can get paid
>> if you are a creator and you are not
like really getting money that is a
you're in your own head you could be
running live you could be doing Tik Tok
shop you should be getting these brand
deals people are just kind of wondering
Why is this money coming to me? And it's
like the money is there for you to take.
>> I'm like considering hiring creators
full-time to do live shopping. Yeah.
Like
>> which is what this is what these so the
people at this luxury bag company,
they're like salaried employees and they
get us small commission and they're
selling like $600 700 stuff and they
have targets and stuff to hit, but they
get that hey I get to come in here and
they all have their own social and it
was an interesting operation to see
happening at scale where I was like oh
they have we could go on their thing
right now and they probably have seven
or eight people live. Meta ads the most
important one probably but also I think
one of the easier ones to explain. Do
you just run all the creative into ASC
and just call it a day or what's the
strategy there?
>> We definitely leverage ASC, but I think
there's so many different ways that we
structure campaign types and like try
and keep uh account hygiene really.
>> So if you nothing you're starting this
for the first time and you're like, hey,
I'm going to go set up a go set up some
campaigns. Like what do you need to
know?
>> I I start with the foundations of like
what is my salesunnel? So like what type
of product and what is the CPA that I
need on that product to have be first
>> purchase. Exact. That's Yeah. So that's
what does it if I kind of in $16 if
someone buys that product do I make
money on the other side or $30 you
basically get to this number what that
looks like and then you know you
structure your campaign types around
that with multiple creative formats
within those campaign types and you can
have all different types of creative
formats within that you have short form
videos you have uh DPA you have um
different types of stats
>> that's actually good we can cover this
so I have this whole section in this
video where we talk through the
different formats like here's a UC ad
here's a standard ad here's 3D here's
what AI looks like we did not talk about
DPA, dynamic product ads, which is
basically saying, uh, hey, let's take
your catalog of what you have in
Shopify, all the products you have, and
let's basically show you those graphics
with like light info on it. And then
there are some services like Marpipe and
a few others, I don't know what you guys
use, that will then like layer some
existing, more exciting graphics on top
of that. And I think the challenge with
Meta once you get into that space is
like they have a pretty robust dashboard
where you're looking at lastclick
attribution and different type of
attribution sources in platform. I know
this video isn't about attribution, but
really the things that I focus on when
we're looking at meta campaigns and meta
performance is we look for hold rate,
clickthrough rate, thumb stop ratio on
particular ads to know what the
throughput is and if the creatives are
performing. Last click attribution is
very hazy because of the tracking
transparency, privacy restrictions that
happened. That's why we leverage tools
like MM. It's very if you're a small
brand, you're only running meta, this is
a very it's pretty easy. As soon as you
start getting into a world of multiple
things running at once, it's it's a it's
an item. But I would say for most
businesses like if you're in fashion
like your statics, DPAs, carousels,
those are going to perform really well.
But don't discourage like you need video
assets. It can be iPhone assets too and
you should you should run those in your
campaign. ASC and non-ASC campaigns and
give the real quick what do you have and
why
>> very close to I would say Pmax in that
you know Meta is going to go out and
you're you're not going to be targeting
particular audiences. It's going to go
out and serve the ad and find the right
audience for your product and it's going
to leverage signal on the advertising
format to determine that and basically
the machine learning algorithm will will
work for you and learn and get better.
That's opposed to doing manual bidding
on the on the meta side.
>> Any other recommendations or things you
absolutely want to know if you are like
really diving into ads making great
creative?
>> I would say like for me the what what
I'm seeing is like creative is really
the big lever that brands have today.
Like if you're a new brand starting,
focus on that. And you know, a lot of
these brands make a lot of these
platforms are very easy to start
self-service in. So don't feel the need
to hire an agency for that type of
stuff. Like I think it's really
important for entrepreneurs to to start
so they can learn like what's good,
what's not good, the terminology, and so
on and so forth. It's a good start
watching uh Orin's videos and this type
of content, but don't get discouraged
with all the acronyms. Like go out and
try these things.
>> All right, so fresh off that, let's go
through types of ads. So your biggest
job as someone who's in advertising is
to make a master list of types of ads.
Again, I will include this list in the
link I have down below. But when you
have this big list, you're basically
going to have a checklist. Every time
you do a campaign, every time you do a
launch, you can go through and be like,
is this type of ad relevant for what I
want to do? Because performance right
now is a game of volume. The more ads
you load into meta, the better your
campaigns do. The more organic posts you
do, the better your organic is going to
do. And so, the more references you have
that are creatable, the more things you
can brief becomes a weapon. So, we're
going to walk through 10 that I think
everyone should have in their toolkit.
The first is the problem solution app
where you lead with the problem people
are having and then present your product
as the solution. This can be done in
more normal ways or in more conceptual
ways. One of my favorite examples of
this is the Snickers bar. You're not you
when you're hungry where they're showing
somebody being a gorilla or whatever it
is and then they have the Snickers and
they're back to normal. It's a good
example of a problem solution. And
second is the founder story ad. I have
run a lot of founder story ads. I took
founder story ads into movie theater
placements into streaming. Tested them
through Meta and YouTube. I've run a lot
of money in founder ads. Dollar Shave
Club being the ultimate example of this.
But basically, how do you tell an
interesting more produced version of why
someone started something? And again,
going back to that hero's journey idea,
how can you have that founder story
follow that hero's journey of something
epic happened? They had to kind of
resolve it and find a solution. Their
arc comes all the way back up. This
especially works if it's a story that
resonates to the customer. The biggest
founder ad I won was uh I ran was with a
couple who was a founder who created a
product for kids because of experience
with their kids. And since their
demographic matched the aspiration of
the parents who were buying their
product, the ad crushed. Then we have
the reaction testimonial where someone
actually tries something out and then
they respond to it. It's a classic UGC
format, but works really, really well,
especially if you can see actively the
before and after. Then we have the
listical or like five reasons or three
reasons. And this doesn't have to be
about your product. It needs to be about
the goal that they achieve, right? Like
the five things I'm doing to improve my
weight loss or whatever and your
supplement is one of them or the five
things you're doing to become a better
creator. and your microphone is one of
them. But making that kind of listical
format, whether it's written or whether
it's in video, is a great ad type. And
one of my favorites, justification of a
selfish desire. This is a killer format.
If you can find it, the best example of
this is the PC Philippe ads where it
says, uh, you don't really own a PC
Philippe. You merely hold on to it for
the next generation. And it's like dads
with their kids. All this is doing is
just justifying you buying a PC Philippe
by saying it's a present for your kid.
Right? We all know that the PC Philippe
is not for the kid, it's for the dad.
And if you can find that same way to
look at it, whether that's treating as a
little treat or you deserve this or
you're actually buying this for someone
else or it holds its share of resale
value is a such a winning format. Then
there's before and after prove it ads I
like to call it where it's like here's
exactly what we like before and here's
what it's like after and just showing
that contrast or you can just go
straight to prove it. Shot on iPhone is
one of the best prove it campaigns where
you'll see a billboard says shot on
iPhone. You're like that is a photo that
was shot there blown up at the size and
it's wonderful. They are literally
proving it without even having to show
the before. Another great one for this
is the legendary Blendec will it blend
where the owner of the blender would
basically throw random stuff inside the
blender to see if it would work and the
more crazy and aggressive it was and as
basically him being proving it on the
product. I'm going to literally prove in
front of you that this does what I say
it does. And if you can do that, whether
it's showing the camera result or
showing if it blends as a massively
impactful thing in the shortest amount
of time possible, how do you in 10
seconds prove your value proposition?
And obviously the will blend has that
element of being really interesting and
aesthetic at the same time. If you can
uh build something like that, you've got
a winner. And there's the POV ad,
presenting the lifestyle of your
customer in an aspirational state. This
is what the life is like with your
product integrated. The transformation
arc or the walking through all the steps
it takes to achieve a desired result.
The expert breakdowns is another great
one where you take someone either
someone in your company that's super
smart and knowledgeable. If you have a
science officer or a founder really
knows their [ __ ] or if you get an
influencer to do this. I do this a lot
for launches for other brands. When you
see my sponsored content, they want
someone from a marketing perspective to
be like, "Here's why this thing is so
good." So, there's an expert breakdown
of it. Then there's a remix reply ad,
another great one for the modern world,
where you basically take a top question
you're getting, put it up with one of
those question graphics, looks like a
Tik Tok comment or Instagram comment,
and respond to it with a video. That is
a excellent just kind of let's take a
really common painoint and solve it.
It's a good ad format. And then last,
we're going to talk about the contrarian
hottake. This is a great talking yapping
format. You just want someone yapping at
the camera where you're going to say
something that people would find often
incorrect. They may argue in the
comments, but it takes a position of
your product. A good example of this is
we had a guy in Cut 30 who had a
fiberbased product and he was basically
like unpopular opinion. You shouldn't be
caring about ingesting all this protein.
You should care about ingesting fiber.
Got a lot of comments cuz people were
obviously all love protein right now and
fiber is kind of an enemy. But he was
able to really eloquently make his point
and then build into that. Same thing as
another cut 30 person who had had about
being like 90% of women are wearing the
wrong bra size and then kind of getting
into some of the conversation from there
but then showing like how you actually
help solve that with a product like
hers. But that is the beginning of the
toolkit. Every time you see an ad from
now on, part of your homework here, I
want you to think about what kind of ad
is it, like especially if it's good. A
lot of ads are bad, but if you see an ad
that's good, be like, "All right, does
it fit in one of these formats?" And if
not, jot it down and make a name for it.
Because I've named created most of these
myself, just as I build my toolkit, and
now you have another thing on your list,
and you'll start to notice the more you
have on this list, and the more often
every time you're doing a campaign or
every time you need to put in new
assets, you can just roll through this
list and be like, "Oh, let's let's do a
POV ad. Let's do an unpopular opinion.
Oh, I we have an expert that we can use
to talk about this." and it's going to
make your life so much easier.
[Music]
That was a whole bunch of ad types you
can use for your business. I want to
have take a second to talk about direct
response. It's a big enough ad type and
it's big enough idea to take it's
warrants it whole section inside this
video. And this is a school of thought
for a certain type of marketer. It's
really sales and conversion focused.
It's worth having in your toolkit. I'm
just going to break down some of the
rules for how I view direct response and
what I've kind of read and utilized
about it that you can look at in your
toolkit. So the first note when you
think about direct response, this is a
sales effort. This is sales focused
marketing. It's done in copy and it's
done in videos. If it doesn't produce a
measurable response, then it's not
marketing, it's art. That's like a core
of this is if it's not going for a sale,
here's how many sales I got from this
that this is not belong in direct
response. And they really focus on the
offer, not the branding. Branding
doesn't matter here. It's about the
product. Branding is a byproduct. Might
be helpful, but it's not the goal. The
offer there is front and center.
Discounts, bundles, bonuses, deadlines.
That is what makes this perform. Not
worried about vibes or looks at all. You
are focused on what you are selling and
communicating it. In direct response,
the rules always include a strong call
to action. You tell the customer exactly
what to do next. Don't just imply it.
Call now. Order today. Claim your free
gift. Ambiguity kills conversion. This
this works. And they build this out in a
structure, and that structure matters.
Headline, sub headline, offer, poof, the
offer works, call to action. It's the
most simple version. There's expanded
versions, too. And then scarcity and
urgency work. People delay actions
unless they're pushed. And you have to
in your ad basically act as the sales
rep on the phone trying to get you to
make a decision today and not call your
wife. Deadlines, limited quantities,
expiring bonuses, calling out people on
their procrastination. These are
essential tools inside of that
advertising. And then repetition,
sticking with that message, having your
we'll talk about message match in this
in the last section I do here, but this
idea that the more you say the thing,
the more you reinforce it, the better it
goes. And that repetition, especially if
you know you have a winning message, is
more important than creativity and
testing lots of messages. And then we
have positioning yourself as a trusted
expert. That's a huge part of direct
response. The person talking has to be
credible. And the more credible you are,
the easier the process goes. But Dan
Kennedy has this thing. I think it's
called magnetic marketing. Basically, it
becomes so credible and useful that
leads come to you basically pre-sold. I
look at this as Huberman selling for
AG1. Anyone is who is a fan of him has
pre-sold whatever he's going to sell
you. And that's your job as a founder or
as a person finding a spokesperson for
the brand to become that magnetic. If I
was selling you a book on marketing and
you've watched a hundred of these videos
I've given you for free, you would be
pre-sold and being like, I believe what
this guy says. I would love to get this
in book format. That's a key part of
direct response is if you're if you're
missing that, you need to engineer it or
pay for it. And then last is never be
boring. If the copy feels like a
corporate press release or a brochure,
it is dead on arrival. Entertaining,
provoking, shocking, whatever it takes
to keep them reading is the goal versus
just filling it out. If you combine
those elements together, you have this
kind of idea of direct response. It's
presented inside a VSSL or a video sales
letter where someone is literally
selling through this on a video like
this or the same thing as copy on a
lander. Get to our next phase, the last
part of this. Landing pages and funnels.
I'll touch on this briefly. It's not the
point of this video, but it matters a
lot cuz you can make the most amazing
ad. If they go to a landing experience
that doesn't work, then basically you're
going to lose the efficacy of this thing
you made because where they're going
isn't built to convert. So, a couple
quick notes on that. Landing pages where
ads die or thrive. There's a couple key
concepts. Message match. That is the
message in your ad should match what's
on your landing page. means you need a
bunch of variants of your landing page
or to incorporate it. But if you have a
core big thing called out as your main
value prop, that better also be on the
page they go to to go convert. Then we
have social proof. Again, this is
actually reinforcing not just with
reviews but also with like videos or
them seeing real people testimonials as
to why this was efficacy right there
where they are to convert. Same thing
with reviews and then questions. Always
having those questions on there to
actually answer any of the objections
they have. Go through every objection,
list out every objection someone could
have, write those and put them on the
landing page. And that is having your
offer be scroll stopping. when you
actually have your price or your bundle
or whatever it is, having it nice and
big on the page and called out and being
like, "Wow, I need to go get that."
Whether that's the power of your
product, photography, any number of ways
you can achieve it. And last is
potentially think about a downell or an
upsell. Upsell can raise your average
value. But downell is important because
if you're not going to convert, making
sure you're getting email, you have some
alternative is worth thinking about if
you are seeing that you're not getting
this efficacy out of that first drop.
But getting those landing pages dialed,
having your funnels dialed, a huge point
of making your ads there. That'll be a
separate video likely, but it's worth
understanding as an advertiser that
sometimes you may be doing your best
job, but if you're not also helping take
responsibility for what happens next,
then you may not see the full value.
Anyway, I know we covered a ton inside
of this video. They're already
downloadable guides in the link below to
get you started building your toolkit.
That is the goal. I want you to start
building your toolkit for advertising.
Hopefully, you've gotten a number of new
ideas into how you can structure ads and
ad types and networks to try on. So,
whatever you worry in the future, you
have this video to come back to start
diving in. There's lots of things I put
in here. You can Google and TBT and go
down the rabbit hole on from direct
response to PMAX, whatever it is. And I
just want to make this be like that big
intro, really understand it. So, thank
y'all for coming along with me, also
seeing some of we put together at CAN
along the way. And appreciate y'all
watching.
[Music]