this is the worst marketing of 2024
nothing up to the Pepsi Kendall Jenner
level but we still had some else I think
it's important to identify failure at
large and then talk about the conditions
that led to it so marketers strategists
and consumers can actually understand
how these things work in this video we
are going to talk about the north Face's
outlandish Rebrand gone wrong with some
context from mimo arter and on we're
going to talk about Nike's brutal
product decisions this year and how
brand campaigns Aren't Enough we're
going to hit the soda Wars with Cokes
failed spice launch and the rise of
ollipop honorary fail mentions from
Bumble and Toys R Us we're going to flip
over to car company marketing and then
end with the category and companies I
feel are fumbling hardest in today's era
and that will be a fun one and for all
these I'm not just going to hate we're
also going to ideate that rhyme was not
on purpose let's do it so first we're
going to start with Northface and the
outdoors space at large so Northface
launched this new campaign entitled we
play different a reimagining of the
brand a tagline and this video with this
mirrored effect on it so a couple things
that are at play here so first we play
different as a tagline is something that
isn't exactly evocative of the feeling
that you may have when you think of the
Northface or a feeling at all related to
the outdoors brand second you're having
this video with this mirrored effect on
it that is very like 2013 GoPros almost
like an amateur design feel that isn't
relevant for kind of today's era or
social media standout at all it's an
aesthetic trick that doesn't resonate on
feed now they're actually coming from a
very iconic place so they have this
tagline never stop exploring which I
think is more relevant than ever
especially in a time where people are
discovering new destinations through
social media people like Tik Tok have
their big Hidden Gem campaigns where I
think it actually resonates as a brand
tagline now I understand North Face's
desire to redo to say we want to do
something different because the brand
does feel stagnant it doesn't feel like
it's carried the same weight it has in
the past but the way they deployed this
with an apple look alike but the tagline
that speaks more to being a kids brand
or some sort of school adjacent thing
actually sounds a little bit like it
would be like an Apple gaming selection
nothing feels quite right but the Crown
Jewel on top of this that takes it from
a campaign that's a bit odd to something
that is just bad is this Manifesto they
launched so shout out to my boy guy
Ashwin he's broken this down in a
previous episode of the brand Brothers
live we do but he says here North Face's
new brand Manifesto is a beautiful
example of horrible copyrighting so I
would read this out loud I don't want to
give you one of the most painful minutes
of your life but you can see here they
have a what is this a 20 line that says
things like kiss Chase with powder we
play hookie with the status quo and hard
to get with boring it is as brutal and
cringe as it gets and it's an example of
copy that is almost obviously written by
chat GPT that's now making it into a
major brand campaign for a moment in the
arguably the least cringe most aware of
eras so let's talk a bit about how we
get somewhere like this and then look at
what other brands are doing that's
interesting in this space in this time
period so first let's look inward to the
when this decision happens it comes from
a brand not really knowing what it
should do or its place and then also
from being too close to the brand itself
so the idea to come up with a new
tagline often comes from people trying
to feel like we need something new or a
new campaign now I encourage a lot of
those Brands to think is this tagline
done to us or is it done to the consumer
for instance I would have looked at it
as never stop exploring needs to be
presented for a new generation of people
in a new way and looked at social media
Savvy ways that could have re-invited
that tagline or even put something like
I never stop exploring we never stop
exploring whatever it looks like to add
a little bit of flavor to what exists
especially in an area that so inherently
nostalgia in fact they can even dip into
the more nostalgic applications of that
tagline and put ads together to have
that look and feel that is so popular
right now even pair that with a vintage
or more nostalgic collection but instead
we got this and this kind of thing where
you have just copy that is inherently
crazy that never should have made it to
life is an example of kind of what
happens in these brand decision making
rooms if you don't have younger people
or more culturally Savvy people or
people are afraid to speak up because
what happens here if you had 10 people
on this marketing team or with this
agency or involved in putting this
together not one of them had the
gumption to say we cannot put this out
this is horrible when most people who
see that would know it and a few things
happen in this scenario one they've been
doing a Rebrand or throwing it around
for so long that basically people have
given up up fighting the fight it just
needs to be done even if it's bad I
don't think that's what happened but
that's option one option two is someone
with the Stick of authority said I don't
care what anyone else thinks we're going
to run this this is the right look or
number three everyone was just didn't
checked out enough or didn't care or was
moving on to the next job to say we're
ready to have this done I will shout out
there was someone on social media who
mentioned that if they did use this
mirrored effect and then the campaign
was something that was more like you
versus you that could actually be a
really interesting application of the
same idea AA and kind of putting it into
your own aspirational look at the brand
but while this is happening it's a big
moment for Northface for the outdoors
industry in general because brands are
making major moves and I want to talk
about that for a moment so mamut a Swiss
Outdoors brand launched a campaign that
says we are not a street wear brand 3.9
million views 3.8 million views and
you'll see what it pictures here and
basically taking a direct shot at people
that wear arcx and these really
heavyduty gortex clothing as fashion
items is that this is a thing meant for
real engagements and so they actually
took this in a very tongue and cheek
Swiss way shot these you know crazy
things like on the actual like Streets
of London of kind of engaging in putting
these things in that environment it's a
really creative take on them positioning
against what's happening in the industry
I love the idea of positioning against
of taking something happening and saying
we are the antithesis of this is a
classic marketing campaign strategy
especially for a unknown or traditional
brand or when people that in your Niche
are doing something that intrinsically
doesn't feel right and I especially like
this positioning because of what arcx
has become now so arcx is an incredible
brand with an incredible history I was
first introduced to the brand where
where it was being actually used by
operators people I worked with in the
outdoors industry who were in the Marine
Corps the military had a high level of
respect for the brand which is about as
good of a stamp as you can get for
performance gear but when you actually
look at how the brand has approached now
and how popular has become as a more
Street Wear element and the way that it
looks and feels is just feels wrong and
so I look at their e-commerce photos
like we see here where people are
engaged in like outdoor activities but
in a white screen environment embodies
what Mamud is positioning themselves
against by saying hey we're doing this
for theater we're doing this inside of a
studio of course we're not doing this in
the real world and so I found that
campaign to be a really refreshing look
at positioning against an industry for a
brand that is relatively unknown at
least in the more mainstream circles and
it's a perfect example of how a single
idea can put a product driven brand onto
the map with a great campaign because if
people feel passionate about the mimo
product are resonate with what's being
said about it that's going to take them
somewhere and the outdoors industry in
general is an interesting place cuz
athleisure and performance and techware
are on the verge of what I feel is like
going to be a pretty major change and so
on- running is one who I think is doing
an excellent job and who has really
taken over beyond their you they had
their moment where they were basically
with everyone older any older person
running or walking was in on they also
managed to become cool to a more
mainstream audience are working to do
that even harder we're going to talk
through two of those campaigns here so
first they had actually one of my
favorite reels of the year with their
collab with post archive faction which
is a Korean fashion brand this is an
incredible piece of standout content
that uses an effect like what I believe
Northface was going for but actually
does it well and this is a collaboration
between two Brands one that is a Avant
guard fashion brand of the highest
caliber and then on itself that actually
brings you know some level of interest
and credibility and audience to both in
a new way then on the other side of that
on things I think that where on could
improve is they announced a major
Ambassador a super expensive move which
is getting Zena onto their team what
you'll notice about a lot of these posts
is that she will be featured in The
Campaign but not on her feed it will
only be on their feed because that
obviously costs a lot more and recently
they actually had one where she had a
carousel with an on her feed and there
was you they kind of bridged that gap
finally this is a super expensive big
celebrity campaign with arguably one of
the most impactful people you could get
as a campaign now but where this Falls
flat to me isn't the the desire the
crossover there even the content and
where it looks but the intention behind
it it is obvious that she is not a
performance Runner or really interested
in athletic activity in fact she gave an
interviewer where she basically said she
doesn't run for fun or enjoy that kind
of stuff so they are basically
positioning it almost as a lifestyle
product they're trying to get the brand
in front of her audience but doesn't
truly have that level of fit and then
with the content really only being
posted on their feed they're only
getting a fraction of the leverage of
That Celebrity now there's a million
other things this brand is doing
excellently but it's an interesting
thing to think about when you do do a
partnership or a position is who is
going to post how much and do they
really embody the lifestyle you're going
for or do they just embody the
demographic and I'll end with a little
bit of where I think the future of this
kind of industry here is going and we'll
talk a little bit more about this kind
of thing when we get to Nike and
Footwear later but this uh margel
sublabel and Solomon collab here is I
think we are entering this like techware
2.0 era where we're really merging all
the high-end a Leisure all the varis and
stuff of the world and the ons with
people more like post archive faction
more like Marella Etc to kind of create
this next level combination of
performance and lifestyle that I'm
actually really excited to see but next
up we are going to talk about soda and
Coca-Cola spice one of the more
ill-advised things that was launched
this year they launched a new flavor a
raspberry soda and then already pulled
it from the shelves I think the general
idea behind what they put out is they
needed their new version of a Cherry
Coke they're going back to their
playbook for previous big wins and
putting it out but this was certainly
not and for a number of reasons this is
both a product and a marketing fail
first there really is no desire amongst
the audience for a raspberry flavored or
spiced Coca-Cola in fact they are seeing
their market share especially with
younger people who this has aimed
towards moving towards healthier
products like ollipop who we'll talk
about in a moment so to kick off let's
look at this video from the actual
Coca-Cola event launch so in this this
Creator here let's roll out NYC goes to
the popup with these huge fruit these
big fruit animations you know like a DJ
some very lightly known celebrity this
whole kind of weird avangard idea that
is perfectly representative of what
people think the younger generation
likes and is into but what no one is
actually likes and is into and you
contrast this roll out with what's
happening with alipop I think is a
strong indicator of how much savier this
new generation of marketers are versus
someone like Coke if they were doing
this they wanted to really launch they
would have been launching a healthier
version of their existing product or a
knockoff of Diet Coke or Coke Zero Etc
they would have been position in flavors
more akin to what people are actually
into and we'll talk about that in a
moment and they would have rolled it out
with real celebrity so by contrast we
can talk about ali poop this was a
amazing year for that that brand they
skyrocketed we actually had one of the
first employees I believe he's the head
of growth was on our brand Brothers live
a few weeks ago and broke down their
strategy like two at te we actually got
the complete Insight on there I believe
that live is on the channel but I'll
break down some of the key points here
but one of the big things that they did
was their launch or not necess their
launch one of their Big Marketing
campaigns revolved CA Cabello and
involved a truly resident star inside
the audience that they're trying to get
inside C's audience that goes far
further than anything K spice could do
and if you want to compare the budget
that ollipop can come with and with the
budget that kooch can come with I
guarantee kooch can come with a larger
one and come with a more interesting
approach to that if they just had the
intention to do it and so what they're
missing that ollipop has is the
intention and the strategy and this is
why these smaller brands are chipping
away from a marketing standpoint at
these huge incumbents that you thought
may never have been disrupted and so
let's talk about that industry for a
moment so when you are in the like new
soda industry these Prebiotic sodas
poppy ollipop all the ones we see and
you're a smaller brand you start off in
Niche grocery you start off in your
whole foods and your sprouts and you may
do really great there when you go to
Walmart you you die people don't buy it
off the shelf it doesn't have that
appeal this is not what happened with
ollipop the Walmart Shopper is not the
health food Shopper is not the
e-commerce Shopper it's a mainstream
Shopper and so is that in all grocery
across the US so to get that you have to
have mainstream marketing and where
where is soda traditionally sold
basically have movie theaters Airlines
fountains inside of restaurants and
sports and for ollipop sports was the
most approachable angle and they went
after that when they went mainstream in
a incredible way so they were actually
recruiting teams didn't have sponsors
they got a team in Kansas City there was
a stadium being built that didn't have a
Coke sponsor yet that they swung into
they immediately went for more Sports
and More stadiums but they crossed that
over as well they sponsored things like
Shannon Sharp's podcast where they're
entering all these dimensions in and
around Sports to say hey this is a place
where we believe we can take this on it
used to be fountains now we can actually
fight that with cans at the same time
they know Fountain Tech is dying because
of the plastic and reusable elements and
all the things that come from that
experience that people are just more
conscious of now straws and lids and
while something like kombucha did really
good and Specialty maybe even crossed
over a bit it was never going to be
consumed in the same way something like
ollipop wood inside these major cultural
moments so not only are they able to
fight against the incumbents below them
but also they can position themselves
against the bigger Brands above them and
then they really actively went after the
younger demographic with their flavor
choices and their roll out so things
like the Ridge Rush flavor from alipop
that came out that was really positioned
towards the college demographic and Rush
week it had a whole sorority component
of it obviously a takeoff of the
Mountain Dew flavor and a position there
but there being able to say hey look at
this next to these two products this is
so much healthier for you for a more
health conscious generation than ever
while also applying marketing directly
to them sponsoring the like sorority
dances at these colleges during rush
week and being a part of the cultural
conversation and while Coke is putting
on these pop-ups in New York that
resonate with nobody so from there we're
move on to the next category and in this
one we are going to talk about Nike so
this is less of a marketing conversation
and it's a product conversation and
we're going to start by looking at some
shoes the first one is Devon Booker's
shoe you're going to see here we're
going to go through all the major
athletes right now Luca Don's shoe this
is the shoe that is being sold under the
Jordan brand for him Jason Tatum's shoe
giannis's shoe what all of these have in
common is they are terrible is that when
you look at them and you compare them to
the era of the Heyday of what was a
Jordan shoe even the LeBron and KDS
which were at least decent these are
just not good they're not aspirational
for a newer generation to turn these
into a signature silhouette and these
are the top players the most interesting
players in the world a new generation of
people not even going to pull up the job
Mor ANS they're that bad this is a
company that can't find a way to invent
something for the most interesting
people in the world while around them
there's Footwear Innovation everywhere
if you look at even like the shoes like
heliot Emil did with Puma at the stuff
the surgeon was doing for these athletes
being with with customs and with their
direct competition is doing with someone
like Anthony Edwards and Adidas who made
a shoe that is stand out it is unique
and has become a signature statement
that looks good and is available at a
very reasonable cost this is a product
issue because Nike continues to have
amazing campaigns to celebrate on these
moments to know where all the placements
are to have marketing and the Ze guys
figured out even when they stumble
they'll come right back with it it's
hard to go a week without someone saying
Nike has an amazing campaign but what
they don't have is product that gets
kids excited and that really makes it
into wardrobes and rotation and instead
they continue to relive the past and
relaunch things that grow increasingly
rest relevant every week if you had told
me a year ago that Adidas's core shoe
would be the number one most interesting
one inside of basketball and that
Anthony edwards's ads with them would be
significantly better than anything at
least it be throwing shots at Nike and
what they did I would definitely be
surprised but this ad from Adidas is an
absolute Master Class and with that the
shoes isn't the only thing where there's
an issue here there's also the product
that happened in general like this Nike
Team USA is a great example where they
truly like brought out the Kmart Bargain
Bin for what they did like if you look
at these Graphics treatments it is it is
bad we have a swoosh at the head of an
eagle we have whatever is going on here
these designs are truly like when you
talk about hey this is the company
that's going to represent our nation and
what they put out this is not the staple
items that I would feel great about
having represented and having the
athletes and the best people we have in
the world this weird Nike smiley face
like out there being being put out while
at the same time people like kith are
like understanding the assignment and
doing something interesting with the
licenses they do at the same time and
I'm a noted kith ambivalent there's a
lot of things that they do that I am not
a huge fan of but what they've done here
by just like tapping into the moment of
nostalgia that we are having elevating
everything in the materials and
applications making things feel rich and
textured and interesting and like
iconically American
is a great opportunity that any brand
with a rich history should be the first
ones to know that they could tap into
and they balance that side by side with
kind of traditional kith pattern stuff
that still has its own kind of unique
feel and even do things like offshoots
like luggage and bags that are
noticeably nice and on Trend and I will
big shout out the wallabies that are
featured in The Styling here that's how
I know I would be friends with whoever
put this shoot together but all this is
interesting and excellent in a way that
a brand at that size should not be able
to do to compete with a brand at Nike
size at the same time even Reebok is
understanding the assignment so I put
out this video now January beginning of
this year and it was it was about Big
Brand social it was really about why
Reebok doesn't post enough and what
rebok is doing in general they didn't
seem to have eye of the ball on
Silhouettes but I called out this
Premier Road silhouette which I love I
wear all the time and I think is
actually excellent but they just weren't
showing off or pushing at all and I was
like hey this is actually a better
silhouette than what most people have
out there and they're not posting about
it there's not much happening and then
by the end of this year it is now a
Staple in what they're featuring and
again this here and it's cultural
relevance its ability to be posted on
Outlander as a silhouette is you know
all the things that Reebok is doing to
kind of reclaim their spot in the game
this lack of product Innovation from
Nike gives room for their competition to
come in and do interesting things and
take advantage of even just one good
silhouette and how far that can take you
so a couple quick hitters as we get
towards the end of this video another
fail is coming from Toys R Us who used
they obviously like a brand who's gone
out of business bankrupt and Back Again
but they use Sora to generate an AI
video it's part of this rush to AI from
ad agencies who will say rather than
make good creative we're going to make a
creative with AI so we can say they was
made with AI and try to win some awards
instead of just making an ad that's
actually good and this ad comes across
weird because this kid is AI he looks
almost ghoulish which is like sad to say
but we wouldn't be saying that about a
real kid so this idea that we're going
to use AI we're going to create
something with this Fringe technology
and about at the same time creating
something uncomfortable versus just
creating something good is an example of
what some of the worst of what I the
advertising industry represents on a
similar vein we have Bumble putting out
a big campaign not really understanding
their demographic trying to encourage
them to leave cell behind and not
understanding their frustration with the
current dating app and landscape and
they quickly retracted that understood
their consumer didn't like it and kind
of moved on and that's one of the ones
where I feel that one was a case of bad
marketing but one that may not
necessarily have been avoided they're
trying to push the limit they're trying
to do something interesting if you had a
bunch of people looking at the campaign
I don't know how many people would have
been like hey this isn't going to
resonate versus some of of the other
ones we saw above that that definitely
would not and then we had Apple I think
they took the original one down but this
is it this is the video playing in
Reverse which is what filmmakers did I
believe maximiz is the other Creator
shout out to him put out the video first
where people actually reversed doing
this but they took one of these
hydraulic press videos and destroyed all
creative things to basically make a
apple thin the thin iPad Pro or whatever
is much more impactful in Reverse to see
them all growing out of it but they were
trying to play on a trend they were
trying to say hey hydraulic press videos
are really popular kids love them adults
love them people watch them all the time
just do our ads as one of those and
we'll note how thin the iPad is and look
this isn't the most offensive thing in
the world but it does have that
intrinsic feel that you're saying man
all these things are being crushed in
the name of Technology just did not feel
right and that backlash did spark enough
that they actually retracted it another
quick hitter we were going to talk about
Vehicles so BMW they had an ad with
Christopher Walkin talking like Walkin
they did an ad basically they doing old
school celebrity to Market BMW and to me
this isn't like a fail or anything this
ad is totally fine but it's indicative
of where some of these older car
companies are and the difference between
BMW marketing and Mercedes marketing
where they're still trying to Anchor a
big celebrity driven campaign to
consider BMW and when you go to the
actual BMW Instagram feed all you see is
the cars they have not gotten the memo
that in today's world you may see a
person or two floating around here all
of these are kind of 2017 era carousels
and highlight reels of some of these
vehicles and very rarely do you see a
story interlined with any of these
versus Mercedes Instagram where
everything is a 50/50 of actual story
being told a participation in culture
this here with nego this here with
Monclair this with Brabus this fascist
show this F1 driver this crazy collab
that was put together this person's
individual story like this this like
interesting Journey all put together
into a series of stories and intention
and obvious cool in a way that I think
is really resonant and so that I'm going
to end with the industry that I think
has the biggest fail going on right now
not from any one campaign but just lack
of opportunity and what they can do
about it and that is the camera industry
so we're going to Nikon's Tik Tok here
they have everything has like 500 views
and it's just absolutely terrible
there's no reason any of this should be
posted on social media in any way and
you go to Fuji Fuji doesn't even have a
Tik Tok and there's two things that play
here the first is for someone like Fuji
that story is being told by creators for
them they have cameras that are relevant
enough in the moment to smaller more
Niche people like the x100v and a bunch
of these even hard to get that they can
say that he our community is telling our
story on social media we don't
necessarily need to and you might
believe them but the other side of that
coin is for someone like Nikon who just
had a resonant campaign I did a video
about this that went viral um maybe two
a year ago where they're doing this
anti- aai campaign they're standing up
for their Target demographic of employed
photographers by basically saying they
did this series of amazing images then
they put the prompt of what it would
potentially be if it was generated by AI
what it is a real photo it's genius
campaign really set themselves up to
actually position to stand for something
in a new era but what is conspicuously
not there is any represent of this
campaign ongoing on social media or
anything useful on social media so what
would we do here what is the opportunity
for any of these companies all you need
to do is do tutorial content and collab
if they did the most base level of
decent Tik toks that just showed all the
features how to shoot using aperture the
rule of thirds whatever that looks like
and then how to use their gear how to
set it up or this photo was taken or
that and before and after and you could
do five of those a day on social media
at their scale and probably have them
all hit not have that be an expensive
proposition and educate an entire
generation on a camera platform that is
the opportunity it's an opportunity for
a generational jump for someone to say
oh Nikon wants to become bigger than
Sony Sony wants to take down Canon
whatever that looks like they will be
able to own double digigit percents of
market share by taking content seriously
and none of them are and the second tier
of that would be collaboration when you
look at the sheer scale of creators and
how many people are photographers and
using it how many people get social
media views you could literally have
your pick of the best of the best for
probably lower budget because people
love gear so much and able to get real
resonance there I think seeing how
someone like Adobe has treated
influencer where every designer has some
kind of relationship or or at least a
pending relationship with Adobe if they
are engaged and influence that they're
saying hey we are going to dominate that
space we're going to enable the creative
space we're going to fund interesting
projects we're going to make people love
to work with Adobe and understand it and
share that and make sharing that a part
of being a creative and I think that
camera companies have that same
opportunity and year after year they
they just let it die so any of them Fuji
in particular Sony in particular just
call me it is what it is anyway these
are my worst marketing of 2024 there's
plenty of good and bad on all different
levels I'm calling out lots of larger
companies here I feel bad bashing any
smaller companies and it's not about how
bad it is not to call them out they all
do plenty of good things but it is about
understanding what's happening about
being intentional about those decisions
you make as a marketer as a consumer
understanding what influences you and
what you can do in the future so thank
you so much for watching like And
subscribe I will break down these
campaigns and the hyper newsletter
description link is below and thank you
so much