Come one, come all. This is the worst
marketing of 2025. In this video, I'm
going to go through a couple different
categories, all the things that went
wrong for companies in marketing and
branding this year, including campaigns
that didn't quite hit the mark or got
rough backlash. I have a whole section
on AI, both the use of AI and AI
companies figuring out the world around
them like newborn babies. We're going to
talk about rebrands that are under more
scrutiny than ever, and we saw some
really terrible ones this year. But it
is not going to be all bad. I'm going to
walk through the good as well and
present some counterpoints and positive
stories when I can because I don't want
to just be pure hating. These videos are
designed to help you learn about
marketing and branding in the world
around you and how things are regarded
and where brands stand today. My name is
Orin. I'm a former CMO and now a
creative strategist with brands around
the world. Working on preventing things
like this from happening every day. And
I do know if you worked on any of these
campaigns that is probably not your
fault instead is the fault of
leadership. I respect that. But overall,
we are here to learn, have some fun.
Let's lock in. But first, I did this
video last year in 2024, wearing the
same hoodie. It is not leather. It is
actually waxed cotton. And in the spirit
of not gatekeeping, this is one that I
actually designed for Ferat, a company
that does funnels for e-commerce. We
actually just did a new collection. I'll
do a video in a few weeks about
designing and putting that whole
collection together. But in the spirit
of not gatekeeping, this was actually
made by Made Blanks. Made Blanks right
here in LA does things like washes and
wax finishes, etc. Custom for Brands. If
you want something like that, they are a
great person to hit up. But who knows,
maybe I'll wear this for the next 10
years every time I do this video. You
never know. But let's start off in the
wide world of rebrands. The wound is
still flesh. Fresh. The wound is still
fresh from Cracker Barrel. This is a
really interesting one. This took over
all the news, took over all the media,
and showed the era we're in now. The era
where marketing is truly treated like a
sport. In this rebrand, the president of
the United States weighed in on Truth
Social. And the president of the United
States is weighing in on rebrands. You
know that marketing and branding has
become far more a center of cultural
attention than ever before. I'm trying
to picture either of the bushes weigh in
on the PepsiCo 400page branding document
and cannot imagine that happening. A
Cracker Barrel hired a consultancy
called Profit founded ironically by one
of today's false prophets, Professor
Galloway. No surprise where they got the
culture of this who then created
something that was extremely out of
touch with where culture is going. They
removed Uncle Hershel from the barrel,
took him out back and shot him like all
the other and gave you the Yasified
barrel. Now, this is actually a pretty
decent identity system overall. If you
were to in a vortex say, "We are going
to create this reusable barrel that's
basically looks like a shield and many
graphics. Not a bad type lockup."
Actually looks pretty good on some of
the packaging that they did. The
patterns are just fine. Colors are
whatever. It is a totally approachable
rebranded completely fine. My problem is
is that people have a real significant
connection to Cracker Barrel, what it's
like there, the stories that are there,
and the people that want to go in it are
getting a piece of history. And in our
world of blanding right now, the public
does not want you to bland, does not
want you to go minimal. It wants
stories. It wants characters. And the
fact that they didn't realize this means
that the people over at Profit and the
people at Cracker Barrel did not
actually talk to their customers. They
did not put themselves in their
customers shoes. Instead, they asked,
"What would Metropolitan people want?"
and gave them something that didn't
resonate. Now, if this happened three
years ago, you probably would have
gotten maybe some minor outrage, maybe
some clawback, but no one really would
have cared. But now, branding more than
ever is culture, and if you release
something on this scale, people care
about your brand. There are high stakes,
as we saw by this getting pretty much
immediately called back, which was the
right move. related. The XG Games
announced new branding. And in a vacuum,
this X behind this girl looks kind of
fine. As you will quickly notice, if it
is not on something really light like
this, this black is going to get really
lost in the background. This looks looks
cheap. It looks techified. It lost all
of its character. It obviously wasn't
done by anyone who really took the
extreme to heart. So, bringing up the
previous iteration of the X games. If
you grew up in my generation, the Red X
is absolutely iconic and you have seen a
number of the brands of this time
actually create identities that last and
that people like. Nitro Circus being a
great example. I'm going to go see Nitro
Circus in December in Long Beach. Their
tour posters are sick. The way they've
maintained and adapted their branding
and their styling is sick. They could
have consulted anyone who did stuff like
this and note still dropping off some of
that trademark red. Give people that
dose of nostalgia. Give people what they
want. That's another example of hiring
people that don't really care about the
culture, who might act like they do or
said, "Oh, but I used to skate." But
they're not real fans. They don't really
understand. And in this world, the world
where one angry voice on a TikTok
reaches millions of people, fandoms
getting seen and being respected really
matter. RIP to the X Games. But by
contrast, a corporate rebrand done
really well was Domino's. Not going to
act like I'm the largest Domino's fan in
the world, but look at these boxes. Look
at that gold. Look at the Domino pieces.
Look at the colors. They are social
media friendly. They are bright. They
are instantly recognizable. They extend
the brand. They create some level of
luxury. I want whatever that black and
gold pizza box is. I'm sold just off GP.
They also announced a new audio logo
that went along with it. The audio logo
is extended within that box there. The
merchandise. Look at this apron. Fire.
And we'll give a big shout out to that
cuz this is an example of one that's
done well. Recognizes the existing
iconography. Extends it. makes things
that look naturally aesthetic that tie
in the brand across all things cuz I
mentioned it's not all bad. All right,
so there are a lot of combos around AI
in marketing right now. I'm going to
show you one of the common ways a lot of
agencies and teams including what I work
on are using it almost every day for my
team works a lot in Leonardo. You'll see
here Leonardo aggregates a lot of
different models you can create content
under for images and video. Plus, they
have a great upscaler and then guides
for things like style references and
creating consistent characters, things
like that. But quickly in my workflow,
you see probably seen a lot of my short
form videos now have backgrounds like
this. We generate all these in Leonardo.
And a lot of the quick images you will
see me cut in and out of videos. We are
using their Lucid Origin model all the
time. Just grab little things to put
into ads and into video backgrounds.
It's ultra realistic and easy to use.
And when you generate with it, you can
generate four or more options. You can
just have tons of options to alternate
your size, etc. Great tool for that. But
what I'm really here to talk about is
hooks for ads. So this is what a lot of
marketing agencies are doing now for
stuff going into meta ads and to fill in
stuff inside of bigger content. So for
instance, this is an ASMR generation for
the intro of video. This is a more
scientific video actually zooming into a
gummy product. This is a 3D animation of
an outboard motor and how it works.
Superhero infomercial. These are the
kind of things that stop the first 3
seconds of a scroll. So a lot of brands
are putting these in their ad accounts
to help their ads get thumb stop and
then they will go into a more
traditional ad from there. All these
you're seeing here all generated in
Leonardo is one of the multiple models
you can choose from they have. But why
this is important and note these are for
hooks is cuz this is the actual tactic
that works. If you throw a completely AI
ad in your ad account that often does
more harm than good. But the hook using
it for that first three seconds and
transitioning into a visual is a
practice that's working very well right
now. So doing things like Santa getting
pulled over, got another version of
that. Boxes being pulled out,
first-person view content, running a lot
of newscasters right now. You'll see
this is a common theme because it's a
great feed disruptor. And then
generating animations like the impact of
a supplement on a brain, etc. This is
really common things here. So in
Leonardo, you can go, you can pick your
model from the drop down. They're all
good for different things. You can have
more realistic models. You can have
quicker models, etc., and experiment in
finding your workflow. There are ones
that let you control like with start and
end frames and do cinematic motion.
They've got all the popular stuff in
here with no watermarks. So, if you are
experimenting like this and you are
using AI commonly inside content
creation, ad creation, Leonardo is a
great tool to be able to work in. You
can learn more about them at the link in
the description. And thanks so much to
them for sponsoring this video. Speaking
of not all bad, let's tap into the AI
world here for a moment. We're going to
talk about both campaigns that used AI
for good or bad. And we're going to talk
about AI companies figuring out
marketing. So this is one of the most
interesting times in the world for AI
and AI in marketing because on one hand
marketing branding people and designers
are using AI every day absolutely
constantly using it to make excellent
strides and do really amazing work. But
then at the same time if they use it
wrong or issue one way this way or that
way it's an immediate backlash. It's
about determining where the lines are
while at the same time this new
generation of AI companies has raised an
absolute boat ton of money. More money
than any of us can humanly comprehend.
and they are spending that money
marketing those companies. And in the
spirit of moving fast and breaking
things that's in the AI and venture
capital industries right now, they are
figuring out marketing on the fly and
spending a lot of money to do it and
attracting a lot of marketing and
branding talent to burn that money for
them. We get to see a lot play out in
real time. We're going to kick off with
Blackbird spy plane a noted like Gen X
fashion newsletter. Uh does these kind
of deep dive exposees really respect the
ownership's writing even if it's for
like a different generation? But they
did this big call out of J Crew for
doing this photo shoot which at first
glance you glance at this photo shoot
looks like a totally normal J Crew photo
shoot throws back to the heyday of J
Crew. But upon closer examination in a
way examination only fashion bros will
ever do. This guy's knee is not quite
right. Or actually not even that. The
lifelines of the boat should go the
other way. Docks don't have fenders.
There's too much rope. The underleg's
weird. His foot is bending backwards.
Stripes are glitching out. They caught
all these little things that would show
people that this is AI. And again, if
people weren't going ridiculously deep
into this, no one would ever know. But
here's what happened. They didn't
mention this at all inside the campaign.
They only credited it after the fact
here. And they chose to recreate a very
normal photography campaign, which
wouldn't have cost them some obscene
amount of money and just replace it with
a AI photographer. So, a couple things
that are happening here. First, the
public doesn't love to be deceived. So
going for deceit inside what you're
doing with marketing is often not quite
the right thing to lead with. And for
many brands or many ads right now when
I'm scrolling my feed, you kind of
assume AI on a lot of things. And that's
okay. Your expectation is you could be
watching anything. But for J Crew as an
established company putting out a
campaign like this, not giving you the
expectation that they're trying
something new or calling it out. It's
the wrong time to be working on
something like this. You do not want to
be on the front end as an established
brand of something like this. And this
is a conundrum, a conundrum we'll talk
about as we get into Cardier. But J Crew
had already been on the outs the last
like five to eight years. I feel like
with the exception of the brief time
when the creative director of Noah
released their collection there, their
marketing has been trash. They have the
wrong people guiding them. They have the
wrong strategies. Women's is different.
But men's has been a dumpster fire done
completely wrong. Thriving off the
little bit of nostalgia they have left
and some of their price appropriate
nature. But I mean they have one time
where they had like billboards of like
random photographers doing like scene
work. The interview series, everything
is like there's so much goodwill towards
J. Crew that they let so much fly. But
they've had a truly misinformed
marketing team for a while now. But
Cardier is another interesting example.
Brands being on the forefront that don't
need to be on the forefront and who
don't have the critical eye to determine
if it's good enough. And that's probably
the biggest thing with J Crew. I said a
lot about J Crew's marketing to
basically say they don't have the eye.
They don't have anyone social savvy
enough, anyone creative direction savvy
enough, still within that kind of like
aging vestage to be able to say that's
not quite right. That's going to get
caught. That's going to happen. That's
not going to work. People aren't going
to get it. This doesn't represent our
brand well. Right? There's no one there
left. And with Cardias, it's
surprisingly the same thing. They don't
have anyone to understand how AI is
applied. Is this good or bad? It says
328 likes. Their posts usually have
thousands and thousands and thousands.
But the plane is flying backwards and
it's hauling this Cardier sign
backwards. It is just bad AI being done
here. And if you look at Cardier, most
of these big luxury fashion brands are
actually patrons of VFX at the highest
level. God, that image is probably AI,
too. But they are employing VFX and 3D
people to make really intricate amazing
stuff a lot of the time. So them going
and doing that relatively poorly right
away is should not even be on their road
map. They did not need to save whatever
money that was being saved there. Now
this is where the conundrum is. This is
where luxury and established brands are
in such a problem as they will get
chastised for this. Cardier never should
have done that. That's bad marketing on
their part. No matter how much good CGI
and VFX artists they employ after this.
This is an excellent video. Who knows if
this is AI involved in this or just pure
VFX or not? Great storytelling video
using graphics and the brand identity
and doing it really well. But if they
try to embrace this new wave, they are
going to get called out for it. They are
going to get fans and people who are mad
and angry about it. But then at the
other hand of this, new companies who
use it savily, who achieve love with us,
are going to thrive. They're going to
take market share. They're going to be
able to do it cheaper. And so you're
caught between a rock and a hard place
with how the internet treats this
nowadays. It's a really interesting
indicator of our time because if I've
noticed anything from going and working
a lot with AI stuff on the internet is
that if people like it, if they think
this is sick, it doesn't matter if it's
AI, they're in. But if they have a
reason to feel that they were misled by
someone they trusted, they expect to be
misled by the internet in general. It
gets even worse. And this is going to be
a complex scenario. This Farerragamo
video, I know several AI people who
could recreate this shot forshot with
absolutely no problem. Whether this is
true VFX or not, content like this is in
for a hard surprise. It's a complex time
that we're in now and every VFX artist
has to really be looking at do I give in
and adopt this in my workflow and where
do I work through my rates and as one of
the most complicated industries to be
acting within right now even though
demand for that because of social media
is at an all-time high. Now to contrast
this, Burberry leaned into its roots.
They did these amazing Burberry weather
reports. They understand social media.
They understand what people want.
They've crushed this rebrand arc they've
been in with its peaks and waves
especially this last year getting their
stars to do these weather reports in
front of the blue screen. having the
right people, everyone from our Smith's
husband, Lucky, etc., while also
executing real life vignettes that
people really resonate with. And even
this, I even seen this yet, the art
direction of their VFX and animated
stuff being pure excellence. But then
this campaign where you've got famous
celebrities, the types of things that
Burberry can afford, having real
conversations with each other in the
rain jackets, Cardier could never. But
enough about using AI. Let's talk about
AI itself. You probably saw friend.com
spent a million dollars taking over the
subway in New York City. Their AI
companion, they made all these subway
ads and these ads were designed to be
graffitied. There'll be arguments. They
didn't know it was going to happen. They
didn't know that people were going to
write all over them and call over them.
As someone who has bought a lot of out
of home in my life, every agency that
you were going to buy something from in
the New York subway is going to tell you
that's a lot of whites space on your ad.
You know what people are going to do on
it? They're going to draw on it. Censor
that one out for comedy. It is a known
thing. This was known and expected and
then generated a lot of attention cuz
people posted these absolutely
constantly cuz New York is the most
triggerable place on earth. This is a
thing that is talked about and used in
marketing circles. As you know, if you
do something in New York, you are going
to get this immediate outcry and
backlash of people with a certain level
of voice and you can basically move them
to your whim. They will do whatever you
trigger them to do. And it is a tool for
marketers to use that AI from friend
used excellently inside of this. So much
so that people used friend as Halloween
costumes including the graffiti of the
friend as the Halloween costume and you
would get the uh what's it called the
marketing for marketers of stuff like
this where hinekin then released best
way to make a friend is over a beer
response campaign buying it in there
that will get other marketers to chrole
but let's actually talk about friend and
was it bad marketing I have here a
friend amulet
>> how dare you
>> I purchased and I'm going to do a review
above in short form I will give you the
first look at the review on here. So,
this is an interesting product. People
give it a lot of hate immediately. Why
do you need someone to listen to all
your combos? Why would you want to talk
to anybody? I am the kind of person, fun
fact, who has an inner narrative. I talk
to myself. It's why it makes it really
easy to talk to YouTube. When I am
working through a problem or writing a
script, I sit at my desk or if you live
in my neighborhood, you will notice I
pace around my neighborhood and
basically mutter to myself until the
ideas are figured out. And so, when I
actually tried this product, it was
quite good. I was able to talk to it
with some pretty significant UX
limitations and have a partner who could
bring back some ideas and concepts and
feedback based on what it knew that was
actually pretty savvy. Now that's the
end of the good review. The potential of
this is excellent. That idea is better
than people think. The execution of it
and its ability to talk was okay. Where
they are going and the ability for a lot
of people around the world to be able to
have that level of companionship I
actually think is underrated. But then
the execution is just bad. I worked in
uh industrial design and the creation of
products for a long time. The agency
that I helped start, Gwyn Partners that
does pure hardware UX and UI design, if
they looked at the design of this at the
quality of what was put out for the
price at the actual uh what was shown in
the pictures versus what they actually
got from the factory in China, they
would be shocked. It is a UI UX
travesty. The look, feel, and quality of
this for the price. And if you get
someone who knows what they're doing in
China, you could have this resolved in a
single EVT DVT PVT cycle. And then the
actual UX of if you talk to it, it
responds on the phone and you can't ever
really get into a dialogue. It'll only
give you a sentence back or a thought.
It's pretty limited into the scope of
the intelligence it has. But that all
said, the potential of that to have the
fullest scope of intelligence if it had
the full backing of Claude inside of it
and understood your voice and you could
talk to it in your headphones back and
forth and it would talk right back to
you. There is a product there that
actually has real resonance. But enough
about that. On the friend tangent, the
last of the AI campaigns we're going to
talk about is OpenAI and Joani Eye. Open
AAI paid $6.5 billion to acquire Jon I's
company and then put out IO which then
they had to resend cuz someone had a
trademark for the name and they promoted
it by putting out this two friends
conversation. So, first paying this much
for this kind of relic of past design is
a stretch, but I get they have the cash
to do it. But B, they basically made
this video where my guy Joanie, legend,
not taking anything away from that,
wanders through the streets of San
Francisco for a [ __ ] minute to
announce a new company at 150. Then they
sit down and two of the most
interesting, prolific people of our time
have a how long is this? One of a
7-minute conversation that is so boring
it is offensive. And the fact that
whoever put this together could not get
a more interesting conversation out of
two people who probably have a very
interesting takes on any number of a
thousands of things with the cost it
took to produce it. The time out of
these guys days from pursuing whatever
great technological feats they're going
after warrants this some of the worst
marketing of 2025. And that bridges us
good people into campaigns.
We all remember the American Eagle good
jeans campaign. And it's interesting.
You'll notice 10 million views in. God,
it's only been 3 months. Time is a
[ __ ] flat circle. Let me tell you
that. 10 million views is still up.
American Eagle has the entire time said,
"You know what? We're just going to run
with this. We do not care what this
backlash looks like. We paid this money
for Sydney Sweeney. We are running this
campaign." Sydney Sweeney has continued
rampaging through the internet with zero
impact to whatever it is she is doing.
And American Eagle got an awful lot of
notoriety from it. But the simple fact
they didn't go through and check that,
maybe they got the positive benefit of
it. But it really was one of those like
you focus group this to just a few
people. They'll be like that's kind of
racist and that probably would have been
pulled. And I get it if I was in that
group if I was sitting around this table
and I was like is this ad going to get
crazy backlash would have popped up like
maybe in the back corner of the mind but
someone would have had to convince me,
right? But whoever had to get convinced
there or was doing the convincing did
not was they able to get it through and
they got crucified. But will this really
have any tangible impact on American
Eagle that can't be brought back with a
great product or a great campaign? I
doubt it. But the response Gap with
Cat's Eye. So basically, they then
released this cat's eye better in denim
campaign and people thought it was a
response to Sydney Sweeney, but Gap does
a denim campaign almost every year. I
actually made a video on TikTok about
when they did this with Tyler. I thought
it was ushering kind of a new era. They
did it Vayner was the agency, I believe,
at least the agency promoting the
campaign. Tyler was doing it for Khaki
or whatever. where they had their fall
campaign, had a dance music video. They
were doing what Gap does, but things
like this take a ton of time to produce.
Getting the rights to Khisa's milkshake
is probably a multi-month process. Not
to mention choreography and the deals
and back and forth and management,
filming and release and all that. Like,
GAP spends a inordinate amount of time
producing these campaigns and worth it.
47 million views, but it got 47 million
views and the positive response it got
because of the luck of timing of
American Eagles shooting themselves in
the foot beforehand. But this allowed
them to thrive in the moment of, hey, we
do this every year. We're already in
here. We are able to make up by doing a
good campaign. If our competitors make
bad campaigns, we actually get a
multiplier. And that is a very much a
2025 thing that if you see your
competition slipping is worth thinking
about and taking advantage of. I do want
to shout out whoever chose Catsai for
the campaign, you're the real MVP.
Moving on to OnRunning and Zenaia. This
is one of the worst celebrity
endorsements of all time in my opinion.
Shop the edit. There's not a single
picture of her on the edit. Here we go.
No, we got we got one. We got one.
Explore the campaign. All right. I link
you to explore the campaign. So look,
why is this bad? She has basically
stated she's not a runner. She's not an
athlete. She's inside these visuals
dancing, stretching. There is not the
fit between the two of them. And while
she's an amazing face to represent a
brand and appeals to a huge swath of
people of all ages, backgrounds across
the world. She's posted the vast
majority of on their account, they have
gotten very little love from her while
investing an absolute ton. They've
gotten one carousel of her posts. And
it's funny when uh in 2024 in this
multi-year deal, they've gotten one post
on her socials about that brand. It's
got 5 million likes. So again, it's not
like this is a flop or anything, but
when you look at today's day and age,
how do you want to cement yourself in
your brand? You want real fits. You want
people that really live, breathe, and
thrive inside the product where they're
going to show up in it naturally, where
they're going to embrace it and love it
and want to be a part of it. The
community online can feel the organic
nature of a campaign. It doesn't mean it
could fail. Doesn't mean it's the worst.
But it does mean it's missing the
potential size of the prize of what a
aligned collaboration, an aligned
campaign could do. And on at a really
critical point inside its business
venture where it's done a lot of good.
On's an amazing brand. I buy on. They've
done an excellent job. The Lee collab is
perfect. The post archive faction stuff
was amazing. But these are the decisions
that basically determine whether they
are able to how much of a share they can
carve out of the Nike Lululemons of the
world. But at the same time, what I like
to contrast this with is the organic
love that they get. So this we may
remember Abisa final boss. Yes, this
happened this year. Again, time is a
flat circle. Wearing on running big on
logo. One of his most prominent
features. Halloween costumes of this guy
feature the onrunning tank top. There
was a there was a natural ubiquity. This
guy got so many views for on running
that damn near rivaled the extent of the
Zenaia campaign. I don't even want to
label that worst. It's not the worst.
Just a cautionary tale for everyone how
to look at this. Diving into the worst,
Elf dragged for a controversial new
campaign starring Matt Reich. So, Elf, a
purveyor of cheap cosmetics, noted
purchaser of Road. Uh, he's a
controversial comedian for domestic
abuse jokes, something worth being
controversial over. And Elf choosing
him, having chosen him before, is just a
surefire sign of someone having no idea
what their consumers actually like or
feel or what's going on on the internet
for a company that's usually very savvy.
end a company is usually very savvy and
ELF is savvy. ELF was sending the dude
who was on the boat from Portland to
Hawaii or whatever packages via
helicopter. They're online. They're are
terminally online people at ELF. And so
this meant that they knew it. People
knew. People brought this up. It was a
thing. People were like, "We shouldn't
use this." And someone chose to do it
anyway. And that is the nature of how
really bad campaigns happen. Similarity
to ones that are just not built right
for the modern era. Gatorade did this
Let Her Cook campaign with the WNBA.
right idea. They are taking a
unempowering line and empowering it.
They are flipping around this concept.
They're taking a popular phrase. They're
applying it here. But it opened them up
to online a lot of misogyny and people
being like, "Let her cook a baked potato
for me this evening." Right? A lot of
Tik Toks of that nature, people being
opening up to the line, the ability to
then put down what Gatorade is trying to
make, right? And I see where they're
going is actually is themed correct. The
right idea of of flipping a phrase or a
circumstance for an exciting time, but
in our current world, you have to think
about what people are going to do with
it and be ahead of it. Especially when
you're doing something that's relatively
controversial like this. That said, love
the WNBA. Great product. Love Gatorade.
And they'll survive to live another day.
Bring up Saratoga Water. Saratoga Water
came up this year because this guy,
again, this happened this year. I know
that's terrifying. The dude dumping his
face in the Saratoga Water. Saratoga
Water did not respond that weekend. made
posts a couple days later still did not
embrace this kind of world that they've
entered into. their response in the
marketing end of this, they have just
our company is not aware of what's going
on in culture, not able to act on it and
why teams need to hire social savvy
people to actually be able to put work
in on things like this. But what they
did do and what you've noticed is they
used that ubiquity in store. So the
salespeople at this company were savvy.
If you go into any store that carried
Saratoga water, it is front and center.
They got endcaps, they got in aisle,
they are prominent placement. They have
expanded their shelf space. Their sales
team was like, "Look at our social media
impressions. Put us front and center.
We're not going to pay a dime for it.
you are going to do it because it's
going to move you a hell of a lot of
water. And they were completely correct.
And this is something to call out for
any of you're in the middle of a viral
moment like that. Give your sales team
the ability to have a field day with it
cuz I guarantee you, go to accounts when
you're in the middle of that. You can
get a lot of premium placement. Speaking
of navigating crisis, we want to talk
about Duolingo. So, when I made I made a
uh video about the best marketing
campaigns in history a while back and
call out the Duolingo owl. It's one of
the best things done, especially by an
education brand. Now, Duolingo had its
controversy and now it's continuing to
try and play out the Duolingo owl, but
it doesn't have the same efficacy. And
so, you're watching this like social
team who I feel for try to get the same
views and same virality and concoct this
same narrative using these same
characters while people are just
trashing it constantly online. They're
caught in that really hard place. So,
they had a amazing campaign and a really
fun thing before and now they got to try
and work through that middle ground of
it. flopping a lot more than they were,
getting constant backlash, losing their
kind of cultural identity. This is a
rough one and one I did not expect to
take the turn it did from a company that
was doing it so well. But to call out a
couple good campaigns, especially good
campaigns that are cheap, Opel, uh, so
Rachel here, shout out Rachel, excellent
newsletter that she runs if you are a
social media manager interested in that.
She calls out Opel, which is a company
to helps you prevent your screen time.
They put a creator on this account,
Olivia Unplugged, talking to you about
how to how to stop feeling tired all the
time, how to cure your phone addiction.
She's doing whiteboard videos and
helping people with their lives. And all
of it was just a plug for Opel. So with
the cost of hiring this one creator and
people experiment with this all the
time. This is a 3K to a 10K a month
[ __ ] project. As someone who has done
this 50 times plus on different things.
This hit right. It was the right
content. It was the right creator. It
was the right timing. But this is not an
expensive endeavor for a marketing
company of any size. If you get the
right concept, you execute it correctly,
and has product market fit with what
you're promoting, and you do Tik Tok
something like this correctly, you can
really win at a small budget. And I want
to call out Opel for doing that. And
guess what? If it hadn't worked, they
would have spent that money for a couple
months, and then no one would even have
known it was an Opal project cuz it was
on this account. I also want to give a
shout out to Claude, my friend Ashwin,
calling out how bad Claude's copy was
last year. Last year, uh, move your work
up into the cloud. That makes no sense.
They had a series of taglines in their
out of home that were uh frankly
atrocious. But then this year when they
chose to release their video ad, they
created an excellent excellent piece
positioning Claude as a tool for the
thinkers, a tool for people doing real
world applications, a tool for artists.
Most importantly, you go through this
video, you see a phone like once, maybe
twice of people doing real world things,
solving complex stuff, uh, with an
excellent score, excellent visuals
presented, you know, amazing music
choice, a truly excellent piece of
advertising. And I love to see companies
graduate from where you're like, oo to,
oh, they absolutely nailed it. It's
great to see somebody win. And the last
note you're going to hear me end on,
something that we've seen in mass this
year that's worth talking about, that is
the gambling ad takeover. You are
inundated. Every podcast is brought to
you brought to you by FanDuel or
DraftKings. Stake logos are absolutely
everywhere. Weird ads for whatever type
of gambling stuff are just popping up
absolutely everywhere. But sports
betting in particular, sports gambling
is paying for and funding this massive
expansion of sports media that we see on
Tik Tok. All these crazy ads funding all
these podcasts. And when I go and talk
to younger people, any of my younger
people watching, I hear a lot that they
actually lose and spend a lot of money
on. Right? If you hear anyone say, "I
won a little bit," it means they lost.
Have you ever hear one said they broke
even? It means they lost even more.
There are a lot of young men in
particular who are running up with meme
stocks or buying day trading courses or
like TJR type [ __ ] who are doing sports
betting and trying to run three-leg
parlays. And you look at how do I ever
get enough funds to start a business or
travel and do something interesting or
get a down payment on a house or start a
family. It comes from having enough
money to do something entrepreneurial,
to give it a shot at something, start
your brand, to start an agency, to do a
creative thing, whatever. And if that
money is going to sports betting, when
you're get, and I understand it, you're
getting inundated 24/7. Your friends,
your group chat, every podcast that you
listen to, every piece of sports media
is telling you gamble, gamble, gamble.
That's truly [snorts] when we look at
the worst marketing of 2025 is what that
legislation and the companies pursuing
have chosen to do to the world around
them and are using in terms of how they
get in front of young men. And if you
are in the middle of that or you are in
too deep on that, you're never going to
get out. That win is not going to come.
You've got to just wake up one day and
say, I am going to put that time and
money and resources and dollars into
what is going to get me to the next
level. It's the end of my saliloquy, but
I cannot encourage you more to invest
that into yourself. I'm sure I missed a
lot of terrible marketing of the year.
Feel free to comment that or any of your
favorite campaigns down below. Maybe
we'll recap the best marketing of 2025
in a future video. This video come out
probably just hit 100K before this video
came out. So, thank you everyone who
watches this channel and supports it.
Please follow along because I'm on a
quest to be the biggest marketing
channel in the world. I don't know if
I'm really on that quest, but I'm
enjoying the time that we're having
along the way, spending with all of you
and talking about these topics. Thank
you'all so much for watching.