getting together in real life is the new
luxury and brands that are tapping into
experiences are getting more value than
ever as people want to connect in real
life and get away from purely online
these are some of my favorite brand
activations we've seen in the last few
years plus a guide for how to throw your
own brand activations whether you're on
a small budget or a big budget so in
this video I'm going to talk about brand
activations from Base Road the real real
Prada Lululemon Mumu run clubs with
local Brands tracksmith Bandit just give
an idea of what events they good and bad
where are some things you can learn from
then I'm going to walk through my rules
of great brand activations and I've done
everything from small brand activations
like I was just that complex comom with
my valuables brand all the way to Major
budget trade shows and programs where we
were doing events all around the United
States on road shows and Global with
bigger Brands I ran marketing for then
I'm get into Pro tips and the little
things people don't think about when
they're doing a brand activation and
then we're going to end with activation
ideas so if your brand is trying to come
up with stuff for next year about how
they stand out we will dive in and get
some great examples
we're going to kick right in with bass a
Creator luggage brand an amazing brand
overall they did the bass luggage wash
kind of like a car wash which ties into
one of my favorite things about good
events these are events that allow you
to participate in something with the
product that the brand has there's too
many events that are just like a happy
hour a popup or come buy our stuff but
when you actually get some value out of
it or it gives you a reward as a
consumer that's an amazing way to tie it
together so they opened up this luggage
wash on Melrose where you could bring in
your luggage to actually get cleaned up
and washed because is anyone that has
luggage knows it can definitely get
dirty over time and there's no like
straightforward way to sit down and
clean it so they're helping people do
that for them then at the event itself
there are tons of very social media
friendly activations and things you can
do there now the downside of this
particular event was they were not
prepared for the sheer attention that it
got there was tons of people that could
not get in were not able to service
their customers their people correctly
and got some light backlash on it but
everyone that did get in had an amazing
experience and when I get into our brand
rules and pro tips here I'm going to
talk a bit through how to handle that
but I loveed this idea let's take a car
wash and apply it to luggage if you do
have a brand that has some sort of
consumer paino like that that said oh we
can't clean it or how am I going to fix
this I mean there's any number of ways
you could apply this to all kinds of
brand strategies and speaking of
customer pain points and designing your
experience I want to talk about the road
popup why I'm talking about more female
Centric Brands is they're often provide
better blueprints than men's Brands
they're often social media savvier have
better marketing activations overall and
so it's always good to look outside of
industries that you may be in to see
who's doing it well and how you can
apply that back to whatever industry
that you work in so Road had this popup
in New York and what's important to note
about this is they are primarily Aid C
brand they are not in the altas and
Sephora and all the big makeup stores so
you actually have a hard time trying and
finding their product even though it is
ridiculously popular as many of you know
I work at Van group and we did the road
website I'm familiar overall with their
strategy and the strategy of how to
position a brand online to be perceived
as luxury you to have an experience it's
amazing for consumers that website
features all these amazing features like
the website Vlog navigation the ability
to transparently see what all the
ingredients look like the art Direction
overall it's just an incredible brand
experience one of the best you can see
online and then when they translate that
into the real world it's very specific
since it doesn't happen at retail
there's a lot of pent up demand from
consumers who want to be able to see and
try the product online if you have a
brand that is primarily online you
probably have that same pent up demand
in in some variants right and to your
degree of size well Ro may have millions
of people that want to try on their
products even if you have hundreds who
say you know what how would I actually
get to even try on the sizing for a
clothing brand or learn about this
makeup or try out this you know this
electronic you have that demand that you
can tap into when you're doing an
activation so what road did here that
was smart is they had the availability
to get sold out product in person at
these events they had the ability to
actually try on something that you can't
try on anywhere else get tutorials of it
a super social media friendly setup they
took care of people in line which we'll
talk about in the Pro tips they had
little things that were extra aesthetic
like you could get matching bags to your
blush sets and things like that and then
of course the opportunity to meet
pregnant Haley Bieber might not be on
the top of my bucket list for the
weekend but for a lot of fans I'm sure
it was this video is sponsored by
skillshare reflecting on what I've tried
to learn and master this year and where
I want to improve I am currently really
focused on Art direction as you can
probably tell from a lot of my videos
and starting this month I'm trying to
actually shoot a bunch of my own photos
to use in my examples and to be more
active on my own brand shoots so in
skillshare I've started several classes
like this how to use Flash example that
we have here and this Advanced product
lighting class because lighting is
definitely my photography weak spot
whether you're looking to improve your
content toolkit like me or just
exploring marketing branding and design
and trying to learn more skillshare has
a ton of class options designed by
creatives for creatives and the first
500 people to use the link in my video
profile will get one month free to start
learning for yourself let's talk about a
less successful event so the real real
did a popup on Canal Street it was a
great conceptual event so Canal Street
for those that don't know is a place in
New York where you can go to get fake
product and before the internet era we
were in where you can basically go
online and find almost anything cloned
in China in pretty good quality he used
to have to go to a place like Canal
Street to go find your fake bag and it
would probably be pretty mediocre but
he's renowned for that infrastructure of
selling fake goods and they set up a
pop-up down there and the idea of the
popup was it was filled with items that
did not pass their authentification
check so the real real sells secondhand
luxury goods they authenticate to see if
it's real plenty of things don't pass
because often times people don't even
know they have dupes I have a story
about that from a item I have in my
interior of my house I did not find out
was a dupe until someone mentioned it on
social media when they saw it it happens
to the best of us but screw the guy the
estate sale that I got that from here we
are but they filled it with those
products they said it was closed every
day of the week on the signage and you
got the idea you could go scan a QR code
and authenticate you know and get
involved at the real real to get real
products this was interesting this was
more of like an art piece right people
walk by run by my friend ashin actually
went down there and parked on the corner
and saw a handful of people engaged but
it's not really an engagement right it's
more of a it's more like a billboard
than anything else whereas if they were
able to bring some of that energy into
something people could go in person and
be say hey do you not know if your stuff
is real come check it with us right here
it's an authentification program or and
we this will tie to Lulu Lemon here in a
moment actually come trade in your dupes
for some level of value there's a so
much more in actually getting that
engagement level and getting someone to
show up versus just making something a
billboard that even though was a great
concept I feel it falls flat compared to
what you could do in that same scenario
or you can actually just get the guys
from Pawn Stars to come down and see if
it's real or not which would be a fun
activation for any brand that does
resale which brings me to Lululemon and
one of my favorite brand activations
ever so when Lululemon was at their like
absolute Peak a few years ago and they
may have a peak again they're a brand I
have a lot of love for they had a dupe
event where basically you could come
trade in your knockoff lemon leggings
ladies out there I know you are guilty
of buying a couple of those pairs off
Amazon Prime these are just as good and
then three weeks later being like ah I'm
gonna go back to Lulu but you can
actually bring those in there and trade
those in for credit towards Lululemon
products and this was an amazing way for
them to activate consumers who may have
had a bad experience to turn it into a
good experience with them to throw
significant shade at all these knockoff
companies that were coming and get
headlines whether people attended the
brand or not and obviously it cost them
and I think I saw a headline where they
got $100,000 where C fate product turned
in so they had to give away $100,000 of
their product or whatever it was but the
Goodwill that that buys the brand sign
that it sends and then the people who
are willing to go to that activation and
meet each other and have fun and engage
with Lululemon I feel like that was an
excellent activation and again if you're
in a market where you're being
duplicated or knocked down and you want
to do something like that and maybe it
has a cost maybe have some limits
whatever it is is an awesome brand idea
that I want to have a big shout out to
their team for let's talk to how do you
have luxury events in pop-ups aren't
some huge thing so one of my favorites
that was done recently was Chanel took
over a diner and made it like a whole
Chanel Diner experience where you could
go in there engage with perfume the way
you engage with old school eating
obviously that's kind of an expensive
social media moment but for a luxury
brand they have budget for it but on a
cheaper note one I love is the Prada
flower carts so they were just really
cute Prada branded Vehicles filled with
flowers the way you'd go up to a flower
vendor there's one down here in Newport
Beach where by where I live but it's
completely Prada branded really high-end
florals and you can get a Prada UK as a
gift for your girlfriend or your friends
or your house I thought that was an
excellent example of something that it's
the cost of a branded vehicle they can
reuse again and again it's sourcing
those flowers from somewhere but the
ability to sell them at a premium with
the prodct logo on it create a social
media moment and I thought that was such
an authentic great fun brand idea that
really resonated with me on a similar
Point Mumu brand of the Year incredible
execution on products and everything
they've done had summer activations this
Summer that were amazing and they tapped
really into their audience and it's not
just the audience that like thee buyer
of Mumu but the new buyer that loves the
brand may not have engaged maybe to have
the price point or they're getting that
one Mumu piece they really love you went
to this event and they were literally
giving away ice cream and feminist
literature this is just a great example
of those aren't super expensive things
to give away it's the ability to tap
into a brand moment that has so much
resonance is so nich specific to this
type of aspirational customer that they
have who is getting to save up for that
one piece to then get a book that means
something to them that resonates with
them in the back of their head to have
that little branded ice cream portion
that they they are an example of even
though they have all the budget in the
world it's a massive brand they're
choosing to do something extremely Niche
and clever that really resonates With
Their audience and if you're a regional
brand there's a lot of opportunity as
well so when I was at the HubSpot
inbound trade show with Ashwin and
Jordan and we were doing our brand
Brothers live kind of big end of year
thing there we went to a run club with a
brand called tracksmith it's they're a
global running brand but they're based
in Boston they have a very Collegiate
Boston feel and they have a retail store
there that's gorgeous lot of old wood
feels very old New England really great
brand representation but every couple
days I think it's a couple times a week
but we went on a Friday they have people
come and do a run Club from there it's a
running brand it makes sense you meet at
the storefront they have some coffee and
croissants and stuff from the place
across the street we went on I think it
was like a 5k nothing crazy in and
around Boston and we invited a bunch of
our friends that were there for the show
they had a nice existing crowd now
there's probably a hundred people
running on any given Friday morning but
they are engaging with and supporting
their local community and because they
have a storefront it's easy enough the
employees of the storefront were leading
the Run it begins and ends there and
raises awareness of it and it was a real
Community feel and what I liked about it
is it was all walks of life there were
tons of young college kids that were out
there there was a lot of older people
that were obviously kind of trying to
get in shape and just wanted like
someone to be able to do that with I
love that idea you know run clubs are
have become almost a stereotype or
played out in people's minds but such a
great thing to engage with if you are a
running brand there's no reason that you
shouldn't be doing one what i' love
there is has such a local feel if you
have a retail storefront or have that
presence even if it's your first one
doing things like that there can really
help cement in your community I want to
shout out Bandit Runnings activation
because theirs is actually taking that
to another level so Bandit very viral
New York City brand brand I love the
running shorts I wear all the time and
they actually do it it's like an
application only run club like you have
to be going for a certain level of goal
they're like looking for those like
Achievers for Marathon or people that
are really going for it to build a
specific Community I love that idea of
taking an existing popular thing like a
run club and saying how do we put our
spin on it okay let's go for you know we
want the people who are really training
for something intense we want them on on
our in our group we're going to create a
community them it's another point of
differentiation that I love as a brand
activation idea so now let's go into
orin's rules of a great brand Activation
so the first is engage in an activity
like throwing a happy hour or just
having the ability to shop is not enough
give people something to do obviously
running and working out is great I'll
throw out some other ideas uh coming up
here in the video but centering it
around an action or an activity does so
much more the second is don't be afraid
to gain some value and educate people
like if you are throwing a makeup popup
being able to have someone to help you
do a look or determine your own style or
do your color or get getting free head
shot or whatever it is is a great
opportunity I'll shout out there's a
phoenix Studio my boy AJ used to run
that would do like a it was like once a
month they would do like an open Friday
people just come get their head shots
done I think like the first couple times
like it was their friends and then like
by a couple months in was like popping
it was like an event to be because they
basically all these like aspiring models
people need professional head shots
people want to hang out or musical
artists would be like okay I can get a
couple free photos done this day I'm
going to come hang out I'm going to
bring other people and it was like a
huge event that brought a lot of
notoriety to their studio and they'd
have like hundreds of people at
eventually from there get sponsors and
move on but the idea that you're going
to get some value you're going to come
away with a deliverable is huge this is
something I've been working on a lot as
many of you know I do like workshops
with Brands where I'll come in and do
like a social media planning session or
a positioning session we'll actually
work over the course of a couple hours
to achieve a goal versus me coming and
giving like a motivational talk which
probably less effective as motivating as
I am and then now if you're able to
apply that to a group say I was going to
throw an event here in Orange County
that's the same thing I want to do like
hey why don't I have 100 people come and
make a social media plan that's much
better than just having a meet and greet
or anything like that how do you give
somebody a deliverable to get something
out of it whether that's fashion tips or
styling tips or learning how to fix
their car or wash their luggage whatever
it is give them some value and then
making it social media friendly there's
two aspects to this the first is is
there stuff that's actually worth taking
photos much like we'll see in the Chanel
Diner or the way the mirrors are set up
making sure the lighting is good making
sure there's places where people can
very naturally take photos that aren't
corny to look good and interesting and
stand out and also represent your brand
not to that it looks good but there's
the ability to have your logo there in a
way that's natural or the product in
there in a way that's natural and then
also can you help facilitate that I was
at a Google event for the launch of like
a Google Gemini for workspace a few
weeks back where they actually had like
handlers there who literally had like
shirts or signs like we're here to help
you take photos for social media and
everyone was using it because like oh
great someone who will just you know and
they had like basically hired freelance
photographers and stuff who could come
help take your photo or help you with
your content is actually like a big come
up and I would highly recommend and last
activate your audience and then partner
to get some audience you want to
activate your local audience but also if
you have local influencers or people in
whatever whatever area you're activating
you can get involved to host or be a
part of it to work on that adding that
extra Community layer through some light
collaboration not just with another
brand but with potential influencers or
hosts is a great way to do it now we're
going to hit my Pro tips things to stand
out you may not think of when you do an
event the first is to take care of the
people in lines something they were
doing at the road event where they were
like bringing around like water with
fruit or whatever they were doing
something that didn't happen at that
base event where people were complaining
or they're hot if you're going to have a
big line or even if you expect you might
people are going be waiting for hours
like have freebies you can give away for
them make sure you have drinks and food
you can help out or snacks partner with
a local brand to be able to help on that
like give those people an experience too
because that's the worst feeling if you
wait in line for eight hours and don't
get in or had a dehydration issue that's
a brand experience you need to consider
I also recommend having a great giveaway
whatever you're going to have that
someone is doing like for the event and
taking whether it's a branded bag or
whatever it is think a bit above and
that side the box to make it interesting
and potentially viral on social media
people love free especially it's
social media friendly and if people
aren't there get them involved too so I
was giving away these Tech pack journals
at complexcon I told everyone at compcon
they could come by we gave out 200 a day
tons of people came by to get them it
was awesome to see but also we gave a
free pdf version away for everyone that
wasn't there and got almost a thousand
people that commented asking for it so
even though they're not at the event
even though we do want to create some
level of fomo for people that are at
least you have some version or a couple
of them you give away for people that
aren't there so they can also get
involved and then collaborate don't be
able to do things be afraid of doing
things between brands or with
influencers and getting others involved
1 plus one always equals more than two
then they have an extension plan A lot
of these events events you want to be
done at 5: and you realize you have a
4-Hour line just know that if that is
the case like have a plan to stay open
an extra hour or two or what happens if
you run out of stuff always be thinking
about what that good result looks like
if you're looking for a way to do this
how do you manage it all because there
is a lot you basically have to sign
people up for the event and get them
locked in you have to have your guest
list and management who gets in you have
to be able to send reminders and stuff
like that there's platforms for that I
did some content on Instagram with
paperless posts they're a great way to
do this they have a paperless Pro
platform for Brands it has like invites
and designs and SMS and all that built
in so there's like one platform to man
it I'd be thinking about you know using
one of these apps to handle that if you
have a retail location don't be afraid
to use it is an awesome opportunity and
again doesn't have to have a ton of
money involved I'm going break down some
event ideas to end out this video in a
second but like you have a location you
are losing out by not taking advantage
of it whether that's a studio or an
office space or a retail location use it
versus having to go rent out someplace
else and last don't be afraid to think
small if you don't have a lot of budget
or even if you're just trying to try
this out having an event for 20 people
can be almost just as impactful as
having an event for 200 cuz think about
how special those people will feel and
the relationships you're going to get
out of it if you do do something like
that I highly recommend thinking about
it now we're going to end with some of
my activation ideas and things you can
consider doing for your brand one that I
love is the office tour in the office
open house especially if you're
launching a new product invite a bunch
of your existing customers anyone in
your region you can parse that out in
omnisend or any of the email platforms
you have you can look by location to see
where your people are to invite them and
obviously put it out in your social
media if you invite those customers or
your locals to be able to experience a
new product and just come to your office
again doesn't have to be something super
expensive get some drinks whatever it is
get them to meet people you are
utilizing your space to help launch
something and doing more than just
putting out an email on a social post
that it exists highly recommend low lift
and a great brand activation idea and
then we have workshops what can you do
to actually get people to improve around
your product if you have a fashion brand
host a styling Workshop or you have a
pro stylist there to help people dress
and they can bring photos of their
wardrobe easy one with makeup say you
have a car accessories brand you can
offer free oil changes or teach people
how to do oil changes themselves if they
grw up without a father or whatever it
is I if that's PC or not I think about
what is a workshop they could get some
value off of customization is a great
option many of you know I spent some
time working at the shoe surgeon tons of
people would do workshops and
customization events with the shoe
surgeon we had the NFL do events with us
there where basically everyone from
large Brands to small brands that people
could bring in their shoes or they could
have white shoes that they purchased
from us and they were able to customize
those and create their own creation
there I've seen the same thing with
screen prints think arcx had one at one
point with an artist series we could
bring in your arcx and there was like a
bunch of pre-designed prints and things
that you could put on it that stuff it
goes really far and again is not super
high lift when there's swaps and meetups
this is a good example again if you
don't have a big budget customers coming
together to be able to swap garments
that they don't want anymore like
honestly as someone who has a lot of
extra large stuff I don't wear anymore
if I could go meet up with some brand
related thing and swap that with someone
else who has an XL for some things I
might like that could be huge I think
there's a lot of that there is a really
fun idea where you're just facilitating
interactions between people but it has a
purpose and then there's games and
competitions I think people
underestimate how silly and fun you can
do to actually have something like that
whether it's some sort of like turkey
sack run or you imitate whatever Olympic
games there are or you go knock off the
squid games or Mr Beast games or just
throw something in the office having a
competition or something that's
interesting especially if you're a gym
or any of those kind of things like
doing some Basics or some fun there and
like having some easy prizes is a great
way to get a community involved yes I am
thinking with lfor force and a few
others of having the old washed
influencer games where you get to see us
compete on things like a javelin throw
and everyone has to be 35 Plus if if you
guys want that if you want to sponsor it
you can just hit me in the DMS and then
last having themes so you've seen all
these lookalike contests be going really
well right now the Timothy shalloway
lookalike contest Timothy shalam look
Alik contest but whether it's a theme of
something like that or whether you're
having people dress up or doing
something in Black Tie people are
looking for an excuse to go outside
they're looking for excuse to wear their
outfits just encouraging people to wear
their craziest stuff or their most
high-end things and doing that or a 50s
night or whatever it is is an activation
in itself it allows people to have fun
one of my favorite brand activations is
born and raised has like a prom in like
Long Beach or somewhere in La that is
outrageous and people dress up fully for
it a lot of people never got to have a
prom experience for whatever reason get
to like now live that out and they had
like the old school photography and all
that just an amazing activation idea
that I absolutely love this is my video
about brand activations is a topic I
love I've done tons of events in my life
I love bringing people together
hopefully we'll be doing some whether
it's valuable events or just events for
myself or for hyper coming up soon I'll
let y'all know about when we do if
you've gone to any amazing brand
activations or have any Amazing Ideas
people should try please drop them in
the comments I'll try and aggregate some
in a future video but thank you so much
for watching
[Music]