In this video, we are going to talk
about the moment Virgil Avalo became the
greatest of all time and some of the
methods that made him a creative genius.
We've all heard the name, seen the work,
but we're actually going to go through a
bit of the history and some of the
impactful moments and what creatives can
really learn, especially now that we are
sadly becoming almost a generation
removed from when he was in his prime.
This is a video I am super excited to
make because Virgil is someone who I
highly look up to, have followed
closely, and have modeled a lot of what
I do in content and design after things
that he has done. When you're young and
you work with a lot of tasteful people,
there's always pressure when you ask
like, who's your role model? Who's your
inspiration to have some kind of
obscure, oh, it's the Czechoslovakian
designer who did this rare obscure art
direction. But as I get older and wiser,
sometimes your biggest influences might
happen to be the most mainstream.
>> Guess what, cheaty?
>> I am basic.
>> You're basic. [music]
Yeah, I noticed. And those that have
followed the full cannon of uh my
content and my creations will see a lot
of Virgil Abau stuff in there. From the
giant not a trade show bag to the tech
pack journals uh that we gave away at
Complex Con last year to the entire
purpose of this channel and this idea of
free game and just giving away as much
as humanly possible and that that only
helps and never hurts and that uplifting
and creating community inside of the
creative space is the most powerful
[music]
rewarding thing you can do. something I
have taken extremely to heart and
something that I would not be doing if
it wasn't for Virgil. So I'm excited to
go through this in this video with you.
It's a special one for me. Let's lock
in. So first I want to start by going
through the power of what some of these
books can showcase you. So you've
probably seen on my shelf in a number of
my videos. This one 123, this is a
Virgil Ablo compendium of all the things
that he designed. And something I wish I
had done from moment one as a designer
is actually just keeping everything from
the first things I put together on some
bootleg software when I was like 17 to
flyers I designed album covers t-shirts
I wish I had that entire thing cataloged
the way he did. He had the foresight to
save everything to keep it all together.
And when you look at a book like that
which I highly recommend you do and I'll
show some excerpts here. You get to
watch that progression cuz what I love
about books like this is you get to see
work that isn't very good. You get to
see it progress and change and shift and
come together all the way to being some
extremely inspiring, really rewarding
work. And I encourage anyone in the
creative space to save what you're
putting together, to start thinking
about what you would want in 10 years,
to be able to have a book like that of
your own, and to take a look at those,
to actually see the journey of a
designer, and be a part of this
generation where we can see all of this
because with the internet, we're given
more free game than ever. But we're
missing one of the key parts. The first
part I'm going to talk about in Virgil's
journey that's important is the idea of
being around a collective. So when
Virgil was first working with Kanye, he
was working with a lot of other prolific
designers in and around that at the same
time, including being in the Bent Trill
Collective. And I want to highlight like
how crazy some of this is if you don't
know this lore. So Ben Trill included
Matthew Williams, who is the creative
behind Alex, perhaps best known for
popularizing this buckle style and
creating really interesting garments on
that edge of technical wear and street
wear. And Matthew Williams later went on
to be a CD at Givvon. And this was also
at the same exact time was with Heron
Preston who as many of you know recently
just rebought his brand back when it was
brought out who's another interesting
and prolific creative but also Justin
Saunders the legend behind Jound brand I
absolutely love for the celebration of
everyday objects designer core notion
core as as friends of mine call it and
it's created a very interesting world
around the subtle and the minimal but
the fact that those three were coming up
together in and around what was
happening in the Kanye West world at the
time and created together is a really
important moment and it doesn't end with
them. There's significantly more
creatives involved. Tmaine Emory, the
creative behind Denim Tears, also
short-lived creative director of
Supreme, was the creative director of
Good Music at that time. And so, I want
to highlight we're in this internet era
that's different than that era. In that
era, you could be in and around Chicago,
New York, in these collectives of
creatives that were physically together.
And when one of them blew up, it enabled
so many of the others to learn and share
together. Reminds me of the YouTuber
anecdote with Mr. beast having a group
chat with a number of other YouTubers,
all of whom reached a certain level of
success and status. But now that we're
on the internet, now that we're enabled
with all of the free game that's out
there, more people are doing it on their
own than ever or with like a single
co-founder or just focused on their
brand. And there's a lot less of that
collective of that sharing. And if it
is, it's all done through the internet,
which is just a little bit different
because I feel like there's almost a
hesitation to share just how obsessed
you are. That's one of the things that
uh like I deal with the most. A lot of
my other friends are creators and
creatives, but I'm truly obsessed with
everything. I'm obsessed with all social
media, with all design. All I want to do
24/7 is create things, think about how
to master these things. Even when I'm
with my kid, we're like drawing and
designing stuff. He knows YouTube and
knows I'm interested in YouTube and
talks a lot about strategy and what he
sees. And you begin to build this world
around you of figuring all these things
out. And that is harder and harder on
the internet than ever. But I think
there is another generation of this
together if creatives start really
leveraging the internet to get together
in their cities to put other people on
to work together to form brands and
coexist between brands in an interesting
way. I noted in my Supreme video the
other week the power of people how
Supreme had to leverage all these
relationships know hundreds of skaters
and brands and creatives and when they
were going to release this or that or
who they were sponsoring and the
financial element of it. People that
have that skill and can move people
around like that who want to work with
other creatives. I think we're a really
powerful force and I encourage you if
you are there, send more DMs, bring more
internet into real life, connect with
more people, find people who are on that
same skill level or obsession level with
you or one level higher and really take
your relationships with them seriously.
With the holiday season coming up, I
want to talk to you about luxury brands,
sales, and positioning your brand for
sales in the holidays. And we're going
to use particle data to do it. So, if
you want to see any brand sale history
and their average discounts, you can
actually just start with the brand
inside of the particle dashboard. And
then, for instance, I'm going to go here
and I'm going to go to last year around
Black Friday. Dive in November 17th to
December 4th and hit apply. I'm going to
I can click over in the pricing tab and
I can immediately see some of their
bestselling products and what was on
sale in this type of view. Or I can go
into the sales tab and you'll see this
column that says average discount. So,
Acne Studios last year ran a 40% off
holiday sale, which is a super solid
holiday sale for Acne. Um, and they
actually included some of the products
that people like, like those ultra baggy
jeans, the heeed boots. And I can sort
by discount here. So, I actually see the
volume. They sold 13 of these, 23 of
these, 25 of these logo TE's. Not only
can I see what the discount was, but I
can see what actually was sold using
that discount. And I like to show them
to start off that even if you have a hot
brand or a luxury brand, that doesn't
mean you shouldn't do sales. And when
you look at Acne's whole history, they
very rarely do it. But every year on
Black Friday, they tend to do something.
Now, going over to a a true luxury
brand, Bautga Vanetta. Acne is more of a
designer brand. And you will see there's
basically no discounting in this period,
even on site, but they still get sales
spikes. People are still buying. There
is just not a big emphasis on
discounting. And that is because these
bigger luxury brands when they do
discount, they move that through retail
and outlets and don't do that on Maine
for the most part. And you'll see they
still benefit. If you have that level of
following, you can still execute a sale.
But this isn't always the case. So
Burberry is a really interesting one cuz
in this time period last year, they were
kind of going through a reckoning of
where they wanted their brand to go. And
they did actually liquidate a ton of it.
So they actually ran 50% off 49ish on a
lot of core items last year in this time
period and moved a decent amount of
units for it. And so just worth noting
that there's this conversation you
should never discount if you're a
premium position, luxury position. And
that is definitely not the case. There's
just ways that they navigate it. And I
highly recommend for any brand executing
that one sale a year or really thinking
through what you want to do and how you
want to position it. But it's not
necessarily a bad thing. And for any
category that you want to explore this
in, Particle is an amazing tool for
this. You can literally go brand by
brand, whether you are in the fashion
category, interior design, as long as it
is sold online. I believe the majority
of websites are in Shopify, you are able
to see exactly what they do down to the
actual sales, so the pricing they chose,
the amount of volume they had. It's
really useful to help predict what's
going to happen in your niche and plan.
In addition, they also have a ton of the
assets. They have homepage screenshots.
You can actually search for assets that
contain the word sale and you're able to
get a really clear picture of what
brands do and execute and what they
release then to help you plan for your
own brand so you don't have to make
those decisions in a vacuum. So,
Particle has actually put together a
Black Friday guide to help you prep that
you can get free at the link below. And
thank you so much to them, my OG YouTube
partner, for sponsoring this video. The
next iconic moment I want to walk
through on the way to Virgil becoming
the goat is his use of iconography. So,
the zip tie being perhaps the most
famous of these, often replicated, a
signature that was immediately known,
something people kept on their shoes.
The Off-White is elevated and progressed
and utilized in interesting ways over
time, but was a completely unique part
of his iconography. And there was some
iconography that came in and out the way
we had this kind of construction yellow
belt. I still have one of the bags I
have from this era with this belt. But
also even knowing that, hey, at some
point this got played out and was an
important piece of iconography or
something like the zip tie managed to
iterate forever. And if you've seen any
content on this, you've learned about
the 3% rule, and you've seen all this
back and forth about iterations and him
taking for the iconic arrows from things
like the Glasgow airport. I'm not going
to go into that, but I do think that the
idea of signatures in our current
creative era where anyone can make
anything and then they still choose to
make just like more heavyweight TE's is
a really interesting thing to think
through. But moving on to collabs, there
were three collabs on this journey I
really want to highlight that I feel are
the most important. And one of those is
with Allessie. One of the most important
things about Virgil's arc was that it
didn't encompass just clothing. And it
had that fanatical obsession with
wanting to make anything. People often
say when they look at my content,
they'll be like, "How can you be this
into so many things? How how do you know
so much about this or that?" Or, "How
have you done so many things in your
life or your career?" A lot of it was
inspired by this by someone saying, "Oh,
you have a background in architecture,
but you did street wear, but you want to
design cutlery." And I think it was
really important to be able to have role
models that do that and are successful
and executed at some degree of being
good at it. and who know that their
angle and their approach and their
obsessions can kind of translate to
these different mediums in ways that
might be unexpected. And so this collab
with Allessie uh in cutlery that's
underappreciated, under showcased, you
know, $745 field set might be one of the
reasons, but this uh the conversational
objects on the table, which I'm debating
getting for this holiday. You'll see in
a video if I if I do end up purchasing
it, do it.
Uh, but the idea of being able to find
and have this kind of almost absurdest
screw that would be on a table with
people taking off their cutlery on it,
but also have it done by a legendary
design house for kitchen wear like
Allessie. It was an interesting collab
that broke out of the expectations you'd
see. Same thing with the IKEA collab.
When this launched, this was a huge
deal. Um, I own a number of things from
this collection. This daybed is actually
the bed my kid had until he was like
six. Like there's something to be
growing up on a virgil day day bed for
your creativity. The sculpture bag is
what houses all my samples around
currently. The wet grass rug is actually
sitting on the shelves right over there.
But this was again that that moment of a
streetear designer bringing their
iconography, their feeling that had been
invoked inside of fashion into not just
furniture but accessible furniture.
While he had designed many more
expensive and interesting things, this
brought this into every home and it
sparked interest. Now, it became so
ubiquitous and became a stereotype at
some point that it would be like the
default thing for a certain type of guy
to buy, but it was also an entryway for
so many more people to think about not
just their personal style, but the style
of their homes, a gateway into more
furniture, more art, some of the more
playful nature of this work. But perhaps
the most important collab would be the
Nike the 10 collab where he
reinterpreted 10 Nike sneakers in his
unique style. And this is an interesting
moment both for Virgil and for Nike. I
feel like this is the last great moment
that we had from Nike and they've had
many, many great moments prior in sports
and celebration, what they've done with
marathons. I'd say this breaking two
came after. So maybe this was probably
the last true proper great moment
they'll have. When it comes to design
and footwear, we haven't seen signatures
from Nike that are any good for a long
time. One of the things I discuss a lot
with my basketball group chat is just
how bad signature shoes have gotten,
right? You look at Jason Tatum shoe or
Luca's shoe, the Giannis ones are okay.
Uh they're really bad. John Morant,
really bad. Not the kind of things your
kids are going out there like really
excited to get, right? They're not into
basketball shoes the same way that we
were. It's not exciting to get the team
shoe. If they are, it's the Anthony
Edwards shoe with Adidas and just how
far that Nike has shifted. But with
Virgil in the 10, he spotlighted all of
Nike silhouettes. He was able to put his
twist and have enough of an iconography
and a base and design sentiment to make
every one of these unique and sought
after in a different way that brought so
much exposure to him to Nike's audience
to Nike to be able to you know basically
I think bring a lot of interest to some
of these shoes from here. I think this
is part of what turbocharged the blazer
coming back even the prestos. There's a
lot that this did for the Nike lineup
for kind of years of ripple effects to
come. that I encourage every designer,
every person with a fashion brand to
think if I was to be able to go not just
do a single collab or so one-off collab
based. If you were to get complete
access to every Adidas shoe, every Nike
shoe, to the entire Polo Ralph Lauren
catalog, do you have enough to be
inspired by? Do you have enough
iconography to dive in and put pieces
together for that? And then what would
it take to get there? Right? It's all
about that journey and where that goes.
This is something I think about a lot as
someone who's lent it into their
creativity more later in their career.
like what does it take to build that
body of work? Because it's never too
late. I think the best way to put it is
it's never too early to start thinking
big and it's never too late to begin
putting the pieces together. But what
most people would assume would be the
greatest moment for Virgil would be when
he became the CD of men's for Louis
Vuitton debut show in 2019. Um his
ability to improve over time, you saw
the clothes increase in their efficacy,
in their style, his ability to utilize
the catalog they have. And so to get
some understanding of what it looks like
when you actually step into these roles,
you're working with a big established
team that they already have. Plus,
you're bringing in your own creatives.
You have a lot of pre-existing things to
work through. And you have to just churn
out so many designs, be able to produce
the concepts and the actual production
behind these shows. Leverage both your
network and their network to make
something. And that's where something
like this becomes special because
sometimes you call people, they don't
have enough creatives to tap in to be
able to do the scale of the work
necessary to execute on something like
this. Even I see him then we see
something like Infel's era now where
he's bringing in all these people but
they're not new creative talent. He's
celebrating an era with his kind of
collaborators and really leaning on
Louis Vuitton's team. That's fine. It's
just a different approach. Whereas here
you could tell they were bringing in
every creative that he was excited about
working with, leveraging all of his
connections and ideas and really working
tirelessly on how they make this
particularly interesting. But the moment
I want to talk about the most important
part of his art that I think separated
him to become the greatest of all time
separate from where we entered into from
him passing away or anything is when he
released this free game collection where
he said I am going to show all of you in
12 steps and a site that's up to this
day how to make a brand. And this
explosion of street wear that we've seen
all of these independent brands the
entire Instagram and Tik Tok era at the
end of the day comes down to this web
page and the knowledge from this has
disseminated out to thousands of brands
right where he's saying here's how you
get a trademark here's how you use Adobe
here's what a screen print is here's how
you find blanks here's how you shoot a
lookbook here's how you make a website
how you get on Shopify and ideas and
lectures that are all put together and
then kind of further inspiration and
this set off a ripple effect not just in
the designers had been able to do this,
but in the idea of giving away so much
of this that now you've seen tons and
tons of creators give away their factory
links, show the complete behind the
scenes of their process, talk through
everything, and realize that there's no
negative from that. That if people copy
you, they're never going to have the
ripple effect of what you're able to do
by giving so much away. That so few
people actually act and the ones you
enable tend to be the ones that are most
interesting and creative and inspired
that then look up to you in a different
way. And then just the value and the
nature of the universe of how much you
give out then how much comes back. And
it's really just a moment of legacy. I
do want a lot of creatives and people
who are watching that to start thinking
in that way as well because when you
start to achieve a certain degree of
success, you get more money. You find
those things in life that really matter
and you realize it's spending time with
people you love. It's doing interesting
ideas. It's less about how much money
you have in the bank or what the
lifestyle that you flex is. You begin to
think about what are the ripple effects
of the things that you do. And I know I
have found way more value and
satisfaction in my life giving away a
ton of things that I own for free and
gotten immense value back far more than
I would have expected. That finding your
own version of how you can either
cultivate community or give the things
that you've learned away to the next
generation is just a really powerful
thing to consider. But anyway, along
that line, I'm going to give a bunch of
things away in this video. So, uh, I
have a blanks guide I used to sell that
was with all the different blanks
companies and merchandise packs and
stuff. That's just going to be free
listed down here. Same thing with I did
this tech pack journal with Crease Group
is one of my manufacturers. Their info
is in it. Um, but we basically did this
and we gave these away at Complex Con,
but I still have some. I think I'm going
to actually do like a drop selling them
later on. But for now, I'm going to give
away the actual digital version of that
with that blanks guide down there. So,
this has pants, this has hats, it has
blank pages if you want to sketch and
diagram them, um, and some notes, etc.
So, you can get the digital version of
that for free. I'm also going to give
five of these away that I will mail
comment like where how I can I can find
you and I will hunt through a couple of
the creatives and I will give five of
these and send y'all an actual physical.
And I'm thinking of going even bigger
and we're getting this channel's getting
towards 100K. I want to do like a big
giveaway for that.
>> What's his name? What's his name? I got
nothing to name
out.
>> Whether it's just of like stuff or
whether it's all digital or like every
resource. I'm not I'm not sure yet and
thinking through that, but we'll
probably do another like big moment
through that. But just in general, a
reminder to be pushing out just more of
the things you have that could bring
value to others. So, I know similar to
some of the videos I've done, but a
little bit different today. I could not
recommend that you pick up [music]
figures of speech or one of these other
books. And I would encourage all of you
to go look at what your iconography
could be. Think about what your vision
for 1015 years is from now. Document the
things that you have. Work in
collectives uh with others. I want every
single one of you out there to be
creating something special that you are
super excited about and to be doing it
with each other. And so I'm just putting
that out there in the universe. I hope
that happens. And overall, I appreciate
y'all so much. Hope you found some value
in this video. And thank you so much for
watching.
[music]