Well, well, well, here we are again for
the arts of the marketing campaign. I'm
trying to make the most valuable video
that I have made yet. Let me know if
I've made it happen. But in this video,
I'm going to define every term and
concept that goes into the planning and
execution of a marketing campaign. We're
going to go through putting together
strategies for campaigns, content plans
for modern campaigns, extensions of a
campaign, working with retailers and
partners and building your brand world
around a launch or a big moment. We're
going to talk about ultra-modern
approaches to take. I'll have a dozen
examples of products that I have worked
on, awesome campaigns that I respect,
software, products. Try to have a whole
gamut, so no matter where you are at in
your marketing journey, you can learn
something. I cannot be more excited to
hit this because I love a good campaign.
Let's lock it. So, first let's talk
about what a campaign is. When you are
in marketing or have a brand, you need
to get attention to things that you do.
But most likely that is going to be
around the launch of something. A new
product, a new feature, the announcement
of your company, or something seasonal.
Like you may have a fall campaign or a
summer campaign. But it's designed to
bring attention and sales to the brand
you work for. And so, I look at the
starting of this always as strategy.
This video is broken into three
sections: strategy, content, and then
the world outside of just your brand.
What do we mean by strategy? When you're
coming up with a launch idea to market
something, generally you are going to
have the why. What are we doing? What is
the anchor? Then you're going to have
your channels to market it. We're going
to talk through three types of those.
And then you're going to have all the
places that it lives in the world. So,
let's break that down. Typically, if you
are launching a product, or even if
you're doing a seasonal more conceptual
campaign, it's going to start with an
insight or a concept. So, an insight is
something that you or your team have
discovered about your customer. Problem
that they have, a thing that they do,
that you are going to capitalize on to
help market and sell your product. love
to use greens as a great example of
this. They have a product that basically
says everyone wants to have their
greens. There's a huge popularity of
stuff like athletic greens and AG1
because people know they need greens.
But the insight is the current
experience to get your greens sucks.
Wouldn't you prefer if it had a sweet
but not too sweet gummy to get all that
same stuff instead? And in particular,
kids, there's no way that they're going
to do it. So, let's get them everything
they need. That is an insight. Another
example of one I was working through
recently as many of you know, I work in
my day job in cosmetics. We had an
insight around buying multiple of an
item that a consumer loves. So, for
instance, they have a favorite shade of
lipstick or a SPF they really like. They
treat it as a luxury, treating
themselves to go get multiple of those
to have backups when it goes away.
That's a consumer habit that we could
play into as an idea for a campaign. And
so, when you go to market something, you
will have either this insight or a
concept. And a concept can be something
that's just like a really interesting
visual presentation. Sometimes you have
both a consumer insight and a concept
for the campaign. Sometimes if you have
no strong insight, you need to make up
for it with a strong concept. But you
are going to want to tie the entire
campaign into the point that you want to
get across. What do we want to make sure
our consumer knows that they're going to
resonate with, it's going to get them to
buy? And how do we package that so that
they're really into it? And to do this,
you have these three methods. First is
core. Core is basically your marketing
efforts, what you already do and have
access to and can afford. So, for
instance, for a really small business,
core may be the Instagram account that
you post to and you're not on other
social media. The website you have that
already gets some traffic, your retail
store you have a sign you can put in the
front. That would be your core. That's
what you have to work with. Now, if
you're a more typical business, you have
your Instagram account, your TikTok
account, one or two people on your team
that make social media, like a founder,
your email list, your SMS list, your
website, you have an SEO program, you're
running ads. You have like all these
different pieces of your marketing
campaign. And you're going to want to
think, how do we deploy all of those to
support this campaign? Then we have
extensions. This is tier two. So, for
instance, if you are in retail, if you
are a gloves brand and you sell gloves
inside of sporting goods stores, you
want to be able to work with your
retailer to help support that campaign.
Sometimes that means you're spending
money advertising with them. Sometimes
that means they will actually do a
cross-post with you, or they have a
newsletter to feature it in. They have
programs where they market together. Can
even be you doing a pop-up event in
their store, that kind of thing. And
then partners, other people that may be
involved. Partners could be an
influencer you have a long-time deal
with. It could be another company that
you co-promote with who has an extension
or an API from your software. Who are
people in network that will also help
promote at the same time? And then the
third segment, one that is really
overlooked, is your existing customer
base. And how do they get involved? One
classic example of this is that if you
are releasing something, well, something
I encourage many brands to do is offer
to your existing customers first. If you
were around for the last drop of the
clothing merchandise brand I have, and
you had bought from us before, you will
notice you got an email from my wife
basically being like, "Hey, we're
putting on a new drop. Do you want
anything ahead of time for this to make
sure it doesn't sell out? And because
you're a customer, you can get
customer-only pricing before launch."
And it was a one-to-one email to
basically every VIP. And no matter what
kind of company you have, whether you're
reaching out to 10 people or your top
customers, or using something like Our
Signal, it's like a software that
scrapes your different customer profiles
and types and analyzes people that are
more important, or you're doing it to
everybody, how do you involve them to
not only buy, but help tell your story?
Could they promote for you? You want to
involve that in your planning process.
How do we integrate the customer? And
then last is going to be merchandising.
It's kind of like an exterior category,
but worth mentioning. So, if you are in
stores and you have displays or cards or
videos that play. If you have a store or
a function, anything that could be a
billboard for your brand that exists,
how are you going to dress it up or
change it for this? A good example would
be if you have a product that's sold in
Ulta or something like that where they
have a gondola, there's so much of
graphics promoting your brand. Is it
worth it swapping it out? How could you
do that to promote what you're
launching? And so, an example of putting
a strategy together for this, I want to
talk about a brand I used to work for, a
brand called Gel Blaster. And you're
going to have I see a bunch of examples
of brands I've worked on through this.
You'll see some kind of different types
of strategies there. And so, we were
launching a product with Costco. a
product called the Gel Blaster Nova. It
was a two-pack. We had never launched a
bundled pack, only ever single blasters.
We also knew that the Costco customer
likes a deal. So, we wanted to take
advantage of a Costco-only product to
offer discounting. Our brand did not
discount much at that time. So, as we
put together that strategy, we had the
big YouTube video we put out on our
channel. We were going to run
advertising on some other channels. We
had our core TikTok content and
Instagram and everything there. You can
see me doing a tutorial video, talking
through the basics of the blaster and
what's inside the box. founder who had
social media talking about the new
product as well. But we knew we needed a
reach strategy that would go beyond us.
We worked a ton with influencer, and we
needed a concept. Because it was a
blaster pack, we got into all these
ideas of could we do video game
scenarios and people versus other people
and have that play out. And we briefed a
large number of influencers specifically
for this Costco launch product going
into the holiday season to raise the
awareness of it. That brief smashed. And
then we had some amazing creators who
did a great job. An example here from
Wes. He's doing video game style POV
where you have the map, you have these
little effects, and he's doing all of
these who had the best fatality,
basically. It has 299,000
likes. He had millions and millions of
views on YouTube on this. This is just
one of many creators we briefed this.
But the best part is this was one of our
small influencers. He was a micro at the
time. He had I think 10 or 20,000
followers, maybe 50. But the idea, the
concept, how they executed the concept,
the teams in between, it all adds up to
the awareness level of the product as
part of the campaign. And you would see
a bunch of videos of people doing
different stuff. You would see these
video game scenarios, you would see
these competitions, and the brief
followed this overall theme that then
attached to the launch video, that
attached to what you would see in store.
And for example, in Costco in
merchandising, this was a product that
was out on pallets. So, there's a lot of
stores that will just take big boxes of
product on a pallet, and you don't
actually get them on shelf, you get them
just sitting there on full pallets or
half pallets out inside the shopping
environment. But you can then design the
corners and sides of that, which we do
to accentuate the value propositions we
have for the category. And all the cool
things that come with the Gel Blaster
experience. Now, we're going to bridge
into content, the idea of modern content
for campaigns, because that is the most
important thing for most brands where
the biggest upside is right now is
organic content. And so, what do I mean
by that? I mean that when you create
content to launch a product or do a
marketing campaign, you create content
on your organic platform. If it's good
content, it will go far larger than
whatever your follower count is, right?
Follower count does not matter on main
social algorithms much. But also, great
performing organic content and that
content there is going to be great to
then feed into your ad account. So, all
the stuff you create for the campaign,
you want to have some variations for
ads. You want to be able to test some of
the organic posts as ads, and it works
well there. With that, you're also going
to be enabling and taking some of the
things that work in the concepts and
putting them out to influencers and UGC
creators to create more ads or to get
more organic reach. This is the method
that works the most for most brands,
including software, including physical
products, that happens today. Is they
follow this cycle. And for any type of
business, this framework that I'm about
to walk through for content will make a
lot of sense to you. We'll look at some
examples to start. This is a company
called Break Archive. They are a
reseller store. And I want to talk about
their Black Friday campaign. So, if
you'll notice, they put out what we call
a teaser to start. It's a news chyron,
crash is coming. They have some stuff
about investment. Obviously, Black
Friday you get a lot of Black Friday
market crash stuff as a common recurring
theme many brands use. And they had a
carousel of breaking news of all
conceptual stuff related to this. And
another carousel of Breakman sacks
concept announcing the sale. More of
these kind of old school style and
carousels with sticky notes. And then
they had the actual debut where they had
this model making basically a joke about
investing in the value of the product,
speaking to that insight. The core
insight here being that these bags are
an investment, right? The Hermes
outperforms the S&P. They turned that
into their hot girl guide to investing.
Then they had basically a meme carousel.
This is a carousel designed to be shared
about this concept. It's a more typical
content, had another round of making the
shareable memes for this. Another
promotional post, another carousel set
there, another card item, going and
going to the point I want to count this
out. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14, I
believe 15 posts just around the launch
of their Black Friday campaign. That is
a typical well-executed campaign. And
this is actually how I structure a ton
of the work that I do whenever we go
into a launch. For instance, I take
ideas for teasers and reveals, different
styles of content. I take ideas for
unveils, which is the moment when the
product is actually shown, and the ideas
for core product, and ideas for UGC, and
I create examples and briefs for all of
them. So, let's roll through each part
of this. The first we see teaser. How do
you create some excitement for the
campaign before you launch it, let fans
know it's coming? That's category one,
it needs its own content. That's
low-stakes content. If it does great,
awesome. If it doesn't, don't worry
about it much, you don't invest a huge
amount on it. Then we have unveil
content. Unveil content is the first
time you see the product or the thing
you're announcing. What does that
experience look like? And that's a
different than the launch. Cuz often
it's the moment of discovery of oh, this
is the thing that's happening. And used
to be the companies want to put it all
in a one big video. That's not the
zeitgeist anymore. Much like the example
of Break Archive with 15, 15 is
typically the amount of content pieces I
go for on a breakdown tier. My boy Alex
Garcia did it, it's another one where
they had like 21 or something like that.
That is the right amount of content to
put out for a launch on your organic
feed. So, you have the teaser, a poster
or two. You have the unveil, showing it
for the first time. Again, depending on
how big your launch is, what you have.
It's another one to three posts actually
debuting the thing that you have. And
then you have the launch, the piece of
the campaign. That was the the hot girl
investing portion that we saw on the
Break Archive. That's the actual core
video, like the big shot you have on
goal. And we usually what you'll do
there, if you're smart, is you'll take
multiple shots. You won't put all your
eggs in the basket of one video in the
social media era when you can have some
slight recuts and differences and
moments of that that give you multiple
shots at launch. And a great example
there was when they did that core video,
but they also used a bunch of still
frames from it to create carousels. Some
a little more meme-friendly than others.
And say, "Hey, let's get a shareable
moment in a carousel format." That
didn't take them significantly more
production time. They just thought about
what the post strategy would be. Then
after the launch is extend. How much
more are you going to post about the
product? So, back to the Gel Blaster
example, when we would release products,
we would have the teaser, we would have
the launch video, we would have our big
influencers go, then we would do
tutorials, and it would be the founder
or myself or one of the team members
breaking down what's all the things in
the box. What are the answers to
commonly asked questions? And those
videos don't get tons of views, but
they're really helpful to actual
customers, and they're bottom-of-funnel
content that helps people buy. So,
actually unboxing it. How do you use it?
And doing that in social-friendly
vertical formats is really impactful.
And I always get people being like,
"Well, you can't do any of this for B2B
SaaS." Like, yes, you can. You can have
a conceptual launch video. You can then
do the walk-through of the interface and
how people use it. And then you can have
someone on your team sit there with the
computer, split screen it, and go, "I'm
going to answer commonly asked
questions." And ideally have some
personality or a funny example that will
at least make it tenable to watch. You
can follow this exact format. In
addition to this extend portion, you
will also have performance. This is what
you want to run for ads. So, your ads
team will likely have a bunch of
requirements of ads that they want to
run. This is an empty version of my
toolkits where I'll have teas, unveil,
launch, what we have for organic, what
we're going to do for UGC, which is
basically getting creators to you know,
paying them to do videos that go on your
feed or to go into ads, paid-only stuff.
And I have a checklist. This is just a
checklist of for most of the campaigns I
do, a problem-solution ad, a founder
story ad, a selfish desire ad, a reply
ad. We reply to a comment, magazine
editorial, a user with a testimonial
static. I have like a list of ads, and
so will most marketers. You make a list
of what you need to go down for every
launch to help your ads team out. And
then, big one that people don't spend
enough time thinking through is refresh.
Two to weeks to two months down the
line, you're going to run out of
traction on your launch, and you're
going to have to drive more attention
for it. What are you going to do? And
can you shoot a lot of that up front or
shortly after or make a plan to say,
"Actually, we're going to do wave two.
Every UGC person we contracted in wave
one, we actually have a second concept
or theme or insight that we're going to
tap into that we're going to launch 60
days later." If you've prepped that and
done that messaging in your launch, or
if you have a plan to respond to the top
comments and the things that come from
the launch to then engineer it, now you
are thinking like a marketing campaign.
And I will put this breakdown inside the
description, too. But this method is
used by brands small and large to launch
their products. Another example to look
at is Patrick Ta. They did a conceptual
campaign called The Menu, where they
teased with this Let Him Cook apron,
unveiled the product just showing what
the front is, but still it was like half
teaser, half unveil, have some vignettes
of food being made, coming soon 10/6,
carousel of the product being put in the
napkin, but again an unveil, but not a
full launch. You're seeing what it is,
but it's almost ready. Table's almost
ready. Now we have a true unveil,
24-hour early access. Here's what the
product is. Here is a proper launch
style video. It's breaking down that
it's three eye palettes. Now we have a
big product showcase video in a more
typical style, and they're going into
the full launch. And this is kind of an
excellent example of how to roll through
something. So, back to what we started
with. Insight or concept. They probably
had an insight driving this product.
This was a conceptual launch, so they
went with the food theme. They got the
apron. They put together the set for the
menu reveal. They had him chopping,
putting together the food. They used the
napkin. A lot of art direction choices.
Then they went into more typical release
content, basically went down their
checklist, did the same thing inside
their advertising account. We
merchandised where they were inside
beauty retail. That is the anatomy of a
launch. Many of you know Alex Garcia
from Sweat Equity, who I run Cut 30
with, the program where we train
creators. And if you do, you know that
he creates content for brands. I work
for a private equity group that owns
brands. I help facilitate content on,
have some brands of my own. He operates
an agency that helps make content. He's
very focused on social shows. He and I
both have great videos about that, but
also does launch content. And he worked
on a campaign for the Tier Mavericks.
Tier is a sports company. They launched
a shoe called the Maverick. Their teaser
was with a mad scientist. I got to
disclose who I am. I was a scientist put
on an undisclosed case. They have a
teaser reel, all this drone footage and
stuff happening from that person's
perspective. For six months is all I saw
and experienced being in the desert.
From the scientist's perspective.
Another foreshadowing of what the
campaign is, a carousel where you're
getting a peek. You saw the shoe in the
first slide. And then getting into a
proper launch. They have a whole
scientist lab set that's built out. They
have this training curriculum to another
video. And another video. Into another
carousel. Now they're outside in another
video. And another with uh a carousel.
And another carousel. This one's
awesome. This is a uh an FPV drone
version. And you [clears throat] get the
point. 1 2 3 4. So, we now let's count
up. How many do we have in this launch?
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16
17 18 19 20 21 22 pieces of content
filmed in two locations, right? With a
concept, with a bunch of actors, as well
as athletes and stuff that are on the
team, maybe they're team members. But
again, back to the point of why business
couldn't do this. If you have a staffing
agency and you say a mad scientist
cooked up our latest method for staffing
and just had some fun with it and
involved some of the people around it or
put together your skit or whatever it
was about the staffing agency having to
go do something out of the ordinary or
be stand-ins for the staff at a wedding
last second. I don't know, you come up
with any level of concept, you can make
it more exciting. And again, uh a lot of
people bulk at oh, I have to go do a
campaign shoot, right? I have to spend
10 grand to 500 grand on something.
Well, if you're spending that money and
you get 22 assets, it's going to go a
lot better than if you get the one to
two. Something that Alex and I have both
tapped into in where we work and where
we preach to people in Cut 30 is that if
you come in with a plan, that one-day
shoot that you had at that location
where you used to get two assets, if
someone's social-savvy knows what
they're doing, you can come out with 10.
And if you follow what we talked about
for that outline of the campaign, you
are well on your way to doing it. My
biggest pro tip I can give there is
outlining as much beforehand. People
will go and shoot all this footage and
be like, "We'll make content." And they
end up making two things. Come in with a
plan. We're going to do a meme carousel,
like we saw in Break Archive. We're
going to do a normal carousel. A teaser
that's a single shot. A teaser that's a
carousel. This video, this take on the
video that's shot on a wide-angle lens.
This where we do the FPV. Can we see
come up with all your concepts ahead of
time to know what assets you're
executing? Cuz you're never going to get
it from just shooting and figuring it
out after. And if your production firm
doesn't know how to handle this or
doesn't know what to do with this kind
of thing, they are the wrong firm.
They're not set up to succeed in the
modern era. They will be stoked to get
into this and realize where things are
going and not charging you more for it.
Or you find one that does, of which
there are plenty of creatives out there.
And people talk about software. I also
talk about budget when it comes to a lot
of this. Software, consumer apps, B2B
apps is a great example. This website
Social Growth Engineers is a good one to
uh look at around this. They'll break
down like New Manifestation app hits 50
million views with a faceless TikTok
format and a dream hook. Here's how they
did it. And they charge for the
subscription or whatever. But there you
will see a lot of very low-fi content
with great concepts put out across
multiple accounts to get interest to
things. I'm showing high production and
stuff cuz I work in a high production
world. But as we see again and again in
Cut 30, that production matters a lot
less than you think. And then this is a
great website for in software in
particular showing you how people are
doing this with ideas, carousels, AI,
etc. to promote concepts. And perhaps
the best example of this is a brand
people are a little loath to talk about,
but Cluey. And I understand why. So,
you're not familiar with Cluey, it's a
cheating app that now pivoted to an AI
note-taker. And it actually doesn't
matter what they do. They are excellent
at marketing. They have not figured out
an app. They have not built a real
product that people care about, which
ideally you do first before you get good
at marketing. But they're at least a
great person to look at about being good
at marketing. They put out really
thoughtful launch videos that are funny
and entertaining and get people to get
bought in on what they're doing and
excited about it and get a ton of views.
They have their core anchor content.
They then have their organic presence
where they're doing lots of viral hits.
And then they have this creator flywheel
that Katie runs for them. Katie's a
frequent guest on Cut 30. She's spoken
to us a bunch, like educating people
about it, a great resource for stuff
like this. But she helps them generate
viral creatives through networks of
people. They will find an idea and then
multiply it through dozens to hundreds
of creators. And based on your budget or
the results of it, you can go to more
and more or less and more. Start with
five or 10 or 100. There's tons and tons
of places to source these or hire your
own or just DM people on TikTok to get
it. But these are examples of companies
who will kind of by any means necessary
get to where they're going around this.
It's a modern launch format, like I
mentioned. And related, you'll see this
even um with large B2B companies. So
HubSpot's a perfect example. How does a
traditional company handle this? So for
instance, I was part of a HubSpot
launch. I was at HubSpot Inbound.
HubSpot will host a huge trade show. And
events are a great thing to have in a
marketing campaign. They don't need to
be as big as HubSpot's. HubSpot's is
absolutely massive cuz they're a massive
company. But whether your event just has
your VIP customers come to your office
or hosts a Zoom for top people or you do
tag it on to a trade show. We used to do
this all the time in my previous life
when I worked in consumer drones. We
would launch products at a big show like
NAB. It was it's a big show like audio
video. We would launch something there
with a big booth. We try to get resale
orders at the time. So piggybacking onto
an event is a core thing you can add to
your marketing campaign strategy.
HubSpot hosts their own event. They're
big enough to do that. They launched
through all their channels. So they have
their own big social media. They will
put out they launched loop marketing at
the last inbound. That the funnel is now
a looped concept that probably heard me
explain that resonates with a lot of
people and then changes how you use
their software suite. They launched it
there. They had their own big YouTube
channel with a million followers that
they're putting out content about it
along with their top creators. They have
their own Instagram. They had a bunch of
us influencers there. I was there making
content about loop marketing. So were a
bunch of other creators with different
audiences and different types to expand
out that way. Then they have their own
media network of all the podcasts and
people that they sponsor. They have
their own advertisements. They take that
message. They anchor it into a core
moment. Lock in on their organic. They
spread it out wide with influence. And
it's just talking to B2B instead of
talking to B2C. And it's really about
doing that at the scale that you're at.
Again, if you are small enough that
you're just doing it on a Zoom with 100
people that came in from your email list
where they get a first look and get to
have one-on-one time with your CEO and
then spread through the five employees
and 10 friends on Twitter. You can
follow the same methodology to get your
campaign out there. If you want to take
more ownership of your campaigns at
work, build a solid foundation for your
own brand or market your services, then
this free creator toolkit from TikTok
and HubSpot is exactly what you need.
I've partnered with them to break it
down for you cuz the best way to learn
all of this that we're talking about is
to really be in the mix as a creator to
learn the tactics. Even if it's entirely
different niche that you experiment in,
the skill set itself is crucial to
understanding how the internet works.
And that's where this toolkit comes in.
Inside, you'll find info on the tech
stack for content creation, example
prompts for developing and refining
inspiring content specific to a target
audience. And how to run lead gen ads to
support your products, your agency, or
your business. My favorite part is
definitely the prompts. They're
particularly useful for ChatGPT and
Claude to tie your content plan back to
your audience's needs, the insights I
talked about at the beginning of this
video. They help you refine that.
Looking to help put real process behind
your content creation and a better
structure for using content to drive
business, then this is for you. You can
get the toolkit for free at the link in
the description of this video. And thank
you so much to HubSpot for sponsoring
this video. So more examples that I have
worked on here, I want to talk about
this brand Lift Foils I worked with on
their marketing for years. It's a
hydrofoil surf brand and used this to
begin talking about getting into a
world. So Lift was a really awesome
place to work because of the marketing
opportunities we had in the space that
were really unique. So it's a viral
product by nature, watching people fly
above water. What was most interesting
is we had a world around the brand. What
do I mean by that? We had people that
operated rental stands to use these all
over the world and also functioned as
resellers. We had hundreds of these
people all around. And so what we would
do when we put together the launch, we
had these immaculately produced launch
videos and a bunch of social launch
assets. All of these people had their
own Instagram and TikTok accounts and we
would feed them content consistently.
That was part of my job. I was running
the content in the main social. I was
working with the video and production
teams and all the sponsored athletes to
make more content. And I was aggregating
it in the one place. So here's an
example of how the world will work. We
had a couple sponsored surfers. They're
giving us content. I'm giving them
examples of stuff we need. They're
working with different people on our
team. We're putting it on our page.
We're seeing what performs. I'm taking
the raw content from that and pre-edited
stuff and putting into a folder our
affiliates can use on their pages.
Affiliates was the name of our resellers
and rental partners. So they then got
access to that content they could post
on their own and make their own edits
with. In turn, a lot of them made really
good content. If they did, they could
request to do a collab post with us
getting them more exposure and allowing
us to get more content. And I
facilitated a bunch of relationships
with those people specifically around
content. The good ones would be the same
thing. Hey, can we get the good content
that you have? Let's use that on our
main page to help promote other things
that are going on or to run as ads, etc.
And we could do profiles. So for
instance, it was symbiotic to be able to
get awesome videos from our partners
promoting themselves that we also
promoted to promote the product and use
them together on our channels to run ads
with them, etc. And of the hundreds of
partners, probably about 10% made
really, really good content. So you
basically began to get a network when we
were launching where I wanted them to
have the product first, to have them
know, "Hey, we're going to launch this
product on this day. If you have any
content ready, you post it the next day.
We're going to collab on the top ones.
We'll run paid spend behind ones on
those. We'll run regional paid spend to
push to you and core paid spend to push
to buying the product." And you have
this idea of all this content happening
in a world around your brand between
your athletes, between your retail
partners, your rental partners, and the
core brand itself. Now not every brand
has a scenario like this, but many do,
right? If you do have a lot of different
retailers or you do have partners that
use the product, your core customers. If
you sell sold something that's used in
gyms, whatever it is, it's really just
about looking at what all those
opportunities are. And so what is that
world? So the first area is influence.
When I talked about our pro team there,
pro athletes and pro teams are really
just the original influence, right? Like
the skate team I looked up to in my
youth is now an influencer team for a
lot of brands. They'll have five or six
people they recurringly use to make
content about things they talk about. If
you don't have that, it's worth it
starting. And then starting according to
your budget. If you only have a couple
hundred bucks, there are small
influencers that will work out there.
You might get an outsized result if you
work together with them to tell a really
good story. Then you have your
retailers, wherever you're sold, and
what opportunities do they have? One of
the biggest legs up you can have is
being better at social media than your
retailers cuz then they want to collab
with you. And that's okay. That's a good
thing. If they're not as good as you
are, but they have any level of
audience, you're reaching new customers.
Can you trade a collab post on there?
Can you also get a feature in one of
their email blasts? How do you work
together to put something interesting
there? And almost every retail product
I've worked on as someone who's super
social savvy, we've played that card as
much as we can. We're going to generate
a bunch of these views. What can you do
on your end? And we're happily push
those views directly to you. Then taking
all that traffic and going to retail and
be like, "Look, we have a lot of
attention in Nashville. That's why we
want to be in your retailer." Then we
have seeding, sending things out for
free. Again, you'll see in the back
corner behind me, there's PR kits from
brands I work with and other brands that
get sent out all the time for
influencers to do unboxing. Huge, super
comprehensive strategy. There is a video
on the Common Thread YouTube channel on
here. It's a smaller YouTube, but uh
they really know their stuff. Our
retailer actually breaks down like a
seeding program zero to 100. Did you
want to dive in on that? But just
sending products for free. Thinking
about the design of the kit and whatnot.
But people also say, "Oh, in software I
can't do that, whatever." Give trials to
the top 40 people, whatever, to
influencers in the niche. Like give them
free access. There's a lot of ways to do
it and you might be surprised what comes
of it. And you have the world of your
email, other paid email, that kind of
thing. Giveaways that you can push. What
can you do in person activate? Now
everyone's always afraid of in-person
events. One of my favorite ones to do is
just be like, "Who in our customer base
lives near our office and can we invite
40 of those people there and get pizza
or whatever?" It doesn't have to be some
big built-out thing. In fact, people may
often more enjoy a candid thing if
they're an actual fan. Then pushing up
into the next level comes volume. How
can we get tons and tons of stuff out
there? Cuz if it's going well, if you
justify the economics, people often stop
and be like, "Well, our marketing budget
was only $14,000." Well, it's like, "All
right. Well, if you made back your
target goal, you sold $36,000 from 14 or
whatever it was, can we keep going? Can
we see how far those economics go? I
hate the the standardized marketing
budget when you have potential to grow
if you have the right inventory, you're
selling something that doesn't have an
inventory constraint, whatever it is.
Pushing for volume, pushing for more,
tying the results of this back to real
sales. You should want to push for as
much as you can. It will help you in
your career. It will help your business.
Then you want to look at crossover. All
these things you're doing, can you use
this organic stuff as paid? Can you use
this partner's post in a paid ad? Can
you put this influencer post inside the
email? Where can you get all these
things working together? Cuz the biggest
thing I want to note about campaigns and
why it works so well is this idea of
making a moment of all these posts that
you do, that your partners do at the
same time, that you pay influencers to
do, and your retailer does it. It's not
a 1 + 1 + 1 + 1 equals four? What? Bro,
what are you talking about, man? No, my
editor's going to have a [ __ ] field
day with that one. It's 1 + 1 + 1 + 1
equals like six and a half because of
the compounding effects of the
algorithm, of people's attention, of
what it takes to get someone to buy. So
all this working together and the more
you can cross it over and the more you
can justify making a nice asset cuz
you're also going to use it over here,
the more you can get out of that
campaign. And running through a few
awesome examples I enjoy to finish this
off, Set Active does great campaigns.
They launched an awesome one for their
Black Friday. It was boiling point
freezing point. They called out the drop
and had everything in heat and they had
these kind of retro-styled campaigns.
They did this little forecast mock-up
graphic and they had their separate
freezing point in here again with this
whole magazine mock-up. They had a whole
campaign and idea around that and then
themes to their photo shoots that tied
into those with their 20% off and their
discount. Again, they had these
conceptual reels. They had mock-up
carousels of the different combinations
of products that fit in with the
freezing point theme. Photo shoots that
tied into it. Amazing example of theme
campaigns. went right after that into
the gift giving day one of Set Miss
versus Christmas. They are going
campaign into campaign into campaign.
Skims is the king of this. They're
probably copying Skims. There's a
relentless There's always a Skims
campaign happening. It is non-stop. And
your brand may not get there, but if
you're at that size and you're like, "We
do a seasonal campaign once every
whatever." It's like, "Nah." The new
thing is to go your Black Friday
campaign and it works. That's why it's a
new thing. Your Black Friday campaign
right into your eight days of Christmas
campaign right into your new year, new
you right into we're announcing the pro
team for next year into Valentine's into
and just always have something
conceptual and amazing and you will
watch this compounding effects generate
massive sales. Another one I want to
call out is Bandit. When I want to call
out Bandit, they do beautiful campaigns.
There's actually a video where Clayton
and I with Air are on a Bandit campaign
shoot. We're talking to Tim from Bandit.
You can actually see his team getting
mad cuz he's talking to us while the
campaign's happening. But he's basically
breaking down the art direction of one
of these campaigns live from the shoot.
You have some video of that. Shout out
to our friends at Bandit. But Bandit
does these immaculate, gorgeous,
aesthetic campaigns. They're shot really
well and interestingly, just beautiful
stuff. And they do they're more on the
lighter side of content. They only have
a couple posts for the things that they
do, but all of it is just immaculate.
But why I want to call them out is on
their blog called the B Mail, you can go
and they give you an amazing behind the
scenes. The winter 2025 mood board. This
I believe is a mood board for the actual
collection itself where they're showing
you all the visual inspiration of the
things that they chose to actually do
the collection. Also have some of those
breakdowns for campaigns with behind the
scenes. You go into list view, behind
the design of Run City. Actually have
the lookbook itself, mood boards, behind
the scenes that put all this together so
you actually see how all these things go
into the products they release and you
get that look. And while this builds the
lore for the brand, it's also amazing
for you to look at if you're looking for
real examples of this. I'll end with
this example when Tom was like, "How do
you see something that's good for an
influencer as Reborn?" This dancing in
Reborn campaign is so easy for an
influencer to go say, "Oh, this you seem
to be have a video of me dancing and
it's going to be part of this dancing
campaign." It's just an easily
applicable concept and shows sometimes
how simple some of this can be. Again,
when executed in tandem with a campaign
so it makes sense. I know this was a
long video. Or was it? Honestly, time is
a flat circle. Like I mentioned, I will
have that outline of Unveil and the ad
checklist and everything available for
download below. I'm always looking for
more campaigns. I shared a bunch of my
favorites, ones I've worked on here. If
you have favorite ones, one of the best
things we can do is all build each
other's toolkit. Please let me know
campaigns I should check out or things
you thought were awesome whether it's
from the past or this year. And the more
references we all have and can browse,
likely the better. This is one of the
last videos of this year. Got the art
direction of Ralph Lauren and Capital
coming up. I have a video about
discovering your taste and all kinds of
things planned for next year. As always,
I appreciate y'all so much for watching.
Any questions you have, please drop them
below. I'll get to as many as I can.
Let's [ __ ] go.