In today's video, we're going to talk
about the dark psychology of creative
people. The forces in your head making
you do the wrong thing or holding you
back are not unique. I get asked all the
time, "How do you make so much content
or do so many things?" And in the back
of my head, I'm thinking, "Everything in
my life is a burning fire and I'm barely
holding on." I'll give some sort of calm
answer. But with the good and all the
advice we give on this channel, it's
also worth talking about the bad and how
you power through it. So, in this video,
we're going to talk about the taste
paradox and the hold people back group
think on the internet, self-sabotage,
inaction, stealing creative work, and
the machine of the world around you. But
it's not a sad video. It's a video to
let you know that everyone deals with
this and that look at strategies or how
it gets better. Because once you
understand the why and how it goes down,
you can build out of it. And there's not
a creative on this planet who doesn't
deal with these things. And I promise
we'll have a little fun along the way.
Come for a ride. Let's lock in. I want
to start by talking about the tasteful
paradox, the idea of organic discovery.
This is something I argue about quite a
bit with people I respect and it is this
idea that if you do wonderful creative
work, you're an excellent strategist or
you do a key campaign, it's going to be
recognized by the right people. It's
going to get you into the right places
and you don't need to be overly
self-promotional about it. And I look at
this continually as the gatekeepers
gatekeeping you, making you believe that
the only way to get work in progress is
for it to be organically rewarded. I
remember I had a mentor once who said,
"What good is a portfolio if it doesn't
get clicked?" And this was a hard one
for me personally cuz I I truly believe
You'll see me do it a lot now if you
follow me on X or Instagram. I celebrate
every milestone. I think creatives
should, too. I celebrated 100K on
YouTube, 500K on Instagram. I celebrated
the publishing of new collections, of
when I joined different roles, of
constantly harping up how cool the
things that I'm doing or working on are.
And this was actually hard for me to get
to because when I look at my own arc, I
haven't worked at Apple or Stussy or
founded some hundred million dollar
company. I worked a lot of consumer tech
and random businesses and did some
really good work. I'm not the guy. And
there were a lot of people who I
respected who did really tasteful work,
who were in scenes like high-end
fashion, things I aspired to be in and
thought by kind of quietly contributing
my tasteful stuff eventually I would get
there. And then I realized waking up in
my mid-30s I was stuck and that doesn't
get me anywhere. And being the operator
and being almost proud of the lack of
promotion that you did or being the the
guy on the side who makes it all happen
wasn't actually a good thing. I was
doing myself a disservice. And so, I
would encourage if you are in that
scenario and there's people around you
that almost frown or look down on you
when you share that work, share it
louder. That in a world of noise, no
matter how good what you do is, maybe
you get sought out from it, but you need
to cheerlead yourself because everyone
is too distracted by their algorithms to
do it for you. This leads me into group
think. I think about this a lot because
of the AI comments. You've probably seen
this. There's a lot of people who will
use AI on any video or some posts that
they have on the internet and you'll
immediately get a bunch of comments
like, "AI slop." That's just railing on,
you know, "Support real photographers"
or whatever it ends up being. And look,
I have this barometer on AI, right?
Using bad AI work is offensive. Doing
good or interesting AI work is
essentially any real working creative is
part of the responsibility cuz you look
around, you look at what people are
actually doing and you'll realize that
this hate online that comes from so many
people is fabricated. It's group think.
You walk into every agency, every major
production house, every brand. Their
life is being saved by generated
transitions, generative fill. They are
stitching together extra shots. They are
doing their logo animations. Luxury
brands are hiring friends of mine to do
3D viz all through AI that you wouldn't
know. Is purely a matter of not getting
caught or not talking about it. And so,
if you position yourself against it and
all of a sudden you wake up realizing
that everyone in the roles around you
are working on it, all of a sudden
you've painted yourself in a corner
because of an online group think.
Because it feels good to pile on
something. And this ties into online
commenting in general. You may have
heard that idea that if you don't have
anything nice to say, don't say it. But
if you're in any scenario where you ever
comment anything that's not either
valuable or funny or supportive, you're
participating in a negative group think
online that is likely holding you back
somewhere else. That energy that you're
putting into spewing negativity, no
matter even if you feel it's put in the
right place, politics, whatever it is,
that is draining the energy you have to
be excited about the world or to be
obsessed with the thing you're
passionate about. And every bit of that
you decrease takes away from the
potential of the art. And anyone who can
live by this principle itself likely
isn't a real working professional.
They've already established themselves
so much that they have the luxury of
time. And I guarantee you almost none of
us watching this channel have that. This
ties into self-sabotage. And this is one
I don't have a solution for. This is one
I grapple with all the time. I will have
everything going right in my life. I
live this right now. I'm making an
ungodly amount of money, a shocking
amount, more than I've ever thought I
would make. I have all these happy
things around me and I cannot help but
at any given time have one thing I'm
doing so ruthlessly and unstoppably to
self-sabotage myself that I am shocked
by how aggressive I'm doing. And this is
an A, this is human nature, especially
when you get to a unexpected level. This
is what happens with creatives all the
time, right? You have that self-doubt
that you're not the guy or the girl,
you're not going to get to this place,
you're not your generational artist. And
if you get anywhere near there, anywhere
above where your expectation of yourself
was, you don't know how to handle it.
And you, in the back of your head, want
to cut yourself back down to whatever
level you were at before because it's
comfortable to you. And it doesn't go
away. This is one where I don't even
have a solution to give you, but the
start of it is with realization of
acknowledging, [clears throat] "I have
this self-sabotaging thing." No excuse,
no whatever, no justification. It's the
thing you're doing. And then continually
trying to do something about it.
strategy, a new idea, anything but
repeat the same thing and hope for the
better. Which brings me to inaction, one
that I have thankfully conquered and I
think if you take anything away from
this video, it can be your formula to do
the same. At the end of this video, I'll
talk about how the world around us has
been plotting against anyone with a a
dream or a vision or a creative thought,
but we'll get there later. At the root
of most inaction is a concept of cool,
is a concept of what people tell you is
all right or what you should or
shouldn't feel. I want to tell you
because it's very for generation of us
who grew up in a certain way of school,
etc., it's okay to want to win. It's
okay to want to be better than others
that are doing the same thing. It
doesn't have to be negative, you don't
have to win at their expense, but it is
okay to want to be amazing, to want to
be the best, and to want more for
yourself. I promise you. It's okay to be
the one that breaks free of the
circumstance you're in and the group
that you are around. And again, you
don't have to look down on them, you
don't have to isolate them, but you can
break out and that will be a good thing
for you. And it is not cool or
aspirational to be lazy or chill. You
don't attract the job of your dreams,
you don't attract the mate of your
dreams by being chill, by taking more
time for you, by treating yourself. I'm
not going to go talk advocating to work
996, but you first to solve inaction,
you need to want to win, you need to
admit to yourself it is okay to go after
everything. I had that moment when I
realized I needed to embrace
competition. I am innately extremely
competitive. It's actually the thing
that makes me publish the most content.
I'm competitive against people I have no
need to be competitive against. I'm
already destroying them in whatever idea
in my head is cuz competition. It comes
back to my childhood, it comes back to
competitive sports, whatever it is. But
I also realize that that's okay, that it
doesn't matter, that that's something
that drives me forward. Wanting to win
in whatever aspect, wanting to throw up
whatever imaginary W on the wall. I
watched that Jordan documentary and
realized there's people that think like
that and use that to their advantage.
They'll make up scenarios to get
themselves in that competitive nature. I
at least have them naturally and it
helps solve inaction. Which ties us to
this concept. If you want something done
right, you want something completed, ask
a busy person to do it. This is a
parable I could not agree with more.
That we all think, "Oh, I'm busy. I I
can't do X or Y. I can't add X or Y."
You know who gets things done? People
who have no choice but to get it done,
who really want to and are pursuing it
and have a bunch of other stuff going
on. Tasks expand to fill the time on
hand. That's the biggest thing that I've
realized is that the more things I sign
up for, I sign up for too much. I got
newsletters and businesses and jobs and
content and networks. I sign up for way
too much. I never am at the end of my
list. I never hit the goal thing at the
end of the day. But you know what I do
get done? Like 10X more than I ever
thought was humanly possible because I'm
attempting to do so much. And at the end
of the day, if something doesn't happen,
everyone will survive. But that action
of I'm going to be a doer, I'm going to
be a shipper, I want to win, I want to
sign up for more than I can do and I'm
going to use those spare moments not to
be chill, not to hang with, to get after
it is the solution to what you're
looking for. To do this, I use the brick
all the time. I'll shut my phone off
social media. You've heard me mention it
before. will leave it upstairs so I
would have to go retrieve it if I want
to go on X or Instagram. And it's funny,
I'm not even addicted to scrolling, I'm
addicted to my analytics. If you're a
creator, you likely know what I mean.
And then lists. I'm a relentless list
maker both on physical and online
because checking them off and getting
those things done, always having a track
of what needs to happen when and
assigning kind of rough times or areas
to it really helps things get done. All
right. In this segment, I'm going to
talk about making an audio plan for your
brand, for you as a creator or creative
posting content or as a service you
offer as part of content or creative
work you do for others. So, we've all
seen the scenario where you have a good
piece of content but there's cheesy,
generic, royalty-free music on top of
it. It will not only hurt your creative
heart, it also does not perform in
today's social world because guess what?
Standards are rising, people are more
creative than ever, content is getting
better than ever, and all those little
things matter including audio. That's
why I partnered with Musicbed who I use
for stuff like this all the time to
break down what an audio plan is and how
you can do it. So, the first thing is is
to build your signature song library.
You will notice a lot of brands and a
lot of creators who actually use the
same songs very frequently to become
basically a branded element. They'll
have a score set of two or three audios
that really define them. This is
something I do as a creator. You've
heard me change in my YouTube's every
six months or so, but getting those
signatures in there. And then build a
world that extends from it. Say, "What
kind of sound do we have? We don't want
to sound completely different on every
asset we do. How can we kind of build a
world out from there? And Musicbed makes
this really easy because of the search
functions they have. You can search by
genre, by mood, by artist, attributes in
the song, by instrument. You can get
advanced BPM, key, build. Build is my
favorite. The has a build is super
useful cuz I use build in hooks and
stuff all the time. And in ads you want
that tension. I will literally use the
has build function to find things that
have those dramatic moments. And you can
get vocals or no vocals, click
instrumental right in one click, and
sort through just a bunch of really
awesome music. There's a reason they are
trusted by thousands and thousands of
YouTubers and filmmakers because they
have an amazing library, curated,
authentic, and most importantly
cinematic songs. But songs isn't it,
sounds is the second part. So you have
an audio plan for your music and then an
audio plan for your sounds. So what do I
mean by that? The clicks that happen
when a picture changes or in a
transition, the risers and tones, the
other things that define your brand. You
want to be able to provide that kit to
the creators or UGC you work with on
your brand. You want to be able to use
it across your creative projects so you
have some signatures. You want that
toolkit of sounds. And the way Musicbed
does this is really interesting. So
basically you can describe what you're
doing. So ASMR unboxing. This is a
common one. A lot of people do these
unboxings that have great audio. And you
will find clicks, latches, plates. They
have tons of those like little sounds in
here, hinges, that you can dive through
and build your own signature set. And
some people even take choose to take
like a humorous version of this, right,
versus a kind of like a literal version.
But you can describe your scenes and you
can build that ambiance around it and
really add that detail into your
creative work. Now is the time for you
to ditch the generic royalty free tracks
and put a real plan in place for what
audio means for you creatively. You can
do that with making the switch to
Musicbed. There's a link for a free
14-day trial in the description of this
video. And thank you so much to the
Musicbed team for sponsoring this video.
Which brings me to stealing, which is a
complicated topic in today's day and age
because there are designers, creators,
creatives who will go, "No one will
notice if I just take this." And then
they do. They take the same hook, the
same video concept, design the same
logo, the same icon, the same shot
concept, brand, piece of clothing, the
barometer. This is the karmic barometer.
Because you do it, it may be just fine,
probably will be just fine. People may
notice or not, there's no repercussions
even necessarily if they do. But you'll
notice and it's going to suck the
creative energy you have, again, away
from creating the masterpiece you have
inside you. You're then forever going to
live on that other person's stolen
written idea. And so your choice is to
make that way better. Anything you take
inspiration from, make it way better.
That is your barometer. Did I take this
and significantly improve it? And just
never give in to that voice in your head
that says, "What if I just do this this
one time? Anyone will notice." Cuz it's
now easier than ever with so no one
know, I saw this thing on Arena that no
one else is seeing them cuz they're not
on there. My work hasn't seen this Slack
that I'm in that does X or Y. Just do
those things with that idea that you can
add your thing on top of it. You're
never going to sharpen your creative
muscle enough to have your own thing
that gains momentum. And now last, I
want to talk about the world around you.
We are surrounded by a machine of lies
and manipulation. I have liberal
friends, I have conservative friends.
They both believe the other ones are the
problem. They're both right. They some
get more work up than others. It can
lead them to unhappiness the more they
think on it. And they are programmed if
a thing happens to want to resolve it.
And And if you're a creative, you're a
thinker. You want to feel responsible.
You want to feel like you're doing
something. It's innate to people that
create. You want everything in the world
to be all right cuz then you can finally
do it. But that's not it. I learned this
during COVID where I was like it just
keeps being one problem after another,
one Trump administration thing after the
next. My family were caught up in it,
we're talking about it, just things
happening. What do these people think?
What are we going to do? And nothing
happened except me not pursuing my
goals. Except living in a shroud of
negativity online. And you think, "Okay,
when this this better when the world
clears up then I can work on it." But
that's not it. It's going to get worse.
Well, that's great. That's just [ __ ]
great, man. And as you get older,
everything is going to get harder cuz
then you're going to have life coming at
you at the same time. And your kids are
going to have problems. You're going to
be taking care of your parents. You're
going to have stuff you'd never even
expected and bills with which you can't
even describe to have to then deal with.
You took the jam out of your donut. You
took the [ __ ] jam out of my donut,
Tommy. You have to ignore. You have to
realize that none of those things
actually help you. And you have to
instead take that energy positively.
This doesn't say don't give back. But
your answer isn't consume more media
about how bad things are. Your answer to
feeling better about it is to spend that
time volunteering or doing a change
thing that's not commenting or posting
online in social media. It's spending
whatever time or energy that you can
commit to help people in real lives.
It's getting excited about things, then
getting others excited about things.
That takes that one energy away from
this constant machine of consumption
that is rewarded by you gambling, doing
parlays, getting way too deep into
whatever's happening in the Middle East,
caring about a New York election when
you live somewhere else. If it matters
that much to you, you contribute with
your actual time versus online. And at
the end of the day when you look at a
lot of those you realize it doesn't, you
realize it is just taking you away from
whatever it is that you want to create
or do. And the last portion of this is
the North Star. Is the creative who's
doing a bunch of these things and they
aren't going right. You've been posting
a bunch of content that doesn't work.
You've been working through a bunch of
these ideas where they can't sit with
it. And a lot of that comes down to not
actually knowing what you want. And
what's nice is is that we're no longer
in a realistic world. We're in a world
where if you have a couple rare glimpses
of knowledge, of applications,
technology, of how to use the internet,
you can progress from nothing to
something in the most rapid time that
you've ever imagined. Any goal that you
find or set to yourself has now become
infinitely attainable in a way that is
mystifying to anyone who has not come up
inside of this era. No matter where you
are on the globe, no matter what that
dream is, it is extremely possible. But
you have to map it out. You have to put
the actual vision on there. And there's
a lot of people who'd be like, "I don't
really want this or I don't really want
that." A lot of that is just you inside
looking at your own self-doubt. What is
it that you don't want? Life isn't
perfect. Life isn't beautiful. Life is
complicated and life is hard. And if you
want things that are complicated and
hard along the way, you begin to enjoy
them. Once you actually acknowledge
that, yes, I do want to do this thing or
I love it or I find it. You need to find
that one place that you want to go in
the next 24 months, in the next year, in
the next 6 months, that one level. And
then break that down again. What are the
six main things I would have to learn or
do to get there? All the tasks it would
take to do each of those six. What is
the first step? When can I put it on the
schedule? Find that North Star, break it
down, and work through some of that in
action. Cuz we're in a complicated time,
but a wonderful one for anyone who isn't
afraid to lean into how high-speed all
these things around us are going. I am
shocked every day. The workflows that I
have now, how fast I can do research,
what I'm able to do in like I use
Perplexity comment all the time, how
fast we're generating images, how the
team can work together and what like
online shared design and creative looks
like, how deep and fast content can move
on the internet, the dollars that come
in and back from that. It is a
shockingly important time. And a year
and a half ago, I believe, I made a
video called lock-in where I told this
is the time for creatives to sit down
and really focus on their craft and
telling their story online. And that was
right in that time. That was the time to
take that seriously. Now we're in a
whole different time. Now we're in a
time where it's not about just
identifying that you want to work
harder. It's about truly understanding
that the limitations to what you can
achieve in this world and the speed with
which you can do it have been completely
eliminated if you just become obsessed
with it. And like a video game, you have
to combat against an entire world that
is designed to stop you from doing that
that gets increasingly better at it
every day. Never thinking that you're
above promoting yourself, by never
falling into group think and
anti-thought and online commenting, by
acknowledging self-sabotage and
continuing to work to change it, by
breaking through in action, by admitting
to yourself it's okay to want to win and
be somebody, to fighting off the evils
of the world around you trying to
distract you. If you take even a handful
of those steps,
>> [music]
>> I believe you can get wherever that you
want to go. Thank you for watching.