In this video, I'm going to talk about
the art direction and content playbook
for modern street wear. I'm stoked to
make this video because streetear is at
a crossroads. We move from the Supreme
Generation Palace world of crossover of
street wear and luxury to the Instagram
and Tik Tok world and the rise of
Instagram and Tik Tok brands and brands
that dominate off of content. Content is
better than ever. Designs are better
than ever. And anyone that's trying to
make quick money, which is an absolute
joke to even say in clothing, or who
isn't amazing with their designs and
marketing and community, is going to get
wiped out. Only the fittest, the best
are going to survive this next 18 months
in the brand building world. Cuz
frankly, everyone can make something
amazing. This is a shirt from like I
think it's a candle brand that's just
like their merch included that has as
good of a wash and a feel as like 70% of
streetear brands. Like the standard now
is so high for success in such a
competitive world that it's actually
forcing brands to do really interesting
stuff and really push the limits in a
way that I quite enjoy. So I'm going to
cover 10 brands here and we are going to
discuss their strategy and notes and I'm
going to break down a playbook for
brands covering everything you need to
know and have on the radar for creative
strategy for apparel. And just a quick
heads up, I have a strategy toolkit.
It's free. It is linked below in the
description. It says content ideas for
teasers, unveils, launches, like all in
an organized database. This is what I
use when I do creative strategy on
apparel projects. You can grab that for
free in the description. Let's lock in.
But first, we're going to talk about one
of my favorite brands, a brand you've
seen me wear extensively on YouTube and
Tik Tok, dating back years now,
preceding their takeover, and that is
House of Errors. And I want to talk
about House of Errors because they are a
brand that truly embodies the power of
art direction. This is a
photographydriven brand. Now, a
combination of photography and
videography, but especially in the
beginning, the power of their visual
images combined with the standout nature
of the items gave us something that is
unlike what anyone had ever really seen.
And I like to use them as an example.
When people were talking about photos or
campaigns for their brands, I feel like
this is the standard. Like this shoot
with these massive faces was pretty
early on inside the brand's journey. The
one that really uh brought them some
significant exposure was this Black
Friday market crash shoot launched on
Black Friday. They are recreating um
some kind of famous scenes here. The
photography is amazing. The casting is
amazing. The way it shows the clothes is
amazing. They've played with perspective
and scale in shoots like this. More
abstract lookbooks and incredible
scenarios. Recreating a famous Zedane
scene here. Every single one of these
shoots is incredible. And I look to any
brand and I'm like, "Hey, if you really
want to go into street wear right now,
are you hitting at this level? Are is
your creative for stills hitting at this
level?" Because that is the threshold.
This was a new brand that came out of
nowhere that is now regarded on a level
of any kind of major streetear brand.
And when it comes to art direction, the
concepts of the shoe, the execution of
them, and what we see there, I feel like
this is what you need to be looking for
where every single thing has a unique
House of Errors feel. It has a concept
to it. We see everything from the old or
models in here. And I'm not saying these
aren't these are uh certainly thought
through and they spent some money on
them, but this isn't like this is
completely crazy either. But this is the
playbook for one of the most interesting
brands. Also shows purely by the
building of this universe combined with
the unique element of the clothing, you
can stand out. But now I want to talk
about a brand that I bring up a lot when
people talk about creative concepts for
content. Especially when clothing brands
look at content, they go, "Cool, I'm
just going to shoot some more stuff on
the concrete background or whatever it
is." They are an example of a brand that
has used virality to their advantage.
You can go viral on social media making
content for your streetear brand and
they are an amazing example of it. So
much so that they've been duplicated a
hundred times. I'm going to leave with
this video. This is the stop and frisk
video that did so well it became a trend
where people basically this guy gets
arrested in front of a glass screen and
it is a fit check for the actual brand
products. Absolute destruction.
Incredible video. Again, I'm not going
to speak to I think a difference between
a brand like this and my house of errors
is that the clothes are much better on a
house of errors. But the creative is
excellent enough here. They've been able
to break through and become part of the
conversation by the quality of the
videos. And you will notice that they
would much rather have an amazing
conceptual video that's executed than
have a dozen quick little Tik Tok
videos. Every reel that you have on
here, from what we've just seen, again,
another variation on the stop and frisk
meme to that explosion pan back and
forth. They are relentless in the
conceptual execution of everything that
they do. And I think when any brand goes
on a shoot now, when you're going into a
video shoot, you need to be thinking how
are you executing on that level. If
you're not coming with those ideas, like
don't do the shoot. But not every brand
succeeds purely on creative. So one I
want to call out is Lwood. Probably been
inundated with Lwood ads or know Lwood
know the name Lwood. So Lwood's organic
content doesn't do well. You can tell a
lot of these just by the like ratio,
right? Like uh some do good, some do
don't, but the majority of their best
content is run as ads in Spark ads and
Instagram ads. They create content for
ads and this is not a bad thing. This is
a good technique that people can do.
This is a technique that uh Cole Buckton
represent. A lot of people have ran
their organic stuff as ads. So common
most brands do, but they've just made a
whole industry around it saying, "Hey,
if we make a fit check walkthrough, we
don't care how it works on organic. We
are going to run that same concept as an
ad and run 100 variations on it." And
you can see this has 530 hearts, right?
And hundred thousands of views because
it works as an ad. And so they are
saying it doesn't m organic distribution
doesn't matter. Spark ads, Tik Tok ads,
meta ads are cheap enough that if we
make a lot of this creative in a way
that we feel sells it, our best bet to
get it in front of people is going to be
doing it through advertising. And they
do a wide variety of it from these kind
of compilation videos to the actual uh
creative directors and people like that
walking through the difference between
their TE's. They are just designing
advertising to look like their organic
videos and putting personalities on
camera to show off the clothes. And I
think for a company, especially a
company like this where if you buy into
Lwood, it becomes your core tea or your
core sweat or you get one, they're
banking on lifetime value, right?
They're like, "Cool, we drop new colors,
you're picking up more." They make a
very stylable wardrobe that accentuates
the existing clothes you have. This is a
brand that is built less around
statement pieces and more around
everything else in your wardrobe. And if
you're going to market something like
that, they're doing a good job for you.
And they've added vintage. That's an
interesting thing about that, too.
They're basically doing curated
thrifting on top of that. But again,
these are they are focused on this
elevated basics, for lack of a better
term, but how to sell those isn't trying
to go organic on the feed. Going viral
with elevated basics is going to be a
particularly hard thing. Even just
having a good organic presence, but
making good content that sells via ads,
they've nailed it. And so, quick notes
on that. I've run a lot of ads on
apparel brands. As many of you know,
I've worked for years and years now as a
partner in the awesome understated
leather. It's a women's brand. I have my
own small valuables brands we're slowly
building. I wish I could spend like 10x
more time on, but frankly, content and
business is more lucrative. I have spent
even that brand everything we do is
based on like success in meta ads when
it comes to online you can get organic
organic is just fuel for that you have a
great organic post it's really that to
me is just an ability for me to run
great ads on multiple platforms and I
can't speak enough to the potential for
brands to really look at their content
holistically like that when they're
doing those campaigns and the total
available market they have when you are
doing multiple platforms multiple
content types and you're doing organic
plus paid you can have nice little
businesses that don't even appear to be
big uh and that is a secret to this but
it all comes back do amazing editorial
and amazing content that's thought
through and then executed. And I like to
call out those brands. I feel like
they're on the up and up. House of I
think is just getting started. Cold
Culture, I think, has cracked the code
for a minute on how to get this viral
attention. I'm curious to see what they
do. Elwood, I think, is an underrated
kind of money printer. They're probably
doing a lot of sales. They're now on
YouTube. They're obviously trying to do
some interesting things. I know they
worked on Paige Lorenz's brand, Dairy
Boy, and a few other they've got their
hands in stuff. I think they have the
right entrepreneur mentality to go much
wider, even though they are disparaged
heavily online pretty frequently. So I
think they are like headed towards more
interesting things as well. Obviously
the vintage launch like they're making
moves. But then there's brands I feel
like are kind of not making moves. So So
uh and maybe like we've ended that time.
So Aly is one of those where they uh did
a really impressive thing where they
basically built a luxury brand out of
nothing. Just not an easy thing to do.
High price points, high quality, high
perception. And then some of these
things like the recurring environments,
recurring characters, the same models
inside the the things that they do. You
see these recurring themes and motifs
executed at a really high level, but
they're still pretty simple when it all
comes down to it, but it's perfectly
curated, perfectly well done. I think it
is very hard for a brand to come out and
do this in in our our era currently at
the same level. The quality of the
clothing, the quality of the art
direction, the content they did, the
premium price point, and this look and
feel, I feel like brands like this and
about blank just kind of like a cheaper
version in its own way where it's very
image focused. It's very
straightforward. let the garment speak
for themselves, like speak to a more
luxury environment. That period is kind
of over and a lot of it's over because
of the nature of who the customer is for
this, right? This is a product for guys
uh you like junior people at Goldman
Sachs, people that are in bank, it's a
like a negative status signaler when
people like or have something like this,
the more you see their customer base
like tech bros, you realize who the our
direction of that kind of thing really
speaks to. Now, you can make plenty of
money with that as a brand. There's
always that difference within fashion
culture of like what actually resonates
and has a longevity of being able to be
cool to people for a really really long
time. What makes the sales and the
interaction that I think is an
interesting play about blank is the same
thing less so on the customerbased
conversation but they make very simple
content and simple art direction. It
really stood out because of its quality
and simplicity when they launched but if
you tried to recreate that playbook now
like you would basically fail horribly
and you can watch them they are just now
starting to pivot a bit of their
playbook to more outside shoots. They
even integrated a little bit of video.
They took the longest time before
starting to introduce those vignettes
and they didn't have to because the
brand was in a certain place. But this
look and feel, the very basic photo
shoot, the very detail- oriented macros,
the branding on everything, this works
cuz they built off of it. And I think
right now it, as you can see, cuz
they're pivoting some of their content
into new styles is the end of that era.
That is not a strategy that continues to
work. I think we need to be really
conscious of like the eras you're in
from content consumption. There's an era
people really wanted elevated and clean
and that to come from independent
brands. And for a moment, I want to talk
about Satoshi Nakamoto for a moment. Um,
this is a brand I was at in Complex Con.
My booth was somewhere near theirs and
they had the uh I forget what it's
called, the cage of death or whatever it
is where it's like the motorcycle riders
can ride around inside of it. They're a
brand who has thoughts about positioning
extremely in-depth. Their photography is
good. Everything they do is like solid
um but not life-changing. The designs
are good, but this is a positioning
brand. This brand succeeds because of
the name. It's probably one of the
smartest branding plays I've seen in
this last decade. They saw this cultural
thing with what's happening with
Bitcoin. The name is Toshi Nakamoto.
Japanese brand and they say, "Hey, cool.
This is positioning to a signaler to
people that really know. We can bring
credibility to it as a Japanese brand
and we can execute something at a luxury
level at a luxury cost and price point
that speaks to this counterculture to
this, you know, Mr. Robot Bitcoin
streetear lifestyle. They've executed on
that just absolutely excellently. But if
their name was something else, they
wouldn't be a fraction of the success of
what that is." And it's a good thing to
call out when you look at a brand has to
kind of have everything. You have to
have the quality and interest of the
clothes and clothes for a brand like
this kind of have to be loud to get that
that name out there. You have to have
the art direction. They're doing really
interesting photos and stuff here. It's
not really popping on social media, but
it's again it's a job of a brand like
this is to be more of a signaler brand
where it may even be a detractor for
them to make really big content on
social media cuz it's one of those like
if you know you know and the name nods
to that as well. But there those are
kind of like once in a decade once in a
fiveyear opportunities to act on
something like this. And so if you do,
if you have an idea of that caliber or
that level or that social resonance, I
cannot speak highly enough to uh trying
to act on it and they've done great
work. This week's video is brought to
you by Musicbed. As always, I'm going to
make these sponsors educational. And so
today, we're going to talk about sounds.
Music Bed just added sounds into their
platform. And I'm going to walk through
a few that you should definitely know
that can help elevate your short form
content, your brand videos, or anything
you make as a creative. So first, this
is a riser.
is a great way to build tension at the
start of a video. You will see a lot of
creators that do this under their hook.
And you can combine it with a hit for
more impact, a reverse to accentuate a
transition,
and then tones or record scratches to
accentuate a hook. I have a whole series
on Instagram where I use that sensor as
part of the hook to get attention. So,
Music Bed now has sounds, including all
of these, live within their platform.
There's over 150,000 plus curated sounds
and you can access them inside the same
platform as the music. So you can get
all of your audio needs for your videos
and creative work inside one place. And
there's also now a playlist of some of
my favorite tracks. I made a theme for
this. It's basically 15 seconds cinema
tracks where you can use a little
section of it to really quickly invoke a
particular type of emotion cuz that's
how I like to use audio. You can check
all this out and give Music Bed a try at
the link in the description. Let's get
back to it. Then there's brands. There's
like 2Js and Nude Project and folks like
this, these kind of more euro focused
brands who are basically taking the
Stusy playbook and applying it to social
media. The 2J's feed is just a like
younger Stuy feed with a really good job
done of it creating iconography in the
same way Stui does doing better use than
they do of objects of collabs of this
like beach culture making it
significantly Euro shooting all this
stuff on film have done a great job with
it. And it's been a good example of like
if you want to be derivative, like let's
do something better than the previous
brand. Be more appealing than the
previous brand. Taking Stusy with plus
western iconography, plus more objects,
more cars, younger, harder, more vibrant
feel. I think they've done great work
with. And one of the interesting parts
about them is is the adrenaline that
comes within the content. This is not an
underrated thing to think about where
it's like the video of the back of the
boat. This is like a light version of
this, but one of their biggest ones that
popped off, I think was like a big
foundational moment for that brand was
when someone was actually hopping off of
a was doing like a cliff dive in the 2J
shirt. Here we got the video here. I
guess it was a big moment, probably one
of their first blowup videos, 364,000
likes. But again, this is adrenaline
focused content. That is a good angle
for younger brands or brands that have
that kind of mythos to be able to do.
And again, we're seeing that dirt bikes
is super again, this is this is Stuy
content, but they're running it in a
better social fashion in a way Stuy
probably would never do in kind of the
modern era. And that is a like a recipe
for saying what was a successful thing.
How do we take that styles? How do we up
how it performs on the algorithms? How
do we up the intensity? How do we make
it more thrill riding, more
thrillseeking instead of a sunburn of a
logo, tattoo of the logo, that kind of
thing. Now, I want to talk about a
totally different approach cuz that's a
new brand playing in an old playbook.
Two of the brands I think are the most
interesting in this world are Broken
Planet and Dursuites. So Broken Planet
I'm gonna pull up on TikTok. I want to
talk about their strategy here. I think
it's one of the best ones. So they
basically have a gang of young people.
They they move them out. They're new.
Like the blonde girls new as of the last
few months. They will have like four six
or so of these folks and they basically
take them on trips along with the
founders and the staff and they go
places and they make skits and you can
scroll through here on TikTok. They are
literally just karaokeing trending audio
being fashionable and mobbing around
with friends doing stupid young people
stuff on camera in exotic places whether
that's Paris as Morocco. You can kind of
scroll back and you can see they'll have
different clothes and different looks.
They've got them all dirt biking in
Morocco. They've got them all picnicking
in Paris. And when you kind of think
about it and you're like, how much
content is coming out? Because there's a
lot of content on the individual
people's pages, on the brand owners
pages, on the core brand page, it goes
in these waves. They're always going
somewhere and doing something.
Characters kind of move in and out. It's
pretty easy content to do all things
considered. But the where the cost is,
they're employing these creators.
They're saying, "Hey, cool. We're going
to let you travel to exotic places and
we're going to pay you x a month and
you're going to make x amount of skits
with us." And then they're booking the
travel and booking the trips and they're
supplying the clothes. You know, versus
like traditional setup shoots where
you're renting locations and getting
more high budget videographers and
photographers versus this is all iPhone.
This is probably the same budget, but
they get way more content. It's way more
Tik Tok relevant. And it's it's
interesting and different in a way that
I feel like has carved out a really
specific niche. And I would say that
like for a lot of brands, if you have
access to young, good-looking people who
will do this and you can build that like
lifestyle and travel thing in there, I
think this playbook is like extremely
it's like underdone at this point. There
are brands that are doing I know YG is
doing some of these things. Like there's
other brands that are doing it, but I
think there's a lot of interesting
angles and places. I'd love to see the
brands that are doing that in like
different continents, different areas
where I think that is just just the
beginning of that strategy and they are
early and no matter what, look, they're
selling clothes to kids, right? The
clothes are for children and so it's a
different market. We have to understand
what your market looks like. Duruits is
another one playing in this new world.
They're doing skit-based content. You've
probably seen it. So, they have the
founder, they have a couple recurring
creators. She's in in most of the
videos. And they are making skits about
fashion boys and fashion girls. the
dynamic between the two, the dynamic of
being like a person in the modern world
who loves clothes, skits that are funny
about the clothes around it and has the
entirety of their content. And that the
genius of this of the strategy is there
the clothes get to be in every video,
but you get to be entertaining enough to
be shared, but they also have accounts
by regions. There's a duruit's London
account has different creators on there
making London specific content in
London. This is like the kind of the
genius of it is you get a good idea, you
can then move it across your locations
and that helps feed the London store
because algorithms are localized. If you
are in London, it will show you content
of other people traveling in London of
what to do in London. If you live there,
it will show you stuff around it. The
algorithm is good at that. They're doing
this for New York with the New York
store now and kind of you can watch them
kind of get it off the ground. And this
is another one where I think the power
of, okay, are we going to do these big
budget shoots or are we going to do
we're going to employ a lot of creators
and be pumping out content. I think this
is just as effective now as that
traditional ad playbook we're seeing
from someone more like 2Js. There's
plenty of brands I want to talk about um
more high-end true fashion stuff who
kind of cross the line like like Martine
Rose where it's just pure incredible art
direction what that looks like on a
luxury level. Only so much time in this
video. I'm going to move into the
playbook section here. So the playbook
for success and what you're seeing every
brand do. The first is spectacles with
production. Like this is what you're
competing against. Nike is, you know,
has giant chunks coming out of a
building with cars with golf balls on
top of them. People are spending money
on pop-ups and productions. There's a
spectacle element. A lot of the 2J
stuff, they had their giant stars logos
on, big metal cutouts in in the desert.
People are are creating these kind of
moments you can make content around and
get people involved with or people to go
photograph. So, I think it's important
to call out because basically every
brand is doing their version of that.
There's an IRL experience version of it.
I would keep it on your radar as you
scale. But the crucial core things is
ecom style. How are you shooting your
ecom photos? Like that is an
opportunity. How your videos show up on
your actual product pages? What are you
doing for social creators? Who are you
employing to be able to have that like
actually on your feed making content
every day? How are you doing lookbooks
and distributing them? Like someone like
Kasa Eris is a lookbook with every one
of those launches and then corresponding
ecom photos that go with it. And then
what is your distribution? You have
organic platforms and then how are you
promoting that on ads and then how are
you seeding or doing other things and to
elevate those you need concepts for
social like we saw with cold culture.
Whether that's you're actually doing the
the lip-s syncing stuff that broken
planet is or skits like Dur Shoots is or
elevating like adrenaline content the
way 2J's is. Every one of those brands
has concepts behind their shoots. If
you're not doing concepts with this, I
don't think you're breaking through into
good art direction. And then
environment. Where are you filming this?
How are you creating this? What teams do
you have? Broken Planet's moving that
environment around. ALD had that kind of
recurring environment of where they
actually shot to begin to tell the brand
story. And how are you bringing these
experiences into real life? Because this
is so competitive. Having a popup and
documenting it the way like House of
Errors is taking over LA. We just saw
that Nike stuff. Like how are you then
making content that applies in that
region and then making interesting art
direction actually comes with. This is a
great video set for House of Errors to
promote like a pop-up that's happening
in in LA. How are you bringing all that
together? Like these things add up to
the foundation of creative in street
wear because like I mentioned in the
beginning, not only do the clothes have
to be amazing now or at least amazing
for their target demo, the actual
creative has to be on that next level.
And then you actually really need to
sell and fulfill and be like doing
things that are interesting because
that's the standard for success. It is a
hard niche to participate in. A bit of a
different ending to this video. This
week I'm launching a new business. As
many of you know, I've been doing
creative strategy and creative direction
freelance for brands now while I create
content for a while. In the newest
business, I'm actually training teams
inside of agencies and inside of brands
to get better at organic social strategy
and paid social strategy. I am rolling
this out at the end of September. And in
the meantime, I'm actually looking for
people, seven in particular. I have
three set up already to help me run a
beta of this to actually test out
everything I have inside the curriculum
before I roll it out to the agency
partners. So if you are super junior or
you have your own brand, this is not for
you. But if you are working in
marketing, any kind of creative space
and you want to learn how to be a
creative strategist to make organic
strategy for brands or to run ads or to
get better at it and learn my playbook.
Basically what I am offering is you will
get a super discounted rate and we will
connect onetoone on that so I can also
learn and get feedback on if you think
this is good and valuable. As always, if
you don't like it, I will just refund it
and then in turn I can make sure I am
honed in before I get into this launch.
So, if that is you and that is something
that's interested to you, I want to get
seven more people in this beta. I have a
type form down below that you can fill
out and I will shoot over all the info
and then y'all will see when that
business launches and I will talk more
about it here when I do launch it at the
end of September. But in the meantime, I
figured this would be the perfect
audience who might actually be looking
for this that I can get some help
evaluating this with. As always, thank
you so much for watching this video.
I've got a fun lineup over the next few
weeks. I'm going to link some of my
other popular art direction videos here.
Look forward to seeing you next week.