In this video, we are going to go
through the art direction of LE, one of
the funnest, most interesting brands of
probably this last decade. They are the
epitome of Spanish luxury. They not only
make true luxury heritage items, but
they also cross over and crush it on new
channels like Tik Tok. And this is the
perfect time to do this video because
their creative director, Jonathan
Anderson, has just left for Dior. So, I
want to take some time and appreciate
that era. I had a blast pulling all this
together and really taking an indepth
look at the art direction the brand has
done in their campaigns, in their
presentation, and on their social media.
So, we're going to break it down for you
as a toolkit of what this means for
brands, what this means for you as a
creative, and what you can learn from
them about your own creative work. We're
going to talk through recurring ideas
and the motifs they use in a lot of
their campaigns. We're going to talk
through the foundations of art direction
for a luxury house like this and what do
they actually build their world around?
editorial, still life, behind the
scenes, sets, even events and showcases.
And we're going to talk about concepts
and the visual concepts that really help
define their brand and make all these
mismatch of things feel distinctly low.
And then I'm actually going to walk
through their social media, their Tik
Tok in particular, and just break down
some of the content and tactics that
have been so effective for them to stand
out in the new world. I am super excited
for this one. This is by far the funnest
of the art direction videos that I've
done after Stuy and Rick and all these
others. excited for y'all to come on the
ride. Let's lock in. So, first I want to
take a look at what Lee looked like a
decade ago. So, if we look at their 2013
ad campaign, it has Penelopey Cruz in
it. They're showcasing the Amazon bag.
But literally, the call out for this
campaign is that they used a wide angle
lens for it. That's how far the creative
and campaigns have come from this era
and this look and feel to the fun and
playfulness of the full realization of
the Jonathan Anderson era. And one thing
I love and appreciate about brands like
this is they've actually published so
much of their work over time. So in
2017, they published two books just on
their past, present, and future
showcasing their campaigns, their
creative process, what they're thinking,
presenting their images and what they do
as art. And this documentation is
something I feel is important and
everyone should think about as their
brand and their creative. If you are
making amazing, interesting art, then
actually showing that and displaying it
as such and releasing it as such,
documenting it is a big part of that
process. I ordered something from House
of Errors the other week and I got like
a book about House of Errors in the box.
Like they're actually making sure that
people know the work that they're
putting into their creative and they're
publishing it in that way. Let's start
off by talking about the recurring
motifs. So every brand visually when
you're making campaigns, it's good to
have a visual toolkit that you can refer
back to kind of time and time again that
has recurring things that come up inside
the imagery. So for Lee, this is
placement within nature. You will see
that so little of their campaigns happen
in anything modern. It happens a lot
outside. You see greenery, you see the
landscape, you see part people
participating in something in the world,
rarely indoors. And this might seem
subtle, but it's important part of the
brand. It would be completely different
than if you always saw someone in an
environment or if they're always in a
brutalist postmodern environment, always
near buildings, always with technology.
That choice to embrace nature is a
visual choice that when it's a
throughine over enough time really
begins to define a brand. And the second
one, and perhaps what they are most
known for to casual observers in today's
era, is the use of fruit and vegetables
within their campaigns. Mostly fruit. I
will argue over whether tomato is a
fruit in a separate video. Does have
seeds, but they are leaning into this in
the form of their products and in the
direction of everything around them from
the packaging. This iconic LeeBe tomato
that you'll now see is on their bags, is
in their website, is on their social
media. They're turning big balloons and
turkey into this. They are taking this
idea of this real world natural item of
fruit and applying it across the expanse
of what they do. And I feel like
identifying those objects that can stand
for your brand is really interesting and
important. And so they've taken motifs
like this and they've applied it to
still life. We'll talk about this in the
foundation section of this video in a
second, but they do lots of campaigns
that basically just feature their
products intermixed with fruit. But then
they've also taken that into editorial.
So in this campaign I'm showing right
here, one of their more kind of prolific
ones, there's no product shown inside
these. It is purely the models of this
campaign. This LE kind of look with
fruit in their mouths. And that is
representative of the campaign and
collection that they were doing for the
time without any product shown. And with
that, with this still life comes this
idea of product as sculpture that when
they're presenting it, you're presenting
as if you present an art object as if it
is something that is about to be
painted. This is an art direction choice
that they're choosing in terms of how
they show their product when they do
show it. You will rarely see anything
that comes from the brand that is
presented in any kind of normal light
angle or circumstance. It is always
presented as if it is a solo art object
or is it if it is a still life in
context of art being documented or
created. And so of those three, the
nature, the fruit, the product is
sculpture. The first three pillars. The
next two are a bit of a departure. Next
one is craft. And something this is
every luxury brand should have. But this
dedication to what makes this product
unique? Why does it take so much time?
Why is it so expensive? It's something
that they relentlessly put inside of
their marketing and inside of their
campaigns. There's a lot of times a
showcase of where something is made, the
texture of it, and then also all these
unique processes to actually create some
of these more complicated things is a
throughine that they've leaned into, I
think, as much as any luxury brand and
especially on their YouTube, which we'll
get to in a minute, have really put
together an expansive behind the scenes
on. And then the last pillar is their
location. this highlight of Spain in
particular. They've leaned into being a
Spanish luxury house by constantly
having Spain as a focal point of what
they are doing, whether it's recording
content there, events there, this yearly
release that they have that's all around
a visa. They've taken this combination
and built that into something uniquely
them. So, what can we learn from this as
creatives or people with our own brands
is to have these through lines. I would
say make the decision of where you're
shooting. Can you build a through line
for that the way that they do with
nature? The way they say almost
everything they're doing is outside or
has greenery in it. What is your
decision choice? Are you always inside,
always outside, always showing people in
a livedin environment, multiple people?
What are those decisions you can make to
stand out? And same thing with your
recurring motifs, the way that they have
fruit inside of so many of their shoots.
Can you always have cars? That was a
through line with a lot of the Stusy
work I covered before, tools, animals,
like what are those recurring things
that you can have as a throughine that
over time people begin to automatically
associate your brand with wiredhaired
dachshund or whatever the way that Lee
is associated with the tomato. Then that
conversation of how do you shoot your
product? They're always presenting their
product as sculpture as still life. Do
you have a unique way that you can put
it there, but you're never showing it on
the white background. It's always on
concrete or it's always a certain type
of lens or you include a macro shot next
to the main shot. Is there something you
can do to make it stand out? And then if
you do have craft to highlight, how do
you do it? I think this is a good point
in time to talk through some of these
craft videos on their YouTube because
they basically do a making video in
Spain for for the majority of their more
popular products. They are showing how
they are made. They're walking through
the design. They're showing inside the
factory. They're having one of the
designers inside this place actually
walk through the patterns. They're
showing this in a level of detail that
honestly a lot of these luxury brands
rarely show. And they'll do this making
of video for those. And you'll see they
have episode after episode from the
hammock bag to the puzzle wallet.
They're laying out every one of the
tools that's being used to create it,
every piece of leather from the pattern
and they're showing that process. And
then right next to that, they're leaning
into the craft of some actual process.
So this entire video is about the
ancient craft of kama, which is a
Japanese craft of iron tea kettles. That
they are basically just saying, "Hey, we
appreciate the craftsmanship of these
things so much that we want to document
it as part of our marketing and content
strategy to associate our brand with
people who take their craft incredibly
seriously." And then last, this idea of
location. So one of my favorite parts
about their locations, they have this
yearly series, the Paula Aabisa
campaign. It's a yearly collaboration
collection that they do, but it's always
set inside a visa. They're documenting
the party and nightlife culture of the
island. They're shooting on the location
of it, and it becomes a through line. As
much as you see them in the actual more
developed areas of Spain, they're
actually seeing to actually create the
products or cut these patterns or do
those events. You're getting into this
legendary island that's part of that
ecosystem to tell a very different story
there. But it happens every year like
clockwork in collaboration. I think for
a lot of brands thinking about where
they're from and their culture and what
they do there whether that's a yearly
surf contest or a rodeo or a race or a
meetup or whatever that looks like is
there where would you want to appreciate
and if you are in Texas do you want to
be going down to Trellinga making that a
part of your lore or Marfa or some or a
massive national park or if you're from
you know some kind of very different
country and you're doing this all from
the Philippines like what are those
things you could highlight that are
innately related to your culture that
you appreciate and want to make part of
your brand. So today's video is brought
to you by Musicbed. They are an amazing
resource for unlimited licensing for
music for your creations as a creator or
for your brand if you are creating
campaigns and content around them. One
of my favorite things about Musicbed is
the ability they have within their
interface to actually search and select.
You can search by genre like you see
here. They have it broken out by mood
attributes if you want to get Latin,
Korean, industrial, grungy. You can find
specific instruments. You can go
advanced and look by key. BPM for speed
and you can cut directly into lyrical
versus instrumental immediately within
any of these categories. So it is a very
easy to build a library of things to go
through to find the perfect song for
you. And to tie this into what we've
been talking about here with Lee, like
music direction is the way I think most
people need to be thinking critically
about the content and campaigns they
create. So what do I mean by that? When
you think about like from a psychology
perspective, what is the music you are
doing trying to achieve? So a few quick
notes there like thinking a lot about
speed. Do you want to create space with
the music you have so people can take in
what the content is saying or do you
want to, you know, with something slower
or do you want to build up the speed and
the pace to make people go along with
it? And even things like minor and major
keys, like how could that define a
brand? We often think about genre to
easily define a brand, but take that
down lower. Like major keys can be
uplifting and like really build some
mood, but can get kind of cheesy fast.
Minor keys can really evoke emotion. I
think thinking about the music direction
of projects is really useful. And one
other tip I have, one reason I really
like browsing music bed like this is I
click through songs, I immediately click
to the bridge because what I found with
like 90% of 15second ads, 30-cond ads,
is the part that I want, I'm going to
find here in this transition between
when they comment down to when and then
they bring back in to whatever drop they
have is often going to be that emotional
moment that's going to work best in your
actual campaign. So, you will see me
extensively as I browse through this,
click into these bridge areas and try to
find those moments. Because really, when
you're doing music direction like in
this era and you're actually looking
through these songs, you're looking for
a couple things. You're looking for an
like an amazing emotional grab that can
stop people and make the music a part of
what you're doing. Or you're looking for
a transition point where you're going to
change something in your video from like
behind the scenes to what you're
actually showcasing or like the
transformation where you can basically
do a beat drop and it will basic and
there's enough of a hardcore transition.
that actually makes like a real emotion
come out of it that's evocative. or
you're looking for something potentially
viral like I have this I hate New York
song bookmarked here because for one of
the campaigns we're working on I think
people would actually potentially use
this audio actually make their own
version of it because the way he does
this thing on the bridge and so if you
kind of hunt for that you hunt for those
transition points you hunt for those
moods you hunt for those viral potential
moments like you're beginning to do some
real music direction and the last thing
is loops one of the keys to especially a
lot of vlog content is if you can start
it and end it so it feels like it's one
continuous thing you're going to get
longer view time so I'm also when I'm
clicking through these always looking
for like is there a banging loop here
where I can kind of really nail in that
7 seconds, 15 seconds to match a social
campaign. So anyway, these are some of
my favorites. I might just do like a
music bed playlist of my favorites and
publish that like in a future video. Let
me know if that's interesting. You can
learn more about them and sign up for a
free trial of music bed at the link down
below. Thank you so much. So those are
the pillars, the recurring ideas you see
within LEB's content. Now let's talk
about the foundations, especially
foundations for building like a luxury
house like this. How do you what do you
build your content around? And from
there we'll go into some of the actual
art direction concepts you can add into
your toolkit. So first every release
they do a combination of things and
there's a blueprint that most brands
follow very similar. They do an
editorial release. So basically using
models to showcase the items that they
are presenting and they also have a
still life for this and you will note
inside their kind of site where they
show off all these collections. They
usually put both side by side. So
literally as we scroll through this you
will see they do editorial with uh Megan
Rapeno here but then also they have this
still life collection. They're kind of
linking both. So they are side by side
always identifying that when we do a
release we do editorial and then we do
still life. And then in addition to that
you will see the behind the scenes like
I pulled up already of the bags being
pulled apart etc. That's a part of every
year of that release as part of their
toolkit. Editorial still life behind the
scenes and then that location element.
They're not doing that every campaign
but they are doing it every year.
They're having this abuses spotlight and
this forms the playground within which
within which they create content until
the Tik Tok era which we'll get to at
the end. But one thing I wanted to note
about the editorial style of this is
they worked with a partner MM MM Paris
for many years of the campaigns you see
on this list. The last few years looks
like they're a little bit less involved
but for a lot of the the years leading
up to they worked with this one specific
partner. I'm scrolling through here
specifically on production. They
basically got a set made for every
single one of these shoots and campaigns
that they did by this group in Paris
that makes these very intricate,
interesting sets. And you'll see within
those actual campaigns, they call it out
each time they will have this kind of
weird black chandelier that every one of
the models is set in front of. They will
have this incredible rope background
pattern. It will have this weird stone
heart sculpture that they have here. All
this is production that's being
engineered specifically to be the anchor
of that campaign. That's another big
takeaway I think people should think
about is everyone's doing these white
background shoots now, right? Everyone's
shooting inside these studios. They will
have a handful of things here or there.
Everyone's setting this up. They're
obviously putting some props or
production, but having someone fabricate
a centerpiece for this is a strategy
that luxury brands are doing and is
something that I think is a great way to
find a signature partner, build out a
budget, and include within each of these
as an approach that you can take because
especially in the social media era, that
gets more and more interesting because
then can you actually put that out in
the street for 36 hours and have your
fans interact with it? Can you shoot
video in and around it to become a set
piece the way I have this behind me that
works for the whole season and comes in
and out? You display it at trade shows.
Bringing those things into the real
world, sending it to an influencer's
house, whatever it looks like is, you
know, kind of a way you can extend that
campaign beyond the photo shoot. But I
want you to think about from your
brand's perspective, what are you doing
for editorial? What are you doing for
still life? Are you using any set for
it? Are you using and if so, what do you
do with it to extend beyond that? You
doing any behind the scenes? And then
are you involving any kind of recurring
locations or going back to it within
that that will help you take some
inspiration from what LOV has put
together. But now let's actually go to
visual concepts. Probably the most
interesting part of the art direction
toolkit is less all these kind of
foundations and the more tactical stuff
I outlay, but like what are the ideas?
What's interesting? So they have
combination of four things that I've
identified and appreciate about that
toolkit. You may look at it slightly
differently. I will never pretend in any
of these videos to be the end all
resource on Rick or Lobe or any of this.
I am just an appreciator and just trying
to break it down in ways I feel people
can learn from. So, I know someone deep
in the lore may look at this
differently. Let's look at surrealism
and displacement as the first one.
Basically, unexpected object pairings,
odd compositions, like dreamlike
elements. It's just a constant recurring
thing inside of everything we saw. But
it's rooted in in realism, right? Even
those last few fabrication pieces we
looked at where it's like these massive
coils of rope. It's all feels familiar.
It feels real. It's just somehow
displaced, oversized, put out there in a
way that we never expected. But it's
doing this rooted in reality versus
someone like Jacqu Moose who's rooted in
a in a inherent playfulness and almost
goofiness in how that's put together.
Something that feels very much more
French versus this feels Spanish. I'd
apologize to all my euros, but I'm not
afraid of you. Negative space and
stillness is the next one. This idea of
a calm, almost eerie minimalism that
forces the eye to focus. Not like
hammering in that they're trying to sell
you something, but basically suggesting
that you look at this thing that is like
featured inside the composition. And
third, the art and sculpture references
are super obvious throughout. so much of
this where they're basically staging
these photos like museum installations.
And even these campaign sets, even the
way you show that behind the scenes
looks like something that's about to
have a glass pane put over it and then
be placed in a museum. And this is just
a composition technique, right? How can
we take something in the real world?
Let's take the way things are presented
inside a museum and present our products
the same way. And then last, this idea
of kind of humor and absurdity. They're
not a brand that's afraid to have fun.
And but the playfulness is done through
essentially like a dead pan weirdness.
It's not done through like a haha funny.
And one thing I encourage lots of brands
to do is a lot of brands are afraid of
humor. But humor, especially in the
social media era, is so crucial, right?
Because it's just a core human emotion
that immediately gets you more views,
saves, and shares. And so, as opposed to
trying to make someone laugh, you or
tryh hard fashion in general, they're
kind of living in this middle ground
where like you inherently appreciate it,
that's nuanced, but you don't have to be
nuance. can pick your ability to say,
"Hey, our brand actually, it's more at
our behest to kind of do some dad jokes
or to have this really elevated level of
humor or to be tasteful about it or for
it to be more like slapstick, so it's
just more visceral when it goes about
it." Think about those approaches and
like how that could work within your
creative toolkit, whether that's
campaign by campaign, brand by brand, or
or for you. So, now last, I want to
actually walk through their social media
cuz they've done an incredible job with
it. And we can walk through some of the
tactics. This is the world that I live
in the most. If you had talked to me a
couple years ago, I would be spending
most of my time on campaign shoots.
Right now I spend most of my time in
tactical social media. What do we do
week to week, monthtomonth? And they've
got a fun approach for some of this.
Something that they do excellently I
think a lot of brands can learn from on
TikTok is they will take a viral video,
something that is happening in the
culture, and just remake it. This is a
classic brand strategy where they will
just get the original influencer and
they will just redo it. Reformation was
kind of like the queens of this a few
years ago where they would literally
take creators that make an amazing video
type or had a viral video and be like,
"Remake this video wearing a Reformation
dress." This is the essentially this
version of this where we've seen these
videos, these people swinging off boats
before. She just happens to be doing it
in a reformation dress, but they're not
afraid of playing into trending sounds.
This is a very account that is willing
to have fun. Same thing with this. This
is just another trend that they are
acting on. And it's funny how few brands
feel uh they're willing to participate
in trends, but then the brand is
elevated as Lee is also trying to do it.
So, this was a uh this was a trend where
you were seeing where people would have
like something to take the edge off.
They had like a piece of carrot cake
where you typically hold a sig. They're
doing this here with progressively
bigger and bigger candles. And there's
just something to playing into those
trends and letting some of the absurdism
of your product go into it. But as you
watch us scrolling through this, they're
doing all types of content. There's no
limitation to what the content looks
like. You don't know what to expect. And
that is a strategy in itself. But
they're doing a lot of it by engaging
influencers, having them on their own
accounts. Like she's opening a blind
box. They're hosting stuff with
influencers inside of their actual
events. You do not know what you're
going to see. This is all right next to
like a process video of something being
made. You do not know what you're going
to expect in the Lee account. I think
that is a good thing for the majority of
luxury brands to be willing to put any
all these kind of concepts out there.
This is them inflating their giant
tomato balloon and showing the behind
the scenes. And again, this isn't a Tik
Tok format. That is the default Tik Tok
font. This was shot on an iPhone. This
is not a high production quote unquote
luxury video. It is conceptual and it
shifts into it with some of the footage
they have at the end. Another one with a
collaboration with where they are
literally doing a trend. I say a lot of
this to say that a lot of brands take
Tik Tok way too seriously. You need to
be unexpected. If you are doing
something normal, you're doing something
repetitive on there. If it does not
work, if it's not putting out crushing
views, you need to just focus on being
more interesting and more exciting
within that. And they've built this
world where it does not matter at all.
One of the things I really want to call
out around this is the way that they've
leveraged influencers. What they've done
for that is they've done like let
influencers be good at what they are
going to do and what they do already.
So, one of these I want to call out is
uh Adnan who makes content very similar
to what I uh make on TikTok or used to
make. I make less of it now where he's
kind of doing histories of fashion or
luxury or telling some of the stories.
He did these really good long- form
stories. And so, he is telling Lee's
story on Lee's account. This isn't even
on his account. They were basically
like, "Hey, come do what you do best.
Talk about us and do it on our account."
And this is the kind of thing where you
would so rarely see a green screen
creator like inside like a luxury thing
like this. But they said, "Hey, we're
going to put people in what they're best
at and we're going to do it in a way
that works in our brand world." And I
have a lot of innate respect for that. I
feel like a lot of brands who don't
necessarily have a strategy, they don't
know what they do, would be kind of wise
to start with this. Say, "Hey, let's get
10, 15, 25 creators over the next few
months and just put them in a position
on our page to create something that is
like what they do really well and let's
see if that works for the audience. So
that carries over and we can basically
use their acumen to tell our story on
our media without necessarily paying
that full price for the post on theirs
or doing both. So anyway, I know we
covered a lot within this, but I really
do feel like this is a useful toolkit
for centering a brand. This is not some
like off-the-wall toolkit. It's not some
big streetear toolkit you can only pull
off if you're a fashion brand. This is
really rooted in the basics of like
amazing art direction, right? Having
these recurring ideas, the way they have
nature and fruit and their location and
craft and product is sculpture. having
these foundations of those repeatable
things you do. The way that they're
doing multiple campaigns a year with
their still life and their editorial,
making a set and also doing a yearly
piece based around a place with a
collaboration, having those recurring
concepts, the way that they have that
surrealism, displacement, negative
space, art and sculpture, like humor and
absurdity, having that world that's like
defined that they can then build within
and out and then having fun and taking
it places unexpected in some what
they've done on social media. So anyway,
if you liked this, I have plenty other
ones on the same playlist in this
series. We've done, as I mentioned, Rick
Owens. We've done Road. We've done Stuy.
There are plenty uh more that are coming
up that I have in the list. I'm going to
do some category ones coming up. I think
I'm going to do one on Quiet Wealth. I
think I'm going to do one on kind of
modern street wear. Still kind of
prepping that. If you have any ideas,
would love the comments below. Overall,
I appreciate you so much for watching.
Thank you.
[Music]