We have reached a crossover point where
AI is actively displacing creative jobs
or at the least significantly changing.
This is a topic that I have resisted
talking about extensively in my videos
cuz I felt we weren't really at that
tipping point. You can easily get caught
in that ecosystem of guys in dark rooms
talking about the new AI model and how
it changes everything. And I'm never
going to be one of those people. But the
market is shifting right now. And in
this video, I want to break down the
scenario that's happening for anyone in
marketing and creative work and in
agencies and in brands. Talk about the
levels of engaging with AI and the gifts
and curses of each. And then break down
how I actually use AI in my work with
exact workflows we're going to share
here. I'm going to show you how I use
Comet to do analysis for sentiment and
social analysis for brand strategy work.
I'm going to show you how we use Manis
to do influencer research. We're going
to talk about the second brain you can
build for yourself or your marketing org
inside Claude or Chatg GPT effectively
using AI for copy. How I built a clone
of myself for my org to use and then dip
into visuals, show you my exact workflow
for how we are generating transitions
for content, how we're doing AI hooks,
how you can do logo animation and some
of the 3D work that you see. We're going
to talk about creating people and the
mumification of people and then scenario
graphics. And then we're going to go
real pro at the end of it. I'm going to
break down how I use agent mode in Excel
and some of the really deep dive brand
prompting you can get into. This is both
an existential video covering a lot of
the future of creative work and also an
ultra tactical video you can pull away
with some exact workflows that will save
you a ton of time. We'll have some fun
along the way. Let's lock in. So, I want
to start by talking about that shadowy
force in the world. I'm the comm. So, in
agency land, for those of you that don't
know, there are these really large
agencies, thousands to tens of thousands
to more employees that perform a lot of
the marketing work for major brands.
There's a big merger amongst them over
this last chunk of time that came to a
finale in the last week or so, including
the loss of about 4,000 creative jobs
and showcases to you just how much of a
meat grinder creative work has become.
We are no longer in the world where
agencies can afford to have a project
manager and a copywriter and a
strategist and an art director and the
actual designer and the actual workers
doing all the things for these accounts.
That is not the way the world works as
they know it. And at the same time, same
thing with analysts. All of these kind
of mid-tier jobs or specialist jobs can
be done by people who are more of a jack
of all trades or can be enabled by AI.
And let's be clear, these agencies a do
not care about you. They exist to drive
profits for their overlords who make way
more money. They want your creative work
distilled down to its lowest billable
hour whenever possible.
>> Can't be an ANGRY MOM WITHOUT PITCHFORK.
>> They want you to live and die by a time
sheet, by a project cost. They will
always be upcharging in ways that once
you start to see the economics of it,
you will you'll seem unfathomable. But
then at the same time, you have to
recognize that these agencies are just
there for safety. They are a safe choice
for brands that are afraid of the world.
this agency can help me navigate through
all these crazy changes of social media
and the landscape. And those companies
are getting ravaged along the way in
terms of overcharge for things that
don't deliver just so they can be told
that things will be okay while their
strategies implode. And if they do
continue to succeed, they do it by the
grace and goodwill of the other things
that happen for their companies. And so
if you are caught in the middle of this,
you are a creative and you work in some
of these scenarios, maybe you work for a
small agency that's great with some good
people, they'll eventually get bought by
the bigger agency. You'll eventually end
up inside of these worlds. Eventually,
you will work at a company that employs
one of these agencies to do work for you
and wonder, "How did you get here?" And
you'll realize you are a pawn inside
their creative games. Now, you've heard
in my other videos, I will always say
for every creative personal brand is the
future. This is your card to be able to
get out of this. It's not what this
video is about. But it is important to
note if you want to have control of your
destiny, whether you have a thousand
followers or 100,000 or a million
followers, being able to go out to those
people whenever you need work or
freelance, etc., and say, "I am here.
pay me money is a superpower that gets
you immediately out of the creative meat
grinder of the agency industry. Now, if
you have content savvy of any kind, if
you understand some of how this new
world works and you have some
distribution and you are a AI savvy, you
can jump what I call the exploitation
gap. Traditional marketing work is
exploiting the brands that they are
charging or they are exploiting the
workers that are below them or both. And
if you are able to with some of the
tactics I'm going to show today actually
conduct some of this work and bypass
that system, you will be able to offer a
better experience for the brands at a
lower rate and you will be able to make
more money yourself than being an
employee. This is an important thing to
think about as you begin to structure
the world around you. And if you are
working at a company that you love and
there are plenty of those out there and
I highly recommend working in org where
everyone's working towards something and
you want to make a real difference in
this kind of new world that's the same
exact scenario where you can begin to
look at how am I enabled by these tools
that are out there and how am I savvy in
the content of the modern world because
then you can make a real difference as a
creative inside an organization. But
this brings us to this heady moment of
AI and when I talk about AI and work I
use AI for imagery and generating
imagery and more creative or art stuff
mainly for my content. uh sometimes for
ad content, ad creative, for brands,
occasionally inside a campaign to like
patch a shot. It is more for strategy
work. It is more for research, for
things that are like actually not
amazing uses of my time comparative to
how AI can do it. And so I'll cover both
here so you can see the full gambit. But
it's worth noting this isn't going to be
your deep dive in your midjourney
workflow to make perfect people because
that content doesn't really matter. It
doesn't really help. But let's start
with the levels of AI. Everyone's afraid
of it and they're talking about it. What
happens? So the first is superpowered
people. You will note that there are
people out there who have crazy
workflows, who are able to do really
interesting things for their companies
because they have been superpowered by
the ability to do all these things with
AI. They are rare and far in between is
likely not going to be me or you or
anyone we know. Then you have AI enabled
with a spectrum. So if you use a lot of
those tools, you're able to do a lot
more in your work. You're able to do
more faster and you're able to bat above
your weight class. That's the goal we
have for most people with AI. And then
there's AI resistant. They don't want to
do it. They only do it if they have to,
which is the worst scenario to be in.
Now the fourth level is you just don't
need it at all. You build fences, you do
whatever. You don't need to think about
it. That's the case. Great. But if
you're in the work where you are being
pushed upon it, you're seeing other
people use it in your field and you are
resistant. There's two levels of
resistant. The resistant, I really don't
want to do this, but you don't have like
some dead heart against it. And then
there's I don't want to do this and I'm
like angrily commenting on videos about
AI. And that's the group I want to
address because that's the group that
finds a way to believe anything that
they read, right? They find a way to
politicize it. They love the dopamine
deep down of an angry comment on a video
that oh call them out for using AI. They
love that dark energy. They love to
hate.
>> Let the hate flow through you.
>> And it's a generational thing. This is a
common thread through a lot of people
that went through co. They need someone
to blame for how they feel about
themselves and what they see in the
world and they don't know what to do.
And this is the easiest target. It's
this big intangible force. And if you
are if you see people in that bucket,
you got to get away from them because
it's kind of the darkest of what the
internet gives us. And if you're
resisting because you don't know where
to begin or how it's actually useful or
don't believe in its efficacy, this is a
great video for you to be able to
actually dive into it. So I want to
start with some creative scenarios
actually show some of what brands are
doing right now. The first is Valentino
in a very controversial move made this
completely ridiculous AI video with a
relatively obscure artist with someone
who just makes oddball surreal AI art
quote unquote and put it on Valentino
Maine as a major luxury brand like
sparking this conversation and you'll
see the comments call me a hater this
looks cheap and on brand and you'll get
a lot of the is a tacky AI mess and it's
interesting to note that when you look
at who is commenting that you look at
who the Valentino customer is there's no
overlap so they probably don't give a
[ __ ] [ __ ] what these people have to say
and those comments only inform their
showcase there. You go this is the
artist page of what he does which again
is like very like odds surreal
propaganda art basically that's one
approach. There's one luxury approach
here and then we have Revolve. Revolve
did a whole series of AI items for their
Revolve world launch which mostly just
kind of your regular female consumer
account comments which are a bunch of
emojis basically putting themselves in
different scenarios with AI. It's very
hard to tell for their consumers. And
the one that was easiest to tell is this
London one, which they've been basically
deleting the backlash comments about.
But they've just leaned right into on
feed on Maine to achieve their their
content goals and really hasn't had any
negative impact for them. Right? Maybe
there's some negative comments on a few
of these, but is just a campaign that is
in action right now by a major retailer.
And the last I want to bring up is
Leebe, which just happened today. Uh
this video will come out a little bit
later. So Leebe has this series with a
creator. So she's basically saying is
this real or is it AI and that is the
she's hosting this on the web's main
feed and they're basically crossing that
fourth wall. It's not is this AI content
or not? Is AI content right or not? Just
is basically using it as a character
inside the story with very positive
response. All of this is happening
within days of each other. This is now a
content format that exists and is out
there and you have people trying to
slide by that are unnoticed. You have
people approaching it as art and you
have people approaching it as basically
like a cultural moment that this is
which is a smart way to do it. And then
the biggest category of all and that's
the things that we just don't notice. So
companies that I work with and talk to,
one of them generates e-commerce images
for AI and they are 20% 30% of retailers
you would never expect have already
moved all their stuff over and you would
never know. Another friend of mine works
specifically with luxury brands doing
all the CGI work that CGI artists used
to do before in 3D viz. His firm now
does with AI. No one better than
eyelash. No one even knew it looks the
same on feed. And that is the fourth
level of how premium brands are
interacting with this. Which brings us
to the head we're at today because that
CGI work is a really important one
because that was high paid, high talent
work that's now being done for a much
lower cost. And so those artists have a
choice of how they're going to pivot.
Are they going to move to the enabled
work and basically change from doing
lots of intense work on relatively small
number of projects or are they going to
embrace kind of the new era and do the
enabled version? And that's a big
turning point for a lot of those people.
what they learned and why they learned
it and what they're choosing to do and
also for any people who are choosing to
learn those skills and it's just a
watershed moment of many other things
that are likely to come. But moving over
into tactical, I want to go into
strategy work here. So I love perplexity
comment for this video is not sponsored
by Perplexity. This is just the best
tool for the job. But I use this to
summarize Tik Tok comments all the time.
So if I was going to do creatine
reviews, for instance, if you're doing
research in a space, I'm in beauty all
the time. So, if we're releasing a new
lip product or a new concealer product
or a new mist or whatever it is, doing
very similar things to this. So, I will
say watch 100 to 300 of these videos,
list out the most mentioned brands with
their pros and cons and what content
strategies are performing best in these
reviews. And if I have it open on this
Tik Tok search, agent mode will take
over. You'll see my screen went blue
like that. And it is going to basically
go and zoom through hundreds of these to
come up with that. You can also
screenshot and do sentiment. I've asked
it to do demographic info on age and
race doing stuff like this before. But
the Tik Tok comments, if you've seen
some of my other videos before, is like
the best brand strategy place ever,
right? Because you get real people in
the comments asking like basically
telling exactly what they think while
people are doing some combination of
paid or unpaid versions of promoting
these products upfront and you get to
have a real sentiment about people will
literally share this is my problem with
this, what I liked about it, I had a
good experience, I didn't. You're able
to get a large synopsis. We do a lot of
these and you get these pretty thorough
reports that come out on the other side.
And while that is working, that's the
beauty of agent mode. I want to talk
about Manis. So Manis is great because
it has access to the Tik Tok API as
well. So what I have been doing with
Manis is I basically asked it to find
influencers and people we can seed
content to. So another time-consuming
thing you work on inside my niche is
influencer research. You always need
more people to seed, more people to
reach out to be creators for your brand,
more Tik Tok shop affiliate leads,
whatever it is. And so Madness was able
to actually search and then load those
people inside Tik Tok. They could do it
based on hashtags. They could do it
based on words. And so I was able to go
through for people that had mentioned
other brands or other routines, link it
by follower size. And they would then
verify that and their frequency of
posting if they're active and come out
with a list. On the other side, I
literally listed out those parameters. I
would say, I'm looking for creators
between 5,000 200,000 followers who have
mentioned these brands or these
keywords. They have posted content in
the last month. Get me a list. And agent
mode takes a while, right? I will go
leave or work on other stuff but 20
minutes later I will end up with a
comprehensive list where it'll give me
100 200 so much. So what I like about
Manis is a kind of full function
interface and ask it to make a front end
for me where I can enter the keywords
and it'll just generate the list on the
other side basically like a functional
website I can use for my team. That took
a little bit of vibe coding and ensuring
it got right was all done within one
platform. And so what do you do when you
get results from stuff like this or when
you're looking to actually input stuff
from AI into strategy work you're doing?
The other portion of this you may have
seen in a previous hyper newsletter I
did we shared kind of the master prompt
from uh we actually did this on the
brand fathers Ashwin Jordan and I on the
podcast but inside this newsletter we
have this prompt that you are the
in-house brand strategist for the brand
and you list the brand's value
proposition and then we list out what
your list is to do and the tone of voice
you have. This is the kind of thing you
can put into a project to get it to work
for you. If you want to make a project,
click over into projects. I have a very
similar one of those in here for this
for a glow sunscreen. You can make a
project. You can add the instructions to
the project. So, my instructions here
have all of the information about the
brand has that complete prompt. You can
add any files if you have brand guides
or other things on there. And then that
becomes something you can actually ask
any of the questions you have. Another
example, something similar is when I was
doing a quizfunnel research, working on
a quizunnel for a brand. basically
people who use ads that lead you to
quizzes to get information that then
sell versus just ads that lead you to
buy. So a good example of that is ilm
makiage where I'm looking at
specifically what do they do? How has
that led to their market positioning?
What does it do to their financial
success? You can ask some kind of
questions about that and get links to go
down the rabbit hole on but then that
becomes something where you can take a
summary of that and then pop it into the
project you have. But creating that
second brain for the brand I'll link the
master prompt here becomes a very useful
thing to do. All of the things I
mentioned in this video you'll have a
link with everything that is inside of
it. you'll be able to get down below for
all the software, etc. See, I pop back
over to comment. It's still going and
that's the beauty of it. I wanted to
watch 300 videos. It is going through
300 videos. But then if you do have a
lot of info or documentation or you do
have a real thesis on how you work. So
for instance, I have all of my YouTube
videos. I have all of my hyper
newsletters and I have all of my
internal documentation. So I made a
project out of that. This one's in chat
GPT because our company or uses chat
GPT. It's a little OJ that basically
whenever anyone has a question about
brand strategy or content strategy, they
can query it and get my response and it
is incredibly accurate. And what it has
is literally transcripts of every
YouTube video I put out from the last
two years. Easy enough to grab. We just
put it through a transcriber. I'm sure
you could probably AI automate that plus
the things I've written, plus the
reports that I've done. So, it's a very
general idea of what I do and not what I
recommend and is eerily accurate. And
so, when we're looking for campaign
ideas, we're able to put it through it.
While agent mode works in the
background, we're going to get into the
visual section of this video. This video
is in partnership with Leonardo, who I'm
going to use to walk through this. It's
kind of a little bit of a different
partnership because I use Leonardo every
day for all this stuff. And I'm
literally just going to show you all the
things I'm doing within it. And you'll
see when I load it, it has called out a
new model that is available inside of
it. So, one of the benefits of software
like Leonardo, it has all of the models
inside of it. You can see for anyone who
has watched my short form videos and
noticed I do all these backgrounds. Now,
these are all generated in here. But the
one that I want to start with that's
likely one of the most valuable for
people is the logo variation. So for
instance, this is the logo for my status
symbols newsletter, but now presented as
a marble sculpture or burned into wood,
dropped onto a toiley style in a luxury
plate. And most importantly, animated. I
know a lot of you have probably spent
either a lot of money or a lot of time
generating animations and things like
that for inside of graphics or on
websites, whatever that looks like. This
is one of the best things you can do.
This by prompt here is literally rotate
around the logo slowly. I had generated
the image by being say hey I want to
make a reflective version of this logo
hovering on a green background. It had
given me some options for that. That was
all in nano banana inside of here. And
then generated this in Veo 3. And you
can see these are the kind of things you
can experiment with. Some of them better
than others, right? Like I might cut
this out with a removed background, but
I wouldn't use the star pattern. And you
can work through something interesting.
These are some of the most practical
uses inside there. The other one we see
all the time is the transition shot.
This is two screenshots that I am
transitioning between. I am in two
different scenarios in this. But
probably the most used of things that we
do in here is literally connecting
footage or piecing things together for
transitions inside of longer videos. We
are generating that all the time. This
just looks like a normal video of me,
but it literally was just two still
images of me looking at one thing versus
me in another booth and it transitioned
between them seamlessly using this
blueprint they have called frame flow.
So this is blueprints are like recipes
for AI [snorts] content you can use
inside of Leonardo. You're able to drag
a start frame and an end frame and it is
going to flow between them and you will
get stuff like this which we use again
all the time to just fill in stuff
inside shots that we need. We'll often
like speed ramp them to like move
through and short form content. Well,
another blueprint. This is going from
the actual product shot they do if they
have product spin videos. So, we've used
these a lot for little cut shots inside
of product videos or ads. We do all uh
so one of the really common uses of this
is to actually animate static ads. So,
if you have a static meta ad that just
had this photo in it with text, we would
animate the background so it's moving
and then put it behind the text in the
same way. And that is the product spin
video blueprint. And then there's the
actual outfit transitions. You've seen a
lot of these online. I prompted this in
cling ended up being the best solution
for this. I'll try a variety of models,
but then this is another one where we'll
just speed ramp it. You kind of see how
it moves from me in the sweatshirt to an
in between, etc. Like that's something
where I would probably speed ramp this a
little bit. It looks pretty good either
way. You've seen a lot of those
transition videos. That's just a prompt
in here. And I'm going to transition
between the two photos with everything
staying the same with the outfits which
blend into each other. That is the
literal prompt in cling. It's way
simpler than people are putting huge
JSON profiles. This is just two pictures
of me and it is transitioning. But I do
this all within the Leonardo interface
where I can just move between models,
grab my library of images all in one
place. And then the last thing you'll
see us doing a ton of is these like kind
of crazy infomercial ads and things that
are just hooks for projects we're
working on. We generated this as an
image to start. It was just an
infomercial of a night and then we had
someone explaining the product as an
infomercial. But again, this is just a
hook for an ad. If you've seen some of
my ad videos and stuff, you've seen some
examples of how those work. But 3D
animation is another just great use
case. Again, I was like, give me an
animation for an outboard motor and it
generates this and how it works. If you
want to do cutcreens in and around
content to explain things, especially if
you have any like rough diagram, that's
going to work great. Same thing with
this going inside the gummy to talk
about the creatine or the sugar. Those
are actual practical uses that make it
into content. And the last one I'm going
to talk about is likeness. You may have
seen this, which is gentle monster photo
shoots combined with me. Nano Banana is
great at combining images like this. And
we use it all the time for mainly fun
stuff. For instance, I hooked a video
the other day with me as every person
from Deal or No Deal. We have done a ton
of grandfather's promos like this where
it'll just be photos of Ashwin Jordan
and I in various scenarios. Same thing
seen the stuff where I have like a mini
me or something like that generated next
to it. A lot of like fun scenarios like
that that you can use to work into your
content and in ads especially little
things like this like putting a massive
product where you have the little
product having a cartoon character that
stuff really adds up when you're
generating variations and stuff like
that inside like a meta ads account. You
can learn more about Leonardo in the
description of this video. There's the
place I'm doing all of this visual work
from one app. Now, back over to
Perplexity, you'll see there's this
analysis. They have all the
comprehensive analysis. Echo Vision,
here's its pros and here's its cons.
They're using urgency tactics, limited
visibility on their reviews. Pros is the
pricing and the flavor variance. Primo
Labs, lots of paid partnerships, higher
price point, a lot of reliance on paid
versus organic. So, teaching me what to
trust. It's literally breaking me down
the brands I need to know, the common
pros and cons discussed like of the
product and the best performing
strategies, the educational list and
breakdowns, the body transformation
before and afters and it'll give me some
hooks, how creatine changed, my
experience, the five reasons why. It's
giving me those with likes. I did this
manually. This is work that I would do
all the time going into a new campaign
or a product launch. I would pull tons
of this stuff that we would then use to
get our ad briefs or to do our briefs
for organic content. And all of this is
now being provided to me. I don't just
take it for what it is, but look, we're
going to keep going here. Like audience,
demographics, primary Gen Z, fitness
enthusiasts, whatever, content format,
performance ranking, what does better or
not based on its likes. I'm not taking
this like as gospel, but I'm going to go
through and cherrypick all these good
hooks. I'm going to note the efficacy of
what that looks like, and I'm going to
ask it to deep dive on certain brands.
If I have one competitor, I'm going to
go be like, give me all the top
complaints about that, and I'm going to
address that in content. Same thing with
a niche. What are things everyone's
concerned about? Are there requests for
any flavors? like this is the kind of
stuff you can be asking and then having
comment go generate for you. Now, in
this last section, I'm going to talk
about the real pro workflows here. So,
HubSpot, um, again, this video isn't
sponsored by HubSpot, something I
actually use. So, shout out HubSpot.
They have this loop marketing prompt
library that is like crazy useful. So,
they have in all stages of their loop,
Express, Taylor, Amplify, Evolve, their
loop is um their kind of new version of
the funnel. So, tailor is all about how
do you refine messages for different
audiences. So, behavioral segmentation
builder, customer lifestyle map mapper,
predictive scoring models, dynamic
content optimizers, accountbased
personalization. These are like very
detailed specific prompts. Also good for
like B2Bs. This is like real business
basically. But, okay, intent signal
identifier. The useful of this is this
is stuff that takes real work. You're
not just going to plug in a sentence and
expect a result. You can go here and it
says literally, okay, paste your
analytics on high intent page visits.
Paste the content viewing patterns of
past converters. And you can go if you
have your data all in Chad Gasket to
spit it out, but paste your email data,
paste your sales interaction data, it's
asking you for a comprehensive list of
your information. So if you actually go
and hunt down this information, which if
you're inside a serious org, you can go
do, and you put it inside these
comprehensive prompts they put together,
you can get like true big kid real
business analysis. And this is where we
go back to jobs being taken analyst
stuff and stuff where you couldn't even
get this or you'd have to pay agencies
to do these massive undertaking efforts
to do this. They are solving this with
prompts. The hard part about this, you
have to go hunt down the data, which
again, if you're a serious company, you
can go do and you may even have
repositories of it. They have excellent
tools for this competitor gap finders.
Nobody will ask you to go be like, what
are the common themes your competitors
have and literally you're just going and
listing your main competitors, putting
the props and messaging from their
website, describing the landscape. You
can get chat to generate a bunch of
that, putting your core stuff in here,
and then it is doing the analysis for
you to come out of that. So, I highly
recommend if you want to get deep into
this or especially if you work at like a
real consultancy or if you are paying a
lot of money to do stuff like this now,
you would be surprised what you're going
to be able to do with systems like this.
And the last one I'm going to talk about
and the real godsend here is Excel agent
mode. So, for instance, this is how I
look at my content. This is my content
pillars, the four pillars I use every
month. My product reviews, my marketing
playbooks, my branding ideas, and my
marketing carousels. This is all my
stats that I pull manually. But then I
do my analysis with agent mode. Agent
mode went through and like topped ranked
these. Gave me my correlations of the
stats with views. Like shares has my
highest coefficient to correlation with
views. Saves even more. My hook rate
actually doesn't have much of a
correlation to views. Then I have my
correlation with follows top five
content. Like I basically have queried
and built out all this information about
my content all being done in agent mode
where I can literally ask Excel in the
sidebar to do those things for me and
then even ask it to plan a content mix.
If I want to gain x amount of followers,
here's my average followers per post.
what pillars should I be doing more or
less of? And I use a funnel system, so
less important, but just an example.
Now, for brands where we have way more
comprehensive data, it's the same exact
thing. You can actually go and analyze
your pillars and your reach and all that
without having to do a bunch of this
yourself, which I know marketing and
social media people hate and agent mode
is a cheat code for that. Another
version, this is a I asked you to make a
scorecard for me to build this out and
did the research. So, scorecards is
great where so setting spray is a core
product for a company I work for. I was
like, "All right, cool. go create a
ranking parameter system and bring in
every product in the market and rank
them against each other. And it created
this system with criteria and the weight
of the criteria which I could go adjust
if I said actually I want hold to be
less important than waterproof or less
important than fish than value. Let's
emphasize value. I could go change the
waiting and it took every company in
here aggregated reviews and put this
together and we could always go through
and change how we feel about it. But it
also broke down its top value props,
pros and cons. I didn't do a thing. This
just got done for me. And so I would not
underestimate at all and then having
this in Excel again where I can like
adjust the table and the rankings change
is wonderful. I would not underestimate
using Excel and agent mode inside this
either. So I know that was a lot of
workflows and a lot of things that we
covered in here. Now I'm giving the
quick version for a lot of these
overviews, but here to tell you where
you can be enabled and where you can
find some success with some of these AI
tools. You have questions about any of
this, what we use for what, what's
actually useful, not drop them below. I
will get to as many as I can. If you
want to see more of this in depth, maybe
I end up doing like a separate tutorial
channel or something like that. I will
link all the tools and props and stuff I
used below. And then you can check out
Leonardo that I use, who sponsored this
[music] video. As always, thank you all
so much for watching.