In this video, we are going to talk
about the art of the personal brand. How
to build a personal brand from beginner
to advanced. So, I'm going to cover
about 20 super critical concepts in here
from levels of a personal brand to
funnels, pillars, testing, what makes
sense for who, the difference between
personal branding and creator, how to
achieve your goals, content types to do
it. I am super excited about this
because over the last few years of
building a personal brand for the first
time, I have messed up constantly done
the wrong things. I've launched stuff
and not followed up. I've blown money.
I've gotten into bad content creation
habits. But every single time I picked
myself up and got right. And right now,
I've been on this trajectory, having
made content just a little bit under 3
years, coming up on a million followers,
and headed to be one of the bigger
personal brands in the space, if not in
general. And I've had to actually think
really critically about this because
I've done workshops at companies who
want their teams to develop it personal
brands. I've trained now thousands of
people in Cut 30 to make content for the
first time. is I've had to distill so
much of this down into actionable
frameworks and that's really where the
power is. And it's also something that
I'm passionate about, especially for a
younger generation of people to stand
out and especially for creatives,
marketers, people who have that special
something. You actually really get to
shine when you put yourself out there.
There's a lot of ways to do it. People
think about it the wrong way. And we're
going to break it all down here. Let's
lock it. So, first, it's funny. You will
see clickbait on here and on social
media that's like personal brands are
dead. And what I think they really are
meant to say is that being an influencer
sucks and being a creator is not for
everybody. But an interesting thing is
promoting yourself is permanent. It's
settled in. It's part of now our
cultural fabric that we exist in an era
of like AI resume generation and review.
We're remote. There's less mentorship.
There's gaps in training. And you can
see an inevitability when the workforce
just basically looks like little blips
on an AI radar. And personal brand is a
way to steer yourself out of that. And I
like to always use this chart when I
talk about this where basically we used
to have these traditional lives. You
have a job and then for many Americans
usually there's a side hustle, right?
But now with the creator journey for any
creative that's become much simpler
because basically you have so many ways
to easily make money that don't involve
having a whole separate business. The
actual networks will pay you to post on
them. You can do affiliate content and
stuff like Tik Tok shop. But also what I
don't even mention in this chart is that
you get basically more enterprise value
with a personal brand especially when
you're recognized in your niche.
companies begin to pay a premium for
those people over time and that doesn't
happen right away. But I say all this to
say personal brand is permanent. We are
never going back to a previous era. You
talk to a lot of people that were in the
workforce during co and they just want
everything to go back simpler. You keep
having this thought of like when are
things going to be like normal again or
easy or simple and the answer is they're
not. They grow increasingly complicated.
Things are increasingly noisy. One of
the biggest things that holds people
back from wanting to have a personal
brand is it feels overwhelmed to be like
in addition to everything else I do now
I got to create content. And to me, that
really feels like a channeling issue.
You're overwhelmed because you're
overwhelmed by sensationalist news and
your phone. They are occupying so much
of your brain power. You're going to be
so much less overwhelmed by creating
something you're excited about or
promoting yourself in a way that then
leads to rewards for you down the line.
I cannot describe how big that shift is
in what you do with some of your time.
But one other critical aspect of modern
culture to think about here is what I
call the flattening of content or the
views are down theorem. If you see
social media content, you created it all
now. see all the stuff online and views
are down. I can't get views anymore. And
one of the big reasons for this is
there's more creators than ever, more
personal brands than ever. More content
popping out into the world. Also, with
that comes algorithms that are getting
way better at giving people content
super relevant to their interests and
needs. They do this by geography. They
do it by interest. They do it by
overlapping interest. If you are in
Tulsa and you are into anime and real
estate, you are getting an algorithm on
multiple social networks, YouTube,
Instagram, Tik Tok, X that is built
around that. It also knows your
political beliefs. It probably knows
what you're attracted to. Terrifying. on
one aspect, but on the other aspect,
there's simply less of a market for
everything. If you make big universal
content, you're competing against way
more niche stuff that may get less
views, but is more interesting to the
viewer. But that is the opportunity for
small personal brands where people that
are just trying to achieve something,
make it easier for them in their lives
is you can actually speak to a niche
that's a,000 people or 2,000 people and
achieve the objectives you want to
achieve without having to create this
huge thing. So, I actually really feel
like the sweet spot for most personal
brands and people that are making
content is really in this like 3 to
10,000 views a video range where if
you're doing more than that, it's kind
of going outside of what you're trying
to achieve. If you can consistently do
that, you have a solid skill and you're
able to reach people that are genuinely
interested and invested in moving your
personal brand forward. This is a good
way to note start talking about the
levels of personal brand. There are four
levels starting with zero make it extra
complicated and it starts with the
difference between a personal brand and
a creator. The goal of establishing a
personal brand is different than the
goal of trying to be employed as a
creator. I want to distinctly do that
because I made a lot of videos about
becoming a creator. But a personal
brand, your goal is to help you in your
career or in future things that you want
to do. Have a platform with which that
will help. And everyone who's online
intrinsically has a level of personal
brand. So I call that level zero. But
you can go through first two levels of
this and make some content but not truly
be a creator. You can casually make
content. And the goal of this is not
necessarily to make you money. It is to
again build the brand. the perception
others have of you when you're not in
the room. Easiest way to define the
brand. Then level one, this is the level
of personal brand I feel almost everyone
should aspire to, especially if you're
in the business world at all, is a
personal brand is an extension of what
you do, but does not define you. You
make content and you put things out
there in the universe on whatever
networks you choose that helps tell your
story, show people what you do, why
you're special, whether that's at work
or personal, but again, it doesn't
define you. You are not a creator. It's
not a primary thing you aspire to.
You're not trying to live off it. You
don't think about it every single day.
is just a thing that is in the habit of
what you do. That is level one. And
there are five archetypes I like to talk
about in level one. The first is the
carousel dumper. This is someone who
basically posts mostly on Instagram and
says, "I'm going to post carousels.
Great format for this, of a bunch of the
things that are happening in my life in
rapid succession." So, I'll have 10
photos of a thing I worked on at work or
multiple things that happened over the
summer. Whatever it is, you can use that
to begin to showcase to people what it
is that's happening with you. And you'll
notice that some people run this kind of
to the moon. You'll notice that there's
like creative directors with 70,000
followers who kind of just do this. But
the stuff is cool enough that it's
actually beginning to got them some
serious traction. Do not underestimate
this. Second is the documentarian. You
are using social media to document your
life milestones, your brand and career
milestones and the things that you are
doing regularly at work. Hey, I got this
raise. Hey, I worked on this project.
Again, you're not trying to be a
creator. Maybe you're not doing this a
ton. You do it occasionally. You're
posting on LinkedIn. You're celebrating
those milestones, whatever it is. The
third is the hobbyist. You have
something you're passionate you care
about. Maybe you are a salesperson at a
roofing company, but you're also a
woodworker. You make content about the
woodworking. and you begin to have some
depth in your personality so that people
that know you and you get closer on it
know you for this other thing. This gets
really powerful when there's alignment.
Hey, you're a real but you're really
into interior design. And so you're
bringing that hobby into real life.
You're showcasing mood boards. You're
showing off stuff you like. You're doing
some response content about that. You
bring that hobby that's tangential to
what you do into the social media that's
around you. This is an excellent way to
do that. You're just passionate about
one aspect of that or a cross-section
subculture of that. It can bleed over.
If you're a cinematographer and you love
cars and you are making cinematography,
solid, really good-looking, real content
about the cars in the free time, that's
going to be a massive benefit to you
inside your career to show off that
you're good at content on social media.
Develop a portfolio that's a side of
your work while not having anyone
question that this guy's really into
cars. Then we have the casual poster,
people that just document stuff in their
life, especially if you're extroverted,
like to yap to the camera. Or if you're
funny, you like to do skits, anything
like that. You are just posting. Not
high production, not super thought
through, but you are putting content on
the internet. A huge chunk of Gen Z is
just like this. They make some skits
with their friends. They post some
content. They're yapping about whatever
it is they bought. That is a thing. It
is an archetype. It is super useful to
begin building a personal brand. Harder
for older generations who just don't
think like this. And then the journeyman
or woman that is you are trying to
accomplish a specific thing and
documenting it. Learning to draw in 60
days. You're basically saying I am
covering X in X time frame. I'm doing
that online. You basically have gone
from zero to one, but you have an actual
plan of what you're doing for it because
being having a personal brand like this
helps you understand content, how it
goes out in the world. This is a huge
thing to think about. Everything we do
now and almost every business comes back
to content. What's going on the
internet? What's going in the ads? This
is inherently now how we consume. This
is a a cultural thing that we
participate in that you then understand
more of by having this brand. It makes
you intrinsically more valuable and
makes more people aware of you. Most
people who establish a personal brand
don't need to go beyond this. Then we
get to level two where having a personal
brand is part of your life and begins to
define you online and offline. You're
known for it. This is the spot where you
begin to develop a brand. You make some
money off of it. Maybe you are a
creator, you're being known for it,
you're doing speaking gigs, whatever it
is, and you begin to think, maybe I
should be doing this full-time. This is
the hardest thing you reach because what
I found is a lot of creators don't
actually want to do this full-time is an
amazing compliment. And what will happen
here traditionally is the first job or
place this happens at. It gets kind of
awkward. People are discovering it. It
wasn't there when they started. They're
like, "Wait, this person does this now.
It's weird." The second scenario you get
in where people knew about it from the
start is probably part of the reason
they brought you in is amazing. You get
to have these two things that exist in
symbiosis. there's value for everybody.
Then you get to level three when it's
larger than life. You build a personal
brand that grows beyond just what you
post to your initial audience. Other
people talk about it that influences
trends. It becomes something big. This
is the Gary V's and all the kind of
gurus you may know, people that are
really respected within their niche or
people refer to all the time used to be
reserved for authors, right? And people
that like had this more traditional
cloud, the Seth Goden, Tim Ferrris,
Cheryl Samberg like era personal brand.
Now that is people that make stuff on
the internet. And you may aspire to
that. We're going to talk all the way
through to that in this video, but I do
recommend for most people just stick to
number one. But before you even decide,
decide where you want to go. Think about
what you want. You can always change
this later. But think about you, what
your priorities are, where you want to
go with this. And then I want you to
know that there is no competition. This
really smart kid, Brier, who did Cut 30.
I saw his videos on TikTok. He made a
video, it's actually I think this is
someone else's idea, but it's a video
about how there's no competition. And
there's a like a model out there for
this. I think this is a really important
thing to think about and something that
has become really apparent to me in my
personal brand journey that I didn't
really believe at the beginning. So,
first you have a hundred people that say
they all want to start a personal brand
in your niche, whatever that is,
hairdresser, sales, funnel, marketing,
whatever it is, 80 of those people that
say they want to do that will never even
start. They will not break zero to one.
So, if you break zero to one, you say
you're going to do it, you make those
first pieces of content, you establish a
plan, beating 80% of the people that
just the people that said they wanted to
do it, not you're already over probably
to the 1% of everybody. That's a crazy
thing to think about. Then 10 more of
them are going to quit early. They come
in, they'll do something like that 3-day
challenge we did, they'll never think
about it again. Now you're down to just
10 of 100. Five of them are going to get
shiny object syndrome. and they're going
to say, "Actually, you know what? I want
to do crypto." That's going to lead you
down to there's now 95 of those 100
people are gone. If you have been
decided to do this and you do it for
more than like 60 days, of the five of
you left, two of them are just going to
be unlucky. Some shit's going to happen
in their life. Stuff's not going to
quite work out. They're going to break
an arm. Whatever it is, life happens.
Now, you're down to three. So, 100
people that started who want to do that
same thing as you, three are left, and
you are one of them. Those are going to
be the only people in your niche
creating content. Now, obviously, if
there's tens and tens and tens of
thousands of people in your niche that
aspire to do it, there'll be a bigger
pool. But in most likelihood, there
aren't. And I think about that on
YouTube. I look around on YouTube
constantly like why are there not more
marketing creators that I want to watch
like marketing and branding. There's a
handful and they're like my friends for
the most part and some big ones have
been around forever. But of like this in
the last like couple years there's
basically no one who's above like 50k
besides like Kane Callaway who's a
friend of mine but even then he's very
focused in on like storytelling social
media but there's really like very few
people being like let's talk about
campaigns. Let's talk about why this
works. Let's do these thorough
tutorials. Let's really approach this
like a YouTuber. Which is just shocking
to me being it's one of the biggest
industries in the world. There's kind of
an infinite demand of those people that
who will consume it on YouTube. There is
money to be made off of it and people
just don't do it. Now, there's a whole
pool. There's there's 100 people who do
this on Instagram. They actually make
marketing content. Of those 100 people,
all of them, all hundred of them have
been like, "Should I do YouTube? I want
to do YouTube." That has been unanimous.
And of that, I can literally call out
the 10 to 20 that have tried and the 10
that quit too early, most of my friends
tried, and made like two videos. I've
got shiny object syndrome. And there's
three left. And of like literally, it's
Kane and myself and Mark now with open
residency, right? It's a small group.
And I say all that to say there is no
competition. You, no matter who you are,
can stand out. So something you've heard
me talking about is that the marketing
funnel is not flowing the same. Things
are different than a year ago. 60% of
searches now and without a click. Buyers
do research with AI and attention is
scattered. Moving people through your
brand from awareness to consideration to
decision used to be a funnel, but now
it's more of a loop that's always
evolving. And marketers have to think
like this. That's why I wanted to share
this new framework from HubSpot. Who I'm
partnering with on this video is
Products I've used for more than a
decade. They understand this change and
created Loop Marketing, a growth
playbook for the AI era. And they
actually put together some free, super
useful marketing prompts you can put
inside your favorite LLM. They're across
the four stages of the new loop and I'm
going to break that down with some
examples. So, the first stage of this
loop is express. This helps you build a
brand guide book and apply it. The
prompts in this stage tackle things from
brand differentiation analysis, customer
journey mapping, archetype
identification, then tailor. This helps
enrich data about your customer and then
create custom experiences that are
better designed for the modern internet,
special landing pages, emails, things
like that. Then amplify to better figure
out how to reach your customers with
prompts like strategic partner
identification, even regional marketing
strategy analysis. And then the fourth
stage is evolve to design testing
strategies and interpret analytics your
brand has. This is about having four
stages that all work together. And with
loop marketing, you're not just getting
random prompts. You're getting a
complete marketing system. It's really
next level. It builds on itself all the
way from brand foundation through to
optimization. So, these are all fully
built prompts you can use inside your
favorite LLM. And they form a super
thorough basis for any marketer to work
to become a 10x marketer who can drive
real impact in the AI era. Stay in the
loop with these prompts from HubSpot at
the link below in the description. And
thanks so much to them for partnering on
this video. So, your toolkit is content
format. What do you actually make?
video, design, carousels, text. Those
are kind of your options to put stuff
out there on the internet. Video, you
have green screen, the kind of content
that I've made on Instagram and Tik Tok.
Green screen is an amazing format. I've
actually tested more produced content,
all this other stuff versus green
screen. It's really hard to beat because
it shows a visual behind you that you
are talking over. You can do it in
Caput. You can do it in the edits app.
You can do it natively in Instagram or
on Tik Tok. It's easy, but you get a
visual you get to watch while someone's
kind of talking over it and you can read
the text. So, no matter what someone
wants to do, they can follow along with
your story. It's an amazing vehicle to
be able to talk about things that are
happening. And there's also just
yapping, which is literally just talking
to the camera. Works best on Tik Tok.
Works a little bit everywhere, but an
option. But if you don't want to talk at
all, you have what I call quick hits,
which is just a video with a couple
clips. So you actually play some text
over. Amazing. Super underrated format.
Huge cam. If you are at all clever or
useful, you can use this to your maximum
advantage. A lot of personal brands are
just built off this. And you have vlogs,
slightly longer versions of these,
oftentimes with a voiceover. We're
actually telling real stories, making
real video content there. And you have
carousels. You have the carousel dump I
talked about where you're just kind of
putting casual stuff out there. is not
really thought through or maybe it's
thought through but it's not like
designed. Then you have produced
carousels, design carousels. This is
easier than ever with like creative
market and templates and all that stuff.
You can make good-looking stuff for this
and having design is like a super
underrated skill set. Putting that
together and being able to share your
opinion on things is like a huge leg up.
And if you look at a lot of text
content, content you put on LinkedIn,
content you put on Twitter is a good
place to start. Text just does not
travel the same way. Especially with AI,
it's super easily replicable. Most
people don't even believe you wrote it
yourself. You can take the format for
that, which is basically like what
happened in the news? What is this trend
I see? I did a thing or this bookmark or
thing I found interesting. Establish
that subject and then a response. I
believe it is good or bad or here's how
I would do X or Y about it. That's a
great way to begin contributing to your
niche. This earnings report happened
inside consumer package goods. I work in
there. Here's what I think it means for
our industry. Here's what I learned from
it. But you then put that into a
carousel format, something more
designed. All of a sudden that travels
way farther. Then you go do a video
about it. You're building in a whole
different way. It's a great way to think
about that. But those are kind of the
formats you have to play with to
establish this on the internet. But to
start, we want to think about this thing
called content market fit. There's two
concepts within it. Niche maxing and
content TAM or content total available
market. So niche maxing is basically
like if you have a super specific
interest again you can get in front of
the people with that same super specific
interest. It may not get huge views but
it gets views that matter to you. Again
200 views,000 views that matter to you
in your career is way different than if
you're trying to be a creator. A handful
of those can just be the people that
will eventually hire you one day or that
are noticing what you're doing in your
journey and taking more of that in.
You're beginning to build that network
out. I would say it's okay to niche max
and I would basically look at what are
the niches you are interested in. Then
look at their tan, their total available
market. How interested are people in it?
For instance, me, I love aesthetics,
interesting looking stuff, the different
aesthetics of everything. No matter what
it is, I like it. Maximalism, brutalism,
yassified design, whatever it is, I'm
intrigued. I'm interested. I want to
talk about it. I want to give opinions
on it. I love it. I also love the math
of money. I love cost models. I love
what things actually cost to produce and
margins and building that out and
rorowass and the whole side of like
marketing that involves the number. If I
talked about the math of money, I would
have a pretty low content tan. You see,
I do not talk about that very
frequently. But I could have a channel
on here that had 2,000 subscribers that
got 1,000 views a video and they were
all ultra highv value people who also
care about the math of money. Ultra
highv value niche, small TAM, and that
would be completely okay if my goal was
to make sure I was aware enough to get
hired in the future. But now I'm in the
middle. Aesthetic branding aesthetics in
general have a pretty good TAM, but
they're not huge. Not the same TAM as I
want to make good, better social media
content, whatever that looks like. It's
a good middle of funnel. Works out well
for me. I love to talk about it. I would
be kind of listing out what are those
things you are excited about and want to
talk about both personal and business.
and then look at what is that TAM and
does that TAM help you achieve your
goal. Goal for most people with a
personal brand, I want to make it easier
for myself to get hired and get paid
more in the future in work. Second goal,
I want to build distribution to be able
to do side projects and freelance. Third
goal and honestly more underrated. I
want to attract a partner, guys and
girls. This is a thing that is very
common. This also works, but begin
thinking about what are what is the
reason you're doing this. And there's
also some overlap between them. What are
the things I'm into I could showcase?
And then what do I do from the formats
above to actually get there? And then a
reminder to reach your TAM, all those
people. No one gives a [ __ ] about you.
they give a [ __ ] about them. How do you
entertain them? How do you give them
value? So, it all comes back to every
piece of content you identify. Am I
entertaining someone or am I giving them
value? So, if you're just talking about
you, it's going to have a smaller tan.
People might notice it. You might still
be able to achieve your objective, but
it's not going to go as far. It's just
worth knowing that in the back of your
head. And so, the system that I use
always to build this out and system we
teach in cut 30 is called this pillar
system. You develop four types of
content approaches and you scale that
over time. That's for creators. You
don't need to think like that in your
initial stages if you're just thinking
about personal brand. If you want to
take it to the next level, this is how
you actually approach it. You build out
four content types and styles you are
doing. This is what I do every single
month. I have four different things I'm
thinking about that are my primary
things. I talk about marketing ideas or
I'm going to talk about product
development for X or Y. I'm going to do
creative travel content. Four pillars.
At the end of every month, I actually
track the metrics on how did those do?
What saves do they get? Views did they
get shares do they get? Is it up or is
it down? Is it this pillar losing
interest or am I not doing good enough?
And I make a plan to say I'm going to
remove this pillar, replace with
another, or I'm going to improve it this
way or that way. as the basics of
creative strategy for a personal brand
in like 30 seconds. Rewind that like
twice. Pillars is a really key concept.
The second key concept is positioning.
You have to decide if you want to be
bigger than just I'm going to talk a bit
about me and that level one personal
brand how you position. So some things
out there counter position. I'm again
going to call out Young Brier makes Tik
Toks about this kind of stuff. He makes
Tik Toks about personal brand content
like monetizing it and stuff like that.
And he counterpositioned himself. He has
a super lowfi. He's in like a basement.
His positioning is like I just had my
first $40,000 month. So, so he's new to
this and he's super young and fresh and
coming at it from an objective position
which counterpositions against I'm Alex
Herozi. I'm all these really established
people with all this production. I made
all this money. That's why you trust me
by having a very relatable take. That's
position type one, a counterposition
versus you see all the things that are
happening in a niche. You want to
establish a personal brand in. And you
say, how do I flip the script on that?
How do I appeal to a different set of
people than what's popular? And easy
ways to think about that are production
level and experience level. Or if they
say it's easy, you say it's hard, right?
How do you basically say what are those
messages that are resonating? What can I
do that's the opposite? And then there's
what I call mirror with a twist. That is
you copy the things that are happening
in your niche. You see a bunch of
influencers or you see big personal
brands, you see people posting on
LinkedIn, they have a really good
recurring strategy, but people who don't
know what they're doing or think they're
doing is they just copy it. Exactly. And
that might work. You've probably seen I
have lots of copycats. They have decent
follower accounts, but you know what
works way better and doesn't get you 100
comments like why are you taking this
from that person etc. is going to do
what I call a twist. We have to change
radically some of the production of the
way it's delivered. So, a good example
of this is if someone was doing written
playbook content and all of a sudden you
did that on a whiteboards. There's a
production twist. There's an aesthetic
or niche twist and be like, "Cool, like
I'm going to talk about the same stuff.
I'm only going to talk about it using
satanic metaphors, whatever." One I like
about this, there's a agency uh my
friend Will has called Cult Holdings
where they position themselves as an
agency. They make agency typical
content, but it's all presented within
this idea of like cult mimedics and like
cult structures. Very similar content.
Let's break down this thing that
happened in marketing or this or that,
but it's like but from the perspective
of how is it cult related? That's a good
example of mirror with a twist. And a
third type of position that's really
good is just a standout demographic. So
for instance, Shelby Sap, some of you
may or may not know her. She does like
sales training for women. Essentially,
you want to be a sales person, want to
make a lot of money doing sales and get
commission sales jobs. This was a whole
niche beforehand, but it was mostly
bros. And you got athleisure wearing
girl showing off the same bro lifestyle,
whipping around cars, spending expensive
stuff, but appealing purely to other
girls as an empowerment method was a
very different demographic. So that's
another one I really like to look at
like how would you have a completely
different angle on that because of your
gender location. I'm going to do the
same thing by doing it in Serbia.
There's racial components that can work
for this. There's lifestyle components
that can work for this. Just some
examples on ways to position to make
your personal brand unique. Again, you
don't have to care about that as much
until you're trying to actually scale it
up. And if you want to get better, you
are making this content, you want to get
better at it, you need a feedback loop.
You make posts, you analyze them, you
make variations based on your analysis,
and you make more of the stuff that
works. It's pretty simple. So what I
mean by a variation, so say you're
making posts about news that's happening
in your niche or about a single concept.
You can make a variant. You can say,
"I'm not going to post the news. I'm
going to post a playbook of the news.
This thing happened, but here's the four
ways you could do it yourself." You
could reposition that news to be able to
tell your story within it, being like,
"Hey, I relate to this cuz I had X or Y
that happened to me." You could do a
versus. You could take this piece of
news and compare it to another piece of
news. Those are ways you basically
create a variant on on one traditional
thing. And this is a good reminder
point. You're always trying to get more
views, but viral just doesn't matter.
Viral doesn't equal money or equal
value. It's about view quality for you.
is about are you getting those thousand
people that are watching that will help
you in whatever you're trying to achieve
with that personal brand. I cannot like
hammer that in enough that there are so
many people out there that are achieving
their goals with like a couple thousand
followers and that is something to
aspire to. Now, a couple notes on you.
You want to go through this journey. You
want to make content on the internet.
How do you make you stand out? And if
you're beautiful, amazing. You're going
to have this easy. But if you're not, it
doesn't matter. If you look unique or
memorable in any way, whether that is a
styling choice, you just have an oddball
facial structure or body type, whatever,
that is a good thing. Do not be afraid
to get on camera. Be memorable matters
more than being perfect. If you are
that, you just need to care. Every
single person on this needs to care
about how they come across, how they
speak. Giving a [ __ ] about the
presentation. Do I look good? Do I look
happy? Am I wearing something I'm proud
of that people would respect? And this
just I basically look at like if you had
to go into the office for a job and the
boss was there, would you be proud of
how you look? And for creative
industries, that can mean a wide variety
of things. Same thing if you were to
show up to a date is an equally good
qualifier. your hair, your smile, your
general presentation, whether no matter
what you look like, just give a [ __ ]
goes so far in personal branding. And
with that, giving a [ __ ] comes genuine
positivity is the other thing. Do you
want to help people? Does it feel like
you're helping people? Because if you
are negative all the time, at some point
people are going to hate watching you
and have some disgust watching you and
you're going to attract the wrong
element. The more positivity you have
and the more genuineess you have, the
more value you give, the better you're
going to feel about it when you make it
and the better it's all going to go. So,
with that said, let's talk about
tackling what happens if you're not
getting any views on your content and
you want to get more for a personal
brand. So, if you're stuck in the 0 to
500 range, this happens to most people.
You can get a free 500 views on
Instagram and Tik Tok, at least, you
know, 50 to 100. You can't break that
out. Your number one question you need
to focus on is why would anyone care?
Why was anyone watch you? Reframe it to
them. Are you giving them entertainment?
Are you giving them value? What is my
presentation like? Does it look good
enough? And am I stopping them? That's
that's the core. It's just the [ __ ]
basics. And you can easily begin to
crack out of that range. Now, getting
above 1,00 comes down to actually
thinking through the structures of that
content. Is the idea good? Is the hook
good? Is it technically well done? Are
you just following the formulas that
millions of people have basically
followed prior to you? That's the kind
of stuff we teach in Cut 30, some stuff
you can hit in that 3-day challenge.
There's a lot of videos on the internet
you can go and just get into the basics
of that. And then 10 to 50K is just
looking at your outliers and repeating
it. You will notice I have a signature
series called Product versus Brand. I do
product versus brand once a week max.
Three a month is kind of the right
cadence cuz I do not want it to go away.
I don't want to be oversaturated. If I
made these three times a week, it would
be dead. And you can watch creators do
this and overdo their series and it goes
away. And getting above that, getting
100K every post. That's systems. That's
scale. That's a team. That's people
thinking through the content. How do I
make this this good every time? What is
my planning like? What is my filming
like? That is more of a process thing
than anything else. Has to be built into
your life. Has to have enough new ideas
and variants. You have to be living it.
I want to highlight you begin to get
into this like the pro version of of
personal brand. Don't oversaturate when
you're increasing volume. Like I
mentioned with my series, like don't
beat the stuff you have to absolute
death. You'll see all these folks like
hey you should get one content type and
just like scale that work highly on that
you have to get multiple that's why that
pillar system is so important having
like four things you alternate in and
out as you really scale a personal brand
is because if you are starting to make
content closer to every day you need to
have new stuff and testing even if it's
not working because what you're doing is
not going to work forever it's going to
fall off and you have the ability to
push in new stuff and iterate and move
on. Uh I would highly suggest doing that
versus always beating the same thing to
death even if it gets less views. And
then this idea of remixing ideas by
format is super when you're beginning to
scale your personal brand, you're doing
one or two things, right? You make green
screen videos, you make yaps, you're
doing carousels. Those same ideas work
just as well in another format that
different people consume. So not
everyone watches video content of people
talking. Not everyone reads carousels or
longer form text or whatever it is, but
the content ideas are likely the same.
If I have a banger video, you'll watch.
I remake those videos as carousels all
the time. They reach a different
audience. People that read carousels
intrinsically different than a lot of
people that watch videos. There's some
overlap. Yes, but not that much. You
have a lot living in your existing
content by just putting it into other
formats. It's a great way to scale
personal brand to reach more people. And
if you want to get better at attracting
initial attention, it's really about
understanding context and attention
hacking. Basically involve making your
topics more interesting by leveraging
things people are already interested in.
Pop culture. When everyone's talking
about Cracker Barrel, it's really easy
to make a video talking about Cracker
Barrel attached to whatever you're
doing. Store, retail, design,
rebranding. A lot of ways to attach to
this thing that's happening people care
about if you do it fast. What are the
things that are appealing to your
demographic? as an awesome opportunity
for you to make something that's more
resonant for your niche. And there's
also this idea of tribal affinity. What
do people really care about? What are
those brands that are really that aren't
recognized? Right? Everyone talks about
like arterics in the outdoor industry,
right? They don't talk as much about quu
or sika. If you talk about those as a
signaler to these tribal people, you
call one of those bad, you'll bring a
whole bunch of people out in a negative
way. What are tribal signalers you can
give that make people understand that
you understand it, right? Like there's
like things that people only certain
people will recognize that are good to
help you get to your niche. Personal
brand goes beyond just talking about a
niche, beyond making content. It's about
building affinity. People have to want
to like you. And with that comes
personality. Personality breaks into a
few like key things, right? That can be
a chill personality, a fun personality,
an outgoing personality, an alpha power
personality. There's a lot of ways to
show that, but it's actually bringing
that through what you really like. Then
they're showing your life. When people
find out about a dad, they have a lot of
questions. I don't talk about it much,
but it adds another aspect to the things
that I know about. And there's the idea
of community engagement. If you're just
replying to everybody, actually
answering comments, making reply videos,
making anecdotes, talking to people,
going live, then you can basically
curate the people you already have by
actually showing that you care enough to
give them your time and attention. Now,
we're going to go into the advanced
advanced section of this video, which is
going big. You start to have a pretty
good creator journey. Pretty solid
personal brand. You want to make real
money. So, if you're going good in your
personal brand, you want to take the
next level. The first thing is a marquee
media property. You'll notice a lot of
these people will have a marquee
newsletter or a podcast or an agency.
They make content if they're selling an
agency service or a program to make
content with. What do I mean by this?
So, look at uh so Maggie Sellers is a
great example. She has a podcast called
Hot Smart Rich. a concept that she
repeated in a lot of her content, turned
it into a podcast is probably more
wellknown than Maggie Sellers at this
point. I wouldn't recommend doing this
until you have an established personal
brand you're happy with, but that is a
good next step. Establish that, brand
it. I have my hyper newsletter and I
made that specifically so it wouldn't be
Orin's newsletter and I partner with
someone on it. We do like reports. It's
like a separate thing in business. It's
less of a marquee than theirs. It's more
of like a side thing, but you can decide
how you want to approach it. Next is
developing like miniseries and recurring
topics from your pillars that people
know you for. If people know you for a
thing of content, the way people will
know me for product versus brand,
whether they like that or not, they know
you for something. Winner series
continue over time. You want to have a
signature thing that you're known for,
that you're comfortable with, is
helpful, and helps you on that journey.
But getting that marquee property,
getting those signature series, and then
going wide, taking these things across
as many networks as you can. If you're
making content, pushing it across as
many places, making sure you're getting
max value from it. You made that video
once, it's also on YouTube shorts and
it's on LinkedIn, and you can post on
Substack and you do carousels on YouTube
community. you've already making these
things. The five minutes to put it more
places is more invaluable than whatever
else you're spending that time on. Over
into making money, the first step to
make money for 90% of creators is put
your contact info in your bio. The
second one is to get an email list. I
cannot speak to the power of the email
list enough. If you want to leverage the
social media component of it and you're
not trying to sell courses and stuff
like that, Substack will grow you the
fastest. If not, Beehive and ConvertKit
are both excellent. If you're not trying
to leverage the social component,
ConvertKit is great for low cost. Behive
is great if you ever did want to pay to
grow or you want to monetize your email
newsletter through their like placements
and stuff and get quick small money. I
really want $100, $400 type stuff.
Doesn't matter. Don't overthink it. Pick
any of those just based on that
description and run with it. And learn
to set up landing pages. They're super
simple. Why I like ConvertKit the most
of these is you can really simply just
create a landing page, put a title and a
subtitle, and someone can sign up for
your list and get a download. You can
set those up in like 15 minutes. And
that's what you want to push people to.
summaries of all the things that you do
or just hey my thoughts this week on
whatever happened or my report from
blank or y or this four-step whatever
drive people to those you can use many
chat to do that you can use stand to do
that there are software that actually
allow you to do the comment to get to it
or you can just tell people to go to the
bio comments more effective bio is less
intrusive they both work but that
concept of lead magnets landing pages
driving people to email gives you this
retained audience it's going to help you
forever even if you send an email out
once a quarter every time you need to
tap in the point of your personal brand
is you being able to tap in when you
want to you can go hit that list that's
saying I want to sell something or I
just started something or I'm looking
for a new opportunity. And now let's
talk about sales and making money. So
the first thing I want to know is why
they watch is why they buy. It's why you
see people that are very humorous
content primarily or content that's
mainly based on them being hot don't
actually sell that much stuff unless it
is being like this can also make you hot
or this will also make you funny or make
you laugh, right? They attaches directly
to it. But if they watch you for
marketing tips, you are selling
marketing tips. Brands that want to give
marketing tips will approach you, right?
So think about that. It's a good
mentality to think about when you
monetize. But how do you monetize? First
is services. And you show your service,
let people know it exists and have
ideas. If I was doing X with my agency,
here's how I would do it. That kind of
thing. Presenting those out there from
the perspective of this and making it
super apparent the thing you do that the
service is something you offer. It's the
easiest thing to sell. Level one,
selling your time and services doing
something as a function of your personal
brand. Level two is low ticket teaching.
I was just talking this through with a
friend of mine who is a photography
creator who's really expert at lighting,
who makes popular lighting content. And
it's like, yeah, make the $50 how to use
two lights to improve your home
photography setup as a super as a micro
moment that people will pay money for
that can't come through in a 60-second
video, but you can give them a bunch of
tips inside a thing. You can sell
something low ticket. And the best thing
about low ticket is then you can have a
high ticket done for you. Hey, and for
$1,000, I'll get on Zoom with you and
we'll all set up the lighting together
until it's perfect. And C, you have
brand deals. You have a personal brand,
you're getting a lot of views, and
you're in a specific niche, you're going
to get approached for brands, especially
if like I mentioned before, your contact
is in your bio. But to make that work,
you need to show value to them. They
need to be able to picture themselves in
your content. They want to see you doing
it for other brands. Might mean you have
to do some free stuff or some spec
stuff. But talk about what you use, the
tools you use, the things you do in your
job, why you like it. And it goes for
anything, your makeup, fitness
equipment, marketing software. If they
see themselves in that content, that
works. Then you make partnerships easy.
Reply to stuff. Be easy to work with.
And then do deals and we'll promote it.
Actively look for people at the
beginning. Especially we'll whitelist.
We'll run ads. People see your ad. Other
companies will be like, "Let's use that
person." It's not the best source of
income in the world. I'd never want to
live off of it, but is an awesome plus
side when it comes that almost every
person with a personal brand of a
certain size can take advantage of. And
then D the hard way is products. But if
you establish expertise in any niche as
part of your personal brand is so much
easier to launch a product in that niche
later. I encourage people, especially if
you're like, "Hey, I'm going to launch a
drink beverage and I don't know anything
about drinks." Make content about drinks
for 2 years online or the lifestyle
you're approaching. Auroretic medicine,
whatever it is. You're going to then
have a following that'll make it way
easier. you follow your drink and you're
probably going to know way more about
what the people that are buying your
product actually want. So, I'm going to
end off with a couple really amazing
personal brand content concepts you
should consider. Then, we're going to
talk through the timing of personal
brand, the most important probably
concept in this whole thing. Let's hit
it. So, the first concept is what called
the free work. This guy is crushing it
with these right now. He basically makes
merchandise for billion-dollar
companies. There's a dystopian thing
there we're not going to get into, but
he makes really good designs for these
people, presents them aggressively and
interestingly, does it relevant, and
brands are commenting asking for more,
and he's getting work from that. If you
do free work online and it's good,
people are going to come to you for it.
And the second one is the niche niche
playbook. So a good example is the three
chest exercises for men over 50. Take a
thing that already exists and niche it
into one specialty. We had a woman Bella
who was a fitness trainer in Cup 30
recently who was just doing like
menopausal women, women over 50,
workouts for women over 50. Excellent
niche. Tam's right there. And you can
kind of look at it like construction
companies in the Midwest. Whatever it
is, make something specifically for a
qualified audience. There's the idea
content. This is Caroline. She's also in
Cut 30. She's doing a great job just
being like, "Hey, don't overthink your
product." And she makes all these little
videos being like, "Uh, you're
overthinking it. Touchlin just did this
for this or Poppy just did this for
this." Like, this is why concepts
resonate. Often very simple. And she
shows this again and again. And then
would and wouldn't expertise is another
awesome one. I know this. Here's what I
would and wouldn't do inside this niche.
So, 10 things I would buy at Trader
Joe's as a food scientist. And if you
don't know where to go or you're junior,
curation is great to all call out
GradGirl Marketing. I think the name of
that account is cuz she started it in
college. She has an amazing account for
covering what's happening in beauty and
tangential spaces and just kind of like
slightly female leaning marketing
overall any kind of brand. Makes
carousels about them, makes some videos
about them and just sharing all the
stuff that happened is an invaluable
resource even though she hasn't quite
like layered over her expertise as much
yet. That's fine. It's where she's at in
her career. When she chooses to do that,
it's going to be a rocket ship for her.
My friend Nate Rosen, same thing. Has
one called Express Checkout and CPG is
better CPG news than I could ever
possibly research myself. I go to him
for that. You are saving someone time.
You're doing them a service. just a few
formulas I think are great for people to
consider when you're developing your
personal brand. And last, let's talk
about time. Time is a super crucial
aspect here. Everyone thinks about
timing for their personal brand wrong.
This is the framework you should really
think about it. Then 30 days, the first
30 days, you complete 30 days of I did
my two videos a week. I posted on
LinkedIn every day. Whatever it is, you
now in your head go, I can do this. In
100 days, you actually do it. That's
when your brain, this is kind of built
in your routine. You done it for 100
days. You're probably not going to stop.
Consistency matters more than perfection
here. 365 days, one year in, that's when
I would expect to make money. Yeah, we
expect to make a dollar until we were
365 days in. This is delayed
gratification. If you get money before
that, amazing. Two years in, now you
know enough to make a plan. Too many
people are like month three trying to
figure out X and Y. You don't know
enough until you've done it for a year.
Now you started to make some money. Now
you can make a plan. Look at this under
a long time horizon. This is your whole
life. Your personal brand is you for
your entire life. Year three, it's where
I'm at. Stay on the plan. You made a
plan in year two. Are you still staying
on the plan? Is it going as expected?
Are you are you following through? And
if you do five years, this is what I
have now mentors talking to me about.
You can do anything. If you have stayed
five years and promoting yourself
consistently, telling your story,
whether you're getting light views,
whether you're getting heavy, whether
it's really scaled up, it is now
solidified. You can take that wherever
you want. It will help you get whatever
jobs you want. You can use it to
monetize. It exists and it is a
superpower. And if you want to say when
you're at 28, anything is possible and
have consistently done the personal
brand from there. There is no such thing
as too late or too old. There's only I
am not going to put in that same amount
of time that the 23-year-old has to put
in to get the results. Anyway, this is
the art of the personal brand. I'll link
some other content here. Talking for a
long time, so I don't even remember what
I'm going to link. If you have any
questions, you want to workshop your
trajectory, whatever it is, I will try
to respond to as many comments as I can
about that on there. And especially, let
me know if I do a follow-up to this,
what little gaps you'd like pieced in. I
appreciate y'all watching so much. And I
hope that you do this. Hit that 30 days,
100 days, and never stop because it will
truly make a difference in what is
possible for you. Let's go.
[Music]