In this video, we are going to talk
about the art direction of quiet luxury.
How do brands that sell at the highest
price points build worlds with their
imagery and some of their choices and
especially the ones that aren't relying
on their logos or some big signatures to
do it? In this video, we're going to
talk about Lao Piana. We're going to
talk about the row. We're going to talk
about Branella Cuchinelli. We're going
to talk about Bautega Vanetta. We'll
touch on a whole bunch of things along
the way. We're going to break down the
playbook that's being used by these
brands to help justify some of their
price points visually and how to create
a world that appeals to the quiet luxury
consumer. If you're interested in diving
more into this world, I have linked
below the luxury online website report
that I did when I worked with Vang
Group, who is one of the more
prestigious luxury website builders in
the world. You can grab for free below.
I'm super excited to walk through luxury
world building with you. Let's lock in.
But first, I want to talk about the
brands I chose for this video. And then
we'll talk about the actual categories
that they use and how. So, first is Laro
Piana. Notorious for extremely expensive
clothing. I've had a moment once they
were featured heavily inside Succession.
Really capitalized on that with how many
stores they've opened and how much
they've pushed into the quiet luxury
movement in general. But a controversial
brand, not a brand I recommend people
buy. I think it is radically overpriced
for what it is. They are notedly in
trouble for exploitation inside their
supply chain, but they are the
quintessential quiet luxury brand, one
worth understanding. Then we have the
Row. The Row is one of the most
interesting ones to me because it is a
newer luxury brand founded by the Olsen
twins. They rely on this concept of
mystery, on curation, on the power of
the form and the quality of the things
they have on a mysterious and artful
nature to actually break into this
luxury world and succeed. And we have
another of the quintessential quiet
luxury brands with Brunello Cuchinelli
extremely high-end men's and women's
wear, most noted for men's that bridges
everything from formal wear to casual
wear and in between and has really
become a lifestyle brand that people can
simply buy into. People that want that
Italian quiet luxury craft that are
excited by the vision of its founder.
And the last one we're going to talk
about is Bautega Vanetta who are in the
highest tier of luxury brand. You can
put them right next to Hermes, right
next to Louis Vuitton, but they have
done it notably without a reliance upon
a logo and upon the iconography of a
brand and instead with pattern, with
form, with silhouette and with
incredible marketing and you have found
interesting, intricate and artful ways
to build a world around their brand
inside luxury at the highest level and
they've done their come to prominence
within this last decade in a really
interesting way. So the four topics that
we're going to hit in this that form the
foundation for the quiet luxury art
direction. First is setting, second is
process, third is curation, and the
fourth is what I'll call upsell to
downell, but really comes to product
positioning. So what do we mean by
settings? Let's go over to Branella's
Instagram. Almost all of their pics
depict basically vacation destinations
from what could be a luxury hotel lobby
to day-to-day life inside of a a
European city. They are showcasing a
consumer who was always on the road. And
Bayga is the same thing. You will note
in basically every one of these Bayga
shoots. So I'm going to scroll by. They
are showcasing a person, a singular
person in an office environment, in a
vacation environment. You'll put product
in the same thing in a travel related
environment, but yet artful where the
thing that they around is naturally
sculptural. They have all these models
sitting all the time. And so all these
kind of natural environments, whether
that's on rocks, whether that's
squatting inside some sort of more of
art. standing in front of an elevator in
an office space. It's the towel thrown
down cliffside somewhere in the world,
the steps of whatever photo you may be
taking in Morocco. They are positioning
it as an individual's choices. you are
the BGA person and that you have the
ability in your life to be traveling and
moving and experiencing these things and
the type of person that does that that
goes to these remote areas whether it's
on the highway side in America right
next down to the craziest Airbnb you
could ever book that is the setting that
they are putting their customer inside
of the artful world traveler and I also
want to call out this is a tool that the
row uses as well in a similar way you
don't see many row environments almost
all of the photography you will see will
either be just plain background. It will
be on the wall inside of a house or it
will be on the streets of New York. But
when they do choose to use setting more
prominently like they do in their runway
shows, it is basically always shown in
like a house environment in what you
would imagine a extremely wealthy
person's apartment in New York or Paris
to look like. And that is the setting
with which they communicate to their
female customer like this is the life
that you as a rogue consumer are meant
to lead is inside these metropolitan
homes walking around inside the loungey
luxury of what we provide where every
decision you wake and whatever you wear
is just inherently sculptural and
luxurious without a logo present. And
that being the only setting you see I
think is an interesting tell in itself.
And the same goes for the Roiana. They
are constantly putting their target
audience, you'll know they skew very
young in the models. They say they are
putting them on vacation. They show
their target customer lounging around
lakeside, walking on the beach by the
ocean in kind of sculptural
environments. And then same thing, they
are depicting artful houses, the places
that you may not live, but you are
traveling and experiencing inside the
majority of their shoots. Everything has
that throughine that it's not just
about, oh, you're going on a vacation.
That's what a consumer who isn't living
that life might think. It's that your
life is a constant travel experience
whether that's for work or for pleasure.
And with Bautega and with Loro that is
inherently artful in the way it's
presented. We'll show how row the row
handles art in the in the third section
we get into. One of the pillars of
luxury I've talked about before is
lifetime loyalty which is built from
insight, service, product quality, and
brand. Because of the opportunity of
luxury branding and the size of the
prize when it's done right, brands can
get customers for generations. It
becomes a family choice. But in the
modern world, loyalty is actually
changing radically. That's why I
recommend you check out this report, how
brands are earning loyalty in an
automated world. It's from HubSpot and
Survey Monkey, and they surveyed 1,800
business leaders and 15,000 consumers
across seven global markets. The biggest
friction that they're talking about is
the trust gap between businesses using
AI and their customers. While 75% of
marketing leaders say that AI is more
crucial than ever, only 19% of consumers
feel excited about it. My favorite
section in here is this best practices
for staying authentic when using AI.
When you're building a brand for the
long term, this authenticity is
everything. And this section actually
calls out five clear strategies for
using a lot of these new AI tools and
ways that build trust with consumers
instead of breaking it. You can grab
this for free in the description below
and get the full breakdown, including
sentiment analysis and operational best
practices. And thank you so much to
HubSpot and SurveyMonkey for sponsoring
this video. But with Loro, we get into
what's called process content. So,
especially these more established luxury
brands showcase they are worth the price
point with process content. So they have
a whole section on their website for
house of mastery where they're literally
showing off the photography of their
cashmere etc. But Laurel is known for
their their ultra expensive wool. So the
gift of king's wool being the most
notable. So they have a whole you know
they're doing shots of sheep that are
about to get sheared the wool stretching
apart. Gorgeous factory shots all to
help justify this $12,000
sorry $12,200
gift of kings jacket. They're showcasing
their materials on the homepage in big
blocks. They have a whole master of
fibers book detailing the history of
their wool. They are justifying the
price point through explaining the lore
and explain the history and what goes
into it. And even an editorial you can
go tour the Laurier Piana Italian
factory and see how state-of-the-art the
equipment is, what the real machines
they're using to create these things to
help justify these price points that
it's done by real people that even
though they're telling you it's all made
in China, really it's made in these
intricate environments. That's an
important part of positioning for these
luxury brands to show the investment,
the time, how this is made, the care,
and the craft. When I did my video on
Loee's art direction, they have every
major bag silhouette. They show the
pattern. They show how it's put together
in an extensive YouTube video, right?
They are proof pointing how why it is
worth the dollars and the craftsmanship
that goes into it. And that's an
important part of especially older and
heritage luxury. And if you have a newer
brand and you can't show that or it
doesn't look that good, you need to
really think about are you worth that
level of price point or you need to work
up to where you can show that craft to
be able to justify it. But if you can't
do that, if you are someone like the row
whose stuff probably isn't made in
facilities that look like this, right?
What can you do? And so the row is an
interesting one where they have chosen
curation. They have chosen mystery as a
core of their brand's creative
direction. So when you go to their
Instagram account, the majority of the
content is art. It is curation of art
and culture. So when that comes across
your timeline, it's not like oh I'm
going to think about buying a row bag.
It's I am looking into this world the
row is giving me a glimpse into. They
are curating for me. This is really
interesting. I like the row and like
talking about them is because they're a
new luxury brand, right? So founded by
the Olsson twins of Full House fame.
Their brand is a mystery much like its
founders. A lot of people tap into the
brand cuz they have this huge fandom of
all these women that grew up with these
girls. They're beloved. You don't know
much about them. They're not very
public. The row is one of the only entry
points you have into their life. And you
get to have this entry point into this
extremely artful interesting world that
they are curating. And the consumer
wonders, are the Olsson twins curating
this? Are there other people? Is it like
is it a group? This is there. There's a
constant form of mystery, but it is a
ambassador of culture to a woman of that
generation in an amazing really
tastefully done way. And that curation
pulls over into the product. The rose
look at jewelry is pure price upon
request is all artful form factors. And
again, when they do show the products,
they are on blank walls. They're based
down. Only times you see an environment
is on those fashion shows that are again
in a house. But their curation doesn't
stop with what happens on Instagram and
art. They've done this on Spotify as
well. Their music provides that cultural
vehicle for their audience. 93,000
followers. They do a monthly playlist.
They're very good. Some of them such as
this August 25, if you want to dive in,
13,000 followers is a good one. They are
again building this world around what is
the rogue consumer? What is the world
that they exist in? What do they listen
to? What art do they buy? What
environments do they live in? and they
focus on this really specific thing and
build a really interesting world and one
that exudes luxury and exudes mystery
and is able to not get into that process
content or the constant travel world is
probably would be an expensive thing to
shoot and look at because they're
basically building around an aura. Could
you do that without having people at the
center of the brand who are as prolific
or interesting as the Olsson twins?
Probably not. But this is where a
personalitydriven luxury comes into it.
Are there people and founders you can
build into these idols for the consumer?
So, we've hit on setting, we've hit on
process, we've hit on curation. Now, I
want to talk about this upsell, the down
cell is the last one. That's a little
more practical talk than uh my usual art
direction. If you look at these products
like Loro's products, they are
presenting, especially in these latest
collections, true design and sculptural
products at the highest level, as good
as any luxury brand can. The silhouette,
design, and presentation of these is
absolutely immaculate. But they're not
selling this. They're selling polos.
They're selling some pants. They're
selling maybe a jacket. They're selling
a scarf. They're certainly not selling a
bunch of these hats. But the product
design itself and its presentation for a
lot of luxury is merely to downell the
entry-le item, the wallet, etc. When you
saw Virgil Abau and Louis Vuitton doing
people dressed as cities, it wasn't to
sell the city bulky jacket. It was to
sell the Louis Vuitton wallet. And it's
worth noting that that presentation and
that care and that showcase that we do
things at this high level you can buy
into below is kind of an omnipresent
thing amongst justifying that price
point visually for the consumers that
come after it. And look is an expensive
thing to buy into and design into. But
that's the game you play when you want
to justify price points at that level to
really exist in the luxury world. But
also it's an opportunity for visionary
creatives to say I have all these
visions in my mind. I have a reason to
bring them to life to make a one of one
to use that as marketing for these other
things. know that I actually need to
have these streams below it and then the
art direction of everything ties it
together. So anyway, if you want to dive
more into this, I want to give you the
really the the core pillars what I feel
represent these non flashy luxury
brands. If you want to dive deeper into
it, I do have that luxury online web
guide below. I think you'll find really
interesting. You can grab that for
[music] free. And I'm putting a whole
bunch of these together going into next
year. I've got Ralph Lauren loading.
I've got some offball ones that you
might be interested in like Lana Del
Rey. If you have any ideas for them or
things that you want to see and learn
more of inside these categories, please
drop them below. We're always
considering the stuff that you guys list
out here in terms of what the content
road map looks like coming up. As
always, thank you so much for watching.