So, in this video, we are going to talk
about the new rules of the internet, the
internet codes, if you will. And
basically break down what is happening
in social media, internet culture, and
the zeitgeist in general. So,
specifically, if you are a creative, you
work in marketing, you have a brand, or
you're just interested, and you've heard
a lot of these terms, you can think
about their implications for culture,
jobs you may have, projects you're
working on, and where the future's
going. We're going to hit on streaming
and clipping, and actually define it if
you're unfamiliar. We're going to go
through how fast everything trends and
why it feels like nothing is cool
anymore. We're going to discuss TikTok's
meltdown under its new ownership,
Substack and X and the splintering of
social media, the complete loss of
journalistic media, and what it means
when they're significantly behind the
curve. How 15 minutes of fame has
shifted very considerably, real-life
events turning into gimmicks, why
prediction markets is about more than
just money, the business of information,
and why monoculture and the events we
still pay attention to are more
important than ever. It is my job to be
on top of this. I work with brands big
and small to help them strategize
through that future on what they want to
act on now or in 3 years. This involves
a lot of research, a team of people that
works with me that's terminally online,
and I'm excited to practically and
tactically share these things with you
and have an open discussion about it.
Let's lock in. So, first, our next
community call is March 24th, where I'm
actually going to be discussing brands
as media companies. What that means, how
you construct them, how you hire, what
the teams look like, and what the
formulas are, and we're going to Q&A on
it. So, any of this is interesting to
you professionally, the community call
is free, and there's a link down below
for it. But first, I want to get started
by talking about streaming and clipping.
So, for many of you that are YouTube
native, if you're Gen Alpha or younger
Gen Z, you already know what a lot of
this looks like, but I think you'll be
interested to learn a bit about the
clipping infrastructure. But for those
that don't, let me just give you the
basic 101 on streaming here. The media
over the last few weeks has been
dominated, but it's already falling off
by the looksmaxing trend
by this streamer Clavicular. Most people
who are learning about streaming have
seen it through Kai Cenat and his
prominence rising to fame or IShowSpeed.
But what actually is it? What's going on
here? So when you look at this, you will
see he is online for 6 hours and 52
minutes, 3 hours here, and everything is
live. They are following this guy around
as he goes to dinner, whether he's in
his studio. Basically, you are
participating in someone's life
completely live and watching it. And so
those of you there thinking, "I'm not
going to watch a 6-hour and 52-minute
thing." You have to think about how
people consume this type of media. So a
lot of people are either sitting at work
or younger person sitting after school
doing homework or sitting in their room
gaming. Streaming is a companionshift
social media piece for this. It's really
important for brands to think about. If
you looked at my video from a prior
week, I had a chart about the fringe to
normie sales to awareness scale of what
brands can do to get in front of people.
And on the fringe, which is basically
things that you would have to commit to
that your average brand wouldn't that
are at risk would have a high upside. On
the awareness side, there was streaming
and on the sales side, there was live
selling. These are two different things.
I'll talk about live selling when we get
to the TikTok section. But basically,
what you have here is a massive amount a
disordered amount of attention. You
know, 200,000 people tuning into a
3-hour live on a very niche as a very
niche streamer. 267,000 people turning
into a more prolific one like we see
here with Kai Cenat. And then thousands
of smaller streamers with various levels
of engagement from everything from
gaming to lifestyle to travel. And that
attention has not been monetized or used
to showcase brands to any level near the
robustness of how that's treated in like
the TV or standard social media
ecosystem. But quick some tactics here.
How do they do this? There is software
like StreamYard, OBS that connect
multiple channels and things to
something like Twitch. When I do lives
where we are on YouTube and X
simultaneously with multiple people, we
are using StreamYard. Sometimes we are
using Riverside. There's software that
solves this. DJI's Osmo has direct
streaming outputs from the camera. They
made it very simple. But the big
strength here is that while people are
consuming it relatively passively, they
can interact. They can comment. People
refer to the comments on screen. They
can interact with each other. So,
basically, instead of watching a video
and commenting after the fact, you're
participating in the action live. Many
people have looked at this and gone,
"Oh, this is a thing for kids." But
perhaps the best monetized podcast of
our time is TBPN, who don't even put up
massive views. Yeah, 4,000, 4,500 on
YouTube. Maybe they're doing the same on
X. But they are streaming technology
news during the day for Silicon Valley
employees, VCs, people interested in the
business of technology. They are doing
this and they are selling
six-to-seven-figure yearly sponsorship
slots to some of the biggest, most
prolific tech companies that we have.
So, for anyone that's thinking this is a
kids thing I don't need to worry about,
this is actually a standard to which you
can obviously see media shifting. And if
you want to be ahead of media, the way a
lot of the reason I'm here today is cuz
I was relatively early to TikTok, this
is something to think about. But there's
two key points I want to make before we
move on to nothing being cool anymore.
And that's first, you need to look at
these things on a three-year horizon,
especially if you're a brand. One of the
scenarios that I love to use is if you
are trying to appeal to young men right
now and you sell a core product, you
sell deodorant. You sell something that
you know that they're going to consume.
They probably do not have the brand
recognition of your brand you'd expect
from being someone that's a household
name. If you are Right Guard, your Axe
body spray, I don't know if that's still
a thing. You might think you are
entrenched forever, but this generation
does not know who you are. They do not
pay attention to your media sources.
They don't care about the marketing.
They don't listen to their parents. What
they have is a singular world revolving
mostly around streamers and the
ecosystem on YouTube and other social
media that splinters that apart. Your
brand is not present. And so, if you are
trying to say, "We need to have a stake
in the ground for a three-year horizon."
Three-year horizon is I think the
longest you can think about media right
now. You should be putting a flag in the
ground of, "How do we have a presence in
streaming?" And a lot of the biggest
brands in the world are relying on their
agencies to think about that, who don't
understand it at all. That's where
people like me have come in handy, where
I can at least have the conversation
with those companies about shifting
that, cuz there's only a handful of
people that operate in between those
worlds. But to really understand
streaming, you have to understand
clipping. And many people have heard
this word, let's break down what it
actually means. It means that people
take pieces of these streams, the most
interesting points in it,
and they put it on other social media.
TikTok, YouTube Shorts, Instagram, X,
Snapchat Spotlight. Now, how does this
work? They are incentivized to do this.
There are places, Wapp being one of
them, where basically, if you are a
clipper for a specific streamer, you can
get paid for your views. So, if you put
up 1,000 views, you get, let's say, a
dollar. Now, if you're putting up
millions of views on Snapchat clipping
these, that becomes very lucrative very
quick. And people are clipping lots of
those pieces. Now, sometimes the person
themself is paying for it. So, for
instance, when you saw the meteoric rise
of personalities who were at the fringe
of this, like TJR, Brez, they had
clipping campaigns in Wapp where they
would offer those bounties for someone
to go chop up their streams, post them
on social media, report back the
results, and get a payout from them. But
now, the platforms themselves do it. So,
Kick, a competitor to Twitch, pays for
claviculars, clippers. He's said that
like on stream and in other places. They
are incentivizing people to to build
stars on their platform. That happens at
the highest level. Some people also have
their own internal teams, or they retain
a service. I started recently testing
clipping myself for cutouts for my
YouTube cuz I don't make edits from
these, and retained a service who have
started doing that a bit on IG and
TikTok. Results are still like unclear,
but I'm committing to making that a part
of how my media moves online. So, why is
this so effective? Because of the way
algorithms work, where different types
of media, different lengths, different
styles of editing, all play into how
someone consumes. We all do not consume
the same things. But, if someone is
popular and notable in the things that
are going on, the algorithms will find
things related to them. They know what
they look like, they know the words
associated with them, and they will
begin to show it to them. You can begin
to build a uh 1 + 1 = 3 scenario of how
your media is pushed on the algorithms.
And the other thing is, this is there's
also reaching new markets to get
traditional media. So, I want to call
out X for a second because the only
reason to clip on there is to reach two
markets, right? The first market is is
older men, like Gen X boomer men, like
late millennial, and to reach
journalists who kind of comb that for a
new space. So, there are people I will
call Fearless for being one of the
biggest ones, where he is consistently
posting this clipping. And this is a
There are a lot of accounts that do
this, so I'm going to just spotlight
this one, but they're being incentivized
for this, and it's not disclosed, right?
I and many others understand how this
economy works, and most people who are
consuming it don't. They think they're
just following a highlight reel. But
this is a monetization ecosystem that is
doing this, where he's being rewarded
for showing it. You do this to build up
enough credibility that you get written
about and talked about by mainstream
media, because they're not in any of
these other platforms. X is one of the
only like boomer platforms left, where
people who are actually resonant enough
to then talk about something or make it
move still exist. So, it's worth
understanding this is a core internet
code. This is not going to change. This
is a significant look at where media is
going, and worth you having in your idea
of what the future looks like. Now, I
want to move on to trends and how fast
they move and nothing being cool. The
first kind of conversation I want to
have there is about the McDonald's CEO
eating the burger. You guys saw this.
There's been so much content made about
this. I mean, Danny Ramirez I mean, want
to make more content about it. But
there's an awkward video where the
McDonald's CEO tries their new burger,
and he is He's awkward about it. He
obviously doesn't seem to enjoy it. And
then a hundred other companies hop onto
the trend of doing the same exact thing.
So, every burger company within, let's
say, 72 hours had done their version.
Probably my favorite being Freddy's. You
could tell this guy actually likes the
product and probably eats it all the
time, and has a very different, way more
organic feel than what's happening at
McDonald's. But this is washed, right?
Every media team was like, "We need to
get our CEO to eat the product or use
the product on camera." There was a huge
trending thing on Threads where it was
like, "I love to see the Talenti Gelato
CEO try to open a tub with his hands."
You know, where people are going through
the obvious like user experience issues
that people have. I'd love to see the
Microsoft CEO try to find an email in
Outlook while on a Teams. You know,
where they're actually is they're
talking about the user experience
problems. A huge trend emerges, which is
an interesting useful trend for brands
to participate in, but it's just cooked
so fast, right? It is now I'm recording
this on Saturday, March 7th. I think
we're 3 days into this trend, maybe. All
these CEOs have posted. Next week we're
going to see 100 more and it's done.
It's cooked. And people have gotten so
good at trends, right? So, I think maybe
18 months ago I put out a video where I
was talking about how brands should
respond to trends, right? How brand
social teams should do that. And how
creators can think about it, too. Where
it's like, okay, you need to have a
framework. What is on brand or not on
brand for us? Do we have the bandwidth
to do it or not? Who does it and do they
have a preset allocated budget they can
act on if you need to do something
short-term? And you need a system where
you can run through that. It's a Slack
channel, it's a whatever. We know we can
spend this much. We have these criteria.
It allows you to quickly respond to
trends. I've talked to now dozens of
brands who adopted that. I'm sure with
the reach of the videos it's probably
more like hundreds. And there's plenty
of other people who are thinking about
it in their own world. But everyone has
the ability to do this now. They
understand how media moves. This is no
longer unique to be able to spit on this
quickly. And it's led to this feeling
that nothing is interesting. And I want
to call that out because I'm going to
Japan. I go to Japan next week. And I'm
looking at making content there. And I
just feel like it's it's washed. I don't
want to make content there. Content's
not going to be intrinsically cool
because everyone's making so much
content there. I have I love Drew's
content. Drew's been out in Japan making
a bunch of decent content. He's doing
all right. Same thing with Nolan Daniel
White, um another creator I've I follow
who's making similar content. They're
all selvage denim shopping out there.
And I say this to say, I've now seen
hundreds of videos. Because you know how
the algorithms work. You go to Japan,
you want to watch Japan content, shows
you more. Everyone's doing the same
stuff. They're going to the same stores.
They're shopping for the same things.
It's repetitive and it's just not cool.
And I'm not saying when these guys did
it it wasn't cool or that it doesn't
make them interesting creators. But this
is the time we're functioning in where
everything that's not intrinsically new
and interesting is just getting rinsed.
And it gives you this feeling in the
back of your head that like, can I enjoy
anything if I have to create from it? In
responding to this trend, if I don't do
it immediately, it's kind of cooked. And
then once I do it, if everyone else does
it, then what I did all of a sudden
becomes cooked. You get this feeling,
this perpetual feeling that everything
is just not quite right. Unless unless,
this is what I want to call out. You are
operating on a completely unique path
unlike anyone else. Then when you go to
these places, you do something so
indecipherable that people couldn't
comprehend it and they would have to
copy it and if they do copy it it won't
be as good. This is the principle I've
operated on on content for a long time.
Even when we went to China, I'm not just
going to the fabric market, we're
explaining how everything works, we're
tactically giving advice. We have this
layers deeper than anyone else can go
where they can go repeat a big bit of
the virality, but not the same value
that comes with it. And I have ideas on
how we're going to do Japan differently,
but it leads to this overarching feeling
among the creator populace and among the
tastemaker populace that nothing is
interesting. That's a worthwhile thing
to call out because it basically dulls
the resonance of anything actually
interesting. And so then I want to talk
about TikTok and specifically what's
happened now that it's moved into more
of a US control. So in the weeks since
we've seen new ownership on TikTok,
we've had two basically breaks where
views have stopped showing, people can't
post, CapCut's down, and views plummet.
And then existing large creators, when
they come back from that they're getting
videos with a thousand views or ten
thousand views. Numbers are now all over
the place. There's no consistency. What
was great about TikTok before is if you
got real resonance, if you had a real
fan base and had a real cultural set
around you that you basically had this
built-in movement through the algorithm
around your personality. And now for
even the biggest creators like all that
is disintegrating. It is a pure
free-for-all every single post. And it
was for most of us. Even my content,
I've never resonated on there the way I
have on Instagram or YouTube. It was
always a fight. But now everyone's in
that. All the people I knew that were a
TikTok first, I'm TikTok third in terms
of my network importance. They're
battling against that. And that changes
things significantly because so much
culture was birthed on TikTok. The last
36 months, more culture was birthed on
TikTok than any other social network and
that is not the case in the last 60
days. Things are happening elsewhere.
Streaming is birthing culture in a way
more interesting way. The conversations
are happening in these splintering
social networks. But what is still
strong there is TikTok Shop is a real
mover for real brands, especially in
consumer packaged goods, is a truly
arc-changing, established way now to
bring real volume and awareness into
what you do. It's no longer like a
fringe thing. It is fully arrived as a
e-commerce opportunity brands can take
advantage of. And then the live selling.
TikTok live selling still works. It's
still impactful. People are doing it.
They don't understand it. There is alpha
in being at the edge there. And then
using those same personalities that are
live selling to be on the main feed and
begin to establish a world around this.
And Whatnot seen this, too. I have a The
parents of a kid my son went to school
goes to school with started their
Whatnot business the other week and
crushed it from the start. There's a
live selling opportunity that is growing
there. It's kind of the shift of where
some of that impact is going to be. Now,
at the same time, while TikTok is
beginning to melt, Substack is a social
network. I want to call this out because
it's important because used to be a lot
of people on X. X used to be the primary
written network, right? Threads has come
out. Threads is okay, but the user on
there is more immature to social media
and to text-based platform and the value
ecosystem around it and ideas that come
out of it is kind of non-existent. It's
just a place to scroll and interact. It
has potential, but it's not like a
zeitgeist builder yet. But basically,
the female users, right? Are not on X. I
know a handful of women on X, nothing
like the amount of men, and way less
than it was 5 years ago. And to the
point, you know, I can't name a single
of my wife's friends that were on there.
Would have been very different even 2
years ago. But where they are is on
Substack. There is a huge interactive
user base because Substack is a social
media feed. You see me scrolling here
unlogged in. These are all posts with a
lot of interaction and views and
conversation. And it's video posts. I
post all my videos on there. I posted a
carousel go viral on here the other
week. And the text posts and the the
promotion of the email newsletters. And
when you interact with them, you get
email subscribers from them. So, the
stakes are higher. But it needs to be
treated like a social network. But
really, it's important to note that the
splintering is interesting. The X user
base, a big chunk of that female user
base didn't end up on Blue Sky. They
ended up on Substack. Where they're
either writing or engaging or
participating or reading. And there's
male and female audiences on X and
Substack, too. And some of them they're
from a zeitgeist forward, trend-related
perspective. This is where they are
consuming media and enjoying it and
where ideas are being birthed that have
legs bigger than just what their
interaction is. And that splintering is
interesting because it basically means
less resonant big cultural things that
can happen than ever in any world that's
really not streaming. Instagram has a
power that Tik Tok doesn't. It's a very
different social network. And then
there's all these little places that are
coming out underneath it that's a lot
different than that when you think of
kind of like the big three of the meta,
Google, Tik Tok advertising ecosystems.
And this relates to a trend I want to
talk about called basically the complete
loss of media. So, all traditional
media, GQ, Highsnobiety, i-D, Vogue, The
Cut, they're all behind the curve now.
Now, journalism always used to be
reporting on things that are happening,
but you'd probably hear about things
bubbling. Now, they are behind what's
being talked about on Tik Tok, what's
being talked about on Substack. They are
rewriting what's happening on social
media for the most part. So, the
conversation has already happened. They
are late to it. And their resonance is
less than ever. Doesn't travel. People
don't click it. People don't read it.
You basically have New York has
resonance. New York Times, The Wall
Street Journal, NY Mag, The Cut have an
outsized, disproportionate impact on
people in New York who actually read it
and engage with it and still participate
in media. And then those people's belief
that that media still has impact
elsewhere, which it really doesn't, is
basically gone everywhere else in the
world except for there. But if you look
at what they're You look at what they're
doing and where they're promoting it.
Like, GQ wrote about the streaming
clicking and clubbing and they were
late. And they're just rewriting a bunch
of stuff that's already happening on Tik
Tok. But they're reporting on stuff that
there's already been hundreds of Tik
Toks and substacks that were out about
this that most of their reader base, of
what little is left, I mean, there's not
a significant reader base there anymore,
has already had the conversation
participated in it. This is an
afterthought that just happens to be in
print that you may have the luxury to
read. It is no longer a thing that has
any ability to showcase culture. Same
thing here on The Cut.
Again, this is a big problem of why
these why these will never work and why
every one of these will die is because
of these interstitials like this.
There's no way. There's just no way
anyone's ever going to
pay for this, right? No new user is
adopting this
to read why celebrity GoFundMe's make
people so angry, which again is
recapping a Tik Tok. And I've seen this
now. Like in addition to people like I
want to call out Neil Patel stole one of
my YouTube's the other day. And that's
Look, there's a hundred people that take
YouTube's, right? But basically just
recounts word for word how like how
brands need to think of their social
media like a TV show or a TV network and
characters. I'm like, "Oh, they're just
taking my exact YouTube." That happens
all the time. YouTube, it's it's known.
He probably doesn't even know. His
writing team just took it. Short forms
happens all the time. Traditional media
are doing it, but they act like, you
know, that like that's a like they're
having the idea or that it's noble in
some capacity when it's just purely
behind. that lack of importance is an
important thing to think about. Because
if you see it being written about there,
you have to realize this is already
behind the curve. And what I want to
call out here is that this Highsnobiety
Insights report where they're talking
about like popular products, optimized
objects, cultural classics, status
symbols. They're writing about, you
know, they're putting in this big report
with Jesus with BCG. Dark. Bunch of
washed ideas that were big tech These
are all just big Tik Toks from last
year. They're trying to recap into
something. It's too late for that. This
is not where this is at. They're making
stuff about the videos that were being
made again in 2025. Now the status
symbols have already shifted. The
objects have already shifted. Everything
they're talking about here is cooked.
And so we're in this really interesting
time where they still have some
resonance for for one reason, which is
people still when they think of I need
to go to a newsletter, I'm going to
browse something, they think of all
these names they already have
association with. You might still go to
Highsnob. You might see it in the feed
and stop because you know it. ID is
doing well with Carousels. You're
stopping because it's ID, not because
the Carousel itself is good. There's
some merit to stopping the scroll with
familiarity. That's the only thing that
these have left. And so we're in this
kind of precarious position where that
still has some relevance. And all these
new interesting properties haven't built
out above that. But at the same time,
like whenever I read Puck, I'm just kind
of shocked at the lack of editorial
oversight, right? People aren't reading
it. It's not researched. It's not
double-checked. You can tell people
don't know the culture that they're
talking about. That's going to be a hard
reality for people to work around and
for us to function in in terms of what
is the importance of media going
forward. And so related to this, um I
want to talk about probably the most
selfish placement that I've had inside
of a YouTube video because I get to show
off my website. I want to talk about the
ease with which you can design and
publish and work through some of the
things now that a lot of that media used
to have, right? There used to be a gate
to having beautiful looking media
websites, opt-ins, etc. And I want to
talk about Framer, who I partnered with
on this video. I'm about to do a series
with on portfolios and web building, and
show you a bit of just how great and
easy it is to build these online
experiences now. So, I have been redoing
all of my online media to look and feel
akin to some of the things that I've
done with my brand on social media. And
this is an example, just to see in the
back end of Framer, of what that looks
like. So, if you've never edited a
website, you want something to look
something good, this is how easy it is
to go in and be able to say, "Hey, I can
just adjust text like this." And all I
have to do to adjust that, I actually
adjust the break points of mobile and
tabs as well. I can have persistent
elements, so components that are in
here, where I'm able to edit this
navigation and it sits on all of the
different sites that I have with
different variants. And there's so many
abilities to position and build a cool
looking experience that in such an easy
way, it's almost shocking to someone who
had to work through WordPress and stuff
my whole life, but like, look at what we
have here. It's just this is the webinar
sign-up. What we're able to do really
quickly on Framer is cloud animation
that goes up over the form. And so, a
bit on the flow that I used to put that
together. So, I hired the developer that
worked on this from Contra. It's a great
place to find professionals if you want
to build a website and something like
this. I have my brand kit. You'll see a
lot of these visuals match the look and
feel of the things you see inside my
carousels. I have a bunch of those
existing elements that tie together. And
then once something is made, it's not
like, "Okay, cool. I got to go to a
developer to make changes each time."
We're able to duplicate the webinar page
out and change the copy. And so, for
instance, this is the the the next one
we have coming where I've swapped out
some of the graphics, I've swapped out
some of the text, but I'm using the same
format and formula just with a new
setup, right? And there are tons and
tons of really interesting themes that
work with this. There's all that motion
animation, which you can use or not use
depending on what you want to do. And
there's forms, there's forms that
connect directly to a Google Sheet or
they'll connect to services like Kit.
But, I say all this to say that if you
want to have a beautiful website, you
want to be able to edit the majority of
it yourself. And you'll see here, you
see this little icon right here. This is
I can edit the content of anything on
the live page as well. It's one of the
beauties of Framer. To the point
basically, we're interacting like this
is like interacting with your favorite
design software, even easier to be able
to make changes that are live on the
internet. That anything where you
thought it required some huge budget to
work through stuff like that, that era
is now completely done and empowered by
stuff like Framer. So, you can learn
more about Framer at the link of the
description here. I'm actually going to
do a series with them coming up about
creative portfolios and thinking through
kind of the web. We're going to get into
pretty in-depth on it. Uh so, more on
that soon. So, now I want to hit this
idea of the 15 minutes of fame. There
has been more coverage of this girl as a
Staples baddie by marketing influencers
and creative influencers than I again,
with everything is back to the idea of
nothing being cool. It is not It is so
torched to talk about this now. So, like
every single marketing creator is I
can't touch stuff like that here. Like
when I'm on short form, I'll talk about
it a bit here. What I want to call out
why this exists. Used to be okay, 15
minutes of fame. Everyone can get on the
news for a second or have their moment
in the sun. We're no longer in the 15
minutes of fame era. It is 150 posts to
escape the permanent underclass. That is
what the trend looks like. Where it's
not like, cool, I'm going to go viral
once. If you post 150 times and you have
some degree of charisma or something
interesting to go on, you have an
ability to project your life into a
completely different scenario. Her life
will be different forever because she
posted at her job about being at Staples
with her vibe and her characteristic.
Now, there are plenty of people that
aren't interesting enough to be able to
cross that boundary, but there are tons
and tons of interesting people who are
150 posts in their lives away from
again, not just the 15 minutes of fame,
oh, she's famous here. This will change
her life forever. It will change how
she's able to interact with the media
landscape, what jobs she gets in the
future, her compensation. It's not like
she just got shown on CNN once or she's
on an episode of ridiculousness. This is
a fiscal life change, the likes of which
are are almost impossible to navigate
for people prior. It's important concept
to understand. I'm going to zip through
a few more of these to wrap up this
video. I'm going to talk about the
gimmicks of real life is another one. Do
people really want to go to in real life
events now? And you saw things like the
Timothée Chalamet look-alike contest or
whatever, but they're a lot of them have
a gimmick or an idea. And I've seen some
media write about how that's like a bad
thing, how can things not just be normal
now. But honestly, people want to be
excited and want to participate in
things that are fun, and I leaned into
this trend here this last week. So, Expo
West is a snack convention here in
Orange County. It's a natural foods
expo. I go every year. And so, I was
with some uh people I know, so the Air
team,
Andrea from SnackShot, Taylor the Rens.
We put together and judged a pretty
popping contest for America's Next Top
Snack. So, we modeled it after Shark
Tank, America's Next Top Model, where we
selected 50 brands submitted, we
selected six.
They came and presented on stage their
brand to a big crowd of people,
including like the Kroger buying team,
like in the front like with legitimate
people in the industry, plus just a lot
of people who are excited about the
niche, people from my social media, that
kind of thing. And then one of them won,
and they won a photo shoot, they won a
pop-up store space in New York. I
invested money into them along with Air.
This brand, Bezzito, who makes an
amazing labneh snack, won. But people
came because it's in it's interesting,
it's fun. There's something completely
different. Oh, we're going to see six
brands basically do a 3-minute pitch on
their product, people are going to be
like screaming or yelling, or they're
getting asked hard questions, and that's
all happening live. And this experience
era, like that's why I like call out
that, like we rented a Bubba Gump
Shrimp, that we had a step and repeat, a
table, like a extremely mediocre AV
system, and that is the extent of the
event production, right? To turn
something from your average party to
just something interesting. And still,
in and around the core hour of the
actual activity, there's tons of hangout
and tons of whatever. But that is where
the whether it's a brand event or a
personal event, people are so attached
to having something be more than just a
hang. That's an interesting thing to
think about if you're building any
experience. Moving on, I want to talk
about the the AI fight. I want you to
understand this in context of the
future. So, obviously, you'll see a lot
of backlash about AI-generated imagery
and video online. Totally get it.
There's a is a conversation to have. But
you have to understand where it is in
terms of what the generations look like,
and and what's coming in the future. So,
you can be as mad as you want at that,
or think that it can be avoided or
stopped now. But, if you look at what
the adoption looks like for the previous
generations, it's a completely different
thing. So, I was with a group of college
designers the other week, and one of
them was working on his clothing line.
And so, basically, they had designed
this entire thing in FreePik. They'd
taken their iconography, they had
generated that into flats, they had
brought those flats into mock-ups,
they're bringing into materials. It's an
entire collection design. Even starting
to go into what patterns and grading
look like, completely prompted by AI.
And I'm not saying it was perfect, but I
looked at it and I was like, "Oh, this
is actually good." And this is just
built in, this is how they are
interacting with the future. This is the
next generation of those people. You
cannot stop the momentum of that. And to
take that a step further, I look at um
in my son's school, he's nine, he uses
Canva. Canva's built into their
curriculum. And inside that, we got him
the the pro version, or whatever it is,
cuz he's spending a lot of time working
in it and creating stuff. They're
generating images. The images that are
showing up inside there, it's not even a
question, it's not even like, "Oh, I'm
using AI to do this," or X or Y.
Generating is just a thing that they can
do, and they type in the stuff, and it's
just built into the workflow. It's
second nature, it's inherent. And I just
want to call out those two things as any
conversation or battle that we're having
around this now is lost. In a
generational shift, they're growing up
with it in a way that's not even
decipherable from reality. And that's
when you know that there is no turning
point. I just want that to be kind of
understood when you look at what the
difference is going to be
generationally, that's already gone.
Now, I want to have a quick conversation
about the legacy media trying to
understand the new media landscape. So,
Netflix recently added podcasts. This is
a good example of this. So, you can get
a lot of you can get podcasts from The
Ringer, you can get Barstool podcasts,
to others, you can get like Breakfast
Club on Netflix. But, what was
interesting to me about that is you
can't find them. I went I want to see
what this looked like. I'm thinking
about what my media looks like in a
streaming and TV world. So, I was
looking for examples. You can't navigate
to them. There's no podcast tab, you
can't find them. You have to search. So,
for instance, if I want to actually go
and engage with that podcast, you have
to be searched down to get to Bill
Simmons, or something like that. Now,
this kind of defeats the point, right?
Because what podcast are going to want
to promote themselves so hard that
they're on Netflix that enough people
search to watch them that it actually
becomes relevant. Even the biggest ones
aren't going to be able to do numbers
like that that would matter in any way,
shape, or form. Without discovery, there
is inherently no use of those platforms.
But then when you actually get to them,
these podcasts are unwatchable. I
There's never been a darker moment than
actually seeing what some of these
people look like, right? And I'm sure
many of you consume podcasts on YouTube.
If you go watch like I looked at the
Russillo podcast or some of the Barstool
stuff, you're like you would once you
start looking at these people, you
realize you would never want to listen
to them. There's a There's a dissonance
there. And the production value's
terrible. At least the Bill Simmons one
at least kind of like looks all right,
but again, it's not compelling enough
that you'd want to watch it on TV versus
even what we're able to do with
overlays, etc. inside a bunch of these
YouTube videos. And we saw this with
Amazon that has been Prime that's been
basically been giving some shows to
YouTubers that are like they're they're
quasi working out, they're getting
there. But this navigation is going to
be a huge thing because there is no
longer the needed Hollywood
infrastructure to push this. Production
is significantly easier than it was.
People want to consume the type of media
they're consuming on YouTube. It's going
to be hard for those streaming networks
to compete without IP and promotion. And
a lot of this it's going to come out of
social media. way that they started to
solve it is not right. It was kind of
rushed. And I think there's just a huge
opportunity in Delta to understand that
and go back to what I've mentioned
before about clipping, about all the
infrastructure we have around media
today, and build something unique. And
the second gen of this, the second gen
of what these companies look like that
end up on there are going to likely be
uh huge cultural moments. And I know I'm
a little far back to be able to
participate in that. Maybe I get to gen
three, but uh we're going to get there
even on the tail end. And the last three
points I want to have here, we'll talk
briefly about Polymarket calls she in
the conversations there. I don't support
or condone these. I want people to
understand their implications. So, I
learned a lot about this when I uh was
going through this with some friends
around the Super Bowl cuz there were
odds on if certain brands were going to
run ads on the Super Bowl. And I had I
won't say insider information, I'm not
betting on it, but I had information. I
know some people were running Super Bowl
ads. I know for sure. And there are odds
on this. Let's look at this Entropic.
Entropic had 50/50 odds you could bet on
and return real money. And people were
able to bet and put context on it and
they have that information. And the odds
kind of adjust based on this. And the
fact that this exists and there's like
this legality and morality that we're
sort of struggling with of okay, well,
can I use what information is usable or
not? Where does the legality lie?
Obviously, someone in Mr. Beast's camp
was like arrested for working inside of
this. The people know more than anything
traditional and they're able to
participate in that online. And I don't
think this is the final incarnation of
this is the point. This idea of
prediction itself, this idea of the
knowledge of the crowd, of the usage of
that insider knowledge and how
monetizable that is. This is like stage
one. So, I wouldn't just ignore this
purely because it's like a casino. I
don't even I don't think of it from that
regard. And I would really look at what
is those implications mean for the
future of how we interact. Something to
think about. And then next, I want to
call out monoculture. You would think in
this social media era, all the things
we've talked about, we would lose
resonance on so many of these cultural
items that were institutions. But the
few things that we have left that people
actually care enough about are massively
important. And I'll call this out even
in my own content. I talked about the
Olympic uniforms for the winter games.
It's a really successful video of mine.
Same thing with the Super Bowl ads. I
recapped that. Did a bunch of coverage
on X that went really viral and then did
same thing on TikTok and Instagram that
also uh did really well. We have so
little to talk about that everyone does
that those exact moments become more
influential than ever. And they
basically give them their own
algorithms. What I noticed about that
Olympic video is there's all these
people in the Olympic Village that are
going viral, posting all their stuff.
And then my video would be shown right
after a bunch of that, right? The
algorithms know what to do with a moment
in time. And there's only so many
moments in time to do it. And so, we
have Black Friday, stuff like that. You
have Valen tine's Day. You have your
kind of standard events. But then you
have stuff like the World Cup or the
Super Bowl or any of those. That is a
worthwhile looking at when you're where
your media spend goes, what the impact
is. I have gone now from thinking that
traditional media wouldn't be as useful
to saying the highest end of it, your
Super Bowl TV ad is probably one of the
most impactful things you can buy if you
build around it. And so, it's worth
thinking about whether it's for you or
for your brand, what you interact with,
what those remaining monoculture moments
are cuz I actually think they have more
leverage than ever. And the last thing I
want to end on here is the monetization
of information. I made a video Um it
didn't do super well because cuz it's
niche. I made a video about how
basically so many businesses are also
selling workshops and courses now.
Basically I look at it like the post
master class era. Master class
normalized the selling of information to
your average people to be able to gain a
level of knowledge. But now we're also
seeing to monetize businesses in retail
or with growing costs your bouquet
flower company is selling how to make a
luxury flower arrangement. Your Japanese
gardening store is doing actually like
lessons online via Zoom. There is this
idea of the value of information that
people would have thought would have
been bad. With chat GPT I can answer
anything now. I can learn anything on
YouTube. I think what people are missing
is how disserved the world's population
is by their educational institutions.
Their desire for learning and actually
learning it like with a group where they
can participate and the kind of dollars
around that and the trend and basically
like the replacement of enough of the
traditional educational infrastructure
with the ability to get exactly what you
want online. But that monetization of
information has not hit the middle of
the bell curve yet. There's a
significant amount of alpha there to
think about for any business of any
kind. So I know this was a long video
but I think it's important to understand
all of these repercussions of the things
happening on the internet for your life,
for the brand you work out or for the
brand you own. Like I mentioned we're
going to have a discussion about this in
the next community call. Info on that is
down below specifically in terms of how
do you build brand and marketing teams
around it cuz obviously that's my
specialty. I've been a lot to Japan so a
bunch of that content is going to be
coming out here in the coming weeks.
We're going to talk a bit about that.
It's an interesting cultural moment that
we have. Love to have a conversation
about any of these things that you see
or disagree with down below. I'm most
interested to see how people are
interacting with these same pieces of
media. Thank you all so much for
watching.