In this video, we're going to talk about
the art direction and branding of Justin
and Hailey Bieber. Justin is currently
on a bit of a redemption arc or perhaps
a full circle as the headliner on the
main stage of Coachella. So, in this
video, I'm going to break down the stack
of how their brands operate. We're going
to talk about the art direction of
Skylark. We are going to talk a bit
about the art direction of Rhode and how
those are different as one is more niche
and one is more mass market. How you
would have to play in those markets to
operate differently if you didn't have
that level of fame. This idea of content
creation as a squad and a group project
in a out
products and how it's a real map for how
to interact with modern media. Let's
lock in. So, first, let's break down the
stack cuz this is really relevant for
anyone that makes content on the
internet and wants to think about
influence or personal brand today. So,
each of both Hailey and Justin had a
career, granted, in the arts. One was a
singer, one was a model. But, on top of
that career and as part of it, they had
personal brands as extension of the
career. That's something where majority
of us are at now, especially if you're
watching this video or tune into my
channel, we talk a lot about it. If
you're already creative field in
particular or a business field, the
audience and the distribution of content
makes a huge difference in where you can
go. And it's not just about making money
from it, it's about being able to tell
your story and reach your fans. And this
is the pinnacle of being able to do
that. Pop superstardom, etc. But, then
they have consumer brands that are
extensions of their personal brands.
Justin has Skylark where he is selling
clothing and accessories. Hailey has her
beauty business with Rhode that recently
sold for an outrageous amount of money,
but warranted. But, then they have
collaborations between the personal
brands and the consumer brands of each
other. So, for instance, they make
content together. He is present at her
debut of a new Rhode product, ensuring
to help its virality. She's a model for
Skylark, a much smaller brand, helping
give it attention and notoriety. All of
this intertwines, not just them
separately building their brands, but
them as couples as well. And the power
dynamic works as it shifts. At one
point, him showing up to the launch of
her beauty product was a big boost for
the Rhode brand. Today, her even being
present inside of his brand is just as
important. The dynamic has shifted. And
what's interesting for both of these,
we're going to dive into the actual art
direction tactics, is the art direction
of these brands are perfect extensions
of their identities. So, let's dive into
Justin's brand. So, those who weren't
around for a while, you remember Drew
House, a brand he's no longer a part of,
he angrily rejected as he went into this
new era, probably a bad business deal.
But, Drew House for merchandise for
Justin Bieber was actually pretty good.
Designs weren't bad, the lookbooks were
pretty solid, it was relatively popular,
pricing was okay as far as that era of
pop artistry participating in
streetwear, it was pretty well done.
Makes sense, it was in the collaboration
with a stylist. It was well
representative of his overall vibe. But,
as that brand fell apart, we saw
Skylark. They do a couple things well I
want to call out to think about as you
are looking at visual representations of
any brand you might work on. The first
is their color theory. This brand
excellently inside its art direction
picks its color combinations, picks both
of the products and of the visual medias
with which they showcase it. This was
then reflected inside what you saw
inside his Coachella set. It has that
same emphasis on color, on motion, on
blur. The brand's tied together. But,
you'll notice this color is a
throughline through time. scroll through
the Skylark social media feed, you'll
notice that all of these different drops
have the same DNA, right? You see the
same grain and noise and motion and
color of the core product photos,
whether it's a portrait or whether it's
just a flat lay, but it moves in period.
Be a whole drop that's all in and around
purple and then it's its extensions, one
that's a little more in red or blue, one
that's in black and white, and is moving
over time to create that artistic
throughline that's doing purely through
its color selection as well as the
treatments it's giving to the photos. It
feels cohesive, it feels unique in a
relatively busy world of today. But,
this had a plan from the start. They
were thinking about this over time.
We're going to use this art direction
throughline through a year, two years,
or more of our brand. And we're going to
think about the colors of the releases
and the colors of the designs in tandem.
This is a great example of visual DNA
for a brand. And if you're a brand who's
doing flat lays, taking every piece of
this seriously. A lot of brands will
just do those shots on white
backgrounds, but can you put them on top
of that color? Can you develop whatever
your theory is for how the products meld
into their background or how their
surreal presentation? Taking the
everyday photos what you have to have to
e-commerce shots and making them
interesting. All of this comes back to
visual DNA. And a couple other big
callouts here is the product is the
hero. You see people relatively rarely.
You see Justin also very rarely inside
the brand's core showcase. The product
is always the primary and it's presented
within that artistic vision. And then
when they do do portraits, they're
really portraits of the user. They're
showing the sunglass, they're showing
the wear, but they're presented as art.
It uses that same motion, that same
grain. There's a throughline through
this that's really well done. Maybe not
the most unique out of the box, but a
good template for what are the basics of
standout visual DNA. But, this is a good
model for most brands for the core. The
difference between Justin Bieber's brand
and your streetwear brand is that a
brand cannot survive without attention
at the top. That attention, when you
have an influencer, comes from them.
Skylark's attention comes from Justin
Bieber and the ecosystem around them. I
made a video about buying some of their
slides, got 350,000 views. Now, it
wasn't an incredible video. It's not
because I made some amazing piece of
art, it was a totally okay video, but
because the consumption and excitement
for what he's doing at his pop stardom
is there. People want to know what his
brand is doing and they want to see it
reviewed. So, if you were putting
something like this together and you had
your visual DNA and your basics, you
were elevating your flat lays, you had
your own structure for how you were
going to do portraits, and you thought
through the throughlines what that looks
like over time, that's an amazing
foundation, especially for a more niche
brand. But, since he's driving top of
funnel content, you need to think about
what you're going to do there. Are you
an influencer? Do you have a personal
brand? Are you able to drive that? Or
are you doing it through content? You'll
see a lot of brands today are doing
relentless styling content. Whenever I
look at who's doing stuff that's in
class, I typically look at Represent.
Also love looking at Elwood, people that
you know are doing really well online
and in e-commerce and who are really
operating at scale. They're doing real
numbers, not doing 100, 200 on a drop.
It's very different. And you'll see that
if you look at the ads that they're
running or you look at the people that
are promoting them, they have lots of
guys who have a great fashion sense and
interesting apartments going interesting
places styling their clothes. And that
becomes top of funnel and they support
that not just organic content, but they
boost a lot of those content as ads. And
so, if you're building something like
that today, that is a way to look at it.
I can drive that attention through
styling content, influencers, UGC, and
ads based on that or doing that myself.
And also what's really popular right now
is historical reference content and
explainer content. One of my favorite
creators, Ken Sekiguchi, does a great
job at this. If he's designing a jacket
or he's working on something, he'll go
into why the indigo wash exists or why a
specific item comes from a specific way.
People are really interested in the
background of fashion and design. You
can develop a top of funnel there for
people to go buy the garments. I have
seen how much Ken cares about his crafts
so much so that I've bought items from
him because I know he's really caring
about the thought and intention put into
their design. But, Rhode's playbook for
art direction is very different. I did a
whole video on this if you want to deep
dive into the beauty space. But, their
playbook for art and creative direction
is meant to scale to mass markets.
Skylark is a streetwear brand. It's only
going to go so far. Maybe you can build
it up into a huge menswear brand over
time, but it's niche. That's a very
different playbook than what needs to
scale. And Rhode executed excellently on
a very straightforward playbook to help
leverage again that level of attention
she's able to give it and the popularity
of their actual products with a
repeatable playbook that they have stuck
to relentlessly. It starts with sensory
minimalism, so you will always see
something frozen, something dripping,
something that you can feel or almost
taste as a throughline of the art
direction. Then you have food as a hook.
They are trying to stop the scroll and
this is not groundbreaking, it's just
executed excellently with a croissant, a
piece of fruit, milk. That works because
we as humans love to look at food.
There's a reason that content does so
well. Then they have a third pillar of
the right it girl muses at the right
time. Whether it's Addison Rae or
whether it's the right model, they are
picking people that are relevant in the
culture and getting them in campaigns at
the right times and executing those
campaigns inside the existing Rhode
world. But, something comes from being
able to leverage that fame and pick
those right people. And what I encourage
people to think about cuz they're always
like, well, I can't act like that. Yeah,
obviously you can't get Addison Rae, but
if you are operating as a brand or a
personal brand or whatever it is and you
have people in your niche or in your
world or in your city who are having
their moment, collaborating with them in
those times and being a part of that
cycle is a really important thing to
think about. We'll talk about that a bit
when I get to this content as squads
concept. It's so important for personal
brands now. Hit that later in the video.
And then Rhode also has that viral
vehicle of form and proportion,
oversized things. When you see these
girls in these campaigns, they're
obviously often interacting with some
oversized Rhode object. They play with
proportion a lot. And look, this is the
straight forward, this is the ABCs of
good art direction. Is it sensory? Can
you feel it, smell it, taste it, touch
it? That makes it more than a single
image. Proportion and scale, whether
really small or really large, surrealism
in general is something that immediately
stops the scroll. The character who you
choose it. They are just taking, again,
the basics of this playbook and is
executing it as well as they can
consistently. Now, I want to quickly tap
into some tactical workflows before I
get to the premium brands squads
collaboration portion of this. So, many
of you who follow my content know about
Particle. Particle is a piece of
software that lets you explore what
companies are selling on their
e-commerce. It will actually show you
data in time periods of what products
are moving volume, what their average
discounts are, how that changes year
over year, and they also cover things
like how their homepages change, what
announcements did they make, what are
they doing in SMS and email, the ability
to hunt down trends of how product
searches or brand name searches have
changed over time. Like you can see I am
Gia's big bump for festival season, all
within this great dashboard. What I'm
going to talk about today is it's
actually more accessible than ever. So,
more and more marketers are basically
using Claude as a command center. You
can tie your apps into these, so these
integrations. Integrations are called
MCPs, making data available within
Claude that you can just ask for in chat
and it will show up. And so, it'll be
really common now for a lot of marketers
to have something like all their SEO
data or their Facebook ads data, results
from their campaigns or their slacks
tied into Claude so they can just
reference that within one chat. Well,
now Particle is available there, too.
So, you can see here I was able to
search for what are Rhode's top selling
products online this week? And it just
answers in Claude. It's telling me,
here's estimated units, here's the top
10 products by what they're doing, and
then summarizing key takeaways. And
since it knows me and knows my context,
knows what I'm looking for, it will tell
me things like glazing milk is punching
above its weight and volume. And then I
can go ask something, what did they do
to promote the pre-order of the new
pimple patches at Coachella? And it will
tell me, oh, they got spot wear. Here's
assets they're pulling in from the
particle data. Here's other stuff
they're pulling in from the web. So,
basically all that particle data and
information is just brought into the
place where you're chatting and
functioning anyway, and you can actually
back it up with what are the trends that
are happening in active wear right now.
What are Vuori's most best-selling
colors that they have in bottoms? So, if
you're planning lines or planning
product or planning to integrate
anything, that particle data is now
directly available in Claude. And to do
that, you just go to settings, you go to
connectors, and you'll see I'm already
I'm connected to Notion, Slack, Asana,
Ahrefs. You add a custom connector, and
you can get the name and MCP server URL
from your particle account and just add
it, and then it is just immediately
available. You don't even have to ask it
to go to particle, it will know. So,
super useful tool if you are in brand
building, and shout out to Particle as
always for sponsoring this video. And
you've probably heard from me and others
that the content theme of this year is
the squad, not the solo creator. It's
the friend group. Who's dating who? The
collab posts, people working together
where you don't just follow the one guy
who runs the run club, you see multiple
of them working together. And then who
are they dating? Oh, and then they have
their own little group. It's the Secret
Lives of Mormon Wives effect. And it
plays out in collaboration posts and
group trips, etc. It's content plus
reality TV, which was inevitable. We
were in this era of value or
entertainment content. That's where we
were in like 2023, where if you made
really valuable content, like then I
made marketing how-tos and tutorials
specifically. And they were ultra
valuable, there's no other content out
there like that. And some people could
just do skits or entertainment or just
be hot. And you could work with either
of those. In 2024, 2025, it was value
plus entertainment. So, you had to be
able to wrap being edge something
educational in a great story. And if you
were just producing content that was
funny or look good and didn't have any
substance behind it, that began to fall
off, too. And then now going into 2026,
it's those things plus the storyline.
People want to know you a bit as a human
being. They want to get in a little bit
of your tea or your drama, where you're
going for your family trip. They want to
see, oh, you're actually friends with
those other influencers, and you guys
hang out together? Oh, and you make
content together? Oh, you guys are all
going to be in France for Cannes? That's
how the social media experience
functions right now. It's really
important to think about for creators of
all types because this is an amazing
time to do it with your friends. And I'm
one of those guys where I have convinced
so many of my friends to become content
creators. Many of them now are in the
hundreds of thousands just cuz I'm like,
this is just such a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity to be able to leverage that
attention either to make money or for
your career. And really, the barrier to
entry is just doing. But if you do it
together, it's always easier. I was
begging my friends a lot at the
beginning just cuz I wanted people to
relate to who are also doing it. And
then those group chats ended up becoming
really powerful. And then Justin and
Hailey is the top example, right? And it
plays out not just with the two of them,
but their friend group. Kylie Jenner
this week is wearing a shirt with
Justin's face on it at Hailey's behest
at Coachella while they're all making
mass content. Now, that's just happening
at the top level, but it works just as
well down below. People know that since
Ashwin and Jordan Rogers and I have a
podcast and collab, they may learn about
those creators because they're fans of
me and vice versa. They may experience
the podcast or see us in an event or
watch those begin to build the lore
around it. And that's probably the least
interesting example, right? We're
marketing creators. We don't have drama,
we don't have tea. We're dads, there's
not some huge storyline. But if you do
have the ability to play within that,
there's a lot that comes from building
those narrative arcs. Because those same
narrative arcs is always how I encourage
brands to think about their marketing.
Who are the characters in your story?
What are the events that they are going?
What are the sets people see you in on a
recurring basis? Your office, your
warehouse. It's the same thing with a
personal brand. All of your story, your
apartment, your car, where you're going
or your trips. This is an arc that plays
out like a TV show. And all the other
people that can interact with it are
characters. And guess what? If that show
is only about one person, it's probably
not that exciting. And in a world where
content gets more and more competitive,
think like that to stay on the edge. And
they've played this up a lot, right? One
of the most famous circumstances of this
is when Hailey and Justin showed up to
when she launched the like the donut
glaze product, right? They played up the
presentation, the magnetism and the
opposites of her in that red dress and
him looking like a slob, both
representative of their brands. But they
knew what they were doing. They are
calling out, bringing attention to that
moment, representing them separately.
This being really him playing the
background and it's her moment. That
visual dichotomy presented her as the
focus, as the star in that moment. But
they played this even further. There's
collab products between the brands.
Obviously, one of her most prolific
products is the Rhode iPhone case. And
he's done the same. I have This is
actually one of the Skylark iPhone
cases. It's a sensory case. You put your
hand in and around it, which I
absolutely love. You can press the the
bubble. As someone who fidgets with
stuff all the time, having my phone be
like this has been great. And then he
launched his variation where you can put
basically like a Lucy within the case.
They're collaborating on products
between brands, attaching the universes.
And now on the pimple patch collab, the
iconography that's more associated with
him, the billboards at Coachella around
his performance, the announcements that
play into that, the arcs aligning
together. This is just the execution at
the highest, best level of what everyone
who's working through premium brands and
brands themselves should be thinking
about. Who are those characters? What
are those events? It doesn't have to be
Coachella, it can be the trade show in
your industry. It can be the local
farmers market. Content is all about the
scale that which you operate at. There's
a locality of the region you're in or in
terms of the industry that you focus on.
It all scales on multiple levels from
10,000 followers to 10 million
followers. And if you want to dive
deeper into art direction playbooks, I'm
linking the Rhode playbook here.
And then one of my next few videos, I'm
going to be getting into the art of
yapping and talking online and how
people are building these kind of more
organic presences. So, there's more
content coming there soon. If you want
to see any other of these art or
creative direction breakdowns around
other personalities or brands, let me
know below. Uh, some of my best videos
have come from those recommendations.
And as always, thank y'all so much for
watching.