In this video, we're going to talk about
the psychology of luxury branding. In a
world where it seems like luxury and
things that are ultra expensive for no
reason are more popular than ever, we're
going to dive into why. I'm going to
talk about the four factors that make
people spend a premium. We're going to
talk about the more sophisticated
psychology that makes people like things
like caviar. How brands have shifted the
luxury codes to make these more
accessible and broaden to a much wider
market. We're going to talk about how
brands build aesthetic worlds and build
products that can fit into their
consumer's aesthetic. We're going to
talk about abundance and its fantasy and
how that plays out in the objects that
brands choose. We're going to talk about
the power of curation. I love this
topic. I've actually spent most of my
career positioning against luxury,
saying, "Hey, we live in the middle top
price point, not quite up there. This is
why you should choose this instead of
this established industry." That's an
area and message that I love to market
to. And as such, I've learned a lot
about what's above and below and how
those are portrayed. Whether you're
really into marketing, have your own
brand, or just interested in the world
of taste and luxury around us, this is
going to be a special video. Let's lock
in. So, I want to start with the markets
of taste and capital are moving at an
astonishing speed right now. We have
more access than ever to understanding
what makes things interesting and
finding really special things for us.
I'll talk in a second about the four
factors that make people choose things
that are on the high end of price
points. And the internet and
self-expression and finding groups
online has opened us up to more
significant questions about what do we
want the aesthetics of our environment
to be like? How do we want to portray
ourselves? How we get into the hobbies
that we enjoy and what that says about
us and the circles that we can move in
in life. There's two core reasons that
we see almost all luxury get bought.
Number one is we have lots of capital.
Let's make it all worth it. So for
instance, if you have made a significant
amount of money, if you were born into a
significant amount of money, no matter
how you got it, if you have it, there's
the purchase decision that this took
hard work or we have this, we need to
make it worth it. And this is why you
see the existing luxury buyer, the 0.1%
spending more than ever. This is a
generational difference from a lot of
what came before where they're more
reserved about some expenditures and
showcases in part because of social
media, in part because of the awareness
we've shown. But the richest of the rich
are spending more than ever. Then we
have the much broader category that
contributes to the lower level of
luxury, which is people that say, "We
have some capital. Let's feel something
with it." When you get a bonus, you want
to feel good. You have an extra $200
left in your paycheck. People who have
any amount of extra money and who want
that dopamine rush, want to feel good
about themselves in a way that
encourages them to spend. And all luxury
purchases fall into one of those two
buckets. You will get a very small
subsection of people who will idolize
something specific for years. That may
be the only third, but it comes down to
four major psychological factors. The
first is belonging. You buy luxury
objects because you want to feel like
this is my life. I participate in
luxury. I drive a Porsche. I carry a
Dior bag. I belong in that world. This
is a very human nature. All these are
very human nature driven. We may think
we're better than these, but all of us
fall for at least one of them. Then
comes individualistic, getting something
special, the I deserve it. I have a lot
of friends that buy from Jacques Marie
Maj. I've gone with more than one of
them to pick up their glasses when they
get them and they had the one-to-one
experience with a rep and someone sews
up and there's papers with authenticity
and they get to sit down for their
consultation. They feel special buying
the sunglasses. The experience of a
sale. When I went to Florence the other
summer, I went and hunted down a luxury
dog collar place. We want to get a
souvenir for our dog. Instead of buying
him a Goyard collar, we're saying, "Hey,
let's get one from an artisan in
Florence who's known for that where you
can go pick it out." It was a whole
experience. They have all these items
you can choose. They make it in front of
you. Our son had a great time and it
became a special memoir of that
occasion. Same thing with the Goyard
wallet with the paint on. You want that
custom thing. You want to feel like it
was made for you. Luxury comes out of
bespoke culture where people would make
a tailored suit or a specific pair of
shoes, spend the premium for something
specific for them. And this carries that
legacy on even though it's been very
lost in the rest of it. Then there is
enjoyment of a skill. So if you have a
pastime that you enjoy like horseback
riding is your one escape in life or you
do something every day, it's your whole
livelihood and you want to purchase the
best for it. Those are the enjoyment
luxuries. Choosing to get the Hermes
saddle or taking those best of times you
have or the times you spend most
frequently the pen to sign your checks
and having a moment of luxury there. And
then the quintessential I'm better. A
lot of luxury consumption comes down to
I want to signal that I am better than
others. I have more money. I have better
taste. I'm a unique snowflake.
>> OO, WE HAVE A SPECIAL SNOWFLAKE. HEY,
THE SOCIAL MEDIA era has exacerbated
this, but it's always been this way in
office culture and guys on the golf
course and women at brunch, people
playing polo, whatever that ends up
being. There's the signalers that say,
"I have the bone business card." And so,
a luxury marketer is a master of human
nature. They know that these are the
feelings you have. They want to
expressly tell it to you, but they want
to signal it to you through the
experience. To help understand this, I'm
going to get into some examples. We're
going to talk about categories and we're
going to talk about brands. And the
first one I want to talk about is
caviar. Caviar is one of the most
powerful status symbols in existence,
and it really has nothing to do with how
it tastes. The sociologist Thorston
Develin coined a term you may have
heard, conspicuous consumption.
Conspicious consumption doesn't really
roll off the tongue, but this goes all
the way back to 1899. And it's the idea
that the wealthy don't buy things for
utility. They buy things to signal they
can afford to waste resources. Caviar is
peak bevel. It's expensive. It's
perishable, and it's an acquired taste
that most people fake enjoying. But
here's where it gets useful to
understand luxury marketing and the
luxury codes. The real flex isn't the
caviar itself. It's knowing the codes of
luxury. It's knowing caviar itself.
Knowing that you use a mother of pearl
spoon versus metal and Y. That you say
Cetra, not a Zitra. That you know
Petroian from Caviar Roose. You know
when these are appropriate. This is what
all luxury brands understand
intuitively. The product is an entry
fee. But without the actual knowledge of
it, you don't belong. So by bringing you
along in the process, by educating you,
by giving you tears to grow up, they're
selling you being an insider. But why I
like to bring up caviar is because after
basically a century of like old money
white tablecloth energy for caviar this
is kind of ending now it's a caviar
bumps at Coachella. McDonald's is
literally doing a caviar chicken nuggets
for Valentine's Day this year. And this
is really the champagne playbook. Moette
figured out that you could position
champagne as a lifestyle. You could
spray it in the club, pair it with fried
chicken. They made it a flex instead of
a formality. And Caviar is running the
same arc. Old luxury is about
gatekeeping. New luxury is about
accessible exclusivity. You democratize
access. It's really available. People
understand fun ways they can consume it.
It makes sense for social media and for
splurge experiences. But you create
tears of connoisseurship. Okay, you
tried it, but do you understand it? Oh,
if you want to understand it, you need
to buy this thing. Go to this place.
Begin to work your way up. Now you can
talk about it. It basically becomes a
video game of taste. If you've watched
my luxury videos before, I talk about a
pillar of luxury that's time. That's
what makes caviar really interesting and
the biggest advantage old luxury has
against new luxury. Because even at the
insane prices that caviar has, the
economics of it are actually brutal. A
beluga sturgeon takes like 20 years to
mature. 20 years of feeding, housing,
and hoping that a fish doesn't die
before you see a single dollar from
caviar. Time is a luxury ingredient.
When Branella Coochinelli talks about
Kashmir that takes 3 years to produce,
when Hermes has a 2-year Birkin weight
list, bourbon brands talking about like
23 year aging, they're selling patience
in an impatient world and your access to
that. And so a way to think about this
for brands is what are those levels of
connoisseurship? How can you bring
people along the educational experience?
How can you make them feel like an
insider? That's part of that luxury
psychology. There's a membership club
called Caviar Caspa that's like known as
a very like douchy establishment. That's
what they did is they basically said,
"We are going to give you access, teach
you about this, be able to flex that in
front of your friends. You're a member
to this club and we're going to base the
entire thing around the essence of
Caviar." And then anyone who has that
membership or who goes there a few times
all of a sudden has the ability to
navigate those circles. Now, I want to
pivot to our second luxury subject,
which is building aesthetic worlds. And
for this, I want to use a metaphor of
the white couch. How the white couch is
presented. And it's funny. If you have
kids or pets and you have a white couch,
or if you bought the restoration cloud
couch, a very popular white couch, you
know how hard it is to maintain and not
have that couch be dirty, destroyed,
worried about things getting spilled on
it. The idea of a white couch to adults
is really the idea of control. That your
life is controlled enough that you have
the luxury that you can have that live
within it. Your kids are well behaved.
The pets aren't on it. The staff will
clean it. And so this extremely clean
aesthetic that people like Axel Vervort
made very popular. He's one of the
architects there where you'd have like
three sculptures in a white couch in a
room. He did the Gen 3 Kanye condo. It's
that like monk minimalist but ultra
wealthy. All of that is about signaling
control that you don't have a chaotic
environment. Of course not. You're too
rich to have that. And it's interesting
because that was an aesthetic that was
extremely popular, right? All of the
2000s to signal a certain type of
luxury. But really now we've seen that
change significantly. Now when I look at
the new luxury brands, look at people
like Matteo stores like Merc and France
or Toast. Flamingo Estates an example I
love to bring up. They're positioning it
as basically rumpled sheets, right?
Every Techla photo has that minimalism
but it feels lived in. And it's
basically saying that having an
interesting life is a bigger flex than
having control. I don't need to have
control because I'm doing things. I have
the stack of books. It's a shift from
controlling your environment, having the
taste of your environment. I think
that's really interesting. And the
Flamingo estate one I bring up, they
they have kits. They have recurring kits
that you can buy of like the curated
pics from Japan, etc. But a lot of it
comes down to like gardening or cooking.
It assumes you have time to spend on
those hobbies. That's a new assumption
of luxury. It's the time you can spend
working on things is the ability to have
hobbies. It's a tasteful life. It's
objects curated from your trips around
the world that show what you do. It's a
livedin comfort. And this is all
positioning, right? When you think about
marketing, you have to think about what
is the establishment? What do people
buy? Now, I talked about this in my Bad
Bunny video where a lot of the Regga
tone artists were basically positioning
themselves to look and feel like rap
music. But that's not what's going to
break through to pop. What was going to
break through to pop was something more
exciting, more interesting, a
counterposition to that, which we saw
with Bad Bunny. And then quickly in the
surrounding world of Rosalia and Carol
G, it was an artdirected more
interesting experience that felt very
different. But it's the same thing in
luxury where if everyone's buying the
sterile, how do you appeal to an
audience has the same amount of money
but that life doesn't appeal to them and
create products for that? That's about
looking at the aesthetic worlds, where
can you fit into and what can you
position? How do you show that visually?
Another example I love to bring up is if
you uh live in LA, you know Olivier,
there's a bunch of knockoffs now. That
was the first one I heard of. I don't if
they were the first one, but basically
they bring over all these planters,
massive gourds, interior objects. They
have like olive trees for sale.
Basically, they have all these like
weathered European, Spanish, and French
looking like ancient things to put your
plants in or to have scattered around
your house. Now, all these knockoffs
spun up. But when you look at the real
provenence of these things, they're not
actually from the south of France,
right? They're from Indonesia. They're
like troughs for animals, planters from
being basically mass-roduced in Asia to
look like the kind of thing that you
would have in Europe. And I'm not saying
every one of these brands has that.
Maybe some hunt down those with
Providence, but even olive trees. You're
buying an olive tree in California. It's
probably grown in California or Georgia.
They're not importing a 400-year-old
tree from Spain to sell you. And it's
looking at those categories where you
want the look. You want to get the
aesthetic world of luxury, but people
don't necessarily need the providence.
Does anyone care if that planter was
really from the south of France versus
being an Indonesia horse trough? There's
a massive arbitrage by being in the
middle of the $4,000 would cost you to
be on first dibs versus the $2,000 you
can charge a California housewife. But
speaking of planners, that brings me
into the third category I want to talk
about here. Abundance and the fantasy of
abundance. You'll see fruit as a common
motif in luxury. Lee is perhaps it's the
best example of this where everything is
a tomato and not just a tomato, a fancy
heirloom looking tomato. And you'll see
this you go into certain hotels if
you're in the so house you go into a man
there's a bowl of fruit right it's
ambiguous is anyone actually going to
eat it like unlikely this is where that
abundance aspect comes in says hey it
doesn't matter we may have this really
expensive fruit if we get to eat it and
experience it before it goes bad if we
don't doesn't matter we have the ability
to waste it and it's the same thing with
gardening right estate has a tomato wash
tomato hand soap tomato everything it's
basically selling you the fantasy that
you have the time to be gardening in the
hills and making your own essence of
tomato soap, but you don't. You buy it
from Flamingo Estate. You're interested
in those subjects. Maybe you participate
a little in them, but you don't have the
full luxury and they bottle it and sell
it to you. The luxury is buying into
that. When I was in London with Air, we
did our series there. We visited a store
called Milwaukee. It's a Japanese
gardening store, and you could tell for
a lot of the people that go there,
they're purchasing expensive things,
really well-made shears, but they're
also purchasing classes, how to do X
thing or Y thing. For them, the luxury
is the pursuit of that. that in their
lives in the city of London, they're
able to actually go spend some time
gardening. That's an interesting one to
think about for a lot of brands.
Everyone feels like they have to sell
product and you can, but also helping
level up those levels of
connoisseurship. Being able to buy a
class from Milwaukee, being able to
participate in the gardening experience
for these brands, understand the
cashmere is a fistal stream in itself. I
think a lot of brands don't embrace as
much as they should. And you'll look at
all the luxury that's spent on these
experiences. is the $20 airwan
strawberry. All the fancy Japanese
fruits, we can go get a $200 melon. This
is all of that psychology of abundance
that while I'm on this earth, I want to
have this thing. I have the money where
a $200 fruit doesn't matter to me or a
$20 onetime strawberry was that good.
That's a mentality that marketers have
to tap into. And I want you to
understand how much of this is marketing
and what people actually buy from. So,
I'm going to go into the particle data
here real quick. One I love to actually
bring up is Monontlair. So you've seen
the Monontlair Genius campaigns, their
collaborations. They will have a
collection with Asop Rocky. They'll have
a collection with Donald Glover. They'll
have a Rick Owens collection, etc. But
all of it is just marketing to sell the
core coats. And what do I mean when I
say that? So here I'm looking at their
sales over time this last 90 days. Look
at their top selling product. It's what
do you expect? It's winter jackets. I
can go look at the details of these top
selling products. It is literally all
winter down jackets, right? Their core
product. But they do all this marketing
with these crazy campaigns. like how
much do those actually sell? And they
put the the titles in there of the
collaborator. So, I'm searching for the
Donald Glover collection, which seemed
like an odd fit at the time. All right.
So, I can look at the volume online.
They've sold 12 of this here. Four four
two 10 t-shirts, four pairs of these
shoes. You go down the list, there's
there's two items that have broken into
double digits. 10 and 12. It is purely
marketing, right? Let's look at ASAP.
ASAP Rocky collection. Even 10 of this
of the hero item. 722215.
This is during like the big holiday
season, too, right? These are marketing
items. Yes, they have stores. They sell
more overall. I'm sure they're not
making three of a thing, but it shows
you the world that we're operating in
here. A world where all these little
product choices are just marketing for
the core thing. And then the categories
that people are big in are ones you
might not expect. So, for instance, I go
to the Brunello store. I'm assuming lots
of suits. Okay. Top selling product,
blazer. Let's go to last month. Top
selling product is a blazer. 171 of
these $4,000 blazers. Nitrun. The shoes
are the third $1,100 and the fifth. A
lot more people are buying into that
entry level point into the brand. The
$1,100 sneaker. It's interesting if that
is the bestselling by volume. So, it's
always worth it to kind of look and
sanity check what people in these niches
are doing and what they actually sell
versus what they market. So, all this is
inside Particle I look at this ecom
sales data. I can get breakdowns by
product types. Color distribution.
They're an interesting one cuz brown is
one of their top colors. Not usually a
brand's top colors are black. Brown and
blue. Black goes down here. here. They
don't have a lot of black options. Price
distribution, you'll still see percent
of product price. Most people are buying
in that sub368. Then percent of revenue
is giving you that $1,000 range. The
sneakers we talked about. That's what's
sneakily driving a huge chunk of the
business. You can gain a lot of
information just by browsing these
pages. It brings up their marketing
assets, things like their homepage
changes, emails, they sent two a month,
give you some of that breakdown. It's a
really useful tool for doing competitive
research in your niche. And I will link
them below here. The last luxury topic I
want to talk about is curation. And it's
interesting because we've been
introduced to all these luxury products.
Now, we know more about luxury than
ever. But that used to happen through
gatekeepers and a lot of it happened
through hotels. You would go to a hotel,
you're in a luxury environment. You
would see the hand soaps or the shampoos
you're using and you would like them and
that's introduction to a product. And
those brands sell those things to their
customers at very low cost cuz it's
basically a marketing tool. The
wholesale take on that is extremely low.
But it's a signaler for the hotel to
have a luxury thing in there. It's a
signaler for the brand and entry point
for people to be in it. And the hotel
often resells that same thing and makes
money as well. But this was also the
introduction of certain types of pillows
of fret sheets built their brand off
hotel placement linens the mini bar. A
lot of this was an opportunity and you'd
see things like people buy hotel quality
sheets even though hotel quality sheets
are very different from what a normal
person needs because they're thinner
because they're washed every day. They
need to be able to stand at that test of
time versus be comfortable and be washed
once a week. So there's differences in
that experience. But the hotel's kind of
lost that right? If you go to a hotel
now and they have Malin and gets like
you already have opinions about Malin
and gets because of the internet and
we're all very familiar with it and you
know it's like okay, right? That signals
something different to you. They're not
educating you necessarily and certainly
not from a position of credibility. We
no longer have that concierge
experience. You're not going to a place
and asking the hotel concierge a bunch
of information about what you should do
or where you should go. And if you are,
you're getting like default kids
activities. You're discovering that
stuff through curation on the internet
through Tik Tockers and Instagrammers
and YouTubes who are breaking down
fragrances, who are breaking down soaps,
who are breaking down taste and styling
and locations. And so this curation
element has shifted from these
gatekeepers and the ability for luxury
brands to kind of participate in an
existing infrastructure to this thing
that happens online but feels it's like
a degree removed, right? It's not in
front of you. It's not tactile. You have
to choose to buy something before you
test it. That's a really interesting
place to be, right? Because I feel like
for a lot of people, especially
creators, stuff like that, they
encourage you to start your own brand,
right? Oh, you should go start your own
soap brand. But in reality, what a lot
of people are better at is essentially
operating a store. And there are a lot
of really cool stores that survive off
curation. We were at Good Hood in London
has an incredible curation. London has a
a rash of these. March and Copenhagen,
Murtha and Paris, Canoe in Portland.
They don't manufacture much. If
anything, they have taste. And I think
that's where this next interesting layer
goes is for a lot of people, the brand
may not be the answer for you. brand is
to get some inventory and to sell that
curation both on the internet and in
real life. I think that's where a lot of
that creator generation are going to be
better off building a business inside of
it is leveraging their concepts and
ideas and thoughts of luxury to sell
many things versus developing their own
because that requires a really hard
skill set. But why I call that out is
because that's changing right that
ability to participate in knowledge to
learn from it to be able to put that out
there has been completely democratized
by the internet that's a very different
scenario than we ever engaged with in
luxury before. I like you to think about
that in niches, right? So, one of my
co-workers is also a creator and she
does a horse girl content. She has
partial ownership of a horse. She rides
it. She go to these tax shops. She goes
to Paris and goes to different horse
items. Really cool content angle. But
there's a whole participatory ecosystem
of people that want to learn about that
kind of thing, of people that want to
buy those kind of products. There's a
luxury consumer waiting at the end of
it. And we together went to a place
called Manhattan Selery in New York,
which is like the only horse shop there.
and being there and seeing that they
have like a thriving business in
Manhattan selling something very niche,
it's kind of eye openening as to what
all those niches look like from the
gardening store in London to the horse
store in New York and what participation
and ownership of that looks like when
we're always sold this dream you want to
have an ecom brand instead. So as we
think about the psychology of luxury
dynamic I think is interesting to be
aware of. So anyway, I hope this was
interesting. You learned a bit about the
psychology of why people buy in luxury.
I am doing a community call at the end
of February. There's going to be a link
to that down here below if you want to
hop on. We're going to do Q&A. We're
going to workshop a bunch about social
media, branding, luxury, as we always
do. You can find more info about
Particle below as well. And thank y'all
so much for watching this video.