These are the six ways that brands can
go viral, the definitive list. Marketing
teams are inundated with requests, why
can't we get more views? And if you're a
brand owner or creative, at some point
you're going to push that button on the
internet that brings mass attention.
[music]
This is the definitive list to actually
do it from someone who has gone viral
countless times myself with my own
content, even more times with brands,
and then coached now thousands of people
in cut 30 how to do it. You're going to
pick one of these six ways or you're
going to fail.
Emotional, damn
But this list exists and this framework
exists cuz I am always in this scenario.
Why can't our content do a million
views? How can we go viral with no
budget? Does our social team suck? And
we are laser-focused on short-form video
here, TikTok and Instagram, the networks
with the biggest impact for this. We're
going to walk through all six, I'm going
to identify what's best for new brands
versus existing brands, budget versus no
budget. We've got examples for
everything and you will walk away not
just knowing how to do it, but knowing
how to talk to your boss or your team
about how to do it to actually get it
done. I designed this video to forward
to your boss the next time they ask you
you're going to go viral, you will have
an answer and it will be by choosing one
of these six things. Let's lock in. We
are going to start with the easiest,
humor. Skits, jokes, pranks, memes. This
is the easiest method, is also one of
the cheapest method. You may need a
couple actors, you just need someone who
is funny. There are tools like
memelord.tech. We'll bring up memelord
here aggregate all of the best memes as
they happen. You can go through and just
look at what is trending or all the
classics and pull from them to how to
make them your own. You just need
someone who is clever enough to work
through the zeitgeist and there are lots
and lots and lots and lots of clever
people who do not know how to monetize
being clever. That's literally what
Twitter and Reddit is for, for those
people to dwell and you can hunt them
down and hire them. And there are lots
of way to do this. There's simple
similar like simple skits, simple
pranks, simple memes or there's more
complex ones. Clewley are now the kings
of this. You've probably heard of them
and their content. This has 894,000
likes and they're telling a
behind-the-scenes story of their company
that's a skit format about how Brandon
somehow got a girlfriend. Another brand
I'd love to call this out is the jewelry
brand Sernucci. They're doing back and
forth skits and they have skits of all
kinds, single person, multi-person.
There's a lot of male-female dynamics,
that's always a winner. But to succeed
in skits, you can do skits, jokes with
one person, you can do them with
multiples. The easiest ways to put up
big views if you have no budget, no
resources, but it is also the least
impact. You have got to do a lot of joke
videos to make up to get a fraction of
the views you get from more value-driven
content. So while it works, it takes a
lot of shots on goal to actually get it
and you need a lot of views to then move
into getting attention for your product.
But as you've heard me preach before,
content is a funnel. You need stuff at
the top that gets attention to even get
more people to bring it down. If you
don't have that attention at the top,
you are extremely limited in how much
you can succeed and so humor becomes one
of the easiest one. Now second is a
thoughtful, produced, episodic or
conceptual series. Series are ripping.
It does not even have to be on your main
account. So Opal did this on a secondary
account recently. Opal is a anti-screen
time device. They started a head of
creator on a secondary account, this
account Olivia Unplugged, starting from
nothing, I believe. 1 million views, 4.2
million views and is all promoting
download Opal. And so they, their
concept, I love to call this one out
because it is lo-fi. They hired a
creator. And a lot of times if you hire
creators I've hired creators all around
the world, you're getting things like
blocks of 20, 30 videos for 5K, 3K,
common monthly retainer to do content
like this. All the way up to people that
are really hitting doing it for 10 or
20. But a couple thousand dollars to be
putting those ideas out there and
validating them and say you're taking a
couple shots on goal on that, you have
the opportunity to find success. So what
made this work? This has a amazing value
to the user, helping with screen time
therapy, how to get your act together,
how to get your personality back, how to
become a smarter person. Tension is a
health crisis. They're providing value
content that ties to their ICP, people
that want to cut down on their screen
time. They're providing it for free.
This creator and the way she delivers it
in her whiteboard videos are going viral
and that leads then to apps. I call this
out as a great example of a low-budget
version of this and again didn't even do
it on the main Opal account. It's a
secondary account. Someone who's been
trying this recently, AllSaints, they
collabed with a influencer to do this.
So this influencer has been on the come
up recently. This hasn't gone nuts that
viral or anything, but it does a lot
better than what's on the AllSaints page
and they basically decided to do this
the gatekeeper series. They have
multiple of them where they're kind of
acting out these like crime familia
vintage series that are awesome. Okay,
this higher production involves an
influencer, but they're putting a
concept out there, a recurring concept.
But if you looked at the AllSaints
content before that, it was the same
exactly what you'd expect, like people
in outfits, lookbooks, like not exactly
a highly resonating. But everyone always
goes to look at examples and they'll be
like, "How could I possibly do this in
my niche? How does it work in in this or
that?" Also one of my favorites, Built.
They have a series called Roomies. This
is a fully produced episodic series, but
Built is literally the equivalent of a
bank, right? They are a rewards, points
and loyalty company that tons and tons
of people use. They have larger budgets
to work on stuff like this. What I like
about this is this is a drama between
people, between roommates. They
basically put a sitcom on the internet.
But again, if you were lower fi and you
had a group of friends or a group of
creators and you were doing this on
iPhone, you could probably execute it at
a fraction of the price and potentially
see similar results, especially if you
were allowed to push it, right? They can
only go so far as a corporate company.
But they did an amazing job creating a
series that's compelling enough to
watch. They built characters, they have
edits, they have writers and they built
a recurring series to go viral. So this
is one of the more involved ones, right?
So we had humor, one of the easier ones
or simpler ones down the line. This
involves you to have actual creatives,
people that can write, people that can
put it together. You will always hear
the old-school videographer crowd be
like, "These are going to cost hundreds
of thousands of dollars or millions of
dollars." Look at that Opal example,
there are tons of cheaper examples of
this, examples on iPhone. And you will
also find that there are just relentless
now, relentless amounts of people armed
with Sony [snorts] ZV-E10s and FX3s and
whatever it is. We're shooting for a
couple thousand bucks a day and getting
multiple episodes done. It's cheaper
than ever to create quality content.
It's about having the idea and that's
where most people will never hit with
this. If you're working on content
creation for yourself or your brand, I
have the perfect resource for you. My
friends at TikTok and HubSpot have
teamed up to launch a free creator
toolkit and I've partnered with them to
help break it down. Inside the creator
toolkit, they have a series of prompts
for ChatGPT or Claude to help you
develop and refine content ideas, then
an overview of how to stack ads on top
of your content to drive leads to your
program or your service and a complete
list of cheap tools and expert tips from
HubSpot's creator network to help you
with a tech stack that makes content
easy. My favorite part is the TikTok ads
breakdown. It shows you how to actually
market your content like a real business
versus just hope it goes viral. And
related, if you are a serious creator
and not using a CRM to organize and
manage, follow up with client
opportunities and brand deals, I
guarantee you are leaving money on the
table, but we'll get to that in a future
video. If you're looking to put real
process behind your content creation or
better structure your creator business,
you can get this toolkit for free at the
link in my description. And thank you so
much to HubSpot for sponsoring this
video. The next and definitely the most
exciting of this, the one that most
people watching this channel will follow
me on for creative direction, art
direction, this is the one that will
resonate most with you. And then we're
going to get into the cheapest, easiest
to execute one for everyone next. And
that is social-first, art-directed
campaigns. So what The Ordinary just did
is an amazing example and this is a
full-scale ad campaign. I'll show a
bunch of different examples. But instead
of doing some huge campaign shoot or
some video like it is for TV, they
created an ad for social media and it's
an amazing art-directed campaign.
Another example doing this is Rains.
Rains is the backpack company. They've
been doing this with games. They do a
lot of games like this is a version of
Stratego, but it required a shoot, a
studio. It was concepted, it was
art-directed. They do again a lot of
these where yeah, they're doing the the
Rains crossword, etc. So it requires
some production, but again this isn't a
crazy shoot. This is a designer to make
it. It's shot in a studio with hands.
This is not nuts to create. And if you
are a creative director, you can have
ideas like this. Another from Diesel,
just an amazing jib shot here. But look,
we're going to next year. One of the
themes next year for all content, I'm
just telling you right now, things are
going to get sexy, right? Victoria's
Secret traditional angels are back.
Diesel is dropping campaigns where
people are thigh-grabbing on top of the
city. Things are going to get hot,
right? You can do a lot on social media
with emotion, with things feeling like
buzzed, right? And so this this isn't
even the core Diesel campaign. This is
the director putting this out with
60,000 likes. But again, it is an
amazing jib shot in an amazing location
with two actors, actresses. But it's
just that it's a conceptual shot showing
off Diesel jeans. Another just truly
amazing conceptual one, Jacob & Co. with
the chameleon going over the Jacob & Co.
watches and switching colors. Honestly,
this is like pinnacle, might be the best
content of the year. But again, a
conceptual art-directed campaign.
Another Patrick Ta had this whole series
of The Menu when they released their new
products and all this food content that
went around it. So what does it mean?
What do I mean by social-first,
art-directed campaign? Social-first
means no people are involved that aren't
social killers. Your director, the
social media team, the approvers, the
heads of marketing, they know short
form. They know what is up. They're not
guessing. They really do this and
they're hiring people that do it and
letting them cook. No traditional
agencies. There's Saatchi isn't doing
any of these. None of these dated-ass,
useless, old-school marketers that
cannot make you move on the internet.
You hire new wave younger people that
know what they are doing on social
media. And then art-directed, real
campaigns, real budgets. Some of these
budgets are way higher than the other
ones, but you are putting real thought
and budget into doing something unique
visually. And then they are conceptual.
There's not just beauty here, doesn't
just look sick. There is an idea behind
each of these. The chameleon moving
through it or the the moment of having
that like West Side Story kiss over a
freeway, of the high concept of The
Ordinary and what we do to our bodies
and faces around the new age of skin
care. There's a concept to each of
these. And this is one of the biggest
ones when I talk to brands that they
don't realize. They'll try to do it
without a concept. Let's just make it
beautiful. And it's so much harder to do
it without an idea. You need the idea.
The idea is what makes the internet
tick. It's no longer an aesthetic vibe
internet. It is an idea internet. But
this one is for brands that have budgets
and have shoots and are repurposing that
to be more savvy on social. It is an
amazing time. More and more brands are
doing that. All the luxury brands are
doing it. Burberry is doing it.
Ferragamo is doing it. People are
realizing and waking up and realizing
you can still make really cool creative
stuff and doing it. So it's an amazing
time to act on that. I would get on that
now. All right, but now the moment
people have all been waiting for. What
is the most affordable way to go viral?
And that is expert content. An expert
personality on camera doing viral takes
or excellent explainers. So this is an
amazing example, ranking celebrity
plastic surgery. Ranking videos are huge
doing this. Where people in a normal
business like plastic surgery or
whatever are ranking the things in their
profession. So there's a Cut 30 grad
from our last session. It was a dentist
who did this. Who's literally ranking
tooth products. 1.6 million views. Had
never made a video before the 30 days of
Cut 30. So it's the start of their
account. And it's literally ranking
common dental items. And they're going
through things people choose to use and
explaining if they are good or bad. But
putting an expert on camera in an expert
environment and giving them a social
construct. Rankings and ratings as the
one that is hammering right now is a
sure fire win. We also had a baker that
succeeded and went equally as viral
doing the same thing. If you want to
dress it up, but those are very candid
and that's why I like them. You
literally put the person in their real
environment and have them actually
explain stuff within again the rankings,
the ratings, the versus format. That's
the key to virality there. But also just
nice explainers. So Craig Hill's done an
amazing job just explaining their
products in well thought out visual
videos that aren't expensive to produce.
I I was there actually. Clayton and I
went to the Craig Hill office,
interviewed their team, met their social
team. It's like a guy, right? They're
setting up these shoots. They're
concepting and writing a lot out in
advance, but they're not like
reinventing the wheels with cameras and
setups. They're just telling really good
stories and doing it in a satisfying
aesthetic way. Another one I like to
call is this is a a resale company. Like
vintage luxury. And they have a woman
who just gets on screen and tells better
edited stories about the key things
they're selling, about different Chanel
bags, what's happening in fashion. This
is not expensive content. There are
editors doing this kind of stuff for a
couple hundred bucks. You have talent
that's on camera. She's literally
sitting on like a block on a white
background and a decently nice camera.
And they're banging out a lot of these.
Any type of business that has something
to explain. Got an expert. I don't know
if she works here or they just hired
her. Does not matter. Awesome if it is
the doctor that runs your practice or
the dentist or the plastic surgeon or
the baker or the product formulator from
your makeup company, whatever. But you
can also hire somebody to do it. What
matters is you're telling interesting
compelling stories for your audiences.
Who cares? What's the background of this
bag? What should I do for my teeth? And
you would be surprised what people care
about. We had another Cut 30 grad who
did the same rankings and ratings for
roof siding. They were a roofing
company. People care about what they're
going to spend their money on. And you
would be surprised at how viral it will
go. The founder of this company is this
is a fiber company. And he is literally
in a hoodie explaining the top five
highest fiber fruits for his fiber
supplement or whatever it is he's
selling. This does not have to be high
production. It's the best cheapest way
to go viral. You use an expert to put on
camera. That expert is either you,
someone who works at the company, or
someone you hire to bring in. But
everyone has that expert floating
around. Another Cut 30 grad who did this
for her jewelry business and went silly
viral doing that, too. And moving on to
the next. Similar to the art directed
one, an easier take that requires less
concept is spectacle. I'll get to the
Gisou video in a moment. But spectacle
means just something that really stands
out on the feed. Like they're pulling a
Crocs that are made out of bread out of
the ar place of an oven and putting
butter on it. That's a spectacle video.
Rod is masters of spectacle. You saw
Rod. Rod would have big things all the
time. Big piece of their makeup, big
whatever. But then even with their
influencer kits, they send out this egg
that dissolves in water for the PR
packaging, right? So this isn't even
just for their content. This is on the
influencer's page. They are sending out
things that are made for spectacle. So
she can make an amazing video. It is
enabling that. They design the PR kit to
be able to do a video that you're going
to watch through cuz you're like, what
is going to come out the other end of
this? And so blowing things up is the
easiest win here. Just making big stuff.
Tons of people do it, but it still
works. Efficacy is dropping, but you can
still go viral from it. People are
animating that with AI a lot, right? And
you'll see AI scenarios. Hennessy went
viral with this. This is just a This is
just a Midjourney image. 29,000 likes
and no one complaining about AI.
Miniature things work really well.
Things that are food. You know, big
brands do this. Adidas has put a running
track in the middle of nowhere. It's
viral for this exact case. There's high
production and low production versions
of this. But the idea is spectacle. How
do you stop the feed with something
oversized, something that looks insane,
etc. And the pinnacle of this is this
content here from Gisou where they are
they're baking. They're doing it in this
amazing environment. There are a bunch
of celebrities here. They're doing
transition videos. They have this
incredible stuff. This is like a high
budget video. But again, spectacle and
it's generating them huge views. It's
completely understandable by anyone that
watches it. You have your spectacle
option. And then the last option that
you have there is influencer collab
post, paying to play. Which is not a bad
option for a lot of brands. If you
cannot figure out how to go viral, pay
an influencer to go viral for you. It
still needs a great idea, but this is
why influencer driven brands have a big
leg up because every time Hailey Bieber
posts for Rod, it's guaranteed to be a
smash. And for a lot of brands that
really understand their audience,
influencers understand their audience.
They know what they can do to engineer
that. But that's kind of the last option
you have. You can't figure it out
yourself. No one can agree on it. You
get the influencer to do it in a collab
format and really give them the tools to
execute that well. If you do not pick
one of these strategies, skits and
humor, episodic or conceptual series,
truly creative social first art directed
campaign, personality content,
spectacle, or influence. If you do not
do one of those six, you are not going
to go viral. There are lots of ways to
go viral as an individual or other ways
to go viral as a person through a random
faceless account. We're talking about
brands. How do you make brand content go
viral? So pick one of those and go after
it. Succeed in social, you need
frameworks. You got to be able to go to
your executive team and instead of being
like, how are we going to go viral? Be
like, hey, here's the six things we can
choose from. These are our six options.
How do we get more views? We can do one
of these six things. What are we going
to do? We got to take some shots on goal
for this. We got to go try 10 times to
go do this over the course of this next
couple months or this year or whatever.
But if we stick with this, this is how
people in our niche are going viral. So
we're going to pick one of these things.
We're actually going to commit to doing
it. We're going to do it enough times
that we can get better at it and good
enough at it that we have a shot to
really put views up. Which of these
you're going to do? Get shots on goal on
it and then keep revising. The two ways
to keep revising, the the crush to all
of this, the only analytics that matter,
thumb stop  hook rate. You can
see this on TikTok. You can see it on
Instagram. At 3 seconds in, how many
people are still watching? If you look
at that, your goal is to improve that.
Key, if you make content of any of these
that doesn't do well enough, how do you
improve that rate? And the second metric
is the share rate. Almost nothing else
matters. If you concentrate on those
two, any of these can win. Is it good
enough that people are sharing it with
other people because Instagram wants to
be a messaging app and not just a
content consumption app. And they weight
sharing extremely highly. And TikTok is
the exact same way. If you concentrate
on those two things, those two metrics,
we're taking another shot on goal. What
are we doing to get the hook rate
better? What are we doing to make it
more sendable between people? Those are
the two questions you ask every time you
iterate. You are going to get to a win.
And so I have this video. Send this
video to your boss. If you're a boss
watching this, this is dead serious. And
we have done this now successfully over
the course of hundreds of times. Anyone
can do this. I also have this in an
email format. I'm going to link down
below in the description. And I have a
short form video version of this. You
want to do the 60 second. But I mean, I
want to give you the tools to send to
the people that matter to make the jump
to get you the views. Before we end off,
before the end of November, we're going
to do another community call. We're
going to get together live on Zoom. This
one's going to be more of like a
creative refresh. Less of a training or
anything. Decompress a bit before Black
Friday. Go through some ideas and
brainstorm together. Had a ton of fun on
the last one. You want to get on the
list for that. It's fully free, purely
for vibes. I've linked that down here
below [music] as well. Thank you so much
for watching. I want to see your videos
go viral and I want to see you succeed.
So please take this to heart and act on
these. I will see you next week.