In this video, we are going to talk
about the creative direction of sports,
athletics, and the adjacent brands to
them. We're going to cover content,
creative strategy, merch design, and
traditional creative direction. And I
want to talk about this because I feel
it's important for creatives and
marketers to understand the niches where
content and creative strategy have the
most impact. Everyone talks about
creative direction for fashion, but in
terms of investment to result in content
and creative, fashion demier has the
lowest [music] impact. all of this work
to sell something that's going to get a
hundred of a drop or have 20% returns
for sizing. It's ultra competitive and
one of the lowest impact callings of
creative work. But you add sport on top
of it, it's a whole different thing. As
many of you know, in my work, I work in
beauty because it's the edge, the
highest result of content. Viral videos
spike Ulta and Sephora sales crazily. It
generates a higher fiscal return on
creative strategy than any other niche.
And the way they handle seating
influencer, it's the cutting edge with
the highest stakes. The next one down is
sports because you have teams, players,
the brands that clothe them and sponsor
them, the fitness industry at large. And
right now, this is particularly relevant
because of the massive amount of money
in sports. In particular, gambling
money. It's propping up all of the media
around it. The [music] ringer, bar
stool, ESPN, the player salaries, all
juiced by this massive sponsorship
ecosystem. And the stakes are really
high while the legality is there. and
while people are still used to being
taken advantage of. I think it's going
to be a cultural move away from this,
but it's turned as we are [music] at a
really pivotal point in the impact of
creative in the sports world. So, in
this video, we're going to cover
everything why you would invest in
content and creative strategy in sports
and fitness. Today, we're going to dive
into merchandise and in particular teams
that have turned around some of their
perception with merchandise and teams
that have hired creative directors and
why. We're going to go into content and
the role of content now in developing
personalities and shifting teams and a
lot that we can learn from it and how
often sports and athletic brands should
treat their content almost like a sports
team. We're talk about the future and
clipping and how big that plays into
sports. And we're going to talk about
brand positioning inside the space in
particular in sports and active wear
[music] and how that world's playing
out. It's going to be a fun ride. I'm
stoked you're here for it. Let's lock
in. So, first we're going to be talking
about two sides of the coin in the
sports and fitness world here. First is
the teams and players. themselves, the
actual executors of sport, soccer,
basketball, football, small leagues, big
leagues. And then we're going to talk
about the brands that interact with
them. So, the Nikes and Kappas that
sponsor jerseys to the Lululemons and
all the new brands have come out that
are just filling the world around
everything from running to basketball
because a lot of this overlaps extremely
closely. And the reason it's such a big
deal and it has such a big impact is the
money that's at play is crazy. So
notoriety for an athlete, basically how
well they're perceived on social media,
how well known they are, if they're
liked or loved, in addition to their
obvious skill level, is such a big deal
in terms of the millions of dollars
they're able to get on a contract one
way or the other by just that shift in
perception that it really matters. Same
thing we're seeing now with the transfer
portal in college sports in the US where
notoriety can change the amount of money
you make from a young age. Same thing
with attracting sponsors. Sometimes your
skill on or off the court matters only
as much as how your appeal is and what
else is going on around the scenes. You
are given a platform as an athlete and
then you take that over to teams. For
teams, especially in smaller markets, to
attract talent, the branding and
perception of the team is a big deal.
And so is the nurturing of fandom.
Getting your team excited, having them
stoked by the content, having them
believe in their team even when they're
not good enough that they get tickets is
a massive fiscal driver. Same thing with
the promotion of merch. And then the
values of the teams themselves, which
all sell at insane multiples that even a
minor shift in perception can lead to
changes that are in the tens of millions
of dollars. And to put some of this in
perspective, I want to talk about
Venetsia first. I'm talking about some
soccer teams. So this is a team in
Italy, not exactly known as the best
team, but known for its merchandise, for
its lookbooks, for its fandom. It became
the kind of team people support because
their stuff looks so sick. When we look
at the role of creative direction inside
of any of these circumstances, it comes
down to merchandise. What are people
selling outside of the core experience?
And does that have resonance? When you
look at evaluating if merchandise is
good or not, there is, is it sick enough
that people buy it? And is it sick
enough that when people buy it, it's out
in the world that it has ripple effects
that people go, they see it and they
say, I want that. Does it lead to more
posts that people have on social media?
Does it build an organic buzz? So,
there's the execution of merchandise
itself and then there's does it have
that extra factor? And what Vanetsia did
is really crush it with that X factor.
So much that people were looking forward
to their lookbooks. They set a new
standard for teams at their level and it
became a pretty significant revenue
driver. Enough so that other teams
looking to duplicate this. We saw the
same thing with KO, another kind of
small market Italian team doing the same
thing by trying to promote these drops,
build up almost like the streetear
version of the teams they have and
they're leaning on the legacy of the
places they are because by nature these
Italian teams and their histories and
the places they're from have that X
factor that you may not get if you are
promoting the Portland Timbers who've
also done a great job with their
branding. But it adds a world around the
brand that allows it to generate more
money, become a more attractive spot for
talent and change the trajectory of
teams might be having a hard time. Then
you take this to the highest level. So
Daniel Archon was a creative director of
the Cleveland Cavaliers in basketball
and he came in and was looking at the
entirety of what the team looks like
from the actual jerseys they wear on
court to what the merchandise is like to
what the posters are like outside of the
stadium trying to craft a combination of
their vision and his vision. And this is
what's interesting with someone like him
is if you come in and try to put
together a vision for a team itself and
you are not a person of kind of your own
creative direction identity, it's a lot
different than when you have one
himself. So Daniel Arsham very well
known for his let's call them decaying
sculptures. This kind of futuristic and
crystal style takes a little bit of what
he does, a little bit of his Arsham
studio flare, but takes a lot of the
calves. And this is an interesting
thing. When you have an identity, people
bring you in because of your identity.
You have to find where that line is
between, do I want it to be 80%
Cavaliers, 20% Daniel Arsham, 80% Daniel
Arsham. These are all crystal jerseys
now and 20% Cavaliers. Where is that
line? I think he did a pretty good job
at saying, look, I'm going to keep this
extremely Cavalierscentric and we're
going to add a design element on top of
all of this. But them hiring people like
him shows you where the future of this
is going, right? They want to have more
commercial appeal. They want to have
nicer stuff overall. They want to be
culturally relevant as a team. They want
the players to be excited about this.
And at every level of sports, you're
going to see this type of integration
you've seen from the soccer teams we
just talked about all the way up to the
top of the NBA. And this happens in
underground sports, too. So, as many of
you know, I used to work at the Surgeon.
And in the building that the Surgeon was
in when I worked there, they hosted this
thing called the league. Basically, a
basketball and a footsole league,
completely independent, completely
underground where they played inside of
this like invite only area. Had a lot of
celebrity attendance like Floyd
Mayweather was at some of the ones I was
at. Kyrie was there. Justin Bieber has a
team like a Skylark team that plays in
the league now. They've gotten a lot of
attention from that for people just kind
of executing amateur basketball at a
high level. It's very skilled, but they
have immaculate jerseys for everybody.
They're capturing the content. They have
this whole vibe and underground
experience. This is just one of many of
these things that are happening around
the world of people saying traditional
sport doesn't serve all the economies of
the world right now. And then people
want to either participate in or view
something more interesting and more
organic. And with that comes a lot more
freedom to design interesting things, to
sell offkilter merchandise, to provide
experiences outside of kind of the
normal sports infrastructure. And this
is where I want to encourage a lot of
creatives who want to get into this kind
of thing to cut your teeth locally.
Right? If you are designing the jerseys
for your high school alma mater, for a
local team, for your kids team, whatever
that looks like, all the way to these
kind of more underground leagues that
exist. You're beginning to put your foot
into these arenas. You can use as a tool
to promote your brand or to be able to
change the perspective with which you
engage with design. I think it's an
interesting opportunity and exercise to
think about and forces you to get out of
that internet comfort zone and actually
go talk to some real people and convince
them that your design will make a
difference. I want to shift over into
content and the important of content and
the biggest one I want to highlight
there is the Boston Celtics who have an
excellent social media presence and
team. So use sports highlights is a huge
industry but it's important because the
proliferation of sports highlights for
your team and your key players is going
to be directly indicative of how many
people actually tune in to a watch or go
purchase tickets. It is purely an
awareness of do I need to see this team
or not? And the Celtics did an amazing
job with these compilations. They would
automatically loop or people would be
actually like frozen on the screen while
others do things around them. They had
those social media tricks and enough
that they had to think it through
beforehand. They had to go in with a
concrete plan of what they were going to
capture, not just capture it and try to
edit after to say, "We're going to
generate these things that are really
well-b built for social media." They end
up sparking significantly more views
than a lot of the teams that are on
their same level because of the creative
team's execution. that then leads to
more hype for the Celtics, more
excitement for players who want to play
there, for the fans to want to go, and
awareness of their team. So, the types
of content that matter now in the sports
infrastructure are important because
there's a lot of teams of ownership of
media companies who still live in the
old very traditional world of this who
haven't embraced the full look and feel
of social media. That's when there's an
advantage for younger, savvier creators
to be able to dive into this and really
build a name or reputation for
themselves. And the playbook A is
releases. Whenever you have a
merchandise release or they're doing
home jerseys or whatever it is, building
campaigns around that where there's an
actual content roll out. You'll see this
with what Bonetsia did with their
lookbooks where they're saying, "Oh,
actually we have a whole new roll out
for this every time we have
merchandise." That would be just as
often seen on Hypebeast or High Snob as
it would just being emailed to fans
because of the quality. Then we have the
typical thing. We have the highlights.
What happens during the game? They are
posting this every time on every game,
every team. What can you do to creative
direct that? How can you make that piece
of footage more interesting, look
different, be special, travel farther?
And then there's aura in this world now
where if you go out and you look at
Jackson Dart, Aura edits, like a new
quarterback is basically being pieced
together to look as cool as possible
through a combination of highlights,
music, and personal clips is a trend of
thing that's happening on TikTok. That's
a huge impact in the sports world for
people to get excited about the players
they work with where someone does have a
particular vibe or particular look.
You're just as likely to have an Austin
Reeves or a real as a LeBron James one.
But highlights have turned into their
own social media machine that builds
fandom that a team and a brand need to
understand what that looks like. Because
if Kappa sponsors an athlete and is able
to then in introduce them into a system
where they pump them out into generating
aura online because the combination of
their actions and their editing and
their infrastructure, all of a sudden
the results of that sponsorship get a
lot more powerful. We'll talk about that
in brands in a section in a second. Then
we have this whole world now of kind of
alternative casts of people saying, "I
don't want to listen to people that are
on TV. I want to listen to our local
people or I want to watch something on
Twitch with funny people that I follow
as personalities. Kind of the rise of
the alternate cast. And I think it's
what we're seeing with brand social
online right now where everyone's doing
these social shows where they're doing
like episodic series. These teams have
media companies like that. They have a
lot of people following them around and
we're going to start seeing that too
where we're actually seeing playbyplays
from former players on that team or
they're breaking down the highlights in
a sports center style way, especially
with basketball where they're very
liberal with the use of that media. But
certainly in other sports where how can
you apply personalities especially known
personalities plus social media plus
this infrastructure people used to
consuming and take some of that for
yourself within the parameters of how
these agreements work with everybody.
And then we have the personality
nurturing because the team part is a
very important thing as well because if
you have a marquee player on your team
but they don't do social media or they
don't do it well. That's actually a
negative now versus what could happen if
they really built that fandom and how
many people will kind of come to the
games or want the merch or embrace the
team. And there's going to be a
responsibility somewhere a personality
nurturing this. My friend Jordan Rogers
talks about this a decent amount with
baseball where it's like, hey, if you
actually get the size of the prize for
sponsorships for life after baseball for
people that are able to build any level
of following or personality while
they're in it is a really important
thing not enough people are considering.
And that's where this goes beyond, oh,
if you're a creative, I'm going to go
get a job for a sports team. That's kind
of probably unlikely compared to could
you get on the extended team for an
athlete who has videographers and
creative directors on retainer, which
more and more of those people do and
more and more of them need to do and can
afford to actively do. and then see real
value from. There's a lot of perception
of building that around that's going to
be a big factor in the creative
industry. And where this gets really
important, where this all collides, and
one of the main reasons I made this
video is this is clipping. So, if you're
not familiar with clipping, this is when
people take clips of things online. They
are paid a reward from systems like
or Direct, etc. to perform, to put views
out there for a creator, a celebrity.
Druski is a known user of this, TJR.
People use it as a vehicle to sell
courses or build a reputation. brands
will do it to repurpose their content,
but also it really matters for sports.
Let me break that down. So, for
instance, let's talk about UFC. UFC is
probably the best, most interesting
example of this where ESPN has a huge
amount of social accounts. Clipping at
it most traditional is people just
taking highlights and putting them on
multiple accounts. So, ESPN has, I don't
know, probably 70 different accounts,
right, for different subsections and
genres and whatever. And they're putting
out clips constantly. They help promote
the things that they're doing. On top of
that, you have the entire ecosystem of
people that are not on official accounts
that are clipping and distributing
things. Let's look at just officially
UFC moving from that where UFC social
media is kind of mid and certainly not
of the caliber what ESPN has built
moving over to Peacock or sorry
Paramount who does not have the
infrastructure for this who are not
social media savvy do not have the
accounts. You're going to see a
significantly less of the storylines
around what's happening in the UFC and
not the biggest moments but all the
smaller moments. They're not going to
disseminate as far into culture. That's
a really important thing because if they
don't do something radical in terms of
are they employing a big clipping
infrastructure like what we've seen with
are they introducing their own
systems for it? Are they building new
social media accounts? This is not just
like oh this is a nice to have. This is
kind of life or death for if that deal
makes enough money to be worth it for
Paramount is how far that content is
going to go beyond what just gets
watched. And so we're going to see this
scenario where sports and teams and
people in the future are going to be
investing in how their content travels
on the internet knowing that there's
ripple effects and networks and teams
that work around this. And this
investment in that early and the
understanding of it, how it works is one
of those career opportunities where
people can get a lot of alpha. All
right. In this segment, we're going to
cover a particularly important topic for
all my brand owners and operators. How
to actually scale your brand when you're
doing well but don't have enough cash
for inventory. So every e-commerce and
physical wholesale brand goes through
this. You order inventory. You have 30
to 60 days of production. If you want to
make the most margin, you send it by
boat. That's another 45 days to get
actually there into the warehouse and in
took into the warehouse and online or to
whatever physical store. In the women's
wear brand I've worked with for years,
we got into multiple huge retailers. And
what you don't know up front is that
most of them pay like net 60 landed,
meaning it arrives at their warehouse.
So, if you pay your factory a deposit,
you're going to pay the rest of on
shipment or receipt and then still not
get the cash actually paid for back from
the retailer for months. Same thing with
an ecom business that's scaling for the
holiday or busy season and you want to
invest in ads if you don't have the
cash. There's tons of times when you
could be scaling more as a business and
you're stuck. So, there's several
services that offer cash in these
scenarios. And one that I recommend and
partner with for this video is Wayfier.
I actually recommended them last year to
my friend Spencer and his brand. and he
was approved for 25K. That really helped
him move faster by being able to get
more inventory and invest in ads cuz he
was bootstrapping it entirely as a
single person who was still working. So
what Wayfier does is offer flexible
financing based on your existing data
performance from sales, marketing, and
accounting from 5K all the way to 20
million for DTOC's for Amazon
businesses, wholesale, retailers, even
SAS and professional services. Now I'm
not hitting that, but they do that too.
Any of those people that want to scale
up marketing or inventory. And best of
all, it is tied to your business, not to
you. They do not require personal
guarantees on any of their products and
they've deployed 5 billion so far. And
importantly, you get all this with one
transparent fee, no hidden cost,
typically 5 to 10% of the advance, much
less than some of the platform
offerings, which are a little predatory.
And it's done over a time frame that
aligns with your business cycle. You
actually plan that out. And the real
cheat code is that they actually provide
funding decisions faster. You fill out
the info, they give offers in minutes,
and then funding in 24 to 48 hours. So,
if you want to fund inventory and
marketing without giving up equity,
check out Wayflyier at the link below.
And don't wait until the last minute
before your busy season. Know what your
options are. And thank you so much to
Wayflyier for partnering on this video.
I want to tie that into brands and this
idea of brands as teams. So if you're a
sports team, you need to think through
all the things we had before. You have
your merchandise. You have your core
product of actually attending the games.
You have your team. You have all the
people that are on it and how are they
represented? How you nurturing their
personalities? The Buffalo Bills did an
amazing job on TikTok of showing so much
of their team and skits and action and
bringing that out there. A lot of uh
teams should model after. and you have
the other, the supporting staff, the
video crew, the coaches, the other
people, again, alternate casters,
personalities that travel it around. If
you're a brand in fitness, you should be
looking at it much the same way. And how
are you promoting all those things? And
and a brand I thought has done an
interesting job of this is Bandit. I'm
not going to talk too much about them. I
know they're very talked about on the
internet. I've done interviews with them
over on channel, but they'll say
something like, "Oh, we're going to the
Olympics and we're sponsoring the team
from like the Grenardines. We're
building our personalities into these
sponsorships. We're doing these releases
alongside the major events." They'll
have a release for the Chicago Marathon
or the store. They're timing events the
same way you'd look at a sports team
having their big games. They're bringing
on athletes into their storytelling.
They're enabling the consumer in the
same way. They're building it so because
it's kind of hard to get into their run
clubs and some of and some of the stuff
is exclusive. You feel like you're on
the Bandit extended team when you wear
the clothing. It's a really interesting
play of this. But the one I really want
to call out that I think is far ahead of
the game who I think a lot of these
bigger companies should be really
looking at modeling their new generation
after is uh this brand called Ladder. So
Ladder is a fitness app that has
workouts with coaches you can do. But
they have lots of coaches. I don't know
30 plus coaches that work for them. And
each of those coaches has a social media
presence that promotes themselves and
promotes Ladder and they function like a
team. They do collab reals with each
other. They're on the main account.
They're there together. Plus they have
all their solo promotions. You add that
up and you got 30 accounts pushing a
message or a new launch or the app in
general and creating content that
constantly interacts. You're building an
algorithmic web that is extremely
effective. And on add on top of that
that they have a creative director is
doing a constant flow of campaigns. They
have a a big [snorts] Twitter campaign
every January. They're throwing out
conceptualbased content on main
featuring their collaborators, featuring
people in culture. So it feels like
you're in this big kind of entertainment
athlete web and that is their marketing
presence is media that moves alongside
of that the ads that go on top of that
to the people that are already reached.
That's a really savvy way to approach it
and an interesting way to think about
it. If you are an ath athletic brand
like who do you sponsor? What kind of
content are they making? Are they making
content with the other people you
sponsor? How does it interact with your
main account? Are they in the campaigns?
And then how does it center around the
major events that happen within your
niche? If you have a brand in combat
sports, how are your releases and
sponsorships tying into the overall
calendar of attention that happens in
that world? Is the savvy way to think
about athletic wear and sports and
marketing now? And I'm going to end here
with this conversation on brand
positioning because it's really
important and a huge opportunity for a
lot of the entrepreneurial people
watching this and also great for
consumers. So, let me explain. So, we
have all these traditional companies
Nike that's just getting their market
share eaten, right? We have Lululemon,
activewear who Lululemon's falling
apart, right? not giving the customer
what they wanted even after they kind of
built this surge. And we have a more
educated consumer than ever. And so what
do I mean by that? People are aware that
you shouldn't go run and work out in
full polyester head to toe. It's
probably not the most amazing for you as
someone concerned about your health. And
brands that won't adapt to it. You can't
right now go on Lulu or Nike site and
find almost anything that is not
polyester or rayon or a combination of
those things. And you have brands are
being built by positioning against that.
It's this combination of positioned
against how you take something that is
ubiquitous that people dislike and say
my brand stands for something else. When
you see that dissonance between what
people want and what's available for
them and what big brands are willing to
do, they're not changing fast enough.
That is alpha that small operating
e-commerce brands can take advantage of.
And brands are doing this. So right now,
if you don't want to purchase heavy
polyester clothing, there's brands that
positioned in that niche. You have Riker
Clothing, you have Wavewear, you have
Soul Department, Mate the Label, Maro
for socks. There's a whole bunch of
these brands that have said, "We're
going to build in that space." And so,
as a consumer, this is great because
this is what you want. You have small
brands you get to support independently
who are doing that. For those brands,
they now have the opportunity to scale
almost as large as where those other
brands could be if they really want to
put the foot on the gas by using these
modern techniques we just talked about.
If those brands offering those things,
all of a sudden, we're embracing the
nextgen of athletes, the NIL people,
people they can get for a cheaper price,
might have outsized results, putting
together savvy campaigns around it,
giving the consumer what they want.
Brands can skyrocket out of nowhere. And
the same thing for brands that want to
revitalize themselves. We look at Umbro
basically coming back over the last few
years. It was really came down to
creative direction choices they made
inside of product and merchandising and
the execution of some of the contests
they did and collaboration and whatnot.
They actually brought it back into the
forefront. And I believe they had the CD
of Slam Jam involved in that. And this
goes for male and for female too because
Riker is just as popular as someone like
Fair Indigo doing cotton leggings,
right? Where you have this across any
spectrum. You have a tailor to any
sport. The ability and positioning to
say we sell shorts for athletics versus
we sell shorts specific to distance
runners immediately niches you down to
be able to have a better message for a
specific consumer. That's an important
positioning thing to understand. You
start with the core. How do you position
against it? Whether your core positioned
against how do you niche you can better
talk to one audience and expand to a
second audience the way District Vision
started with running and then went into
biking. It's worth thinking through like
positioning of how both you consume and
what you'll be creating for a brand. And
so on that note, if you are looking to
get into stuff like this, I'm going to
put uh we used to have a paid report on
merchandising that I made with Clayton
uh maybe two years ago that I'm
basically just putting out for free now
that if you want to grab down below. You
can get a free download for that that
has all the factories and people that we
encourage for like brand merchandising,
people we've used and vetted of
different kinds. Again, it's a year or
two old now. You should be able to have
tons of stuff in there for how to
develop stuff like that for a place
where you work or a place where you're
at. And I'm hopefully it got you excited
about this new state of like sports and
athletics and where creative roles live
inside of it. So, by the time this comes
out, I'll likely already be done with
tour. So, I'm going to not be promoting
that here. But, if you'all liked this
topic, I'm going to do a deep dive in uh
any of these or any of these brands. I'm
thinking about doing like an art
direction video like I've done before
specifically about like an active brand
maybe on but I'm not certain yet. So,
let me know if you have any input on
that below. I appreciate y'all so much
for watching.