In this video, we are going to talk
about the creative direction playbook
for brands. And we're going to do this
through the lens of how food has been
used in recent branding. We'll talk
about food and grocery is a status
symbol. Create a playbook for how brands
can develop and use visual themes. Talk
about brand association, object
curation, and all the fun parts of
creator direction that should really
spark you up in terms of what the
potential is for building your brand
world. And for examples, I'm going to go
all the way over to Korea to this cafe
Nudake. Hope I don't butcher that
pronunciation. That is owned by the
gentle monster sunglass brand just to
get off of your current algorithm and
show you something completely different
in that world. And then we're going to
go through road skin because I think
their playbook is one that every
branding person and creative should
understand even if it's outside of your
normal wheelhouse. I've done videos
about things like Stuy in the past.
We've got a future lineup of these
include stuff like Rick Owens, things
you'd expect me to do. But this one I
want to do because it highlights how
this creative direction playbook can
apply in just a different industry than
you may have considered. And we'll touch
on Jacqu Moose, Flamingo Estate, and
many more who use food as part of their
creative direction approach. And it's
just a fun lens you'll look at things
through. If you've been looking to
expand your art direction or creative
direction toolkit practically, this is
the video. Let's lock in. So first I
want to talk about food as a status
symbol. So you'll notice that something
unique happens just in the world as we
go through time and we see things happen
on the internet is that things happening
in culture permeate into visuals. And so
right now there's a lot of conversation
around the cost of food around what
luxury is about the changing perception
in nature and make America healthy again
and everything that we've considered
about what a healthy life looks like. At
the same time, things like air, a very
upscale grocery store, has taken over
pop culture and some of the cultural
conversation ties very well into this
conversation we have about road skin
later who actually have an airwan
smoothie. But a lot of it comes down to
this idea of everyday luxury of people
saying instead of buying Louis Vuitton
bags or lusting after these really
expensive things, instead we take our
luxuries every day that purchasing the
$40 jar of honey or getting the rare
strawberry or picking out some light
smaller luxury like a food item. But
then having that experience be so good
and look so good you get that double
reward of the taste and the visual
experience is something that brands have
noticed and played into. I'm scrolling
through a lot of examples here and
they've made fun and unique. Uh you'll
see here some examples from Gohar World
who make like food accessories. They use
the presentation of the food as part of
the storytelling and world building of
what they do with their brand and their
accessories. But you'll notice in
particular that food is a motif inside
of women's brands. you see all the time
whether it's brands like Road or fashion
brands who are putting this combination
of things whether it's a flavor or a
look association the way it is with road
or just part of a lifestyle that they're
trying to sell like you see with Gohar
World to a more organic feel like with
Flamingo Estate probably the most unisex
brand on the list here all the way to
Jacqu Moose presenting this kind of cute
beautiful chic life through the lens of
destinations and food and this brings me
over to my millote board about road and
about food in art direction in general.
So, I discussed a lot of things in that
last section. They're actually really
important to dive a bit into. Brands
don't just create imagery. Neither do
creators. You have to have these ideas
and themes that tie things together to
make it cohesive for a brand. And they
have to be in line with your consumer's
perceptions and the insights that they
need. So, good art direction starts with
an insight. Starts with something that a
consumer wants that roots into the
visuals and things that you make.
There's a lot of ways to approach this.
There is a tactical way that a consumer
has a problem and you're showing them
how to solve it. There's an aspirational
version where you're showing them a
lifestyle that they want to have.
There's almost a subliminal association
like you might see here where you look
at this and you have that sensation of
hunger or pleasure that you associate
with food being associated with this
imagery. Same thing with a sensation.
The way this image may make you feel
cold or may take you out of the
dimension that you're in while you're
scrolling your phone and place you
someplace else. And there's all kinds of
other tools. There's fear, whatever it
is that actually gets you thinking about
whatever the brand wants you to go in
its imagery and in its messaging. But in
this video, I'm going to look very
practically at a couple key topics that
form your brand playbook. The first is
objects. What do you use and how do you
present it that associates with your
product that fills out the scene? So,
it's not just your packaging in a photo.
And Road is an excellent example of this
where extremely rarely do you see their
products. And you do see them, but
they'll mostly be together. But usually
they are presented in context of
associated objects. And they do this to
as a creative direction technique to
help build their brand world. As you see
here, these are presented all with food.
And then by the same regard, you have
people. And how are people integrated
into your creative direction and art
direction story? And in roads example,
they do a lot of like night out. So for
instance, we zoom in here. They did this
is from an email campaign they did where
they're having they're showing a model's
night out and what she's wearing. She's
wearing this lip shape. She's you doing
X and Y, but it's a bunch of photos of
her actual night and the product
naturally integrated while she has her
matching martini versus just a picture
of the product. It's kind of the basics
of world building. Get the objects
associated with your brand. Then you get
the people associated with your brand.
And we'll dive into this in the whole
like the deep dive road walk we're going
to do shortly. And then you got to think
about how you want your product to be
shown when it is shown. There's objects
that represent your brand, their use and
styling of it. But then there's just
other ways your product's going to need
lots of different applications for
different shots, different ads, and
probably more than one use case you do
for that. And road has several. So if
you even just think at that core topic,
there's many more here, but what are the
objects represent representing? What are
the people that represent your brand?
Then how do you show your product when
you do show it? Those are three things
that when put together give you the
foundation of some creative direction
for your brand. If you make decisions
around those and they make sense
together, they can begin to be the
foundation of a world. But then you have
to think about where this is actually
going to go. So whenever I'm looking at
a brand, I go pop over into their
foreplay account. Um, so this is where
it actually shows you all the ads
they're running. So I can scroll through
every road ad. It gives me an idea of
what they are doing to sell their
product, how they use those motifs
inside the sales process. Like this, one
of the most popular creative direction
techniques you see all the time is
scale, making something really big.
They're running that in ads. They're not
just using it as a social tool. It's
something that they're using as a tool
that helps stand out campaigns they run
ads on as well. You'll see they're
running tons of creative. They're using
people as the face of their brand using
some of the same creative direction. But
we'll go through foreplay and see what
ads they are running because creative
direction is application to ads. It
obviously has application to social and
just looking at social media and then
has application to brand items like
website and email. And so for instance,
this is the email that I had talked
about earlier where there is creative
direction applied to it's not just buy
my thing, it's here on sale or here's
this new thing. Instead, it's late
nights with this model and road here's
the product in context. Here's what she
was wearing inside of her look and the
ability to then shop that look. is their
email content. That is the difference
between like a standard sales email and
a creative directed email. The sales
conversion on this email versus a more
standard email may even be the same.
Maybe it's higher, maybe it's a little
lower. But the idea of building that
brand association and that world and
applying some creative direction to it
is what separates just a product from a
true brand. And so you have to think
about where is it in ads, where is it in
email, and then what's happening for
things like physical mailers, what's
happening at events that you go to, and
what's happening with your actual
product. And how does it tie into it?
All of those together kind of create the
basics of a creative direction world.
And so to take us somewhere outside of
our normal algorithm, I'm sure many of
you have seen RO before, but one of my
biggest things I like to talk about for
creatives is getting above their normal
algorithm. Getting to places where you
don't know where it's going to be taken.
You're not seeing the same ideas as
everybody else. And so I have been
spending an awful lot of time in uh
K-pop social media and Korean social
media looking at their packaging
presentation, their art direction, and
the things that are popular there. And
so I want to talk about this restaurant
which is the child of gentle monster the
sunglass brand. They are also owners of
this and they have created like a visca
viral destination restaurant where if
you look at not just how the food the
product was prepared they said we're not
going to make a carrot cake. We're going
to make a carrot cake that looks like
this. We're not going to make a
croissant. We're make a croissant that
looks like this. But then you get to the
actual stores themselves. For instance
this one which has these massive
croissant themed tables and breakdowns.
the statues, this world they are
creating around their cafe. This one,
which you've probably seen on social
media, I know I've posted a few times
where it's all this kind of
weightlifting but all made out of bread.
It has become a destination, looks more
AI than real that they are using to
build their cafe world. That's why I
wanted to do this video where I talk
about cosmetics brands and I talk about
like a bakery because creative direction
goes beyond street wear. People often
ask like what does that job look like in
some of these other places? I guess this
is an example of a creative directed
cafe from the interior and the quality
of the interior to the motifs you see
spread across the product and the
marketing. They are making intentional
choices that say when we do our
investment into our interior design or
into our furniture if we make a creative
directed choice. We can reap the
benefits of that. The benefits being
that it is a destination where people
want to go to purely because of the
aesthetics of it before you even get
into the fact that the food is great.
And so with that note, you'll notice
that kind of perfect merger of product
of mystery and they're integrating this
well. I don't know what this fog product
is. I would order it. Micro croissants
like tiny croissants. They are making
things with virality in mind with that
creative direction lens on everything
that they are doing. That's a
combination of that culinary skill set,
the creative direction skill set, and
the aesthetic skill set. And then
they're executing all of this with
campaigns. So how I stumbled upon this
is I was looking at K-pop art direction.
This is part of one of their collabs
with uh the K-pop artist Jenny. And you
begin to see the tool, that same tool of
scale we talked about before,
presentation, the use of color, the
objects associated with the campaign,
how they present the fact that there are
art directed campaigns and collabs with
stars on their website, like as a
bakery, and the different aesthetic
choices they use inside of their world
building, using holiday cards for their
New Year's collab, like everything
having some of these kind of cutesy and
celebratory through lines. They're using
that miniature scale in the same way you
see Road use the large scale. I love
finding and going through these from
brands that are unexpected so you can
begin to find and look at that toolkit
in a completely different way. And it's
interesting when people talk about the
cost of creative direction and putting
creative direction into life. And I
would argue that like this is the
highest end of that, right? They they
have already taken this into like years
and multiple occasions worth of
completion. But it is just as
fascinating to think about it as what if
you started with one thing. What if you
said we were going to optimize our
product? We're going to use the product
toolkit that they have here and we are
going to make miniature versions of
popular things. We are going to showcase
that in a really artfully like
photographed way before we even get into
campaigns and interiors begins you means
your brand is taking one step of
intention like towards a more
interesting world. Going back to road
I'm going to summarize their toolkit. So
I've got a millote board here and
Millote is the sponsor of this video.
Big shout out to them. I use them all
the time because it it works the way
that I think. So as a visual thinker
when I'm doing things like market
research I will put competitive stuff
together for this. This is actually for
an exercise I'm working on a project now
where I've broken down a number of these
brands and how they approach different
art direction techniques like what their
creative direction toolkit is. And I
will go and I'll literally I will pull
in a bunch of images and I can also pull
in links and embeds. Like for instance,
this is an Instagram real embed that I
can play and watch right on camera or
right on screen. I will pull a bunch of
these by category into a document. Now
I'll make some of my notes over here.
For inance, these are the notes I'm
going to go through in the video of the
five categories that are related to it.
I have a little mini board for each that
versus just a mood boarding app where I
get everything in one place. I can
actually have my notes here. I can have
some of the embeds. I can structure it
where I can say, "Hey, cool. Here's the
all the section around scale. I have all
that in this this segment. All right.
Here's the stuff around people going
out. That's in this segment. I've got
videos inside of it." But Millote helps
me work the way I think as a creative.
In addition to having all those
embeddible types, I can also create
little subboards. Like I have a subboard
here we're going to talk about for
Flamingo State where I'm able to
actually put in all the different kind
of images and gathering. And I will run
everything out of these from my planning
for collections and campaigns all the
way to market research and competitive
research doing like this to how I think
about art direction. Anyway, Milanote is
a great tool for organizing your
creative projects. I'm using it to
organize all of my art direction work
right now. If you're not sure where to
begin, Millanote offers over a 100
built-in templates to get you started on
almost any kind of creative work. And it
is available for free with no signup
limit. You can get it at the link that I
have both in the comments and the
description of this video. So, big shout
out to them for sponsoring. I always
love it when it's a tool that I actually
use all the time. I can literally just
show you the workflow throughout the
entire video. Let's get back to it. So,
I break down Road's career direction
toolkit into five things. Use of food,
use of scale, sensory application, this
idea of like models night out or like
models lifestyle, a simple surreal
little bucket in there. And the last
thing I'll note they also have is
there's a whole segment on on celebrity
which we'll get to. So what I mean by
that? So food like we talked about
earlier in almost every campaign they
are doing in everything there is a food
association with it. It is merely as
simple as placing the product on food.
They do it extremely basically for the
majority of this. It is on white or
black. The food is extremely artful in
how it is portrayed. That matters almost
as much as anything from the
heart-shaped French toast to the
artfulness of the strawberry or the size
of this ice cube. Those are intentional
decisions. But also you'll note that
they experiment with this as well. And
this is where I like to talk about the
overlap of creative ideas. We'll get
there in one second. So you'll see some
other applications that they have of the
same food idea inside of basically every
campaign, every product they're doing
has its food connections. Then they also
have this idea of what I call models
night out that whether it is Haley the
founder or people that are on their
influencer team, they're always
showcasing people actually doing things.
And so for instance, it was like
ordering room service. This is an
influencer they have and it's got the
shot and there's actually it's just it's
all the makeup to this is the
combination of the look that they had,
the food that they were having and the
display at their event. They are showing
all those things in there together. And
since those worlds are kind of far apart
between that food here and the the world
over there, you'll see they bring it
together with some of the shots that
they do where you begin to bridge the
gap between those two like inside the
art direction. So I feel like a good
creative directed brand takes some of
these motifs and allows them to kind of
work in between each other and that
impact of food creeping over into the
more lifestyle content like in the same
way uh I think is really well done. And
second I want to talk about sensory when
the product is not shown with food which
is relatively rare. It is shown in some
kind of environment that makes you feel
something. This is an amazing tool in
the creative director's toolkit. I
talked about this in my art direction
video with the fridge exercise. But if
you see this in ice or in snow it makes
you feel cold. Same thing in hot, same
thing feeling wet. That is something
that separates an image from just being
a standard image of a product and can
get people to stop scrolling, which is
the ultimate goal of the majority of
these ads and copy. Then we have the
idea of scale and making everything big.
This is again a popular one for brands.
People will talk about how this is
probably overdone. I think basically if
it works, keep doing it. I think the
idea of making something really big or
making something really small like we
saw with that cafe is just an easy thing
almost any brand can execute on and have
some fun with in their shoots and they
have done all the time. What I think
about their toolkit this isn't you know
these aren't extremely out there amazing
creative ideas. They are basic ideas
executed excellently. A reminder you
have to overthink some amazingly deep
creative strategy. Same thing with the
product shots when they do show just
product without some of that same
context. They all have this like lightly
surreal nature to it in terms of like
those don't actually stand like this.
What's happening in this corner? The way
these are kind of drifting or flying,
the fact that these are on the clothes
pins, even their basic shots, all just
have a little bit of intention. I call
it simple surreal. But I also want to
call out the celebrity face. So Haley is
obviously the founder of this and she is
all over their ads and content. And if
you are an influencer brand, even a
small one or a celebrity brand, you
should be using that. When you go to my
valuables page, I am all over it. Not
the only model. probably want to be the
only person telling the story, but a lot
of brands feel like they need to step
back from some of those founders and
integrators. And guess what? If it
works, keep that as front and center as
you can. And so how this plays into the
other things they do, like putting the
juice boxes as an item that they have
inside their events or using the scale
and the packaging as a design for an
interior. But this is basically a
creative direction toolkit visually for
a brand. And what I would encourage you
to do if you're looking for how do you
build that world yourself are just to
break this into a couple key things you
can use as a playbook. What objects do
you associate with your brand? So for
instance, you say I want to do food, but
I want to do luxury objects or I want to
do machines, cars, whatever it is. What
are the objects you associate with your
brand? And then there's the people and
what are the people doing? It's like who
are the folks? Is it always models? Is
it always everyday people? Are they
certain racial makeup or age makeup? But
then what are they doing? Cuz they're
almost always having a night out inside
the road. They are going into a
lifestyle of a road girl. You need to
think about what that lifestyle looks
like for your people. That's an exercise
in itself and then showcase that. Then
when you do product shots, what do you
do for product shots and not have them
be standard? Is there a technique or a
look you can do that makes it stand out
in any way, shape or form? Yeah, we
always do concrete product shots, but we
have animals on them or whatever it is.
What is one thing that makes it stand
out? And then think about application.
How do you actually show that inside
your website, your email, your events?
So, I like this uh models night out
example perfectly because they said,
"Hey, we are going to do this. We're
going to put on social media, but also
we're integrating it into our email."
And maybe that's vignettes on some sort
of landing page. Same thing on that that
site that we saw for the bakery. They
have a whole section there. We're
displaying our creative direction not
just in campaigns on social, but it has
a whole website place where it lives
where we don't expect you to go to our
website and order a cake you can't have,
but you can go there and lose yourself
in the art direction of the brand for a
bit. It's basically a portfolio as much
as anything else. But that's where your
job is is to be like with these things
we create, where are they actually
going? Where is it useful? And the
answer is never just organic social. It
needs to be social plus ads plus website
plus email plus events. where do we able
to bring our toolkit inside of? But if
you just go through that basic exercise,
the objects we associate with, the
people we associate with, and then how
do we show our product, you're basically
building a foundation of thinking more
about creative direction for your brand.
And if you want to go one level deeper,
I think about how do they overlap? Like
how do how my people show and that
object motif? How do they relate? In the
same way that you see them combine food
and into this, you know, the displays of
what the models are eating or maybe the
product is on a tray and room service,
they're combining their two ideas. How
do you do that same thing? Right? And
I'm going to pop into a subboard here
and I want to show Flamingo Estate as
the last example I'll walk through here
cuz they're another brand that has used
the association with food extremely
well. And so their background, if you
know Flamingo Estate, they're a very
popular LA brand that has everything
from like candles to body wash to like
boutique honeys and things like that.
But they started as a vegetable delivery
service and they have these vegetable
themed like tomato themed or scented or
included washes, things like that. and
they include that in the art direction
heavily and they're always incorporating
basically sculptural fruit is what I
would call or sculptural vegetables
sculptural garden even better inside
their product art direction. All their
products are rarely shot just product.
They're shot in this context with
extremely healthy and organic looking
tomatoes. Second thing, when they do
shoot their other product, you see tons
of these shots of them surrounded by the
greenery of the garden. They're putting
the garden in context in their product
shots. Another tool they have in the
toolkit. They take this to the next
level with some of these kind of like
display shots and more artful
applications. But again, always centered
on the food itself, even if they are
selling like a honey, etc. And the last
thing which I didn't dive into on rogues
doesn't have it. But another thing that
really helps set a brand that you know
applied to that bakery and applies here
is location. So flamingo estate, part of
what has given it its resonance is
there's this amazing location that is
the home of the brand has a lot of
storytelling. It's this beautiful 1970s
estate in LA. Not all of us have the
ability to have a state in LA, but your
even your little creative studio space,
your house you run your business out of,
your smaller cafe, your cafes in Korea
with croissant themed weights, whatever
it is, is that story in the brand. And
what I like about Flamingo Estate and
what they've done with their creative
direction is the estate itself is a
character in the brand. This is the
debut of a rug collaboration that's
happening inside a room in the estate.
To see the brand process happen, is a
part of the lore. It's another thing
that's inside that toolkit. We'll
probably do a whole locationbased
creative direction video later on, but
that's where we are here. So, anyway, if
these are new concepts to you, I do have
a video, art direction 101, that will
start really breaking down the basics of
what this looks like. This is getting a
little more integrated into it. Pop that
video at the end. But I love talking
about these visual worlds of brands and
think about the steps that smaller
brands can take and creative directors
and aspiring creative directors can take
to begin building those worlds around
whatever you're working on. So hopefully
this was a both a glimpse at what
something amazing looks like in a few
different industries, but also some
practical steps and how you can think
about it yourself. If there's any
categories or any brands you'd love to
see me dive into, I know someone asked
for Palace the last time. I did think
about having them in in a video
recently. I know I've got I've got Rick
coming up and we just did Stuy recently.
Please let me know in the comments and I
will definitely consider it. This is
always kind of a work in progress. I
usually base these on things I'm working
on dayto-day in my day job actually
doing some of this work. But I'm always
open to ideas. Love to dive down the
rabbit hole. Anyway, I appreciate y'all
watching and getting into this with me
and thank you so much.
[Music]