This is the art direction of spectacle,
a playbook on the creative direction of
Demna and the incredible and bizarre
visual world of Balenciaga. For better
or for worse,
>> you are Balenciaga, Harry.
>> We're going to cover characters and
archetypes and why creatives should use
archetypes as a methodology to think and
create with. We're going to go through
motifs for a brand and Balenciaga's
codes. We're going to talk about product
as marketing and actually break down
some of Balenciaga's sales numbers and
their wild products. and then
distributions. Balantiaga uses a
three-pronged approach to attention that
you might not expect. And then get some
pure aesthetic insanity by running
through some of my favorite runway sets.
My last art direction video is about a
low-budget, high concept helping new
brands take off. This is a pure
explanation of a creative
direction-driven brand with essentially
unlimited resources. What worlds did
they choose to make? What can we learn
along the way? But this is going to be
probably the most fascinating one of
these hard direction videos I've ever
done just because of how out there
strategy and looks are. Let's lock in.
So, I'm headed to New York literally in
the morning, but I wanted to get this
into editing ASAP because Demna just
released his first character study for
Gucci. This is his debut with the brand.
Not a full collection that comes next
year. I' had a Balenciaga vid outlined
for a while, but seemed like the right
time to strike. But speaking of
spectacle in New York, I am speaking
with Shingy, the CEO of the Atlantic and
the editor of It's Neistat and somehow
Taylor Loren's all at the air age of
Aquarius conference and air who many of
you know that I work with ongoing
YouTube series and a few other things
are essentially the boniaga of
enterprise digital asset management. I
bring that up because there's a lot you
can learn from any industry about using
a playbook like this. It's not purely
something for high fashion. You can use
it to think as a creative, as a software
company, as a service, as an agency. All
of these concepts can translate if you
just break them down to their essence.
So, let's start with the character
study. So, this is the Gucci first look
where Dena, who while many think of him
purely for his Balenciaga work and more
avantgard stuff, I actually think is a
excellent purveyor of the idea, look,
and feel of glamour. He runs through a
series of the Gucci customer. Each of
their archetypes leading off with some
trademark luggage, but each of them
presented in a frame with a title. And
what's interesting about this, what I
want everyone to think about is if
you've spent any time working in
marketing, you know this concept of an
archetype. You're going to make up a
persona for your target customer and you
are going to come up with selling points
that appeal to that customer. It's an
exercise you do constantly because, for
instance, let's take a creatine gummy.
If you're selling that to a 19-year-old
kid who's trying to get ripped versus a
woman who just went through menopause,
who's trying to maintain memory and get
other physical benefits along the way,
they have very different lives, consume
very differently online, take very
different messages for the same product.
It's just a good example of what an
archetype is. But good brands are
constantly thinking in terms of their
archetype. I use a piece of software
called outer signal. No relationship to
them in this video. Actually goes
through customers for all the brands I
work with and literally builds
archetypes and shows me here's the
people you have. Here's are they
influencers or not? Do they skew this
demographic or that demographic and you
create names for them and you refer to
them inside your marketing teams as your
various archetypes. You're selling to a
Susan or a Bob or a Carl or in this case
for Gucci a party boy laba number two
laba influencer. But in their creative
direction, they've taken this very
common concept of knowing and
understanding your customer and building
things for them and then designing for
them in the case of a fashion brand and
turned that into the art direction. And
this is always an interesting choice
because one of the things that character
studies do inside fashion has potential
to show yourself in the person. We look
at pictures of models and clothes to see
what they would look like on us. Now,
often times we aren't presented from a
physical standpoint because they are
tall, skinny, and beautiful, or in
Balenciaga's case, often very strange
looking. So, it's hard to tell how the
clothes would actually fit on you. But
if you abstract that out, you start to
look at the type of person that you are,
the confidence you exude, the archetype
that you've become that's beyond simply
what you look like, but the world and
persona you inhabit. One that we refer
to all the time in the creative work I
do is the Norman. The Norman is one of
those new generations of guys. Wears a
lot of simple one or two color graphic
TE's, very Manny Mat like 70scoded
mustache, flat bill hat, has like a
remote job, wears some work wear. That's
an archetype we refer to all the time,
but also one that when you make products
for that person that look like that
person, they see themselves in and buy.
So, Demna with Katherine Opie, who shot
these photos, is setting the stage for
what he wants that character to look
like for Gucci. He's telling people from
the start in my presentation, here is
what I picture our customer to look
like, and here is how I would dress
them. I think this is just an amazing
interesting way to begin that
conversation. But it's also worth noting
that he ended the Balenciaga
conversation in the same way. So if you
look at one of the last things he did
there was this exactitudes. He's picking
from 35 different collections to do a
bit of a homecoming in his own words
kind of reflecting on Balenciaga's
combination of high luxury spectacle
street wear and forming those characters
which look significantly different than
the Gucci characters. Right? I think
that's a way to create a strong
separation is here was this chapter.
Here's who we were designing for. We
were pushing this limit. The person that
sees themselves in these clothes or sees
themselves in these looks is far more
out of the box likely far more
individualistic thinking and looking for
different things than the Gucci
customers that we presented. But he is
showing his strategy of I do character
studies inside the context of the brand
that he is leaving and then showing that
vision for the brand that he is
entering. But this has been a recurring
motif and so he collaborated on date and
vision. It's a summer campaign that they
released. This is with Nadia Lee Cohen,
another kind of noted portraitist for
lack of a better term. her style, the
way that she shoots this, her own unique
lighting, medium format film. They took
the same idea presented in another
visual motif in these like classic
Hollywood film tests again with people
of all ages, sizes, races. There's no
discrimination inside of a Balenciaga
campaign. These are all being looked at
as cinematic archetypes. They're
basically playing into the stereotypes
you would expect to see in these
scenarios and presenting them in a
Balenciaga driven way. A character study
is a core and something to think about
for any of your designs and decisions.
Who is that customer? How can you
present them? How can you mirror them?
And then potentially how can you make
them art and your lookbooks? We often
think in terms of how do we create an
aspiration. It's interesting to see it
abstracted down so much into a title
labeled picture telling you if this is
who you are, this is for you. Balenciaga
has a handful of motifs that we've
really seen over the few years. Four in
particular. The first being the
elemental world. It's not what you think
of when you think of Balenciaga, but
then you start to look at their sets.
Models walking through mud, things set
in a blizzard. Most of their seasons
pick a hostile environment and then
dress into it. In a previous video, I
talked about Lee and Lee always putting
nature inside of their content. You
almost always see the model outside or
in greenery or then surrounded by the
extension of that fruit, vegetables. At
Balenciaga, it's the extremities, the
hostility of nature, but nature
nonetheless presented within its art
direction. And the next motif is this
meta media. This idea that there's a
whole another world operating right
around Bonsiaga's world. is one of
absurdity and reality that we live in.
Collaborations with the Simpsons and
Fortnite, political campaign shirts,
paparazzi, the line between video game
and real, just like the line between is
this clothing actually something that
exists in the real world or do we just
see it on screen? And this goes right
next to the apocalypse chic models and
looks you'd expect to see in Fallout all
the way to actually having full sets
that resemble a destroyed world. And
then last, this idea of anonymity, aura,
this concept of identity. You see so
many things like face shields or the
person completely covered with the
clothing or the tape so that they're not
discernible even if they're a celebrity.
Padded sets that make you feel like
someone else. But all of these giving
this like immense magnetic energy to
whoever is wearing it where that
anonymity or that costume makes them
larger than life. Those four motifs and
codes really define the Balenciaga brand
more so than any of the spectacle or
other things we see. It comes back to
these deeply entrenched art direction
roots. And a way to think about it
that's kind of useful for any brand is
there's how does it interact with nature
in space the way they do with these
hostile environments. How does the brand
then interact with the world around it?
Balenciaga chooses to interact with the
Simpsons characters with video games
versus the actual reality of the day.
And then what is the brand's vision for
the future? Some brands present utopian
or a future where everyone's beautiful
or future where we're more reconnected
to the earth and sustainability or
luxury and they are painting a very grim
picture of what do things look like in a
cyberpunk world and then what story is
being told to your customer. Balenciaga
is giving them the story that the
garment turns them into a character that
is larger than life so much so that they
may not even matter. But this is
supported by spectacle. We've talked
about character study. We've talked
about motifs. I want to talk about
product as marketing because they are
arguably one of the originators of this
at scale. Many, many brands have copied
this. It's an effective strategy, but
they also use it to really make money.
I'm going to use some particle data. And
again, this is purely just using the
data. They're not a sponsor of this
video to kind of show you that sales
breakdown before we dive into
distribution and the sets. One of the
most notorious, their IKEA bag knockoff.
It's literally the IKEA bag, but for
$2,145.
This is a conversation piece. There a
lot of these bags being sold right
alongside the destroyed Paris sneaker.
They said, "Hey, people are distressing
things. You're making looking unworn in.
We're going to make them unwearable."
This graphic doesn't actually even do
how destroyed these are in real life
justice. Here we go. This is a better
one. $1,850.
Headlines everywhere. But then we have
the Trip Sneaker. A staple for them that
sold a ton of units. These were
everywhere. Tons of colorways. And it's
hard to describe inside these photo how
absurdly large they actually are on
foot. They are like unwarably large.
Even these photos make them seem smaller
than they are. But the clownishly large
shoes actually sold really well. We're
going to get that data here in a second.
Then led to more and more generations of
these because you began to associate any
absurd oversized shoe with Balenciaga.
And the more of those were making
attention in headlines, the more of
these slightly smaller but obviously
Balenciaga ones they actually sold.
These tire ones were incredible as well.
This is just online. 24.8 million in the
last 30 days. This isn't a sponsored
post. I can say particle is like
directionally correct. Let's give it 85
to 95% accuracy, right? It's not
perfect, but it really tells you in the
ballpark what's actually happening with
the brand. And you'll see the track
sneaker for 1150, 543 this month,
600,000. Serious seller for them. Let's
go look at this year is actually their
best seller for the year. So the track
sneaker, 4,800 units, 5.4 million just
on those. And there's a bunch more.
Other tracker is the runner gradient.
The trip S like we just mentioned,
multiple trip S's here in the in the
thousands of units. Big old shoes. The
3XL is a massive shoe. 1,800 units. They
are clearing big shoe units. What you
don't see on top of here, the IKEA
knockoff bag. Also, what you do see,
Rodeo bag, city bag. All of this is
attention to sell true luxury handbags,
actual luxury brand stuff. Are they
selling a lot of sneakers along the way?
Sure. But what they are not selling a
lot of is things like the trash pouch
bag, a literal large drawstring purse
for $17.90. These draw attention. People
draw the hourglasses. This is one of
DNA's real hits that they have. And
these things like the Balenciaga bag
with a single arm bridge the gap where
people will buy this to be their flex
piece to be their insane I'm going to
get all these Tik Tok D views 3.7
million likes and still have high
fashion on the other side of it and be
in in the middle of the two. That is
what a lot of this is built for for this
attention level era. And even with the
collabs Fortnite Crocs Airwan these are
attention grabbers. The Crocs collabs
might sell. Crocs are generally
generally popular but it's bizarre for a
high fashion brand to be collaborating
with a injection molded plastic sneaker.
It's bizarre for a high fashion brand to
collab with a grocery store in LA no
matter how high the prices are to making
skins and emotes like in Fortnite. Every
one of those is an attention-driven
decision. They have a few types of
attention. They have prepared attention.
They have unexpected attention.
Attention for its own sake and attention
to the moments that they really want you
to pay attention to. But overall, above
everything is this constant non-stop
chatter of Balenciaga. continual voices
always in the zeitgeist because of how
crazy a thing they did was or how great
the production of something was executed
or a celebrity they played into the hand
of they have a three-prong distribution
strategy. It's a little bit different
than you might actually think. So first
is the kind of runway and installation
infrastructure. They take the actual
physical presence of shows of the Paris
Fashion Week of the World extremely
seriously. They make true art inside of
it. It is spectacle. It is shared. It is
you have to see the Balenciaga show more
so than any other show. It's not even
very arguable that when it comes to true
cultural crossover, what is the imagery
or the things that might actually remind
people that these fashion wings exist? A
lot of it comes down to Balenciaga. The
mud show being a perfect example of this
where it transcended culture in a way
that any more reserved fashion brand
simply couldn't. Not saying that they
deserve to or not, but those brands can
stand out every once in a while with a
great concept or a beautiful collection
or amazing piece or thought or insight.
Balenciaga does it again and again. But
they combine this with this idea of
publicity as performance with anything
that might be paparazzi ready a fit to
the mech gala Cardi B Kim Kardashian all
these folks that have come out decked
out in their clothing as an event that
they're wearing something Balenciaga on
the far more couture end of Nicole
Kidman doing that and then doing
vignettes on their YouTube. They take
this really produced attention and they
counteract it with what seems like
almost paparazzi level attention, but
it's them utilizing the vehicles of
social media and of the celebrity and
the people that want the attention of
the costumes they provide to get this
second level of more chaotic
distribution that feels more organic
even when it's contrived. But the third
level, the one I I generally find most
interesting is that they are also
hammering creative volume. So inside
foreplay here, they are running
thousands of ads. We have the full CGI
unexpected. We have the new fragrance
and we just have tons of imagery and
videos, relentless retargeting. So, they
are doing the trap media right alongside
this. Their meta-p is up there with the
best of them. They run tons and tons of
ads. If you are in their funnel, you are
in it relentlessly. There's variance.
They're good little character studies
and vignettes, but they're running
through the entire ad playbook in every
way, shape, and form in massive volume
from catalog ads to campaigns to
collaborations to showcases of all
different kinds. Like as I scroll
through this, every one of these is a
variant to call out specifically to
Demnum. They're not messing around on
the actual meta ad. And a lot of people
would assume that that wouldn't be a
cornerstone of the strategy, but it most
certainly is. Then we go into the set
pieces. Probably my favorite. Again,
this is something done with so much
budget and care. It's hard for us to do
more than kind of stare at.
This is one where they actually flooded
the runway. Skies on fire. The models
are walking through water. pure level of
of spectacle. And going back to that
motif that I mentioned earlier, then
they had one where guests walked like a
fake red carpet to then watch a film of
the Simpsons going down the red carpet.
But then the fake red carpet ended up
actually having was being streamed.
People were actually debuting Balenciaga
fits on it and the performance art was
it actually was the runway was what
everyone was participating in.
Not going to lie, not a big Simpsons
guy, so I'm not going to make my way
through that.
>> You had touch it, swine. Perhaps my
favorite this clones runway where they
actually sent a model down again and
again. There was the same model using
photoggramometry and tricks but
basically one person walking the whole
show. Going back to their identity
basically becomes the garment and these
ideas we talked about in the brand
character study and costume in general.
The blizzard and actually putting the
models through in snow. The entire
collection is debuted like this. again
back to that motif carrying the trash
bag as one does to of course probably
the most talked about from having Kanye
West inside partially not can get into
that or probably most importantly the
viral woman trudging through the mud
that led the show when they have a
moment available to them they seize it
but as we end this out what can we learn
this is an interesting one to think
about a few years ago Balenciaga went
too far they put out some weird
unacceptable I had several
Balenciaga pieces as did my wife and we
either sold them or gave them away I was
kind of expecting that that was going to
be a new phase of the brand and things
were not going to go well. But guess
what? It wasn't. Absolutely nothing
changed. No one stopped buying or they
were replaced by others that did. People
were too sunk in their investments into
those luxury pieces to give them up, too
tied into their identities. And I don't
really have a lesson there or a good
answer or theme that comes of it.
Something I have actually thought about
relatively often. But I say that to say,
don't feel bad for one second ripping
any of these ideas from their playbook
or strategies or dupes or whatever it is
because they deserve it. And on that
note, let's talk about some of their
playbook for creatives. This idea of a
character study is a super interesting
one. What would your perspective be as a
designer, as a brand owner on that?
Actually, making this video made me
think a lot about that for myself and
some of the things I work on where we
use models all the time. But I haven't
really thought about the archetype they
represent or how we really showcase our
consumer in that same light versus kind
of telling more model driven stories
because that's what you do in a
lookbook. Then this idea of product as
marketing in today's era, like what is
that one piece in every collection
that's designed to get actual attention.
I've been harping on this now for years
in inside Instagram videos. I can't be
stated highly enough. that is now a core
part of a lot of the marketing and gives
you a real interesting chance to tell
some stories or take some shots and
guess what they might actually sell or
might start a trend that does something
for the brand and people always worry
that they're going to be defined by that
one item that one time. Well, if you
consistently do interesting things and
you're going to be defined by the body
of interesting work that you do and this
idea of distribution moments. Are there
other things you can hijack the way that
they grab red carpets? Are there other
fame hungry people inside your niche or
whatever it looks like that you can
leverage with the things you are doing
or support? And when you do have
moments, conferences, sets, etc. is
worth maybe going three times the extra
mile, making that a known thing for you.
Is that tension level? The media that
comes from that and the presence worth
it. But overall, less tactical than some
of the other videos I've put together,
cuz again, this is more spectacle than
anything. It's more interesting to look
at, more thoughtprovoking, and the brand
has layers beyond just buy this $1,500
trash bag. I hope it made you think a
bit about archetypes, about brand codes,
about motifs, what it means. So, a quick
heads up, I'm doing a new creative ops
guide with Air. We put one out a year
ago. basically workflows for creatives
who are doing social strategy, creative
strategy, operations in general. We're
releasing another big report here coming
soon. I'm going link down the landing
page below if you want to get that when
it comes out. It will be free. Anyone
working in the creative space who's
trying to navigate technology,
workflows, etc. We work really hard on
these and they're pretty special pieces
of work. Let me know what other brands
you think I should be diving into. I'm
actually thinking of doing one on some
personalities next. I have a few more
themes. Got one on quiet luxury uh in
the works I'll have some fun with. But
all is to be determined. If you have any
any ideas or anything you'd want to see
me do, please comment those down below.
And as always, thank you so much for
watching.
[Music]