In this video, we are going to talk
about the rebrand that pushed Bad Bunny
to the next level, but really we're
going to talk about creative
relationships and the creative direction
of personalities. It's timely as we are
about to see Bad Bunny in the Super Bowl
and there is a cultural conversation
around him like never before. But also,
this is something I've been looking a
lot at personally as someone who has
gone from a normal person to a internet
personality. And I've been noticing more
and more kinships to what actually
happens with musicians as we've gone on
tour, [music] begun thinking about our
content in releases, had to think more
about art direction beyond just the
content being made online. And with
that, in Southern California Life, my
friends are musicians. They're on
reality shows, and more and more we're
talking about how they can creative
direct their career. And over the course
of the last 2 years of sharing all the
creative and marketing things I know,
I've been hit up by countless artists
and had a quandry I'm sure a lot of
other creatives deal with. Should I be
solving for them or for me? which vision
makes the most sense. So today we're
going to talk about counterpositioning.
We're going to talk about the power of
art direction inside developing a
personality in the music industry. We're
going to talk about creative
relationships and the role of having
someone by your side as a personality or
the role of being a creative in someone
else's world. We're going to talk about
vision extension and how to create a
movement that's larger than life.
Creative bravery in the modern era and
authentic unapologetic cultural
authenticity and how staying true to
yourself is helping people go more pop
than ever. It's a bit different than any
other video I've done that still have
those same through lines of tactical
creative advice you can apply to your
career. Whether you are a personality
yourself or whether you are on the
creative side, we will have plenty of
Bad Bunny's incredible [music] graphics
inside this video. Let's lock in. But
first, I want to talk about positioning.
I've used this term before in marketing.
Basically, how your brand stands against
the others that are in the market
already that are established. Now, when
you walk into a store, this is easy to
think about. If you're launching a mac
and cheese brand, you're positioning
against craft mac and cheese. You can
choose to position based on making a
healthier option, a lower price
alternative, specific ingredients, a
look and feel like the liquid death
position to say we're counterculture.
But how does that work for a
personality? When Bad Bunny entered the
regaton category, he came in with a
perfect example of counterposition. The
current category codes were extremely
hip-hop based and mainstream hip-hop.
Cars, chains, ultra masculinity, and he
came in with nail polish, pink hoodies,
crossdressing, but the same attitude and
feeling. The album title YHLQ MDLG was a
turning point for this. And it
translates into I do whatever I want.
And this wasn't just an album name. This
was an operating system for how Bad
Bunny as a personality approached this
industry. But while loudly moving left
when everyone else moves right, he
immediately positions himself out from
the crowd. And we've seen examples of
this before. Tyler the Creator basically
did it twice. First with the collective
they had with Odd Future, which
counterpositioned against the current
hip-hop at the time by being extremely
in its skateboard roots by being a
collective, by being provocative, but
also by just having all of its facets,
its ability to move back and forth
between his music to Frank Ocean, the
storytelling of individuals, the
personalities in a way that we'd rarely
seen in that era, especially from people
so young. But then he repositioned this,
rejecting every visual code both of
underground hip hop and of mainstream
rap. Pastels, golf, preppy camp, flower
boy aesthetics. Smart in several ways,
it positioned him against himself,
against the dark and angry lyrics that
we saw prior, against the vision of the
odd future as something that wasn't safe
for families or kids and your teens
shouldn't be listening to. His brand is
the anti- streetear street wear and
created a lane so strong it arguably
didn't exist before and took him all the
way to collaboration with Louis Vuitton.
something stylistically without this
visual lane never would have gotten
there. And you can imagine as someone
fashion forward when you're starting to
look at that vision, it's not about
where that vision is, it's about where
it can take you. In 10 years, is this a
vision that can collaborate with Louis
Vuitton? There's data that came out this
week about Bad Bunny's appearance at the
Grammys did for Scarelly's number. A
Parisian couture house making a
men'swear look for Regaton, their first
ever hot couture men'swear look. And
something that when you look at this
initial vision, this initial
counterculture, you can see all the
through lines and how that would be
embraced by modern fashion to where it
gets to today. In female pop, Billy
Eyish being a perfect example, refusing
the hypersexualized pop star uniform
that we see again and again today, baggy
clothes, spider imagery, and when she
does choose to do it years and years
later, it's on her own terms. That gives
her the ability to collaborate with
Nike, to be able to be an outlier versus
the field. And this has more power than
you'd think. Look at this in the guru
world that I inhabit. guru counter
signaling. Think of all the old
marketing people you've heard talk about
the things you learn from. And there's a
certain demographic that will hear me in
a House of errors hoodie. That says a
lot about me and how I want to
communicate to an audience versus what
the field was prior to be able to say,
"Hey, the expertise doesn't necessarily
come from the old guard now from people
whose fashion or look doesn't matter.
People like Hermosi that position
against that, against caring at all. But
if you want to be good in marketing, you
want to be in branding, you need to be
in the no. Everything you say is a
signaler. This whole presentation is a
thing that embodies the taste that I
have and why you would listen to me
versus someone who doesn't care about
the details. Which brings us to art
direction over everything. You'll notice
this transition in 2020 at the album I
talked about where all of a sudden Bad
Bunny's videos became spectacle. The
album shoots became mirroring what we
see in the rise of street wear and
fashion that happened at the same time.
And this now for a large part defines
pop rea general. Rosalia is perhaps my
favorite art directed artist overall.
She deserves her entire own video. But
the combination of high fashion,
religious iconography, execution of
campaign, there's nothing she does that
is not visually stunning. And the
combination of the two of them and how
visually driven they are, how every
release looks like a fashion shoot, how
every music video is an art form, set a
standard for that entire niche. But it
couldn't happen without this next
segment, creative relationships. So,
this video is a little bit about Bad
Bunny, but it's more about Stills, a
photographer that started his Bad
Bunny's tour photographer at 21 and
eventually became his creative director.
His partnership became official around
the 2020 music video release of Vete,
and you'll see a specific creative
vision and all the work that mirrors the
creative director. You go back through
Still's entire Instagram, you see all
this shot on film and shot on Polaroid
items that capture real life in a
specific way. A lot of it of Bad Bunny,
a lot of it of scenes from all around
the life he's lived around interesting,
fame adjacent people, but there's a
relentless connection to the moment.
There's a focus on craft and that film
narrative. But importantly, there's a
story of the two of them going together.
It's not just Bad Buddy's journey,
you're just still journey, but we're
wisely watching the vision play out in
music and visuals and amongst
personalities that couldn't exist
without the other. And in a world where
anyone can be a creator, where we could
all pretty easily attain some degree of
internet fame, pop stardom becomes
harder than ever. How do you rise out of
the ashes, get your viral song, make
your hundred clips again and again until
something catches on, becomes a Tik Tok
trending audio, then release proper
visuals and continue forward? In the
same way that if you are a photographer,
a videographer, an artist, you're just
chipping away to get whatever fame and
work you can utilize in these
democratized platforms. But the power
comes in numbers. One of the themes
we'll hear me talk a lot about
throughout this entire year is the theme
of squads that we don't want to follow
just the one person. We want to follow
the group. We're inherently more
interested in how people interact about
the friend group that's online. But
collaborations go so well and they're
algorithmically rewarded as well because
if you watch a video with someone, they
do a collab video or show up in someone
else's video. The algorithms test the
audiences to each other and if they like
them, they cross-pollinate them. And
it's why you'll see there's a relentless
stream of TJR and Brez all the way to
TJR and Chris Hayne. If you're operating
in the male world with the same thing
happening with Alex Herozi and Tony
Robbins and a lot of this creator
collaboration is based on the
traditional music collaboration on the
guest verse feature. There's a lot more
that these have in common than you'd
think. But for anyone who's in that
creative field, you need a vehicle.
Whether that's a brand, whether that's a
person, but tends to be not just your
own stuff, someone else to build on top
of. Can you go creative direct inside of
someone else's world? Help them build
that out and create something bigger
than either of you could have done
prior. We've become so self-reliant. We
can do so much on our own that there's
less of that collaboration than ever.
And if you look at this, Kanye West may
be the most interesting example. Roel
Abau, Kashi Murakami, Vanessa Brooft,
George Condo. He didn't hire designers.
He collaborated with artists. He brought
them into his world. Other producers,
other people operating around him at all
times, helping propel his vision
forward. And they all leaving with even
more fame, recognition, inspiration, and
understanding of how to navigate this
world of fame, of music, of branding
than they had before. Even at the
highest level, the Murakami graduation
bears an entrance point into a different
world. Kanye elevated them and they
elevated him. And we haven't seen
anything even remotely like it since.
And it doesn't have to be that big. It
can be what we see here, that onetoone
relationship. All right. So, I want to
help you add a skill to your toolkit
today. So, I'm going to give you an
overview of how to do a competitive
website audit in 2026 using the platform
Similar Web. And you won't believe the
info you can actually get about
competitive brand websites. And so, if
you have a brand, you can actually
research what's really happening with
your competitors. And if you are a
marketer, you can create a concrete plan
of steps that you need to do with your
team to have an impact. So, starting
inside the platform, there's a whole
bunch of tools you can see here. keyword
research, backlinks, advertising
activity. Uh we're going to start with
AI brand visibility. So this is a big
conversation right now and you can
quickly see if a brand has a modern
strategy. You'll get a breakdown of how
much traffic they're actually getting
from chat GBT, Copilot, Gemini, and
Perplexity. And we'll break down how
often AI chatbots recommend your brand
in the topics relevant to your business.
So you can see here brand visibility,
the brand mention share, the key topics
that are happening and an LLM comparison
based on those topics you can go
through. Then a list of prompts with
their top brands. There's also some
notes on where it pulls citations from
and then sentiment analysis whether the
AI talks about your brand in a good or
bad way. This is the first year where
for a lot of brands this is becoming a
significant referral traffic source. So
you can go into any website specifically
and then look at much more information
inside Similar Web. So, I can go here
and click into referral and see how many
referral visits that they're getting
over this 90-day period, adjust the
timing, and I can look at what sites are
actually driving that basically monitor
to see where sites are sending traffic
to competitors and not you. Same thing
in search. You can see the search
traffic that a brand is getting. You can
see their branded and non-branded
keywords. And importantly, you can see
their landing pages, where are they
driving their organic and paid traffic.
You can see what's being tested and
click into those. Same thing with ad and
campaign performance. You can actually
see the display ads that they're
running, Google ads, YouTube ads, info
on their PPC spend, and exactly what
creative they're running. This checklist
will give you a comprehensive list of
how I would go through a web audit and
all the different things that I would
check if I was doing a comparison inside
an industry that you can tap back to
anytime you need. And you can get all
this info about your industry on Similar
Web, which I will link down here in the
description. And I want to thank them so
much for sponsoring this video. And with
that comes others, right? Sturdy does a
ton of Bad Bunnies tour work and have
amazing looking product and a real focus
on what they do. Rosalia has multiple
creative partners Canada pill and Spain.
But this doesn't come from waiting for
the gig to hit you up. For stills, it
was a tour photography gig that led to a
creative direction. It comes from
collaboration in the moment with people
as they rise. That leads us to vision
extension. Taking a creative vision
beyond music into a full world. the
album art, the stages, the merchandise,
the collaborations, the other artists,
the social media presence working to
become a vibe. There's been a lot of
talk, you know, I didn't go deep on it
cuz it's so saturated about the Marty
Supreme roll out. And it's reported that
Aiden Zamiri, the creative mind behind
Brat was also behind the roll out of
Marty Supreme. High impact, bold,
unconventional marketing tactics that
built a world that surrounded themselves
with the color, the green of Brat to the
orange of Marty Supreme. the stunts, the
iconography, taking the platforms these
artists already had and saying, "How do
you escalate on top of this as heavily
as you humanly can and thinking about
the cultural moments, boiler room and
how that's branded into this roll out,
people being able to make their own
covers into Timothy's run across music,
film, shouting out Susan Bole, creating
a world isn't easy, but it starts with a
vision and someone at some point on the
creative side or the musician side has
to sit down and say, "We need a vision.
Who's going to craft it?" Fun anecdote I
have is uh before Brat rolled out, I'd
say maybe nine months before that, I was
on a call with Charlie XX's creative
team because they were hunting for
people. They want to do merchandise
better. They want to do creative
direction better. I was very popular
online talking about a lot of that. That
was in the era where I still did tons of
uh custom merch is one of the main
things I worked on. And their team was
hunting for the people that eventually
became the Brat team. And I remember at
the time being like lightly bummed and
surprised that I wasn't hit back on
stuff cuz I was pretty good at the
things I was doing. And then when I saw
the full extent of the roll out, I was
like, "All right, touche." But it starts
with we have to hunt for the vision.
Then comes the people you are going to
work on it with and what it could be.
And then comes the cultural ways things
move in the world now. And it has to
exist in memes and sharability. It has
to exist in leveraging the monoculture
moments that we have left and the
clipping of those. Boiler room is a
monoculture moment for a certain
segment. Monoculture might not be the
right word, but penetration of a
subculture to its maximum amount for the
London New York party megaplex. You hit
complete saturation there and there's
enough taste makers it can shift
outward. The press moments, the
collaborations, the generation people
can take in their own hand, the physical
artifacts people can pick up and buy,
the popcorn buckets, the extensions into
the virality of the world, the sphere
that's operating at the highest level.
How can you operate at the level that
you're at? If I think about my small
town that I'm in, the handful of
accounts that there are, the places
where everyone congregates, you can
begin to film a picture of what that
universe looks like you can operate in.
But it comes down to wanting to have
that vision. Someone has to decide that
they want to take it that far. This ties
into creative bravery because a lot of
these campaigns weren't for everyone.
Tyler the creator dressing like he did,
saying what he said for better or for
worse takes significant amount of
creative bravery. Bad Bunny going in
full drag, getting involved in the
politics of gender in both America and
Puerto Rico. Being in the ring for the
Super Bowl, Kendrick Lamar choosing to
go as hard as he did on a beef where
he's essentially risking his life. This
ties to that bigger trend of true
authenticity. So, one of the things I
love to call out about Bad Bunny is that
if you're in LA, you've ever worked in
any kind of manufacturing warehouse, if
you know some of my past, we had a bunch
of manufacturing in Los Angeles, in
Arizona, and in Oregon, you'll remember
that the only music everyone can agree
on. Why Bad Bunny is so popular in these
areas, is that everyone in general,
you're in any space like that, and you
have a bunch of different cultures.
Everyone agrees on Bad Bunny. So, it's
constantly playing throughout that, but
it's all in Spanish. There's no English
crossover. I like to run a parallel
between Bad Bunny and BTS, the K-pop
stars, who also are Korean language,
Korean concepts, Korean cultural
references. They refused to make English
language albums to break America until
very late in the arc. They made the
infrastructure and the stardom theirs,
and it carried on beyond them without
language having to be a factor. The same
thing happened for Bad Bunny. A kid
knows more Spanish from Bad Bunny songs
than anything else. Cultural
authenticity can reach industrial scale
because we don't buy into just the songs
anymore. You buy into what's happening
in pop culture. You buy into the
visuals. You buy into the social media
experience, the fandom. And the mantra
now is we do not go pop. Pop comes at
us. Brat is an abrasive album for most
of the population. It's not an easy
listen if you like traditional pop
music. But all of these are rooted.
Whether her and the queer adjacent party
scene, whether Bad Bunny in Puerto Rico,
BTS in South Korea, they have actual
cultural authenticity. And you'll notice
that the scale with which people can
operate is limited without it. Timothy
Sha perhaps the most interesting one
where he's a able to embrace his love of
the Knicks and his New York culture and
the film references and how deep he is
inside of his own world and comfortable
in being this kind of next generation
savant of so many things that people see
themselves in and being able to love New
York sports and love college football
and love film equally and be authentic
about it versus a lot of people who
simply just aren't that interesting who
don't have anything to be intensely
passionate about and there's a huge
difference there and what I'll call out
is you'll need to change yourself to do
it that the more in touch you are with
however native that is to you wherever
you are in the world whatever that true
culture that you actually represent is
the more powerful it is to not try and
change to not be apologetic about it to
lean into it as a through line in what
you do in a world where everything
mashes together that more and more
people have an appreciation for so much
about the world because of how we
consume now so anyway I know this is a
very different type of video from some
of the ones I've done before but
continues this art direction and
creative direction through line next
week I'll be back and we'll be talking
about luxury as always we are doing
monthly community calls. Another big one
coming the last week of February. I'd
love to have all y'all join. I'll have
the link down below. This is just
covering the tip of the world you can
get into of Bad Bunny's visuals and art
direction of music and culture in
general. If you enjoyed it, when we talk
about any other artists or people, I'm
always looking for recommendations and
uh we've been doing more and more of
those videos. The creative systems video
is a recommendation. The starting a
social media from scratch video was a
recommendation. I'm excited to try and
take on some new angles this [music]
year. And as always, thank you all so
much for watching.
[music]