In 2018, there was a tiny bag suddenly
appeared everywhere. And all of a
sudden, a new luxury brand appeared in
our lives. It's logo carved into butter,
beach clubs, lavish displays of French
wealth, whimsy, oversized thimbles,
boats, celebrity. Perhaps one of the
best attention-getting moments in
history. Jacquemus. The hype continued,
sold out Nike collabs, bags, shoes. The
brand seemed to be everywhere, but even
in the most luxury of places, with
people consuming fashion, no one you
knew actually owned it. Maybe one piece.
Maybe. All the conversation, all of the
attention, for what? This is the art
direction of French luxury, the creative
direction of Jacquemus, and an excuse
for me to talk in depth about
traditional versus created luxury, soft
power culturally in the world, how
Jacquemus actually pulled luxury without
having [music] have the time and history
behind it using the power of art
direction. We're going to break that
down into six art direction and creative
direction principles you can learn from,
and end with a quick guide if you're
ever in Paris. The marketing of luxury,
the prestige and mastige price points,
are something I've spent my entire
career working on. I have a super
in-depth new luxury ebook I put together
with Van Group, who've done things like
the Road and Jacob & Co. websites you
can get for free down below. And it's
apt timing to do this video, cuz I'm 24
hours from arriving in Cannes myself to
begin the summer lock-in from the South
of France. I'm so excited to talk to you
about this topic. It's both fun and
educational and pertinent for how we
consume in the modern times. Let's lock
in. So, I was in Paris the other week.
As many of you know, I do workshops
around the world. I'd been speaking in
London at the Vervant Pulse Conference
prior about creators. But I was in Paris
specifically to work with the brand on
content, and in particular, luxury
content. Cuz that's always the question,
right? How do you succeed on social
media while keeping the allure of
luxury? And I will take any excuse to
spend time in Paris, a city that I love.
And as I was there, I was having this
conversation with people I was with, and
having these moments actually inside the
city about this idea of traditional
versus created luxury. So, inside one of
my favorite department stores there, Le
Bon Marché, and I'm going to butcher
pronunciation this whole time. I
apologize for my Americanness. I was at
the 1803 Buly counter. 1803 Buly is very
interesting brand. At first glance, they
look like they have been around for
centuries, but in reality, it's only
been a few decades. The brand was
actually founded in 2014 and acquired by
LVMH in 2021. A pretty quick route to a
luxury creation to massive luxury exit,
but it is based on the heritage of
something that existed far before. An
old perfume house that faded into
history. And they play into that hard.
You would not know from looking at their
ornate objects or the beautiful setup of
the place that I was in to pick up a
souvenir for my wife with their engraved
combs and various scents and soaps.
Their emails that go out extremely
lengthily in French detailing all the
wherewithals and travels behind a new
product. It feels like something that's
been around for a hundred years and it
borrows pretty lengthily from the
history of those things, but it is most
certainly not. It is new. Borrowing from
the concepts of traditional luxury to
sell something traditional. You buy from
1803 Buly, you buy it as a tourist, you
buy it as a souvenir or a gift to feel
that you are partaking in this old
ancient piece of luxury that really is
something new designed to sell you. So
much so it's been embraced by the
largest of the French luxury houses. And
this concept, the idea of French luxury
overall, plays into the soft power of
the world. What do I mean by that? So,
the culture that a place creates,
whether that's a state, a city, a
country, impacts its power on the world
stage. When I was young and first moved
to New York, some of the biggest bands
in the world were Justice. Ed Banger
Records was incredibly popular. Daft
Punk had crossed over with Kanye and
their own volition to this powerhouse of
culture. The Pigalle basketball courts
were Nike's hottest activation, one of
the most social media dominant
experiential things of that time. Louis
Vuitton attacked Virgil Abloh shortly
thereafter, kind of entering into a new
era of what French luxury meant in the
modern hypebeast movement and executing
it impeccably. And with that, you would
see the country of France, the idea of
French luxury, the idea of French
interpretation of culture in music, in
fashion, had an outsized influence
compared to the size of the country,
compared to anything else that the
country was doing in the world. The
culture permeate. And interestingly
enough, the majority of that has faded
away because these things change.
Hip-hop music was that for the US for a
long time. Now when I travel with a lot
of sub items, a lot more of how many
people learn about the world and America
through YouTube and American YouTubers.
We see Korea's rise in the global stage
with beauty, with fashion, with music
influencing the world in an outsized way
far more so than whatever that French
impact had been in the previous era. All
of these are part of shifting global
landscapes that change how we consume,
how brands are put together and are
fascinating to think about. Probably its
own video. But for now, for France in
particular, that's all faded. And what
there is left is really the last six or
eight years, Jacquemus. It's the
beginning of an apt metaphor of where
the French luxury is now. On one hand,
someone you can easily admire, someone
who built a luxury house out of thin
air, we'll talk about in a moment. But
on the other hand, a good metaphor for
the complicated state of old luxury
inside the world we adopt today. So why
I always love to look at this example
isn't just the fact it's so viral
everyone has appreciated it, you've seen
it as a brand come across your feed. So
the brand started in 2009 and in about a
decade in 2018 began an extremely rapid
ascent to being considered on par with
the largest fashion brands in the world.
With its shows generating as much
attention, a global name associated with
luxury with nothing that has probably
ever moved that fast in our history. One
of the only other examples you can talk
about is 1803 Bully which did that on a
much smaller scale and in very different
category. And they did that by executing
an art direction and creative direction
playbook impeccably. There's a formula
for emulating luxury in the modern era.
And I do always love to call out this,
it wasn't overnight. It wasn't like it
started in 2016 and 2018 had the big
moment. It was 10 years of working
through this. Because I do think there's
a lot of perception that if you want to
start a premium brand now, a luxury
brand, begin building that, you can do
it in a handful of years. And even this
that seemed like an overnight rise was a
decade in. But the reality of real
luxury is it's over the course of
decades and decades and craft. And some
of these things we'll touch on in a
moment. But what you found is because of
the visual world that we were in in that
2018 to 2026 time frame, aesthetics play
an outsized role in the establishment of
luxury. Same thing with the execution of
social media, and they did a playbook
that was as good as any brand has ever
done. Let's start with the core, the two
things that really defined this. They
helped it associate itself with old
luxury as a newer brand. The first is
craft. So you will note when you go
through the social media, you will see
that the brand is showcasing the craft
that goes into the product for the
receipt of these ornate looms or
craftsmen working on things. They are
taking the time to show that it is a
luxury creation. And you look at the
pillars of what makes someone want to
spend a lot of money on a thing, quality
is one of the non-negotiables. You need
to have a thing that equals to at least
somewhat near where the price point of
what you're doing is, and at least be
significantly better than what is
significantly cheaper. Now, you have the
actual quality of the product itself,
and we'll talk about Jacquemus's quality
in a bit, but even the perception of
quality, the showcasing of the process,
the details that you care about the
craft, that you employ a certain level
of designer or art director of the time
it takes to design and build and sew and
architect all these things. That
storytelling establishes the prestige
necessary, and should be a pillar for
any one of these brands' content. You've
seen this in my video on the web, when I
talked about how they actually show the
complete process and the patterns of
their bags on their YouTube, and in
videos that are basically designed
purely to just show you why they cost so
much. It helps establish a brand as
something worth its money. Jacquemus did
this in a beautiful, artful way, but it
also took the iconography and the
symbolism of craft into its visuals.
That's the second pillar we're going to
talk about here. It's not just showing
the craft, but how to use iconography,
and in this case, the iconography of
craft. You may have seen the iconic
video where Jacquemus is using scale and
oversize, which I'll get to in a moment,
in the whimsy of its art direction to
attract attention by having people
carrying the elements, the iconography
of craft through a town. They were
carrying the thimble, the thread, the
scissors, these large items that are
immediately associated in your mind with
what it takes to create something, being
carried around as symbols of the brand,
as the campaign for the brand. They're
using the repetition of iconography to
associate themselves with craft and
craftsmanship. And they're doing this in
this very overt way. But overt works in
the social media world. You want someone
to remember something about your brand,
make it big. Make it viral. Continue
that association over time. It becomes a
creative direction tactic that a brand
can have. And that combination of craft
and the iconography of craft, and then
how that places into content, which
we'll get to in a moment, becomes the
foundation for why brand can be regarded
at a higher price point. Why people can
feel that it might be worth it to
embrace it. Before we get into the
content strategy there, let me get
tactical for a moment. If you have a
business with traffic or sales that's
based on legacy Google search, or you're
building a brand or media business where
you want to leverage SEO, I have some
exact data for how this is changing, put
together by my partners at Ahrefs. So
first, best X blog listicles are the
single most prominent content format
cited by AI chatbots. So if you're
selling something where people might be
searching for the category, whether
that's a luxury bag or best-made suit,
or whatever you sell, these best X
listicles make up 43.8% of all page
types cited by ChatGPT. Make sure you
are featured on these as a priority, and
you're creating these. Related, YouTube
mentions have the highest correlation,
0.737, with AI brand visibility out of
all the factors Ahrefs studied, both
with ChatGPT and Gemini. So what does
that mean? People don't search just
within chatbots. People search Google
all the time. But Gemini now does the
overview you see at the top of almost
every search, and those overviews have
reduced clicks to the first link by 58%.
That's up 34.5% from just 10 months
earlier. This trend is accelerating. You
need to care about being summarized in
the answer, not just having something
that shows up on the page. That's a new
opportunity to skip that whole old
system with all its entrenched money and
time spent if you're a new brand. The
internet is losing page traffic at an
insane rate. If you want to be in the
results, every brand needs a plan for
their YouTube or being featured on
others. So how do you do all this? How
do you actually make a plan? Ahrefs has
launched Agent A. It's a team member to
work on new age SEO with you. It has
unrestricted access to Ahrefs. You can
chat with it and you will build
workflows and take action. One of my
personal SEO goals is to be more cited
in search. Leverage my YouTube platform,
my newsletter, etc. So, Agent A analyzed
my presence with my multiple websites.
It built a plan, actually found some
spammy links to my Substack, and then
built a disavow file itself that I could
then upload into Google. And it made me
a dashboard for ongoing visibility I can
monitor in minutes. If you listen to
anything that I have to say here, I
would have it be this. Think about your
marketing team of the future is you have
your team members, your human team, and
then their agent team. Agent A would
serve as an SEO strategist or agency,
and someone on your team spends an hour
or two a week managing. You can learn
more about Agent A in the description,
and thank you so much to Ahrefs for
sponsoring this video. Now to content.
We talked about craft and the
iconography and those big elements, but
what Jacquemus really executed was a
content strategy based around two core
things that every brand should think
about. It was based around place setting
and we call the vignette. So, what we
mean by place and setting? You will
notice when they begin to launch
collections or launch pop-ups in stores,
they would do profiles, lookbooks
campaigns in certain places. Whether
they were going to Brazil, whether this
was in the south of France. It was a new
city and they needed to document the
luxury of that city. So, when you are a
brand creating content, the places you
show, you become a parasite for lack of
a better term, taking what that place
has to say about itself and say about it
the identity of the people that like it
or enjoy it or consume around it or live
there, and applying that to your own
brand and what people think of it. So,
Jacquemus is doing that same thing and
saying, "Hey, we're in this luxury
destination. We're opening in a pop-up
on Bond Street or in Selfridges or in
Italy." They used to associate that
luxury with the brand. They really used
that place around it, and you'll see
they will do these rollouts of content,
10, 12 posts around the place, bringing
its DNA into the brand, associating it
with luxury. And this ties really well
with what we call the vignette. How do
you, within a short vlog that keeps
attention, that hooks with what it shows
visually, tell the story of the brand
and that luxury association? So, you
will see this whether it was a giant CGI
bag training its way through France,
whether it was people in these boat
scenarios riding around or carrying the
massive symbol. These are all vignettes.
How in a brief glimpse, a single shot of
a movie scene, can you tell a story that
is eye-catching enough to hook? And
proportion is a tool that Jacquemus uses
extremely well inside of all this. Set
off a whole trend we've seen brands used
to death. What are the 15-second stories
your brands can tell? Then go immerse
yourself in them. And I would encourage
you, if you have a brand you're thinking
about this, whether it's your vision as
an art director or a creative director,
or it's your vision for the brand you
work with, what are those places? Are
you associated with the farms of Texas,
Hollywood Boulevard, New York, places in
Europe, in Africa, in Latin America?
What are those scenes, moments that
capture the identity of a brand? Your
audience would be like, "I love this. I
want to participate in this. This speaks
to me." List those locations out. That's
part of the setting your world exists
in. And when you begin to think of art
direction or creative direction at a
higher level, your job is to be able to
articulate that world both from how you
would describe it to be able to get a
campaign produced, but then also to be
able to actually go to those places,
know where they are, find and coordinate
with the models. That's how you get
advanced in this is you both have the
ideas, you have the ability to present
the ideas, and the networks to execute
them. And if you build your career and
your thoughts around how you begin to
execute that, you begin to think a lot
more like a true creative director. And
I would do that homework for you or
whatever brand you work on. What are
those places that make sense for your
brand or for you personally that would
embody those things that you care about?
And then what would be those vignettes?
What are stories you could tell
underneath them? In the second
collection I released for my little
experimental valuables brand, we thought
about this a lot. We had one of our
models in the car. We've been shooting
with a lot of vintage cars. We basically
have the vignette of our customer was
someone who would appreciate it, go out
of their way to live and have to take
the time and energy that goes into
maintaining an older vehicle. And then
we had shot him with an oversized dog
inside a gas station, living this kind
of life that appeals to our very
specific customer. Same thing with the
brand I understood leather I've worked
with on marketing for for a long time.
Some of our best performing ads were
from a lookbook the founder Jen had
concepted called In Her Element, where
we had kind of like the modern cowgirl
for lack of a better term, riding her
Clydesdale in the country of Texas. And
then in the bars, the apartment, the
places that she would occupy. It's a fun
exercise to think through, to begin
putting those practices of place and
vignette into your toolkit. And then to
get tactical, you need to think in terms
of hooks. So the two that are the
elements of French luxury that Jacquemus
has pulled are proportion and whimsy. So
we see proportion is one of the easiest
things ever. You make something really
big, you just make something really
small. It immediately catches people's
eyes on feed. Is that played out now?
Yes. Does it still work? Also, yes. One
of the easiest solutions you have to
just make something big, to know that it
can work on social media. And being
early to one of these tactics or trends
that can work on feed goes a long way.
People can associate this trend, know
that Jacquemus was part of pushing that
forward when it first did it. But then
also being able to ride it the way Rode
is kind of in the follow-up of this,
still uses it to this day and it works.
You don't always have to be first if
your customer doesn't necessarily first.
But whimsy is another. Whimsy is at the
heart of everything related to French
luxury. I think an understated element
here where everything just has that fun.
Yes, of course it's in butter. Yes, of
course it's little illustration. There's
fun, it's cheeky, it's odd. It's the
underrated X factor in a world where
everything's so serious and luxury is so
buttoned up. There's something
distinctly French about the fun little
illustration or the brief moment or the
saying something snarky at the exact
right time that ties all of these
campaigns and moments together. But when
you talk about is this whole world that
we see here, is it a true luxury world?
Is this a luxury brand? One of the
biggest conversations you'll find is
that's missing the product. To achieve
this true modern luxury where you can
justify top dollar, you're popular and
people believe it's worth it, you have
to have all of these things. The craft,
the history, the content, the execution,
and also the product. And that's where
Jacquemus has fallen short. Most people
who've bought have bought maybe one
thing. If they did, most of them
probably didn't have a great experience
with it. Maybe one suit, maybe a dress,
maybe a bag, and it's all right. There
isn't that signature, that amazingness
that maybe oh I bought this one hype
sneaker, I did whatever that worked out.
I had this one tangential experience
with the brand, but there isn't that
core product that keeps everyone going
back the way you know you need your
Proenza Schouler sweater, your Bottega a
The things that people purchase and are
proud of and pass around like an
artifact. You can have all the other
things and not have that and it's just
not quite right. But, this is all a game
of time. With all of this foundation, if
that thing comes in a decade or another
decade, all of the rest of the setting
is there and then you'll watch
everything click into place. And if
you're interested more in these
principles and these tactics, we talk a
lot about this on websites and in art
direction inside that modern luxury
ebook that you can grab down below if
you want to get some reading in on this.
That's free as well. And if you are ever
in Paris and want to explore some of
this or just be inspired by some of the
creative direction or moments around
there. If you have recommendations, so
first you'll see a lot of content on
TikTok. So, let's go to like Sephora or
Merci. Those are in my mind just kind of
traps. Products being created to sell
you an idea of something Parisian. I
would highly recommend the Grande
Epicerie, which is a upscale [laughter]
supermarket full of from other brands to
wine to truffles to drinks to
chocolates. It's an incredible
experience. They have Le Bon Marché,
which is across the street, which is a
department store. Kind of has
alternating seasonal displays. Ex Libris
is inside there. They will make you a
crest for your family or brand. more fun
keepsake than some of the other options
you may see. Rue Saint-Honoré, and
again, I'm destroying these
pronunciations. I already know. It's a
street all of perfumeries. And if you
are into fragrance, it's an excellent
place to go experiment. Your nose may
never recover. Musée de la Chasse et de
la Nature is a gorgeous museum and
gallery that highly highly recommend. La
Samaritaine is another department store,
I believe one of the oldest ones in
Paris that has again, just their own
branding for their own establishment.
The seasonal campaigns that alternate
the way these brands present. You can go
see Jacquemus's display in there and and
kind of see this kind of weird
half-world that it operates in. If
you're into cookware at all, Dehillerin.
Can't wait for the pronunciation
corrections down below.
Is it kind of from the source cookware
for copper and pots and knives and
actual cooking equipment and
accoutrements if you are into that the
way I am. But, I'm here for the next
weeks in France. I'm in the south of
France hosting at our house for Cannes.
We are going to Monaco. I'm doing a a
workshop with some personal brands
there. I will be inside the luxury
industry for a good chunk of the summer.
We have more content coming about some
of these topics which I love to explore
and talk about. Thank you all so much
for [music] watching.