Today we are going to go through the
worldbuilding playbook for creatives.
This is going to be a case study of Rick
Owens. Rick Owens takes an approach to
designing to creativity to his brand
that is so unique and tasteful and
beautiful and has broken through so many
molds of what people would consider a
brand to be. And the magic of this is
he's created a world that whenever you
interact with it, it's almost like it's
alien. like you're not on Earth, you're
transported somewhere else while still
somehow being commercially approachable.
So, I'm going to distill this into terms
and frameworks that are applicable for
any creative, whether you're an art
direction, creative direction, a
designer, have your own brand, or just
looking to find your own visual style.
And this won't do justice to a fraction
of the world that Rick has created, but
hopefully spark something beautiful in
your vision of what you can do along the
way. In this video, we're going to cover
spectacle, trademarks that designers
have, the product funnel, muses and
characters, the designers as lore,
aesthetics, creating their own worlds,
how that all comes together into the
world building of a brand. Let's lock
in. I want to start with a goal. I feel
like every creative or designer should
have their own version of, and that's to
build a world completely of your own
vision. If you have aspirations that you
want to be someone important in the
visual or aesthetic field, you need to
have an actual aesthetic ideal that when
someone enters your space, whether it's
your home or your retail store, goes to
one of your shows, even sees the cars
you drive, a party you throw, they're
taken out of the common world and you
merged into your world, into something
that is unexpected, that is completely
designed and created to be an extension
of your vision. And if you can build a
world that's that big, where all these
different creative ideas you have are
pulled into the reality, then you are
one of those like magnetic creatives as
the ability to like shift the way we
feel and understand and resonate with
the world around us. And it's so
intrinsically powerful. We've broken all
of our creativity down now into design
this web page, create this 30- secondond
video, launch this like single capsule
collection and less into these massive
worlds that people like Rick Owens
built. And I'm going to talk about the
funnel of creative here because at the
end of the day, this does tie back to
commerce. I think many people who would
have been artists in prior generations
now are clothing designers, product
designers, content creators. And so this
is art and commerce kind of fully
intertwined. And by that nature, these
things have to make money. It's all
going to come back to a funnel. What do
I mean by a funnel? If you've watched
any of my marketing videos, you know
that kind of a top of funnel means you
need things that draw attention, that
get attention to your brand and your
vision. Middle of funnel is about
education, about nurturing, about
turning people from just being aware of
it into advocates of it. And then the
bottom of funnel is what people actually
convert. They buy, they become leads,
they do the action that you're looking
for. And all marketing comes down
eventually to a funnel. And looking at a
brand the same way is a really
interesting proposition, particularly a
brand like Rick Owens. So at the top of
funnel for Rick is art and spectacle. I
think he's one of the core kind of
pioneers in this world we've seen of
product as marketing, right? You can go
on your social media feed nowadays and
you can see a massive oversized bag
being hauled around by someone like
Fugazi or you can see some crazy product
that was made purely to succeed on
social media. Like I look at the Gentle
Monster Bratz dolls, right? That is made
to be a social media product. Now Rick
has been doing this generationally,
right? And whether it was art he created
like tables of himself or inside the
shows that they were doing where models
were wearing each other as backpacks
like down the runway. This is being
created for one goal and that is to
create art in the name of spectacle to
bring awareness to the brand and world
that he is creating. And many people who
aren't deep in what are you going to buy
from a fashion perspective only know
Rick Owens from these crazy shows from
all these visuals we're showing here on
screen that are just wild things that
people are asking who would ever wear
this? What is the proportion of this?
And all of this is just to gain
awareness into the world that this brand
and this identity exists. And in the
modern era, this is increasingly
important. And people do this in
different ways. Shock Moose might do it
in a cute and playful way. People might
do it by having a founder or a key
celebrity. But doing it from a pure
artistic vision perspective. And then
doing that as an entry point into a
larger weird world that the brand has is
something that I feel Rick has done an
incredibly powerful job with. But then
right below that in the middle of
funnel, what actually brings people
awareness? What makes it into a
trademark? what becomes a thing that
people are familiar with that they
consume more of that they can start to
see themselves doing that becomes that
that middle of funnel territory of what
the brand looks like and this is why
trademarks are really important for
brands has been a great example of this
where you actually see these things in
different ways come into the clothes
that are uniquely and signaturely Rick
the first is these shoulders that we'll
show here this almost batwing style
design that shows up on all this
different clothing that when you see
somebody wearing no matter what kind of
celebrity they are you go maybe that's a
Rick Owens piece He has taken shape one
of the core things that goes into any
fashion design or any product design and
turned it into one of the signatures and
you see as a through line between years
and between collections. So you begin
with that idea of spectacle we had. I'm
drawing in attention and you bring that
down to signature. What are these things
that are rememberable trademarks of the
brand that when you see you begin to
associate with and it becomes a signaler
to people that know. If you go one step
down, he also did this with strings and
laces, both all the pants, the long
strings that they have and the shorts,
which became a very simple thing, but it
was very connotative of the brand to
then updating that and saying, "Hey, I'm
actually doing these mega lace
versions." And all the shoes and a bunch
of the collaborations now feature these
extremely complicated lace designs. And
so, you begin to see trademarks emerge
that are signature for a design. And
what I like to call out about this is
every designer has these, right? This is
the the core thing that we do every
season after season. and they'll have
their things that are uniquely them. But
doing them in such a visually impactful
way that is so different from what else
is out there, that is so separate that
it can only really be from one designer
is what separates making something
that's good from making something that
is really resonant. So going back to the
start, we have our spectacle that brings
in attention. We have our middle of
funnel, the more trademark things that
occur frequently that people are into.
And then we'll have what I'm going to
call the bottom of funnel here, which is
what people most often choose to buy
from the brand. And this is a really
interesting concept I think every
designer and every creator should think
about is what is your take on
entry-level products? What is your take
on classics? This is something that's a
foundation of the Rick Owens brand. Part
of one of the reasons that he's a
controversial designer and there'll be a
bunch of people in the comments here
being like Rick Owens is torched because
there is so many takes on these known
things. So if you were to look at
footwear for instance, you can see the
Rick Owens footwear and be like there's
the Ramon which is a direct Rick Owens
version of a Converse. There's the Geo
Basket, which is their version of a Nike
basketball shoe. And then also typical
things like a short, a pant, a cargo
pant. You will see he has his unique
take on all of those. Some of them more
inspired than others, but basically is
crafted enough of a worldview to be able
to have a take on them. That's really
useful exercise for any creative. If
someone was to hand you some Vans and
say, "You have to make these uniquely
yours. So unique that someone will be
able to recognize that they are yours
from your signatures." That's a good
signaler on if you've developed a unique
enough style for yourself. And then the
same thing with a short or a pant,
right? What are those signatures?
Whether it's, you know, with Rick with
the pod shorts, you have a drop crotch,
you have those same strings then applied
across others. It changes and moves over
time, but they're able to take a
signature style and apply it to any
given item. And then this ends up being
what the majority of people purchase
because no matter what high fashion and
spectacle you have, people buy in at the
entry level. CDG isn't held together by
the highest end fashion it does. It's
held together by the Converse with the
heart on them. All these brands succeed
off of their entry-level products. And
the more wide a swath and the more
adoptable it is while still remaining a
vision that also is basically a walking
billboard for yourself, the more
successful a brand world becomes, the
more interesting and spectacle and
things you can do on the top end. But
that Rick Owens empire is an empire
built on Ramon's shoes and pod shorts.
And so I encourage any designer, any
person working at a brand, this can be
clothing or not, to be able to think
about what are the things that are
drawing in attention for me. And they
may not even have to sell. Their idea is
to bring in attention. What are the
signatures that you have on a brand you
can see recurring underneath it? And
then what would your take on entry-level
things be? Because more often than not,
when you establish your own design
world, you're going to be entering into
your collaborations with Adidas or Nike
or Vans or New Balance or Converse. And
that's what questions you're going to
have to be asked. They're actually going
to provide pretty deep implications as
to whether or not you're going to be
commercially viable. Does your world
you've created translate into those more
common items? But now, let's move away
from products. Let's talk about
characters in the world building story.
If you've seen any of my brand strategy
exercises, I always encourage brands to
look at their content, to look at, and
content I mean everything from lookbooks
to website to social media to what you
run in your advertisements to runway
shows as a TV show, sets, characters,
etc. And the characters that represent
your brand tell you a lot about the
brand. And Rick Owens has taken this
world and basically continued to make
almost an otherworldly segment. You
could watch a Rick Owen show and you're
watching essentially like a sci-fi
horror concoction from a lot of the
choice being the characters that are
involved because to his in his own
wording is a cast of freaks. The
characters in the story in every one of
these runway shows and the models they
have on there are designed to take you
out of the world of reality. Whether
they are hyper beautiful or seem like
some sort of fictional godlike character
or whether they are repulsive and would
make people think twice about what is
happening there or is this person even
real? Am I in a horror movie? Are they
made up to look like that? And in one of
my previous videos on a similar topic,
we talked about Stucy and the idea of
the homie lookbook and basically the
opposite of this where they're saying,
"Hey, our friends and collaborators and
the people that we know and skate with
and write graffiti with are the people
that are in our lookbooks." This is a
very popular strategy that Stui has had
with the Stui tribe for decades that we
see a lot of people and brands do now
where the common person has become like
a part of the brand story and it's an
awesome way to feel community with your
brand. Then there's the opposite
approach. Let's take your brand and put
you into a fantasy world. And that is
what Rick does. And that is a difference
between something that a brand that's a
community and a brand that is art. And
they can both resonate in their own
ways, but the art one is the opportunity
to really bring a design and artistic
vision to life for people that have that
vision more than any other way. And in a
world of about blank and represent and
ALD, having models and shoots that all
look very similar and their knockoffs
and spin-offs all having their own
shoots even look more similar. The
passion to hunt down the freaks of the
world, to make them the stars of your
show, to find the correct visualization
of your brand that is completely unique
or completely its own story, no matter
what that may be, is increasingly
powerful as the algorithms center more
and more brands around looking the same.
All right. So, if you've ever looked at
brands like this and wonder how much do
they actually sell and how are they
tying all of their marketing together in
one place, we're going to take a moment
here to go through Particle, who I'm
super excited to sponsored this video,
and show you how their competitive
analysis software works. So, starting
here on a brand many of us know, you can
actually go and click into all the
best-selling products and see how much
volume it is. So, for instance, in this
last time period, they're selling 76 of
this hat, 33 of this hoodie, 13 of this
belt. You can go inside any of the
companies that they have inside the
database to actually check out what
level of volume they're really doing.
And this is great if you're planning a
brand to see what a brand has done over
time and to see what their current
promotions look like. So for instance,
if I go over here to Cole Buckton, I
click over to the events tab, I can
actually see a summary of what they
launched and when that is basically auto
put together by the Particle platform.
And then over here on the assets page, I
can actually see by this little note
when they've updated their homepage, new
meta ads that they've launched,
Instagram posts that they've put
together. And for a lot of brands, their
email will be in here as well that you
could look at. But homepage swaps will
actually show you campaigns and other
things that might be hard to dig up when
you're looking for a brand
competitively. You can look at the rate
sold per day. You can look at the
average discount, see if a brand is
discounting. You can see when they do
their sales and when they have their
peaks and valleys throughout the year.
But say I need some email inspiration. I
could go over here into represent. I
could go down, I could select email,
filter it, and it's actually going to
show me a bunch of the recent email
campaigns and the dates that they were
done. The last thing I'll show you in
here is there's also trends of what's
actually rising in search over time you
can look at to evaluate new products. I
like to look at it on a two-year
timeline so you can see seasonality
because some products might just be
popular because of the holidays. You can
look and see things like bookshelves
rising in macro level popularity.
Balenciaga having a bit of a resurgence.
Obviously they have brought some new
talent and things have moved around and
it will show you this by a combo of
brands keywords and ideas. You can
integrate your own search as well. So,
if you're looking to understand more of
what's happening in your niche, who's
actually selling what, put things
together by price or color as to what
you could sell, and also evaluate some
of the trends happening in e-commerce
products, you should check out Particle
at the link in the description of this
video. Thank you so much to them for
sponsoring. And that brings me to my
next thought in the characters, which is
this idea of the designer as lore. We
have a generation of influencer
designers. Sometimes they have a
lifestyle involved with it, but they are
telling their story of their brand as it
comes together on the internet. And this
is something that Rick is doing as well,
but completely on his own terms. Because
when you see content with him and it
doesn't look like anyone else's content,
maybe it's being shared by one of his
muses, maybe it's on an account, but the
music is weird, the ratios are off,
things aren't made to look like other
content in terms of how they succeed
because a full world is built around it.
And contrasting writing that completely
unique world, that world around you
versus being completely normal is a
choice that people have to make. What do
I mean by completely normal? I mean
people are copying each other's content.
You basically see a couple different
classes of builders. You have like the
workout influencer brand owner where
it's like, hey, I design clothes. I have
this brand and all my content is around
doing those things and being fit. That
is like bucket one and we have enough of
that. Then we have bucket two, the
people that are building their brand in
public and sharing a lot along the way.
And we have a lot of that too. Like I
did all these vlogs and videos where I
went to China and showed all these
places where people make their brands
and then this year there's like 40
people making the exact same videos,
right? Then I go back, I make some of
the same similar content. doesn't do as
well because people are continuing to
kind of distill these things that
happened. And I feel like that same area
is also just uniquely as as basically
done as the as the first and there are
plenty of people that do it amazingly,
right? There's always going to be the
first people like if you look at like
George from represent, you look at
Marcus from Minted, people that have
done that influencer athlete like at a
high level and continue to are, you
know, they're the pinnacle of that. And
you have a community built up underneath
it that is just based off these same
ideas isn't going to go as far. Same way
with people that are sharing the
blueprint as they go. But then what
they're always just room for is someone
doing it from a completely new artistic
perspective based on their unique
vision. And this is the hardest one,
right? This is the one where you can't
just go copy the same videos where you
have to have original aesthetic ideas in
your head that honestly a lot of people
don't because it's extremely
complicated. But hopefully this playbook
begins to identify a bit of that world
where you say like what is my spectacle?
What are my visual motifs? And you'll
see everything that Rick does from the
naming of the runways and the
collections to these set pieces they
have on there where there's this these
combinations of like ancient Egypt and
you know far-off gods near sci-fi pieces
of horror all this brought together and
clashed into a world and I encourage
people to sit down and think of what
does your world look like from that
perspective because that's what the
world needs right now. It needs more
Ricks because the bar for that is
higher. another brand owner sharing
their workouts as part of how they build
their brand is taking from the same
market share of people interested in
that one thing when there's a lot more
people out there who are interested in
other subcultures and ideas and who
frankly are looking to be inspired
because right now more and more people
make content more things are on our feed
it looks more and more the same it's
harder to take apart and to be pulled
from that which everyone wants everyone
wants to be pulled out and find
something that makes them feel something
it has to be unique so now I'm going to
talk about aesthetics and how they move
through a world beyond simply like the
core core category you're in because one
of the important things that we've seen
from Rick Owen's world is that it can
move in how it collaborates and how it
moves through different categories. So
he is a recurring collaborator with
Monontlair. They have all the Monontlair
genius stuff with Rick spanned out from
just clothing. It was easy enough to say
what is his motifs of fur and oversize
and logos and iconography laces. Let's
apply that to cold weather gear. Easy
enough to figure out popular in its own
right. But then adding to that, moving
into all these different realms, whether
it's vehicles, whatever it is, and then
seeing the same thing of like he
develops his own system for interiors,
the Glade system, and then having that
then be Travis Scott's traveling studio
is like a tech glade version of his
architectural world. There's furniture
that comes from that. It can all live
off of these same things. That's the
other piece to ask yourself as a
designer. When you are going and playing
in these different realms, what are
those visual things and how do they
actually translate? Do you care enough
to submerse yourself into all these
items in a way that makes you love and
be interested and resonate inside of all
that? And another designer who many of
you know who's done a very good job
building their world across things in a
unique way without having it be as wild
as Rick is Samuel Ross. What he did with
a cold wall, what he's doing now with
his own label, what he's done with his
collaborations, where it's applying this
more technical design world into all
these areas that he touches. But the
exercise for that for a designer now is
if you begin to think of your motifs and
your brand and your design begin to ask
like how would I apply this to
furniture? How would I apply this to a
vehicle? What would those things look
like? It begins to take you outside of
that world you're in of just what am I
going to make this t-shirt look like?
What am I going to make this product
look like? And begin to understand a
world not just by the characters and the
styles that are in it by but by its
application and application to things
that people use and engage with more so
than the statement of what they wear. So
anyway, I hope this video sparked some
ideas and thought as to how you think
about what you design and what your
vision and potential could be like. And
I would encourage you to go back and
look at some of those exercises to be
like, how would you approach or develop
enough signatures to be able to design a
pair of Vans that people recognize them
as your own? To be able to apply your
visual world, what do those characters
look like? What do those muses look
like? To be able to have your own unique
content style, to be able to say, "Hey,
when I make furniture, it would look
like that." and beginning to open your
creative mind a bit more to what those
worlds look like than surely into that
world of short form content or the
things we're kind of boxed into. Now, it
feels a really useful exercise for any
creative. Now, I would just encourage
you to also not have any restrictions in
your vision of if you really have an
interesting aesthetic idea or an idea of
what the world could be like this is now
the time to be able to create it. We
have the ability to bring visuals to
life cheaper and easier than ever to put
content on the internet to see things
resonate to make any product in any
category. If you have the strongest of
visions or the most unique of ideas, you
are in the best generation in the
history of the world to be able to do
that, bring it to life, monetize it,
create something interesting that
resonates with people. And I would
encourage you very, very highly to
actually go do that. That was my guy.
Like I mentioned, I'm not beginning to
touch on the full world of Rick Owens
and do justice to all the things he's
created, but hopefully spark some ideas
to what you can do yourselves. Thank you
all so much for watching. Please like,
subscribe, all the above, and I will be
back next week.
[Music]