Today, we are going to talk about the
art of yapping, how to talk on the
internet, why it's so powerful, exact
frameworks on what to say, how to write,
where to edit, all of the different
styles of yaps, a complete playbook for
talking into your phone to change your
life. And thank you to HubSpot for
sponsoring this video. I just got back
with the fam from Coachella. You'll
notice if you look at my content,
[music] I was doing a lot of yapping
there, just talking on the iPhone,
minimal graphics, about what I saw, why
it matters for brand strategy. In pretty
long, two or three-minute videos. I
thought it'd be a great time to tap into
this strategy and explain how to use it.
Let's lock it. So, the other week, my
boy JT dropped this video called I
really think you should become an
influencer. And in the video, he details
that even though you see all of this
content like the end of the influencer
age, or AI is going to replace creators,
in reality, everyone we know that's done
it has gotten this like massive outsized
value. And it's not just about, "Hey,
I'm going to make all this money." or
"I'm going to get this huge following."
Talking on the internet and yapping is
like the simplest version of that,
right? Yapping is just putting a camera
on, an iPhone camera, not caring about
anything else, and just talking.
Easiest, most straightforward way. But,
I think it's important to understand
like the repercussions, like how this
impacts all the other things in your
life, right? So, the primary method of
business and personal communications now
is short-form video. We see it in all
the feeds, Instagram, TikTok, LinkedIn,
Netflix is introducing vertical video, X
wants more original video creation. And
when you go online, you're being shared
with your friends in your group chat,
with your wife or your husband, you are
sharing reels and TikToks. This is an
innate part of our culture, and it's the
same thing in business, in Slack groups,
in team groups, people are sharing
content. And so, if you ever, you know,
work in marketing or as a creative, and
you want to make a good ad, even if
that's on TV, even if it's like a text
design, it comes down to understanding
video and this attention complex. And if
you ever want to market your business or
build your career, having the ability to
do that yourself or manage others
becomes really important. And what was
interesting to me is the number one
value I got as someone who started
making content at like 37 was becoming a
better communicator. So, I'd always been
quieter, more introverted, and in the
right scenario I could spit out a lot of
quality information really quickly to
give people context. But my mind always
worked faster than what I would say. And
so it just be this like stream of
consciousness. But when I started making
content, it allowed me to think in a
more compelling way. I'd be, "What
message am I trying to get across? How
do I get this person's attention about
it? How do I dispel the limiting beliefs
they have around what I'm saying? And
how do I present a story they're going
to pay attention to that's going to get
them from their perspective to the
finish line of whatever I'm explaining?"
And now I think of all the conversations
like that. It's made me a better
salesperson. It's made me a better
marketer. It's made me better at
articulating ideas in important
scenarios and just more personable
overall. And that's such a huge impact
from simply talking on the internet. And
the last impact is the ideas it's
facilitated in my life, right? So, if
you watch a lot of my short-form
content, it's about ideas. I am
fascinated with putting out original
concepts. And so I'm constantly
workshopping those bits with the people
around me. Like I have one right now
about how your zip code over indexes as
a factor as to where you go in life. I
have another one about how people don't
really need like McMansions and these
big homes. And the ideal home size for
almost everybody is like 1,700 square
feet. And like I have all these ideas
that I'm kind of workshopping. And I
have these conversations with people
where I bring it up. They know I make
content. We talk about this idea. They
share their opinions. We facilitate just
kind of more interesting valuable combos
because we're able to think through so
many of these because we're articulating
ideas. It's just led to a more
thoughtful life. Speaking of yapping, if
you want that content to do even more
for you, LinkedIn is an extremely
slept-on platform. What I love about
LinkedIn is it doesn't matter about the
views. The quality of the views is so
high that you cuz you're reaching actual
professionals, potential clients, those
who might hire you at a job. Even if you
get a handful of views and likes, it's
going to be people that can make a real
career difference. That's exactly why
HubSpot put together this free starter
pack. It's called the 10X Your LinkedIn
Game Starter pack. Inside you get Adam
Biddlecombe's growth guide, the exact
playbook that he used to go from zero to
100k on LinkedIn under a year, which is
also what led to a HubSpot acquisition,
so it clearly worked. You get Mind
Stream's one-page cheat sheet, this kind
of thing you can print out and keep next
to your monitor to remind you to be
attacking LinkedIn each week, and you
get a LinkedIn profile playbook. Covers
the fundamentals how to optimize your
profile and build content that performs
there. My favorite part is the personal
brand section. It's about building a
consistent perception of what you're
known for across your photo, headline,
summary, and the content you post. If
you've been yapping anywhere else and
neglecting LinkedIn, this is your sign
to start, and especially if you're
making brand content, do not sleep on
LinkedIn. The link to HubSpot's 10x your
LinkedIn game starter pack is in the
description, it's free, grab it. And
thank you for HubSpot for sponsoring
this video. But if you want to start,
let's tap into types of yaps. And I'm
going to go into how you actually write
and make the takes. And so this is all
important for a vernacular. You want to
have the right terminology, be able to
talk about and explain it, the right
examples. But this is an example from
Brandon, who's great on TikTok. He is
just talking. He doesn't even have
captions. This is a standard yap. He
turned his iPhone on, he's added a
graphic like at one point in here, but
he is literally just talking to camera.
Same thing with this, she's going
through the best chicken Caesar wrap in
Orange County. Simple enough content,
but she is literally just on camera and
talking. That is the most basic yap. You
do not need anything else. Now, I highly
recommend for almost everybody that you
put the actual captions of what you're
saying on it, but this is a standard
yap, nothing else required. Now,
slightly more advanced is the walking
yap. This is my friend Christian, he's a
a yap king. We'll talk about some of his
techniques later here, but this is when
you are literally just in motion talking
to the camera versus just sitting there,
which I don't recommend to start out
unless you have a good understanding of
what content moves. It's too many
variables, but the common technique
people will do is you're able to kind of
stay in motion, you're talking, it seems
more like a FaceTime with a friend.
Yeah, this is Tom, noted cut 30 grad,
his handle is Bonus Footage. He's doing
a car yap. That's when you're in the
car, he's not even looking at the camera
a bunch. He's kind of going back and
forth with that very candid environment
of just sitting down as a part of your
day and talking. And those are the base
yaps. So, if you before you even get
into graphics, before you get into
overlays, any of that, if you just want
to start talking on the internet, you
basically pick one of these. Standard
yap where you're sitting down, walking
yap, car yap. It was just worth having
inside your purview. And why these
matter is it's about the candid setting.
It's about the easy scenario, the ease
of recording, about not making yourself
have to worry about I need a set, I need
this, I need that. All of these are just
a simple tripod. Mine is literally right
here. It's in a Tumult Tech from Amazon.
It expands out, legs on the bottom,
Bluetooth remote. It was like 50 bucks.
Or one of those little dash cameras that
connects to the MagSafe on your iPhone.
Then you get into the next level yap
where we call graphic yaps. These are
yaps where you're actually placing stuff
over your video to make it more
compelling to watch. Cuz you'll notice
if you just talk, you need to be pretty
compelling to get your value prop
across, but it's still great practice
and great to do. But graphic yaps help
keep attention by just providing
examples of what you do there. Another
Cut 30 Grad. She's doing what we call
basically graphic yap. Where you don't
care about the production at all. You
just put the graphics over. And she is
using the overlay function in edits or
CapCut. Literally, you just put stuff on
your camera roll, you just hit overlay,
you can put it over, and you can adjust
the length of the clip to do roughly a
clip every 2 seconds, which is what we
recommend for people in Cut 30. And all
this does is it makes it that her story
is more compelling cuz you always have
something to look at. And this video
ripped for her. And a great thing to do
is if you're planning a video and you
think it's going to be about 60 seconds,
get 30 images. That takes way less time
than you think. If you don't want to
think out your framing slightly more,
it's another Cut 30 Grad. He sets it up
really well where he frames himself on
camera and knows he's always going to
have a graphic above him and he gives
himself space to do that. Note his head
placement, the caption placement, and
the graphic placement. This is if you
are the kind of person who the the
chaotic one gave you a little bit of
didn't feel great about it, this is an
awesome one where you can literally copy
his framing. Always make sure your
graphics are vertical so they're easy to
overlay. And it's easy to both look at
him, read the what he's saying, and look
at the graphics roughly at the same
time, which is how you keep a really
compelling yap going. Now, I do a
full-screen overlay a lot, cuz if
visually I like it visually. So, you'll
see I am talking. This is a slightly
more professional camera, but I'm
putting full-screen 9 by 16 images that
I edit in Canva that go over the screen
while I talk. And again, I am shooting
for that one for every roughly 2 seconds
that the video is going. And you will
see a lot of the more design-focused
creators, people who get really into it,
do these kind of really cool setups
where they'll put in graphics in and
out, little video. And you can get as
advanced as you want, but it does not
matter. The key to the yap is you just
do it. The whole thing is set up to make
you want it to be easy. So, now that we
know what those formats are, what do you
actually talk about? I'm going to give
you five frameworks to use for your
yaps. The first one is a strong take.
So, Christian, whose videos I showed,
he's the king of this. He can make a
strong take about anything. He will be
in Orlando, and he'll be like, "Orlando
is the best sports city in North
America." He'll be in Philadelphia, and
he'll be like, "Champions is the best
sports bar on the East Coast. Black
pizza is the best in wherever."
Basically, you have a strong take, you
say something is the best or you say
something is the worst, and then you
defend it. And this is a really easy way
to get your yaps going, cuz it forces
you to have to have a really strong
opinion. And then people are going to
respond to that opinion positively or
negatively. And conversation is what
drives videos. So, if you feel
passionate about something, you can put
it inside that. It's something worth
talking about. And to put this in in
perspective of anything you can yap
about, and we'll talk about the things
in your life, etc., later. Every beauty
product is the absolute best concealer
for people with X skin. This is the
superior energy drink versus that one.
This is the best choice for your
influencer marketing software, whatever
it is. But forcing yourself into a
strong take means you have to have
conviction, and you basically have to
make something interesting, and it's
going to generate conversation. Now, a
second, a variation of this that I do
all the time is strong take into
education, where you say something, but
you're just using it as a hook, as a
setup. So, I did this with Coachella,
where I was like, "There are way too
many Coachella influencers. The brands
can't possibly be getting value out of
this. That's a strong take. But then, I
immediately go, "Well, let's actually
break down content supply and demand."
So, I immediately pivot to education,
where then I'm talking about, "Well,
it's not actually too many influencers
because the demand for the content is so
high, and the content outperforms it
typically." And I break down the
differences between evergreen and
current content. So, that hook is
literally just leading me into something
educational. That's a great way to think
about your content is whatever you use
to get people's attention, as long as
you're providing value and not being
super clickbaity on the back end, it's
about starting the conversation. The
third style is a small epiphany. It's
like a relatable thing that you see all
the time. Do you notice how husbands
always do this? Do you notice how East
Coast people are always doing that?
Notice how we like, just basically going
into the things that happen every day
and finding something funny and
relatable. It's an awesome way to look
at this. What are the things you always
see yourself doing or unexpected or
funny or a shared experiences that you
can talk about? Cuz people feel some
kinship with that. They either go, "I've
never noticed this." Or they go, "Oh my
god, that's so funny. I hadn't thought
of that." They're like, "Oh, yeah, I do
that too." And then build camaraderie in
the content. Then we have humor yaps.
Just saying something funny or a funny
scenario that happened or making fun of
something. Like, there's a yap who goes
around critiquing all these different
places in LA that are like overrated.
And then we have story time, where
you're actually going to tell a
narrative of something that happened in
your life. Hey, this thing happened. I
just got rear-ended at blank and blank.
And I can't believe that Z happened.
Strong takes, small epiphanies, and
story time is like the foundation for
90% of the content you can make yap. You
notice what I didn't say? I didn't say
my top three favorite whatever. I didn't
say three ways to run e-comm or this is
my motivational speech. None of that.
These are all narrative arcs or strong
opinions. If you are thinking outside of
that box and it's generic, it's not
going to work. So, then how do you
actually come up with the ideas to do
this? So, I call it a yap map. So, how
do you start a yap map? A yap map is
basically, let's say it's a whiteboard
or a piece of paper or a note app in
your phone where you're writing down
stuff. And usually what I recommend is
you take some time out of your day. It's
a commute time you'd normally be
scrolling, and you just map out things
that that happened to you. And so first
is the touch points of your day. What
happened at work? What happened in the
morning? So did you What kind of food
did you get? Any conversations that came
up? Any meetings that happened? What are
the little things that happened? And so
this is the constant source of my
content is more business content focused
is a question that came up that I had to
explain. Why do people do influencer
marketing at Coachella? Should we be
doing that as an accounting brand? And I
answered you're like, you know what?
This is actually a good content topic
for a video. Oh, I'm at lunch with
somebody and they're talking about how
they're depreciating their G Wagons for
their business. Jokes that came up,
movies that people saw, whatever it is.
You'll be surprised how small it is. And
people are all talking about watching
the same TV show. Do you have an opinion
or perspective on that based on your
background? Same thing with your
personal life. What are those
interpersonal things that happening?
Dating is an awesome source of like,
"Man, have you noticed guys are always
doing this? Why is it so hard to find,
yeah, a trad wife in Minneapolis?"
Whatever it ends up being. Then the
media you ingest. If you're reading
tweets, if you're watching stuff on
Instagram, is there stuff happening that
you can respond to? "I don't like this
trend. This news thing is crazy."
Another big one is your shower work out
thoughts. A lot of people will be like
processing things in the background. the
few times in the day they're not on
their phones. You'll start to notice,
"Oh, there's like these little things
that are coming up that I'm thinking
about. Would that be a good video
topic?" And so with all of those, your
goal is just to get three or five ideas
down a day. That's always what I'm
trying to do. And I have hundreds and
hundreds and hundreds now. And then, on
top of that, once you have an idea, you
need a take. What is my take? Do I have
a strong opinion about this one way or
the other? Do I have a story I can tell
about this? Or do I have a relatable
thing I can break down? And that is
literally a map of content that you're
going to be able to make. And I
recommend just doing that every day. And
you'll be surprised even if you put one
down and three down the next day, you're
going to start having a big list of
topics. So then how do you script it?
How do you script it? Yeah. So a couple
of frameworks for this. I'm just going
to give you a few and you can start
experimenting with your own. But the
first is hook, story, point one, point
two. So how does this work? Hook, you
say the thing that you're going to talk
about in the video. Like, "Kit Coffee is
the best coffee shop in Newport Beach."
Then you tell a story. "So I was getting
a latte uh the other day with two
friends of mine who are realtors. They
wanted to go to this shop. I wanted to
go to this shop. X happened, Y
happened." And you get to wrap the
narrative of why you think this is the
best coffee shop. But do you have an
anecdote from your actual life or do you
have a story of somebody else? When
Steve Jobs was 19, he did X and Y. My
friend has blank happen. So basically
you hook them, you tell a story that
keeps them retained, then you get into
your two points. This is the best
because of this and this is the best
because of that. Awesome framework for a
yap. The next one, which I like to call
the eight mile,
is you do your hook and you call out the
opposite argument and then you make your
point. So for instance, if you are
taking a strong position about something
and you want to talk about a great piece
of software or why companies shouldn't
do X or Y, you say it and then you say,
"Now people might say this or that." You
basically explain all the things that
people would argue against you and
disprove them and then get into why I
say this because of that. And so then
you're basically getting rid of all the
objections people have like right up
front and it keeps people retained cuz
they're probably thinking these things
and you're explaining them and then you
get to your reasoning. And this all
works exactly the same if you're doing
like a personal anecdote. Hook it, you
tell the story. Hook it, you talk a bit
about the scenario, and then get into
your points. Another version that I like
to use all the time, this is the last
one I'll mention here for frameworks, is
the the four things or the five things.
So I'll say something like, "Hey, here's
observations I made at Coachella as a
brand strategist." And I'll basically
make four mini videos. I'll say, "I saw
this thing and I have a strong take
about it. I think Nike's falling off
because I didn't see any Nikes on feet.
I think Gap is doing a great job because
the lines were out the door and everyone
was buying X or Y." I'll do like three
or four of those and people will stay
through to the next one. That's all you
need. All you need to get started doing
this is to take those frameworks, take
that style of yap, any of the ones I
called out, write down some of those
ideas and fill in these and that's how
content works, how everyone makes
content. And then I want to remind you,
you are there to light people up. You're
there to get people excited, to make
them laugh, to have them be thrilled. So
be excited, be passionate, care, have
fun with it because that really comes
through in the phone. One of the advice
I give a lot of my friends is try to
make content, they just look like
they're not having fun and if that's the
case, it's probably not going to do very
well. People are going to feel that. So
quick notes on recording, few things
there. Just to get tactical on this.
iPhone with a mic, I use a Rode plug-in
USB-C mic for the phone. You don't need
anything more than that. But you should
get a mic to do it. You can also use the
Apple EarPods. AirPods do not work.
Couple ways to do it. One is just record
and talk and talk slowly enough that you
can just keep it going. The other is
what I do, which is called the Recut
method. So, I will talk. I will take a
breath whenever I need to think of
something or look at a note. I will just
stay quiet. I will make sure I maintain
eye contact with the camera until I'm
quiet. I'll take as long as I need to
think about my next thought and then
I'll go look back at the camera, make
sure I'm looking at it, and then speak
again. And then you can use I use an app
called Recut. It's like 20 bucks or
something. You can do it inside a lot of
the editing software, but you can just
basically chill all the silences in
between and edit down your video. It's a
really effective way to do it. You might
end up with a six or seven minute clip
cuz you're taking a bunch of pauses, but
allows you to think and get your
bearings before saying the next thing.
And the last piece of advice I'll give
you when recording is that redo the
start at the end is always a crucial one
because usually when you start and you
begin your recording, it's the most
important part of the video, but you're
the most awkward, especially when you're
new. But by the time you're done talking
for 3 minutes, you're in a much better
mood, you're in a much better flow, and
I would just redo that intro a time or
two, and you have a really easy time
editing it. When you do this, you can do
this directly in the TikTok app, but I
would recommend doing it in CapCut or
edits. Then you can bring it into any of
those, and you can add the captions that
you have, and then add a title. These
are really important to do. I'm not
going to get too deep into them, but I
will have a cheat sheet down below that
you can grab on this. And I will remind
you, no matter what your age is, your
expertise is, if you haven't seen any of
my videos about this before, people want
to hear from people that are at their
level or a level right above them.
Doesn't matter how experienced you are
or not, it's about sharing that journey.
And also on the opposite end, there is
nobody who is too old or in too weird a
niche to do this. It's just about
getting [music] through it. We have this
month's community call coming up the
first few days of May. I have the sign
up down there below if you want to
workshop any of this, any questions you
have. We do live Q&A in all of these
after we do some training. It's a great
time to connect with myself and with
anyone else like in the community who's
dealing with the same stuff. A lot of
people meet in the chats. That community
call's below. The next Cut 30, if you
want to do this with a group, I would
recommend just go and get started with
what I have here. If you want to do this
with 30 days of accountability,
>> [music]
>> the next Cut 30 starts early May as
well. We do them roughly every 6 weeks.
So you have 30 days of doing this with a
team and coaches and curriculum. But
overall, I cannot overstate what said in
the beginning, what JT said in this
video, that I really highly recommend
that you become a creator. Even just to
learn the skill set, to learn the
communication, you get thinking about
the things around you, to understand how
the modern world works. And then on the
high end, to significantly [music]
change your career trajectory, be able
to make money on the side if that's
something you're into, and to
participate in this new economy that we
once-in-a-lifetime [music]
opportunity of getting free attention on
the internet from. Thanks for watching.
>> [music]