This is the rise and fall of Supreme.
Arguably the most important streetear
brand of all time and one of the most
important brands overall. In this video,
I'm going to break down what made it
tick and took it to greatness and then
what the scenario is now that they are
supposedly falling off, bought by big
business, traded around, values
changing, doesn't have that same
resonance it had before. What is the
real scenario? And most importantly, so
you can learn and digest what made this
so special at the time and how to craft
a truly unique brand, creative presence,
and creative direction for a new era
based on some of what they did in the
past and be changing world that we're in
now. We're going to hit the people that
made Supreme, the spaces, their infamous
collab playbook, the crossover of street
wear into luxury, and if that luxury
playbook still exists, highlight some of
their best products and stand out
creative direction, and end with some
exercises for you to think about
Supreme's world creatively for what
you're passionate about. Let's lock in.
So, to start, my experience with Supreme
was when I was a young designer living
in New York. I worked for a PR firm that
was on Broadway, right by Lafayette
where the Lafayette Supreme store was.
And so we would consistently be going
over there after work because it was a
cool place to be. Friends of mine had
friends that worked there. There's a lot
Colomb right down the street. And it was
a thing, a constant presence of lines,
an easy place to meet up, especially for
young dudes at the time. And it was
having a cultural moment in New York
City. And so I want to call out the
impact of what's called wild posting,
those posters that you'll see up in
major cities, and just how big of an
impact that has in places like New York.
So we saw this recently. You guys may
have seen the Friend AI campaign where
Friend took over all the subways of New
York with advertising for their AI
companion. And anyone who has been in
New York advertising knew that this was
a setup because one of the cardinal
rules is you don't want to leave white
space on any ads that are in the subway
because they're just going to get
tagged, drawn on, filled in with stuff
that is not going to be on brand. So
anyone that's doing that media buy is
going to tell you you shouldn't do it
like this. But they knew what they
wanted and they knew the attention this
would garner and did it. and New York
becomes a canvas because there are so
many people there that are documenting
it. It's a very reactive population.
There's an outsized influence that comes
from the population there. When you do
those campaigns, because of both the
people that live there and the tourist
traffic, people get exposed to these
brands in a major way. And Supreme at
the time that I was there and at times I
visited prior to moving was dominating
by having extremely impactful campaigns
that were basically posted out of home.
They would show up on Tumblr. They would
show up on early Instagram and you would
see the faces of Kate Moss or Moresy or
Mike Tyson with the Supreme logo that
drove a significant amount of people to
want to go hunt down that store. And
similarly enough, when I moved to LA,
that Fairfax location was a place where
people who I knew frequented, hung out,
and for someone transplanting to the
city from New York, which plenty of
people do, there's something immediately
familiar. And it's worth calling out
that this brand wouldn't be what it was
without those places, without starting
with that like skate shop fixture rooted
in the actual communities there. You can
spend thousands on brand campaigns, but
if you can't track what's working,
you're leaving money on the table. This
video is brought to you by Bit.ly, the
tool that helps marketers run
sophisticated campaigns with branded
short links, custom domains, trackable
QR codes, and landing pages. One of the
biggest questions in influencer
marketing in particular is how do you
track ROI? With Bitley's analytics
dashboard, you can see performance by
campaign, by influencer, and a big one
by audience location. I have actually
used this in the past, supporting brands
that are in retail to show them interest
in regions they have stores in. All this
means that every click becomes
measurable data that you can act on.
Bitly also gives you branded short links
with custom domains. So, your content
doesn't just look professional, it
builds trust, and trust boosts
click-through rates. Because links are
secure, audiences trust every click. And
for bigger campaigns, Bitly lets you
shorten links in bulk. And redirect them
at any time. This is a lifesaver if you
change things mid campaign or want to
move to a custom landing page, update
your offer. We have all been there. And
you can use Bitly to generate QR codes
for events or packaging. You can track
all those things in the same dashboard.
If you want to stop guessing and measure
real results with your links, Bit.ly is
the road map to track, grow, and
optimize your marketing campaigns.
Signing up is free. You can check the
link in the description to get started.
And this is important because what
people forget to talk about when you
talk about Supreme is just the sheer
magnitude of the people involved. So
what do I mean by people? So when I look
at Supreme, I don't even necessarily see
a brand. I see more of a magazine
because really what they've done is just
an immense curation of skateboarders,
celebrities, but that fit their own
mold. Musicians, directors, and
photographers and brands. They've
curated a world where there are so many
of those people coming in and out. Like
if you were to go say, I want to make a
list of every skater that Supreme has
sponsored inside their from 19 mid '90s
to now run, it would be more than you
could count. I mean, just off the top of
my head, and if you have any background
in skate, you know how significant it
is. But Jason Dill, Mark Gonzalez, Taon
Jones, who we'll get to in a minute,
Shawn Pablo, Noel Smith, Beatatric,
their female skater, Kater Silia with
this huge social media presence, actual
legends, like so many legends skated for
Supreme. And everyone wants to talk
about the collabs and the brands and the
logos and the hype drops, but at its
core comes these people. And what I want
to call out these people is that they
not only propelled skate culture
continually into the mainstream as it
was kind of e ebbing in many ways, but
they also supported it fiscally in a
significant way. There's been a lot of
news recently about the Tyon Jones
lawsuit with Supreme where Supreme was
paying him $1 million a year to stay
headto toes Supreme at all times. Now,
he's a skater of a super high visibility
level. I think he has a Louis Vuitton
deal now. But a million dollars to
support somebody in that level of sport
per year as a clothing sponsor isn't
just doing something positive for the
brand. That's doing them doing something
back positive for skate culture. And it
didn't start like that, right? They had
to build up over the 30 years the brand
has been in business, which is another
thing to remember and think about. It's
been around since that mid '90s. This is
not even though we had the phenomenon in
the 2000s. A lot of history here.
Someone had to embrace those
communities, get them in the videos,
continue to curate who all these best
people are, figure out the routes with
which to pay them, and then continue
that time and time again, then release
legendary skate video after legendary
skate video. And I grew up in Hawaii
around surf skate culture, not amazing
at any of them, but knowing a lot of how
this works. And the directors and the
people that are shooting this and
putting these videos together are just
as important often as the people being
inside of them because they know what's
popular, how the culture moves, they can
wrangle talent. And so both getting the
skaters and the directors to work and
continue to put this output out is an
interesting and unique approach that
really really leveraged this subculture.
And it's interesting because you look at
Supreme, there aren't like overwhelming
amazing lookbooks, right? The majority
of their lookbooks are all presented in
extremely plain format, right? They're
letting the clothes speak. They are
plain white gray background lookbooks
for the vast majority of all this
content. And then the skate videos, the
actual action, the films in the streets
became the lookbooks. And there's a very
strong delineation between showing those
clothes and then showing the action and
the people inside of them as like the
real content. But when you look at a
brand's role within the people that it
serves, Supreme didn't just have you be
cool automatically by wearing the logo.
It taught you how to be cool by the
curation of the people. You may not have
heard of Morrisy. You may not have heard
of Neil Young. Even now with the latest
musician there is NBA Young Boy, right?
They are putting people on to some
extent. And they're doing that across
everything. an introduction to music, an
introduction to subculture, an
introduction to directors,
photographers, to personalities, and
then most importantly for everybody to
other brands and the ecosystem of
brands. We'll get there in a second. I
want to end on the point that to do
that, this is one of the most underrated
things now that people can start brands
from their apartments. that can do
everything online is that the amount of
juggling that it takes to get this many
skaters, this many directors, this many
lookbooks, this many rappers, this many
brand collabs requires so much
interpersonal relationships, so much
hunting stuff down and texting and DMing
and calling and meeting up and keeping
those relationships over time and
figuring out where to put that inside of
an arc that that is a massively
underrated brand building skill. And the
thing that Supreme did better than any
of these other things, drop culture,
merchandising, all these things that
they were amazing at, the people
curation was really the key to it. And
it's also something that we haven't seen
to that extent inside this new
generation of brands. We've seen it, you
know, down some niches, but no one's
harnessed the internet community to this
level in such an interesting way. And
there is certainly some fantastically
interesting brands to be built out of
that. But this slides over into brands.
So when you look at the collabs, we all
know and are familiar with some of the
more prolific collabs they have, but
there are just so many Vans, Keith
Herrings, Nike, John Smemedley, the Polo
company, Hannes, APC, Budweiser, Oreo,
Burberry, Louis Vuitton, Stone Island,
Timberland, Clarks. You can literally go
there's it's hard to actually find
companies there hasn't been a Supreme
collab with. But what's interesting
there and worthwhile knowing is that's a
machine. And the most popular ones like
the Northace collab became a yearly
release, right? Right? It's like, hey,
this thing is popular enough, has enough
cultural resonance, important enough.
Let's actually make it a marquee inside
our calendar, which I feel like now
there's a lot of like splash collabs, a
lot based after the Supreme model. But I
think the real one to take away is that
North Face saying, "Hey, cool. We're
doing a bunch of these collabs. You're
doing collabs to validate market fit,
right? Does our consumer care about
this? Is it important to them?" And the
ones that stand out, it's like, okay, we
should be doing that annually. Now, that
becomes a thing that we can build upon
and repeat. I think it's a really
important way to look at this
collaboration culture. And with that
collab comes the power of the logo. And
one of the most interesting Supreme
parts is obviously everyone knows the
box logo. That's the most prolific. But
most of the Supreme clothes do not have
that logo on there, but still say
Supreme. And this is where it's
important to understand that visual
language of a brand where you may have
your one marquee logo, but then there's
marquee logo that's not always
available. Has a higher price point.
It's harder to get. There's a bunch of
sub logos that are more readily
available. So you can represent the
brand without that a lower price point
usually more available. But that's
thought through inside the iconography
of how the brand is presented. And if
you look at any Supreme drop to this
day, the box logos sell out first, have
the highest resale value, and then it's
a trickle down, right? Small box logos
and anything else with a name on it is
probably still available if you get to
the drop relatively early. So, a lot of
people end up copying that when the
other stuff gets sold out and that
proliferates the brand name. And then
what's usually left over is more like
basics, stuff that doesn't have any logo
on is more readily available for anyone
to buy. If you missed out, you're not
going to go tune in with the drop, you
can still buy into Supreme. and they
have enough care and design and make
good enough stuff and a lot of it at
more reasonable price points than the
resale value or the highest end of
Supreme. Then when you do buy into that,
you begin to look at it more as a staple
business because that's what people can
buy into. That's a little fascinating
hierarchy to think through. And one last
note I'll have on those kind of drops is
that also because of all the stores,
there's lots of city specific releases
and drops, which is another thing that
again in the internet era, we've thought
less about that uh is impactful for
building a community around where you
are. And one of the brands I think has
done that really well now is uh is
Bandit Running opening their Chicago
store just recently for this last
Chicago marathon and really putting a
display into this moment in time
happening in Chicago. Their display of
store and the releases around that was
really well done. But then I next I want
to talk about pricing and luxury and
this idea of high price. So Supreme
basically I won't say pioneered but
certainly got the most exposure for the
crossover of street wear into luxury.
Luxury's obsession with the high price
points were being commanded by street
wear because of its demand that they
wanted to latch into. And so with two
collaborations, Reova for luggage and
then Louis Vuitton, both sets of those
brands were able to accomplish something
brand new, exposing the luxury customer
to be able to buy into cool in a new
way, getting the highest end price of
that streetear customer who does have a
lot of money to be able to buy into
luxury and be exposed to new luxury. And
this was a turning point at culture in
general for how people consumed brands
like Louis Vuitton, like Burberry to
where it is very mass consumption. There
is actually very little reason for 90%
of anybody, 99% anyone watching this
video to ever have consumed luxury.
Honestly, even at the amount of money
I've made in my life, I really have no
right or reason to buy a luxury product.
It's for generational wealth. when you
really look at the price point versus
the value of the product you're getting.
But it became so ingrained in culture,
it became so normalized a lot because of
these street wear collapse a lot because
of that era in time that allowed those
brands to move downward into the market
to like change that nature of
aspiration. It was a really important
trend to be a part of. But right now, if
you were trying to repeat that playbook,
that doesn't really work anymore.
Everything is overpriced. Medium price
where people are charging a good value
for something amazing with lesserk known
design is like the sweet spot now. or
things that are expensive or rare for
the sake of that just don't have the
same appeal because it's so much of it.
So, what is this new the way that luxury
and street wear collided with Supreme?
Like, what's this new generation look
like? And one that caught my eye from
literally just this last week is a Trap
Star and the New York Jets because I
really feel like the new luxury in terms
of a consumer demographic being exposed
to brands and vice versa is sports. And
we've seen that creeping of, you know,
soccer clubs hiring creative directors.
You see me wear lots of uh Venitzia
merch prior. They take their art
direction and merchandise extremely
seriously with Kappa and Nocta and more.
But the true level of brand crossover
especially for big things like American
football and fashion has happened with
the athletes, right? And you've seen
brands like Rude and Namas really cross
over into that like highest end street
wear, lowest end luxury all the way to
full luxury with someone like Amir by
really basing their playbook a lot
around like the athletic consumer. But
then there's the athletic fan. And I
think that the Trapstar Jets is an
interesting one of like how street wear
and a major NFL team can interact. I
don't think it's happening at a high
price point the way it is luxury. I
think it's an accessible price point.
But that frontier, it's, you know, it's
already started. We're not at the
beginning of the curve here. I'm not
calling out something that's not
obvious, but this is a major trend
that's still climbing the pure size of
the adoption curve and what that looks
like. But now I want to talk about the
fall of Supreme. Right? We rose through
all these things through all this
community, all these people, all these
amazing videos and content and exposure
and collaborations. We'll get into
product here in a moment, but they sold
to VF and they resold again to Lxotica,
$2 billion sale and $1.5 billion sale.
They had their big blow up with Tmaine
Emory when he came in for creative
director. And in general, you would look
around the world, if you were to ask
nine out of 10 people who are familiar
with Supreme like, did Supreme fall off?
And they would say yes. But here's where
I think this is an interesting video to
make because I think the real answer is
actually no. When you look at the sales,
you look at this, they're a public
company. So from their first quarter
owned by a public company, so they had
$142 million in I think it's a I think
it was like a 4month period of their
initial reporting in 2021. They've done
in 2022 561 million, 523 million, and
then 539 million in 2024.
>> What are your superpowers again? I'm
rich.
>> So they are still putting off half a
billion in revenue a year. I believe it
is sitting at around 100 million in cash
spit off from that. And so the truth is
they haven't really fallen off at all.
What has fallen off is hype piece
culture has fallen off. Sneaker culture
has freef fall. In fact, you would
assume that Supreme would have fallen
off much more. But what they haven't
done is the expectation of a company
like VF. VF bought Supreme was saying,
"Cool, there's 500 million a year here.
We can take this to a billion dollars a
year." And the guys selling Supreme were
smart about it because there probably
wasn't that next level there. No matter
how amazing the execution was with
timing, with culture, with what it takes
to execute a brand like that, have a
billion dollars a year is probably the
extent a brand like that lives. And so
the aspiration to do more was probably
asking a little too much.
>> I'm tired of this, grandpa.
>> That's too damn bad.
>> But the ability to keep that at this
level is interesting cuz think about
what's happened since. So the box logo
may not have the same power. You may not
say that in the street. I haven't worn
this shirt in years. I brought it out
the closet. I got two pieces of Supreme
left in my collection. Everything else
went to grill, but they've clouded with
Corteiz, Spider, Young Thugs brand,
actual hipster stuff like uh like
Japanese stuff like Hysteric Glamour,
like real like cult brands. They are
still rolling out really interesting
collabs, introducing this new generation
of Supreme Consumer to a bunch of these
interesting brands, still functioning in
that older brother role, still having
lines on top. And I was in New York just
the other month. They had taken over a
spot off like Hston and Bowie. They had
a huge pop-up. And things are very much
more available, right? You can go on
their website right now. There's like a
$62 mini box logo ton there, which is
like a super reasonable price to buy
into Supreme. They're still putting up
these massive numbers. They're just
doing it without that pressure of like
the high like everyone's going to fight
over that box logo. And it's being done
without that eye of like Supreme,
Supreme, Supreme always in the middle of
the conversation, but quietly putting up
numbers of one of the biggestear brands
in the world. And so I think that that
idea of falloff like isn't quite real.
It's just the evolution. And then when
you talk about the value, what did the $
1.5 billion of their secondary sale look
like? Yes, they could make that back in
cash bit off or ebida or whatever over
the next 15 years or more than that if
you have to then account for what that
money would have made you. But it's the
fact that brands at that level always
have an opportunity to come back. We've
seen this everyone from Abberrombie and
Fitch Gap and people have been able to
ride the waves of popularity up and down
until the end of time based on a name
that is known versus having to pull a
name and an identity like out of the
essence of the world and the internet.
So many people know it is unreplicable.
again. So, there's still a lot of value
there. And I think that that descent,
while it's not clothing that same
consumer would choose to purchase as
much, there's still an amazing
interesting business. Now, let's talk
about the playbook. How does one
actually get there? What are the most
important things here? So, the first
thing we haven't done yet is
merchandising, the development of
product. So, they were one of the first
brands to truly release a ton of oddball
stuff. Fire extinguishers, bricks,
nunchucks, MTA cards, pinball machines,
bicycles, motorbikes, everything under
the sun. They have their merchandising
team. legendary, best-in-class, and
you'll see a lot of people like Hidden
puts out a lot of random objects now,
but a few people really do it well in a
really interesting way. The one I'll
call out is Vandy. Vandy the Pink does a
super interesting job. Furniture, really
unique items, has crafted a brand I
really feel like is a natural successor
inside his niche to like the kind of
worldbuilding Supreme and and Bape and
previous generation of brands did. But
that merchandising is uh embraces the
idea of product marketing. You've heard
me talk about is hard to pull off and
actually have the quality be anything
good and to get people to care and buy
into it at that level. But sometimes for
a lot of people it's a lot more
interesting than buying clothes. Then
there was the people operations. Like I
imagine they had to use a CRM at one
point to be able to manage all the brand
deals, the skaters, the photographers,
then the personalities that come. That's
the other interesting part. Look, Terry
Richardson shot a lot of Supreme stuff.
I'm sure that there was all kinds of
nightmare issues that came up around
that. Obviously, we saw what happened
with Tyon Jones. Just managing that
level of relationships and people with a
lot of people that are entertainers and
have egos and are in that world is like
sounds honestly like an absolute
nightmare. It would be extremely hard to
figure out. But overall for a brand that
people operations is a underlooked
thing. I have a project where I've been
like sneakily toying with like a new
experiment with this inside of a brand
and like how brand touch points work.
But that is still something that I feel
like if any brand wants Alpha. If you're
like I make the same t-shirts as
everybody else or I got the same
manufacturers as everybody else for my
hoodies and my sweats. What is your
people ops? Not just seeding free stuff
to get people to wear it. How are you
building your version of the Stousy
tribe or what Supreme did here inside
your own region or your own subcultures
in a really interesting way? And then
that retail idea, what are those key
markets? How do we make our stores more
than just something? I feel like running
brands have really co-opted this brand,
a bandit, tracksmith. I was by like a
tracksmith in London. I'd been to I'd
hosted a tracksmith run club with Jordan
and Ashwin in Boston at one point. I was
by one while I was in London. There's a
run club happening out there. A bunch of
young people and people of all walks of
life really. You seeing them put the
activity around it in an interesting
way. But to give you your blueprint as a
creative, what can you really take away
from this? What are your things to think
about? It starts with who. How can you
bring people in the worlds and
subcultures together in an interesting
way, whether that's in your design work
or as a brand or a studio or an agency
or a collective? What is your approach
to that? And this applies to all
businesses. As many as you of you know,
I went back to work uh part-time with a
firm in beauty. And what's interesting
about them is even the fact that they
call people like me, and I'm not the
only person on that roster, but they put
together, they're like, "Cool, this is
how normal private equity firms look at
approaching this world, but we want to
have people that are like have influence
and specialty inside of creative
strategy and social. So, we're going to
put that on our team. And we're going to
match that up with your traditional like
Harvard MBAs. And that's an interesting
way to start with with who? And then
iconography. Do you what is your box
logo equivalent? Do you have something
you can hold on a pedestal that could
mean more than your standard
iconography? And how are you kind of
testing that? And the idea like
ritualizing your calendar, the way they
had Thursday drops or the yearly with
the Northace like what is that cadence
and how you approach things and can you
really hold tight to it and make it
amazing because it compounds over time.
People expect something interesting. And
then collaboration being an art. They
did this with discipline, with
relentlessness, with vehicles to execute
under. I guarantee they were like stock
contracts of like this is how we do it.
This is what we pay. This is who funds
what. They had an approach and they
repeated it. I do want to have a video
all about collabs and bring in an expert
at some point in the future. So that's
like in the pipeline. A lot of you have
a lot of questions about that. And I
will always shout out the licensing expo
in Las Vegas cuz a lot of people don't
actually collab. They just pay for a
royalty percentage of this. And that
licensing expo, you have access to a ton
of IP when you go there. every head,
every metal band, all kinds of oddball
music and toys and games that you can
basically buy into for collaboration,
which is what more brands than you think
do. And then the idea of like scarcity
and the hygiene of of scarcity, what's
really available when, what really has
value, resale, what that looks like.
Again, a harder game than ever, but an
interesting one to think through. But
overall, a fascinating brand and thing
to look at. I hope you all enjoy my
perspective. As usual, I've varied away
a little bit away from like the pure art
direction videos here. coming back with
another art direction video in the next
week or so that's really more focused on
that to think more about the holistic
look and feel of like the branding and
marketing world and what you can learn
from it. As always, more coming soon, so
please like and subscribe. I appreciate
it always so much. Let me know any other
brands you'd want me to do inside the
comments as I prepare next year's list.
And thank you all so much for watching.
[Music]