today we're going to talk about viral
products specifically products that
people make for their clothing lines for
coffee shops cpg products accessories
HomeGoods that look so good on social
media that when you make good content
about them they get an outsized amount
of views and this video I'm going to
break down easily 20 examples of those
products and the content they make and
why it works I'm going to talk about
viral products as a collection anchor or
as an anchor for a brand versus it being
its entire identity and I'm going talk
about it brands that just focus on viral
and then we'll talk a bit about the
authenticity of making things that are
viral the longevity and how it impacts
brand identity throughout so first off
I'm going to talk about a lot of
clothing in this video because there's a
lot of viral clothing items but I'm not
just going to leave it to that and we're
going to start off with this beverage
video from this Cafe because I want to
show you that this is is about something
that like brick and mortar businesses
can do businesses that create any kind
of like supplement product or recipe
based product or food product clothing
product HomeGoods product even if you're
you know advertising your yoga studio
whatever it is don't think that you're
cting out of a viral product strategy
and so this is basically just about
making an aesthetic drink and you'll
notice that it is filmed in great light
you know this not quite golden hour
light but certainly good light but
you'll see this happen frequently with
cafes and things like that there's a
local cafe to me called kit they have a
like Uzu matcha combo that really just
looks good on camera a lot of people
order it looks good on camera sure it
tastes good as well but there is
something to be said for you walk into a
cafe you see a drink that looks crazy
and people go oh I want to get that they
see it on social media they want to go
go to the location this video for this
Cafe is 605,000 likes that's why I want
to start with it and is purely off the
Aesthetics of the drink there's two
principles to know here one is there's
the ability to kind of look at anything
and say can we take an aesthetic twist
to it so any standard service you can
basically go to the lever of how do we
make this look cool enough it stands out
on social and then the second thing is
what is the video format that works so
for a location or something that's
offered at a place like say this was a
pizza place you'll see this caption do
you want to go grab matcha same thing
could be said for do you want to go grab
pizza a viral looking pizza you want to
go to whatever Gelato Cafe if you have
the look and feel this is a simple
repeatable one- shot video it's really
based on the light more than anything
like and the process and look of the
product and should be how you're looking
at creating stuff like that is getting
not just your account because this is
non account but getting creators and
other people who are around you or who
are local involved as well so this is
another example in a HomeGoods brand
where basically they've taken a very pop
art looking feel and obviously this one
is like Nike branded that kind of old
englishy font and apply it to something
traditional and this is a strategy for a
type of viral product it's saying I'm
going to take something traditional and
I'm going to apply a new wave look to it
is one of those things that works very
well on social and then when we talk
about the video content he is just
presenting it literally the spin is what
makes this video because you watch it
you see the sides and you are basically
incentivized naturally in your head to
watch it finish spinning and then the
whole process starts again but this
entire brand that we scroll through here
he has made really cool looking stuff
appeals to a very certain demographic it
has a repeatable looking feel that you
can identify specifically as his and the
entire brand exists around a viral
product concept if he was just making
vases that had a more standard look it
would be a lot harder to get attention
on social media but all of these have a
standout look and it's a trademark for
him people can tell as soon as they see
the font and the form factor that it is
one of his products and he does that in
different color treatments different
ways Etc but this is an example of the
entire brand was concepted around a
visual look that is built to succeed on
social media and in a category you don't
often see on social media so if you had
a vase business and you want to do the
same thing you'd be really looking at
okay he kind of owns this like tattoo
style meets Old English like large font
look here what are other things with
which I can do do I want to apply like
an anime aesthetic for it like what if I
was to do goth opium vases whatever it
is running through that Aesthetics list
and I do want to do a video that's like
Aesthetics and why they perform at some
point but we'll get there and then aen
in how you apply it to your category all
right now I want to talk about Umbro and
umr's comeback and just a viral product
as part of a collection right so that
last brand bases almost its entire brand
on things that are inherently viral
before that that was just one drink
offered at a cafe that gets at some
level of virality when umro decided to
come back and they hired this creative
director from slam jam and they
basically began putting out amazing
stuff they did a couple things that are
cool marketing probably worth its own
video but this chain mail Jersey was one
that is just an excellent concept and I
like about this is the other two things
if you're looking at these things
objectively with taste kind of have an
inherent corniness and corniness whether
it's a small amount or a large amount
sells I am a Serial victim of using that
for my own success and you have to kind
of recognize when it's useful to be
tasteful or not but this is an extremely
tasteful like more of a high fashioned
approach being taken by a soccer brand
that gets featured on people like
Outlander who are curators of good taste
but this is an example of getting
attention for the brand by the single
item that I don't know if it's for sale
I don't if they can buy of people are
actually going to wear it via chain mail
but it brought attention to the brand
and made a statement for the brand at
that period that we are now in the
cultural conversation purely by this one
piece as then part of the entire story
that the brand is telling and so I want
to point this out to to basically brands
that are trying to establish their
Identity or want to capitalize on this
but have a more subdued like I wouldn't
say Umbro as like an edgy brand prior
like even if they're making good-looking
stuff you know they're making kind of
more current stuff having that one thing
that is viral and showcased on many
places is a really interesting way to do
it and this is another technique and
it's a great technique to apply same
technique as you kind of saw with the
vase just a little bit different is how
can you take a traditional thing and do
it in an insane material right could
this jersey be a full suit of armor
could it be you know completely in like
thatch suede whatever it is as a
technique to have in your toolkit for
any product to think about how you make
it more viral and then I would be remiss
to talk about this category at all
without talking about arguably what is
the precursor to all this I didn't want
to leave with it because I know most
people will just scroll away from the
video as soon as you see these but this
is a classic example of of this kind of
principle in action perhaps gone too far
but what I want to talk about here is
the roll out tactic for this so this is
a inherently viral product from the look
but they debuted it with influence right
and that's something I want a lot of
Brands to think about if you are a brand
that is rolling out something like this
for the first time or you have a item in
your collection we'll talk about
collection design here in a minute then
having someone anchor that right having
someone who is relatively she was Niche
famous she comes out wearing the product
to begin to kick it off and it Sparks a
cultural conversation then it was then
her and then a number of other
influencers and then people wanted to
get in on the moment of being involved
in the launch and this Playbook
obviously feels like forever ago but was
only 2023 and is a good example of if
you have that moment you have the
opportunity to try to make it go viral
on your own or you can get basically
almost guarantee virality by adding that
concept of viral PL product plus viral
influencer which in a lot of cases if
you want to generate a moment will be
worth the money because people that want
to particip in that moment will
immediately be reaching out to you and
you'll begin to have like basically
clout happening in your inbox another
great example so obviously just like the
design of the bag and the look here
again leveraging a popular aesthetic
you're basically taking CET applying it
its scale putting their own kind of
twist on it but it is the anchor you
know an anchor product for this brand to
stand out on social media to get 177,000
likes on a bag when not all their
products would necessarily get that and
this is what I want to bring up as a
good point here is that this is like not
a super utility driven bag I don't think
we're going to see like a ton of people
out in the streets with it it may be a
statement piece people use to go to
something really special which is its
own kind of demographic Market but like
you need to look at the place that your
product has inside the catalog right and
this is where I want to talk about
collections where you can use viral
products as the anchor for a launch what
we saw in the me old China Brands their
entire brand revolves around having
something that looks good on social
media that will inherently get views
because it looks better but if you are a
brand that does not necessarily have a
bunch of products that consistently will
do that and you don't want them to be
your identity then it's about having
these statement standout pieces that
anchor The Collection because what it
does is when people see that viral video
of the bag that we saw there they begin
to get a level of curiousness about the
brand you begin to enter the
conversation around all the things that
the brand offers get to the actual
collection page and even though that bag
might not be the thing that people buy
they may go ahead and say hey I see this
skirt or this wrap or this corset or
whatever it is and this is the product
that I become most interested in and to
reinforce the point that I had earlier
about the chain mail Jersey this is just
basically another application of the
same exact idea but on an accessories
product I want to call this out as an
accessory product because you this
happens across categories it does not
always need to be apparel obviously a
tie is quasi apparel but it's not like
you're selling a suit or a jacket that
same concept of material transformation
can equal inherent virality and then
this video where they're actually
showing the process behind making it is
just another example of doing that and I
love the format of like show the Finish
thing really quick show the process it
takes to make it because people are
going to want to see the finished thing
again that first shot if it's a viral
item and you let go of it pretty quick
they're going be like okay I want to see
more of that but then all of a sudden
they're in a story and they know the
story has an end they know okay this is
going to end up with a better view of
what I'm happening you get to watch it
come together that basically makes
people watch the video through you're
basically ensuring watch Time by
utilizing this format which is a really
crucial idea to be thinking about and
then the same thing can apply to
Interiors as well or again this is a
statement piece I actually do think
people would put this inside their house
they're taking something familiar they
are changing its appearance to be
inherently viral and it is an anchor
item to get people to post and recognize
the design of the studio and just a
reminder that this does exist across
categories and again this obviously is a
blinged out version but it's relatively
classy as an option to be able to
present inside that world to say hey
this is more of an art piece it's more
of a statement thing it actually could
make a subtle room really pop as a
contrast item worth thinking about and I
want to point this one out from Vandy
another one that feels inherently
interesting where it's taking a Garin
and adding a simple thing to it like
like the ears that we have here that is
this kind of in between where it has a
little bit of virality from it it's not
hugely distant or overly wild but kind
of adds that little element to it that
actually makes it like this is the kind
of thing that people will you'll see
this in the streets you it's an
approachable version of this that is
actually wearable which is kind of that
middle ground between pure attention
getting and attention getting but it's
going to probably make some sales that I
think he executed really well all right
so brief in by I am back for more so
this is an example of using a viral item
purely as a brand place these are Stone
Island G wagon rims that they posted and
it's not something that's available for
sale as sad as it is I also believe it's
likely a hazard based on how rims work
but but basically you they debuted the
photos there's obviously this billboard
that they they put out with it but this
is more starting a brand conversation
from it I actually don't like the idea
of putting out like a viral thing that
no one can get their hands on especially
in today's era I actually think you
should make some of them and get them in
people's hands and have them available
no matter how vanity it is because we're
in an era where people will buy it and
it becomes an actual engageable consumer
experience or at least like put them in
the stores or let them take photos on it
whatever it is but this is a good
example they're just using this as a
marketing tactic this is product as
marketing creating a one-of-one thing
specifically to raise brand awareness if
you have recognizable iconography and
kind of the clout of someone like Stone
island or if you are trying to achieve
that in your space in a relatively
recognizable this is a interesting way
to do it by doing something like like a
G wagon Rim still on if you want to send
these to me I I will put them on the
wagon we will put that in the video
we're going to talk about this concept
of viral as a brand identity in a moment
but one someone who I think does it
particularly well like kids super and
House of errors are two people that
basically have things that are
inherently tasteful inherently viral
like lightly viral but make it part of
the identity where you're always
expecting the unexpected from them where
you're expecting a Twist on anything
regular you see and a lot of brands are
making things pure purely viral this is
an interesting case this is a watch
brand where they're basically taking the
card crash and they're saying cool we're
just going to make an affordable version
of it and that is our entire brand hey
we're knocking off someone else's
concept obviously there's always
something to like knocking off a concept
making it affordable is like a thing and
they see some success from it but
they're knocking off that concept and
that's all they do is like this viral
design they're not like offering
anything else but this like concept of
virality that brand exists specifically
to be a viral take like on an existing
item obviously they have this other kind
of like viral looking item they have
they have there and like that the core
identity of the brand and so while I
think they can achieve sales and sales
is honestly for a lot of econ people can
purely be the goal that's totally okay
for brand longevity this might be a
starting point they can transition out
of but they're kind of setting
themselves up for some degree of like
failure from a longevity standpoint and
again if your goal is money does not
matter you can make money doing exactly
this and if they are smart and Savvy
potentially they can pivot that into
something bigger later we all start
somewhere I don't want to hate on it
there's a difference between someone
like House of ARS who's making
inherently viral things but they are
unique they are interesting there's
always some conversation about who's
referencing what like regarding them but
they are able to continually take
interesting things and put a spin on
them but do it in a way that is not like
overdoing it in any particular fashion
is not too derivative in any other way
and make it as a core of the brand
identity that it's going to be
interesting and a tasteful nature of
viral another example in the interior
space and obviously like a very Artful
creation but this is uh this is one
where like every product another one
where every product like lives inside
this viral realm but they're all insane
this is basically art as brand like
personified where you get kind of these
pieces that you can't believe are real
versus AI where they're creating this
like amazing immersive world around this
idea of oneon-one in art and sculpture
but it is presented in a way that is
like inherently going to be successful
online these are inherently sharable
curatable people can make content about
them if you do buy them and you post it
you're going to go viral as well like
that is the dream right is if you are
trying to make a brand that takes Mass
advantage of organic social media you
need that flow when you post it no
matter what still image real whatever
you get a ton of organic views off it
you don't have to pay for it it just
just shoots off because of the nature of
the design which each one of these
achieves and then second you get to
follow up with other people are going to
curate it and talk about it the way I
make green screen about cool content and
cool products I'm like great I'm going
to include this in this YouTube video
and this Instagram so people are going
to know about it from curation or just
like I've shown a bunch of Outlander and
Saint posts on on this where they're
curating
to a certain degree more people realize
it but then whoever actually gets it in
their house they're like they are going
to want to post it anyone that interacts
with it is going to want to post it or
at least recommend it in real life or
send a picture to their spouse and you
have now maximized the organic virality
you can possibly get without having to
deploy ad dollars and that is the
foundation of this entire concept and so
you have to basically look at where can
you fall in that chain to make Max
Advantage for where you are this is a
fun example of like a simple accessory
around this that allows you to make fun
content this is the kind of idea that
any company could do in the space a dut
shop could do this a dut company could
do this a coffee company could do this a
coffee shop could do this a fashion
company could do this a design studio
could do this where they just made a
really fun-looking coffee holder four
people to walk around with is inherently
looks viral on social media and they're
making a video about how to use it that
then could get remade like 50 times and
so that's another key concept I want to
talk about in the scheme of these things
is that one thing people don't
understand about virality is that like
if you have a a video do good for your
products you should continue to remake
that video with slight variations in
perpetuity there's a couple ways to look
at it on Tik Tok you can just basically
make that same video every day on an
account and it's not going to hurt you
on Instagram it's like when can I
reasonably you know repeat this without
having people get too tired of it it's
like well okay once every two weeks once
every month you'll note that like as a
Creator you'll see I update my most
popular videos like every like six
months and basically add a couple new
things or make it better to a better
Creator and then put the same thing out
cuz I know it works we need to find that
formula for you and should be then
repeating that and then also getting
that in the hands of of others which I
mentioned back when we talked about the
first product of the matcha if you have
a viral format get other people to do it
the idea of taking that brief and going
wide if you have something you know hits
that's when you activate influencer
right one of the big things about
influencer marketing that I feel like
doesn't work often enough is that
they'll ask the influencer to come up
with a brief you get you get 50-50 shot
or they'll come with a brief that they
kind of know sucks if you have a video
that goes viral for your brand take that
brief to the influencers right because
then you're basically saying hey I'm
almost guaranteeing you vities the
influencers immediately like oh great
this is not going to flop because most
branded content is not good and then
they're going oh actually this could be
successful here how I can put my Twist
on it and you know you're getting the
views in Roi back scale these Concepts
whether it's the your one-off item like
this or the core of your brand like make
the most of that bravest with a classic
example of this kind of with the
Footwear they're an interesting one
where they do have like a lot of kind of
staple regular items but then they're
they're running Footwear like purely as
viral where this is just a funnel right
like this stuff is is wild it is on The
Fringe of like is this cool do I really
want this for my brand but it gets them
so much attention 188,000 likes you know
16,000 likes that it then helps them
move their more core products which are
like nice and well done that is is
basically a funnel for them right a
viral funnel for Success then sell more
typical stuff and I have friends of mine
have these shoes and really really like
them that's worth thinking about it in
context they have a lot of items that
look good naturally like everything here
is designed to be lightly good on social
media but there's a difference between
that and this but they are making like
social media friendly products and then
leaning into to the big social media
success because it gets them the
followers that consume the other things
and we have to talk about Bo Carlson's
um I don't even know how to pronounce
the brand avav avavav so they did this
as a collab with Adidas where again this
is purely to get attention and Adidas
doing a collab with their brand is to
get viral attention that's the only
purpose of that right they are not a
brand where people are coming to them
constantly for their clothing because
it's wearable it is a viral brand in
concept their creative director is a
master of virality from how they debuted
it and how they debuted the shots and
they're very known for their Runway
items this is another you know another
product that they have in the Canon this
was the you what really blew them up
this runway show and some of those like
big fuzzy boots that you saw in there
and obviously seen very variations of
like The Stomping and the models falling
and like all the different things that
this has led to like what we see here
this is a brand engineered for virality
in the high fashion realm we've seen
Brands engineered for virality now from
like the lowest kind of common
denominator we're selling a cheaper
version of a luxury good like all the
way up now to doing it at a high fashion
level and then you can see when someone
goes and collabs with them they are
doing that because they know they're
going to get this certain level of
eyeballs the way Adidas did on this
campaign and that is worth it for an
Adidas to be then considered next to
this to get those eyeballs to have that
conversation and for some people where
brand awareness is a big part of that
metric and then brand awareness
tangential to art for lack of a better
term is a a concept that big brands are
begin to look at if you become a vehicle
for that as a creative director or as a
brand it opens up a world of opportunity
and then another example of a brand that
leans really deep into that with with
fugazi who put together like interesting
good-looking products right with it all
have this kind of like viral component
of it that's done in an interesting way
that's built into the Brand's design and
it's interesting and as I reflect on how
I launched some of my kind of recent
products I've been thinking a lot about
this I designed a lot of things that to
spark conversation but I didn't have
like a single like shocking viral piece
looking back on it I would have gone for
one or two like way more viral pieces to
launch with but I do like the idea that
all of them can have a conversation
right so I did this video about the
beach pants I have the beach pants are
inherently see-through I knew that would
be a controversial topic but also a
really cool item if you and you actually
have it if you have it and you style it
it's amazing people like it both male
and female it sells a lot but it's going
to spark conversation online which is a
good thing for me I want to have that
conversation online and I saw it I made
a video about this got 100K plus views
whatever it is nothing hugely viral cuz
it's not inherently hugely viral but it
sparked your conversation people either
love it or they hate it and then you get
that innate mechanism when people do
that of people that love it kind of
Defending it or supporting it for that
reason and then when that video hits
like it was an immediate like 30 sales
or something like that and so you begin
to know like this formula now I'm going
to end with the formula like the formula
of more organic success when you're
launching whatever line you have or
brand you have or product you have is
how many videos you make to how many
sales that you make organically you
begin to get a a formula on that and
this is the formula for every Creator I
have all these calls with creators
people with big followings who've
launched Brands who don't sell enough
and they're like why am I not selling
enough of this product and obviously
there's some stuff around affinity and
fan base but actually the reason for
most of them is they expected it was
going to be some drop like a hype brand
and they were going to sell out
everything the first day when in reality
when you are a Creator or an influencer
you have an infinite ability to sell
with content that you make about it
right it's like okay all right you sold
40 t-shirts your first day of you bought
a thousand I'm like all right well how
many videos did you make that first day
okay you make two videos all right you
have a 20 t-shirt to video ratio so you
can sell the rest of that thousand
t-shirts but you're have to make 50
videos about it but guess what that is
your job as a Creator to be able to make
videos that sell product and whether you
are a brand account whether you are a
Creator whatever you have that has
access to to virality and organic growth
like that is the ratio to think about so
like when I did that pants video and I
sold 30 pants or whatever it looks like
now I know I still have another like 40
or so of those in stock so right now I
go hey cool that's two more videos I can
probably sell through that inventory
right there that is now my organic sales
to organic video ratio but that's what
you begin thinking about as a brand even
with collection design okay well how
many videos do I have to do about each
product to move that okay am I going to
move this the other stuff like naturally
through my email list through ads it
becomes a component you begin to think
about of like do I think this item is
viral when it goes viral does it sell a
lot and then how can I kind of test and
quantify that I tested that with a color
changing fabric concept I had I already
have the bag kind of designed but I
wanted to validate okay is this going to
go viral as much as I think it is it
went super viral like a 3 million view
video and it was like all right cool I
think I can get that for the same
product yeah I think I can do a million
views every time I make a video on that
concept and then with that how many do I
think I'm going to sell I think I could
probably sell a 100 per one of those
videos and so all of a sudden that helps
me forecast a bit of what I'm thinking
about and that's the conversation that
you can begin to have but you know that
the answer to selling more of those
things is always creating more content
and then the web you need to get into is
I can create more of that content myself
or I can enable other people to take the
successful formats I have and act on it
but no matter what brand stage you're at
starting a new brand and you want to get
attention you're going to use an anchor
viral product one viral product to
support the rest of your line whether
you're going to make a viral brand
concept where everything is designed to
be aesthetic and conversation starting
online or you're a bigger brand who
wants to get attention and be in the
online conversation and wants to
collaborate with someone who does that
like we saw with Adidas here or make it
part of their strategy like the way we
saw with Umbro that is how the viral
product landscape works and is worth
understanding because it is a tool that
is now built into the marketing and
branding toolkit going into the future
as always drop any comments or thoughts
that you have down below I'll happily
hit some of the questions I'm doing
longer form answers to questions on Tik
Tok all the time now I do a lot of like
offthe cuff videos there so if you have
a quick question I can probably answer
it faster there and we will be back with
more videos thank you for watching