today we are going to talk about some of
the best marketing campaigns and
marketing initiatives ever I'm going to
cover a wide swath from Fashion to
liquor to Cosmetics what are those
campaigns that resonate generationally
we're going to talk about why they're so
impactful and build out our toolkit as
marketers and people understanding the
world around us at the same time
covering diamonds dualingo Ralph luren
Lego absolute dois Keels all over let's
lock in and we're going to start with
one of my favorites and that's Ralph
Loren and there's two standout things
that I really associate with this brand
I think are perfect takeaways to have
and it all comes back to being an
ambassador of the American lifestyle and
the storytelling of that so we've all
seen these iconic print campaigns where
they basically put this idilic New York
adjacent horses skiing American
Lifestyle on display for Generations in
print letting the imagery talk for the
brand no tag lines just the basics of
the brand or the line has become
synonymous with this storytelling like
around the fabric of America in American
fashion but one of the C the campaign I
feel really ties this all together that
we see comes up every few years is Ralph
Lauren's choice to be the Olympic
provider where when you see the clothes
that people are wearing the uniforms
that they're wearing what happens when
we unveil anything they basically said
we are going to spend our money
sponsoring and making clothing for these
Olympic teams so that on a world stage
whenever everyone from America Tunes in
they see us as the brand that is the
ambassador and when the world Tunes in
and then watches America win a
disproportionate amount of all the
contests they are going to see our brand
as an ambassador and it's one of those
marketing campaigns that is so high
level that is often kind of overlooked
as to the power and impact it has
generationally by having a choice to say
we have this huge anchor moment that we
do again again and again this synonymous
with our Brand Story at the highest
level and being consistent like that
over time has benefits right I think
we've seen Olympic viewership dwindle
less and less people care in the
internet era than ever but then With
viral moments it comes right back and by
staying consist consistent with that all
of a sudden you know staying through a
downturn of less interest up into the
hey there's Tik Tok things happening
constantly and for any Olympic event
that goes down you begin to ride the
waves of the potential of working
through an initiative over time but
small Brands can learn from this too can
learn from having an anchor event at the
highest scale that portrays yourself in
your category I want to bring up Bandit
running for this so maybe not one of the
best marketing campaigns of all time but
certainly one that could turn into it if
continually executed is Bandit basically
said we're going to participate in the
Olympics as a smaller brand and in
running with their unsponsored project
where they say any any people that are
competing for their own places in there
that don't have a sponsor we will give
them unbranded clothing and they promote
the actual campaign itself and they took
this a step further but I think they
actually sponsored two Runners who lost
their sponsorship from St Vincent and
the Grenadines and they said hey we're
going to inside this Niche that we are
in play above our weight class in an
initiative that speaks to the Goodwill
promoted by the brand and then make this
a marquee that we go back to every
Olympics we have some variation of the
unsponsored project even though we're a
small brand and we're going to be able
to play again at a global scale at a
skill that's really recognized within
the pros inside our community and
leverage a similar strategy to what
we've seen Ralph luren do now for
Generations but shifting gears into
something completely different one of my
most favorite recent campaigns I feel
brands are really apt to learn from
right now is what we've seen from du
lingo and the DU lingo owl so a few
months ago I was speaking on a panel at
the notion conference in San Francisco
and I was actually moderating with the
social media manager from Duolingo and a
social media manager from from Arc I
think she's actually the head of
Storytelling was her title but at
dualingo was talking about some of the
workflows they happened there one thing
that stood out to me is they treat their
content creation process more like a
writer room where they really think of
their content from a comedy angle and so
we've all seen this owl right this owl
has permeated pop culture it is somehow
part of the squid games roll out it is
at the was at the brat concerts when
they were at their Peak is on social
media feeds in the way that any pop
culture character or influencer is and
has this like this ever Perpetual
association with anything going on in
culture and navigated in a way a
corporate Mass Scott simply never has
before and the important takeaway that I
have here is treating your marketing
like entertainment right that idea of
hey can we have our Brands mascot or our
Brand's influencers or our Brand's
content how do we treat that like a
writer room how do we make this episodic
how do we bring on more characters how
is our goal to be ubiquitous to this
level that may someone may never have
associated with a language app with
whatever it is you're building as
opposed to saying oh we need to make
more videos walking through our Brand's
products and I like to show that as a
great example of a modern brand of
something that shifts and moves with the
culture but it's also equally as
interesting to look at campaigns that
have lasted the length of time and have
expanded the life of an industry so
perhaps the most prolific marketing
campaign of all time is this idea of
diamonds are forever and if you pull up
even these specific debers ads where
they anchor the price you know basically
two month salary it's been the price
anchor of what a diamond should cost
when someone proposes to marry someone
else and this is interesting to me to
look at in the face of what this
achieved for them when lab diamonds came
out right so for decades and decades
they set mented that this rock that came
from the ground is now worth this
enormous sum that's a forever commitment
it's ingrained in our cultural Essence
but also that it has a set price that
really the minimum you should be
considering is is a two-month salary for
the price point so they anchored in
price by playing to the emotion of the
people that do it by setting a standard
of expectation between male and female
which is a dynamic that as much
marketing they could take advantage of
probably should but then look at how
that positioned itself for when lab
diamonds came out lab diamonds are
diamonds you can take them to a jeweler
they cannot tell them apart they are
chemic Al the same they are
significantly cheaper they're for all
intensive purposes every single person
there's almost no reason that they
shouldn't be buying a lab diamond versus
a regular Diamond but because of the
marketing that this industry had
cemented as a group that took way more
time than expected now when you survey a
group of people and you say you want a
lab Diamond a regular Diamond you'll see
a disproportionate amount say lab but
they basically bought themselves years
and years of this by having cemented
themselves at this high price point and
then also how they played the moment
when those diamonds came out some of
them released their own lab Diamond
lines at a significantly lower price
again price anchoring in the campaign
and saying this is actually worth less
than what we have is worth more and
again it's consumer psychology it didn't
last forever but it's extending the life
of this industry right versus watching
it just die outright and that's what a
great marketing campaign and a campaign
that potentially reaches across just
your brand and into category which you
should certainly be thinking about as a
category leader or a secondary in a
category is how do we give that Moe that
gives us time to figure out what do we
do with all these deers stores if
diamonds are not worth as much or if the
pricing has to change what does that
mean for our business model if you need
to figure that out in 4 months then your
brand is probably [ __ ] if you need to
figure that out over the course of 7
years you can probably come out with a
great plan and that is literally what we
are watching play out from the power of
this diamonds are forever campaign so
another one of my favorites a more
specific campaign is Patagonia don't buy
this jacket campaign so Patagonia has
lasted through generations as a brand
people believe in as a highquality
product as a mission driven brand that
people say I see transparency in their
supply chain they put an ad out in the
newspaper on black Friday saying don't
buy our product in fact reuse it sustain
it we'll help you repair it they stand
by their values when people started
using the wrong people to them you know
Venture Capital started using their
vests as merch they they cut their merch
programs they're a brand that stands by
their values and stays consistent with
them as opposed to Someone Like A
Northface you know who released that
kind of like gibberish AI Manifesto
campaign who's kind of lost a bit of the
plot over time and that has given
Patagonia room to maneuver so one of the
most interesting things of this last
year is Patagonia launching Provisions
so they said after I think they started
the 19 73 after 48 years or whatever of
being a brand 50 years we're going to
launch into a completely new category of
food not only food but like tinned fish
and that's an interesting choice to say
hey we have built this up we built up
this reputation and we're going to very
carefully move when we move we're going
to move all in on it they said there's
an overlap between our customer we can
leverage our existing retail
relationships and we're going to be able
to put this line out and succeed with it
in a completely different market and not
only they done that they've now expanded
it now they've got sardines and beans
all these things you wouldn't expect but
they come from having that cemented
identity that has never wavered over
time that build an expectation with a
customer allows them to know their
customer well enough to 50 years in be
like we're going to launch a new
category I want to talk about pans one
of my favorite topics I've gone viral
about pans on Instagram many times for
some reason but Le cruset specifically
Le cruset has used color as the anchor
of their marketing so when you go on
their Pinterest this is a great example
of a legacy French brand using social
media to their own devices very well
their Pinterest has endless Boards of
color combination where you can say if
you want to buy a if you own these three
colors of Le CET already or pans of
these colors you want to add one to it
here's how we match that here's how you
style your kitchen so they have turned
into a knowing that they are a not a
once a year purchase so once every eight
or 10 years purchase that their customer
cares about their kitchens that they can
allow them to get into that purchase
decision and get excited about it
they've made these visual guides for how
people can put together their array of
pans and colors that's not where their
color strategy ends they introduce new
colors every year there's a new L cruset
palette and they exit colors every year
so now these are going away and they've
built into their distribution and they
channels both online and in stores how
to actually take advantage of that so
when you see new le cruset colors get
released all of your William Sonoma and
all these places will have their
displays of the new La cette colorways
then at the same time online you'll see
all the Bon appetites and all the you
know kitchen blogs all release hey
here's all the new colors that are
coming out and then at the same time
you'll see all them promoting this is
your last chance to get these three
colors that are going away and this
cycle happens every single year and
gives the brand an extra four or five
touch points from announcing it to them
actually releasing to these are going
away to here's your final chance to oh
my God like lime is coming back this
year to actually have that marketing
talk and what's worth noting is those
affiliate links those news sites that
you see they write about this every one
of those they're making a percent on
those sales there's a whole clickback
economy of Brands and blogs newspapers
major Publications getting paid by Le
cruset per one of those purchases by
reporting on these colorways and this
campaign is powerful because it gave
people the framework to do it a
framework for merchandising in store for
cons consumers to engage in social media
and for writing and the kind of content
creation establishment to work around it
and it is absolute genius and a brand
that's often replicated this is is yeti
that's a separate conversation next I
want to bring up two campaigns that
didn't last that probably should both in
alcohol the first is absolute so in my
era the absolute ad was was Peak people
had these posters on their walls they
cut them out of magazines and it was
genius they took the silhouette of the
bottle and they gave locations and
artists and cultural figures and their
art Direction team a canvas with which
they could work in advertising that had
the ability to appeal to everybody from
specific regions to the fans of specific
artists to just certain and specific
Lifestyles it was immediately
recognizable as absolute one of the best
brand building plays of all time and now
you see they have the remnants of that
decades later but it's gone but I don't
think it would have to be in the social
media era that they used that same exact
framework today but it was in video it
was in Tik toks it was in carousels it
had artists it had locations it had that
Nostalgia it wouldn't have to be gone
anymore which brings me back to another
liquor brand that's worth talking about
dois and the most interesting man in the
world by far the best beer campaign of
all time I'm not afraid to say it put
dois into the purchasing stage in a way
that nothing else would but eventually
became so big it almost was bigger than
the brand it was associated with more
than just dois they became afraid of the
campaign and eliminated it had problems
with the guy tried to bring the guy back
just not lasting it but again another
one of the social media era that if you
were thinking through it from a social
media perspective has the opportunity
for Pure genius because nowadays you
don't need to make a mascot for the most
interesting brand in the world you can
go find those people find the most
interesting folks all around the globe
have them tell their stories have those
intimate human moments on social media
of who the most interesting person in
whatever town is and begin to kind of
Leverage that into its own life and
series and always in their hand a dois
outside of liquor I want to talk about
one of the best brand collaborations of
all times it's one I think it's a little
unthought of because collaborations are
are a campaign sometimes can last a test
of time so KS very a longtime standing
Cosmetics brand lotions soaps shampoos
that kind of thing sold in department
stores forever sampling was one of their
Key Programs you can always get your
free sample always have your trial
natural to that that Niche but their
collaboration with Equinox where up
until last year this was the all the
products you would find inside of an
equinox would be KS is to me one of the
most legendary co- benefiting
collaborations of all time because it's
a product that most the guys I know had
were introduced to that product through
Equinox and guess what if a guy finds a
soap they like or a soap that's reput
capable in whatever way and they like it
and they buy one they're going to buy it
for the rest of time especially if women
then note that it was a good choice then
they are locked in and that introduction
for the vast majority of those male
clients was through Equinox he said this
is a great product it's in my Equinox
it's Ambiguously branded enough I'm
going to get compliments on it after I
am locked in shut up and take my money
but same thing for their entire customer
base right female customer whatever it
is them betting on Equinox and then
Equinox blowing up for the level it was
and that luxury Association of the
Equinox brand the luxury Association of
their brand and this just basically
massive sampling over years across the
globe by the Association of the two of
them is in my mind one of the best
collabs for both it brought a level of
credibility to to Equinox in terms of
their choices and their tasteem and it
brought the introduction of a brand
associated with this new luxury for an
old luxury brand to an entirely new
level it's about new channels and new
discovery in a way that is more than
just a couple videos online so I'm going
to talk about one more iconic campaign
then we're going to talk a bit about
kind of modern marketing and people that
are rolling all these together so this
last campaign I want to talk about is
the revitalization of Lego so forever
Lego was a staple toy was slightly
falling off but lived in its own world
there were no Star Wars Legos or Marvel
Legos they created their own characters
they had Ninjago they had a few they
were trying to create their own lore but
they stayed away from we are going to
let other IP cross over with rip and
then one day they said you know what
[ __ ] it we're letting the Cannons loose
we're doing everything and now literally
you can go buy a fortnite Lego set a
Batman Lego set Dungeons and Dragons any
cultural thing you could humanly think
of is now available in Lego and it was
the right time right maybe may it wasn't
the right time prior years before to do
it but when they actually opened the
floodgates and said we're going in major
was in the right timing of the world
niching down of fandoms becoming popular
of people's identities becoming more and
more wrapped up in the game they really
love with the TV show they enjoy of
purchasing those things and all of a
sudden it allowed these experiences to
cross over in a way that has revitalized
the brand has led into literal movie
channels like headlight all these things
that would not have happened for Lego
without the ability to actually then put
all this other IP in place around it
platform which is the right term for
what Lego had built and I like that it
took so long I don't think they should
have been running Star Wars and Star
Trek like in the 80s necessarily but
when they did it they went completely
wide with it they put it across channels
and it led into one of the most
interesting conversations ever and
Licensing is a huge conversation I think
more brands should talk about in terms
of if you have a popular product like
for instance I sell shoe bags people on
teams buy my shoe bags I'll get 10 or 15
bought at one time people lit be buying
them for their team or whatever that
looks like and to me that means you know
what one day as this product grows this
brand grows I should be doing NFL
versions of these with NFL logos on it
whatever tied into it that is a thing
that's attainable if you had a certain
amount of money a certain amount of
reach you could pitch that right but
certainly a level back being like hey I
could do this cross branded with smaller
leagues or we could do it with rugby or
whatever it is that licensing is a tool
for marketing and branding where look
it's usually a flat fee and like a 10 or
12% royalty of sale if you can build a
business that works around that is a
massively powerful tool and every time
you see a Lego you should be reminded of
that for your brand now the last brand I
want to talk about is one that kind of
has pushed all these together which is a
really interesting session and they've
done that to disrupt a massive
traditional industry so we going to talk
about the new generation of soda and
we're going to talk about poppy CU poppy
has done something interesting they've
basically hit every single note of
marketing they've struck on and they've
basically been able to say hey for a
fraction of what Coca-Cola spends on
marketing we're going to just do all of
these things that they participate in
but do them well and do them in a modern
fashion and then use that to basically
disrupt an entire category and it's
interesting I was speaking at a brand
the other day and I do this uh anytime I
I do kind of walk through poppy or
something similar to that I will survey
people hey how many of you drink
traditional soda how many of you drink
this new wave of soda the poppy ollipop
and you know the younger the crowd SKS
and even now middle age the more people
just drink these modern sodas the market
for that bigger soda is shrinking in a
way that I would be absolutely terrified
if I was those companies but then you
look at the marketing Cannon of what
they've been able to do so Poppy's a
great example because the founder is in
the content and there are creators in
the content and the founders is a
personality herself where they have
taken personality from the start and
associated with the brand the way
Coca-Cola never has we got a polar bear
that's it and they also have those same
celebrity collabs at the highest level
post Malone Paris Hilton where they're
activating on social they're doing Tik
toks that are going viral and their
inside of the mainstream campaign
something that the big brands have not
been able to do right they'll still put
a you know they'll have Britney Spears
in a TV campaign they'll have their
modern version but they have not been
able to cross that over to successful
social at the same time while also
activating in store while also
activating in branded activations while
also making sure they're present inside
sports stadiums there is this kind of
War coming on by saying hey we are going
to do everything a traditional brand
does but more cost effective with more
personality with more social reach
behind it with a product that speaks to
a better lifestyle that is basically the
blueprint for disrupting any big
category that came before so anyway this
was some of my favorite marketing
campaigns of all times of all different
types if you like this series please let
me know cuz I have a laundry list of
kind of 50 or more that we could walk
through inside all different types and
categories but we'll keep a little
shorter here today than just some of my
favorites hope you learned a ton and
appreciate yall watching
[Music]