in this video we're going to explain the
Seven Pillars of luxury so when I hear
someone say they want to start a luxury
brand what I often hear in the back of
my head is they just want to charge a
lot of money for something and when you
see someone present you know oh I do
Luxury Street Wear I have luxury X or Y
really I often feel there's an inherent
lack of understanding around what makes
something luxury and I've broken this
down into Seven Pillars as many of you
know I have a product development Studio
it's a luxury product development studio
is how I position it I help people
develop products for their brand I help
them develop merchandise so a brand
doesn't put out promotional t-shirts
I'll put out really nice bags something
like that I do a lot of work like that
and obviously put out my own products
and I choose the word luxury for a
reason because I'm appealing to people
who want to do much nicer things and
things with more of a story things with
more brand more quality than what they
would normally do so I've thought a lot
about these Seven Pillars of luxury how
any brand can build into them what that
really means and what luxury really
feels like and the time that it takes
I'm going to break all that down here so
we're going to go through quality of
products we're going to go through
design we're going to go through
desirability the concept of time and
luxury brand building we're going to go
through resale value which is actually a
key important thing people don't think
about a lot we're going to talk about
experience and we're going to talk about
brand and brand world let's lock in so
the first and number one thing that
defines luxury and I'll end up in these
conversations where I know I rub some
people the wrong way or I'll be like hey
your hoodie brand is not luxury right
and that's because a lot of luxury comes
down to Quality and if you have an
extremely nice over-the-top hoodie like
maybe you can get there but 90% of the
people that claim that don't even
understand what quality is and luxury
and its basis comes from True quality of
product and craft and you'll notice this
goes back to Legacy in history right
like Hermes making saddles for French
princes or whatever it looks like all
these brands that have all this history
as leather makers and cobblers and
people that outfitted things for kings
and that's why you notice there so much
European luxury un Less in the United
States is because there's that history
and that time to draw from it is simply
an older area in an older country that
had this level of like privilege and
quality that lasted significantly longer
than more recently developed parts of
the world and so I want to First Call
out this concept of bespoke right there
are people that create extremely quality
Goods that don't inherently become
luxury Brands but create quality things
what we call you know like bespoke
custom items that will make you an
amazing suit or tail you or a specific
belt they have luxury quality they're
able to say I create something with an
immense sense of craft but they have not
don't have these other tenants I'm about
to walk into and I'll say if you are
starting a brand the foundation has to
be you are making the best and most
interesting thing so for instance I have
this luxury product studio right I I did
bags recently for the collaboration with
Vermont i a on this but we had bags of
like the finest too leather with this
crazy lining and all the details were
amazing made on the same line as they
make like gon and that is me going to
Quality as the thing that's going to
help separate the service that I offer
and when anyone is making products at
this level whether you're making a
supplement or a drink or a beverage or
have an experience or have a you know a
studio or a coffee shop if you want it
to really be luxury it has to have that
quality and never be given up in any
circumstance so I want to highlight that
as that first tenant that is Omni
presentes some of these other ones can
kind of EB and flow or come and go but
that is one that always is there and is
a tenant of anything you might want to
create in luxury and this goes into
design and I want to separate here
between designer Brands and luxury
Brands and talk about the concept of
design is that design that is inherently
appealing and exciting and functional
and it actually is a product that that
really does its job well is another
thing that is is table sticks and much
like we have bespoke products that may
not become fully luxury there's designer
products that may not have crossed over
right there are things that look amazing
or are functional Etc but haven't
crossed over in luxury cuz they haven't
hit some of these other tenants if you
are creating something in that space it
needs to have aspiration and execution
to design that is truly special that is
truly resonant that product is there
it's another one why I call out why it's
so hard to create that luxury feel
inside of clothing is because the
expertise required to do that is
something that isn't you know you can't
start with a few years of experience you
have to be in significantly deep and
have a team that is in deep to be able
to design things with that level of
intention and you can have a designer
brand designer brands are wonderful
Brands transition from designer to
luxury I'll use off-white as a good
example of that and they've transitioned
back down all the way but basically had
gone from elevated street wear all the
way to becoming a a luxury brand and
being in scents and retail locations and
and hitting the price points and doing
the quality of their products and and
then that just disappeared over time
which talk about in the time Factor but
designer is the second aspect you
basically have this concept of quality
this concept of design all right so a
product that I appreciate very much as a
designer and as a content creator are
these Taurus iPhone cases they one won
some industrial Design Awards there's a
reason why one that first caught my eye
was this one that does a full 360
rotation but the most useful one the one
I use now is the oan 360 spin that you
see here where it actually has the
ability to spin in all directions and
push in all directions to get a perfect
angle for no matter what you trying to
film so some of the standout design
items that I like is that the details
are extremely thoughtful it's got a
shatterproof back panel the edges are
raised for lens and screen protection so
it's not like those flush cases where
you can actually still break when you
drop it all the angles that you can use
with this stand are great if you're
capturing odd angles for your footage
especially and as someone who's either
filming content filming for myself
filming videos cooking or putting
something together or want to get an
interesting angle on a factory floor
whatever it is they are giving you all
of those options with this case and it's
not just magsafe but has magnetic
charging and it's perfect for adapting
to places to shoot with the magnet and
all the little things like the tactile
feedback and like Smooth retraction and
the way it sounds is just from a company
you can tell puts the time into
industrial design even the finish on the
case is that perfect mat so if you're
looking for some standout protection for
your phone would recommend checking out
Taurus and the 360 spin the third tenant
one of the most important is
desirability people have to actually
want this product and want has to be
backed up by dollars right and so if you
are starting a brand where you meet the
quality standards and design standards
but no one wants it it doesn't really
look at it in the same way as a luxury y
brand because people are buying luxury
for how it makes them feel and how it
makes them feel is both a product of the
experience and a product of what it says
about them and the perception of it and
how they feel as an owner of it and that
desirability factor is not there for
some Brands and you can be desirable on
your own Supreme is a desirable brand or
was a desirable brand that is not a
luxury brand right and it doesn't have
that same like the quality is not a
luxury level the design isn't really a
luxury level right and so but they would
have the desirability of it just goes to
show how each of these things can kind
of operate outside of this and still be
successful they kind of operate together
to begin to build a picture of luxury
and that desirability ties really well
into resale people look at a lot of
luxury goods as Investments right when
someone goes and buys a Louis Vuitton
bag they know hey I can go sell this
back to the real reel at X price or this
is something I can you always have the
ability to move it or pawn it or get
some level of value back on it put it on
griled whatever it is that is a key
aspect of this as well because there are
luxuries that are you know not permanent
that don't have this aspect but so this
is one where I would say this is not the
most important but it is a huge winning
aspect when it is added to these others
and that's the ability for it to hold
value over time for a customer to look
at what they're purchasing as an
investment instead of looking at it as
merely something that's going to be in
their wardrobe or in their home and
that's a really important thing that
will can can separate any brand from the
rest inside this category that's that
extra sauce that anyone can have is that
resale value I think it's worth plotting
when you start your brand right and
potentially controlling that experience
I look at arter who's not necessarily a
luxury brand but they um are certainly a
designer brand and they have amazing
performance their products and they
control their secondhand Market you buy
secondhand arcx through Arc there's
other brands think about that as well
and that begins to show people the
desirability or the factor they know oh
I can go sell this back to them if
you're able to potentially control that
experience say you launched a brand
where you say hey we will buy back any
product that we release at any point in
time at x% of its value then you begin
to say we're putting our money where our
mouth is you can look at this as an
asset there's a lot of interesting
psychology that comes in resale and
requires you to play into some of these
mainstream things like what is your
presence on eBay is there desire for it
are you sold on the real re are like
there's some of these cultural tenants
that resale begins to interact with is
there a community around it on gr has
gred written about it what do you begin
to look at and and perceive how does the
world perceive it is these interesting
connotations of resale value as a pillar
of luxury and desirability and resale
then tie into time this is one of the
hardest ones to hear and most people
again they want to start a brand where
they can charge a premium you can charge
more money than everyone else you want
to be able to sell your t-shirts at what
rude sells them for of course like we
all do that sounds wonderful but really
there needs to be a lot of things to
actually execute that one of the biggest
things is time right there's all these
videos going around we use rude as an
example and rud being a quasi luxury
brand has had some periods of that or
perceived as that by a certain Community
where he was not selling a lot and then
Kendrick Lamar bought something or wore
something on stage whatever it was and
then kind of blew up overnight and then
was able to continue the story building
and telling to do that but the
continuation part is important right
like that brand has had a rough time for
the last few years right there's still
some people that go into it it's not
perceived the same way it was if it had
executed this level of perception over a
long enough period of time it could have
potentially gone on to develop like a
luxury standard whereas now it's kind of
it's middling and still has plenty of
good going for it but there's yeah it
does not have the potential it once did
as you can tell I'm not the hugest fan
of the brand but this aspect of time is
really important because if you are
setting out to start something luxury
it's often generational you look at all
these true luxury houses and brands with
very few exceptions they have lasted
over the course of literally like
through families they're passing down
two generations and this is how I would
think about it if you are building it is
this is not a thing you build to sell
it's a thing you build to be profitable
and pass on to your children and it's
something that is taken as a family
approach right there are no luxury
designers whose families are not
extremely deep inside it is not a is a
operation of that pulls everyone in
because of its magnetism that is
something is important to think about as
you create this and to set your goals
because if your goals aren't that then
you're creating in the wrong category
and you look at some recent exceptions
this I'm fascinated with brands that
shortcut their way to luxury so jacam is
one right where they were able to come
into the luxury playing field they uh
operate on a level of a luxury brand
brand in the luxury houses they have the
feel of that whereas being a new brand
now their product quality leaves
something to be desired as a lot of
people kind of note on the internet I
don't think they fully cemented
themselves in there but they've been
able to shortcut it through intention of
design through desirability through the
attention and experience through the
resale value and the things that we've
kind of mentioned here they have been
able to shortcut that Flamingo estate's
another one I like to call out and so
they sell a lot of bath products Etc I
put them on a level two a very similar
like a California version of ESOP who is
a kind of Quint essential luxury Brandon
May and they did some a couple things
were very interesting is one they
started as a service high-end service
they provided like farm- totable
vegetables to the Discerning and Elite
of Los Angeles right that was the start
of that business and then they added on
to it like a number of consumer goods
operating at kind of a very high level
but they purchase their time is a kind
of a decent way to put it they have a a
brand is based around the flamingo
estate a 70s like incredible like
physical structure and location that the
brand is named after the content is
based around there's a huge part of its
lore is absolutely gorgeous and again it
has has a magnetism to it that you are
inherently interested in but as a newer
brand by applying this real estate
component into the storytelling of it
that has history they were able to kind
of generate some of that time element
which is a really interesting concept to
me and then now we're going to talk
about experience I mentioned ESOP before
and they're a good example of this
because experience goes across a couple
things it goes across the service level
that you receive from the brand like you
can walk into a Louis Vuitton store and
buy something but most people have a rep
and have someone they actually talk to
or a salesperson the company you can
access things and get them there that is
the way luxury is purchased at a Louis
Vuitton then there's expectation what am
I going to see when I get this what what
am every time I get the product is what
is the unboxing like the packaging like
the every time I talk to a person on the
phone when I interact with the website
this overall brand experience walk into
a store the scent the thought everything
needs to be considered every aspect up
to standard this is why I think ESOP is
so important right because they have
this branding and this packaging That's
Unique they have this quality of product
that's amazing you become a a brand I
think is is worthy they have packaging
that is worthy when people use it like
they'll take their ESOP bottles and fill
it with some other cheaper soap to still
have the connotation of that brand out
there but you look at their experience
level right you can book a consult on
the ESOP website right now to have
someone talk to you about what products
you want to buy or skincare or whatever
it is and they will like have a person
Zoom you right that's a level of service
that you're not getting from a lot of
soap Brands second their locations when
you physically go into them are museums
of their own right they are immaculately
designed they have a presence that is
unlike any other that's presented with
absolute incredible luxury looking feel
but then not only that they tell the
story of that in their taxonomy of
design website they have every single
location archived with every material in
it the copper in their Japan location
the wood floors of the one near me in
Newport Beach everything that they've
chosen in there from a materials
perspective with diagrams and breakdowns
is in this master materials archive they
just keep on a website because they care
that much that is an example of a luxury
brand experience and so I would
encourage you to think about that right
like I look at little things like Mr
Porter as a luxury reseller always
referring to their guests as Mister the
way that their customer service
signatures are that have with a kind of
a more of an upscale feel and something
I'm very much looking at as I get into a
product studio is what does my service
look like what do the engagement what
does my team members look like how do we
present ourselves how what does that
look and feel like for a Services
business especially that luxury
experience and that customer service
that expectation is huge and again that
goes into unboxing into packaging into
anything what it really goes down to is
every single decision needs to be made
with intention around brand and live up
to the brand standard or it is not done
that ties into the last part we have
here of the Seven Pillars of luxury
which is brand overall and the brand
world and the brand experience so every
luxury brand has a brand World often
times it can involve the founder it can
involve the story it can involve the
faces of its models or its designer or
its lead but there are personalities
there are locations there are things
that are happening and events that are
happening and there are crossovers into
different parts of the world Louis
Vuitton opening cafes a new creative
director entering a brand these things
are all events that work around each
other and not every brand has all these
things but you need to establish what
are the people involved are the people
the luxury standard and when the people
come and go is it an event and how is it
considered and there's the presentation
when we release a thing or a collection
like how is that done this goes beyond
simply like what can happen on social
media right there is an inherent feeling
around that in the world when these
things are adopted there's the campaigns
that go with it and there's that story
that happens over time of that history
how it's archived and how people can
find it because the best luxury brands
have archivists that do this for them
accounts that hunt down their best
things and post them people that are
obsessed with its history and collection
if you are creating something new you
need be thinking about how that becomes
what you how what you are doing becomes
so important it is generated and curated
by others so you tie all those together
quality design desirability resale time
experience and then the brand world you
have the Seven Pillars of luxury and how
to think about these Brands and building
these Brands and interacting with them
and you have a formula for creating
something really special but it is a
long journey like I mentioned it is a
journey that passes down from family to
family but I do think when you are
looking to create a brand in a world of
so many ephemeral Brands I'm doing this
quick thing or I'm creating this or I
want to make my own money money or
whatever it is creating something with
this idea and this passion that is built
to last takes a certain type of person a
certain investment and I believe that
for people that are truly passionate
about it or really want to create
something that is a fitting Legacy for
them that it's a the path to choose so
thank you so much for watching and if
you have any questions about this or
disagree with any of those use I'd love
to hear it below and I will create more
videos about the luxury Topic in the
future thanks
[Music]