I'm going to take you inside the week in
the life of a creative director in
China. I refer to China and Wangjo where
I'm at as side quest city because
whenever you go here, you just keep
going a level and a level deeper into
more interesting things. I've been to
the jewelry markets where we got to see
all this like how this hip-hop ice like
Moite was made all the way to lab
diamond providers to natural sapphires
and just dove deep into the world of
jewelry being made in China. I actually
went to Fosan which is this big
furniture city where you can actually
buy oneoffs of any like immaculate
design piece and outfit your whole house
at a fraction of the cost. And then in
the core of Wangjo we went into fabric
markets, trim providers, all the things
you kind of seen in China that make for
an ultimate creative vision while also
just exploring the world around us. We
had Michelin Star Coffee, went through
all the coffee shops, amazing
restaurants, found a bunch of local
brands and hosted an event in this
amazing space with my friends at Crease
Group. We're going to walk through that
whole week and what it looks like to
take what I feel is the ultimate
creative trip and show you everything
along the way. Let's lock
[Music]
[Applause]
in. So, most people have heard of Wangjo
because of the Canton Fair. This is the
largest wholesale trade show in the
world. And to put that in perspective,
we're in front of one hall. This is hall
9. There are about 20 halls all of this
size that are filled with actual
factories and manufacturers who make
everything. And it's even so large it
has to happen over three phases in 3
weeks. I'm here right now during phase
2. This is mostly homerelated. We're
talking gardening, furniture, outdoor,
kitchen wares, anything related to
building materials, plumbing materials.
There's hall after hall of all the
factories that make these kind of
products. The majority of them are from
China, but there's also sections with
people from Turkey and India and Korea
as well. My friends at Crease Group,
who's the manufacturing that makes all
of my valuable stuff and who also I work
with on tons of projects. We decided to
take over this space down here in the
middle of this kind of new arts district
and just have a showcase of all the
amazing things that we work on and throw
an event for anyone that is here that's
building in the kind of fashion world or
the design world to come have a place to
hang out and see what we do. Let's come
take a look. So, first we've got this
huge centerpiece of all the steel that's
just showing off a bunch of the
different fabrics and projects. And it
has a bunch of these. These are like the
crease kits that get sent out to kind of
VIP clients. Have examples of all these
different fabrics and tags you can see
down here. It just show off all the
production capabilities. It's actually
one of my hoodie samples. It just shows
off all the things that a group like
Crease has access to. So, we want to be
able to walk people around to get them
to see all the things that can be
produced and the world that exists. if
you want to kind of bring your vision to
life. And so this is a great example of
love showcasing like technical fabrics
that are washed like these that people
like CP Company in Stone Island do or
like grails that are really hard to do
and some stuff that they've been pulling
off for a technical brand out in the UK
and showing off some of those
capabilities here. And then also some of
these fabrics, this is actually fabrics
I'm looking at for some valuable bags so
people can understand what that looks
like. But I'd be remiss if I didn't also
bring up this massive bag. So, just a
quick event marketing pro tip. Always
try to like have something viral. So, we
actually took this to Canton Fair. I
made a video with this like bro is
trying to start
4,531 brands where I'm walking around
the trade show filling it up. I already
has a couple hundred thousand views.
It's just a fun little generator. And
then all the people that are coming here
must have seen that video and they get
to take a picture with it inside the
event. And so, you'll see all around and
throughout there's just more of the mood
boards, more of the actual projects that
Crease has worked on from the hats and
leather accessories. And so if you don't
know Crease Group and what they work on,
what we work on together, they are a
manufacturer that has multiple
facilities, including one for leather
goods and another for active wear. They
actually just produce things for
clothing brands in China. So you can see
on their page the kind of people they do
work with. They obviously make a lot of
my valuable stuff. You've seen on their
page do a lot of stuff with people like
Form and SA and all these different
brands. All the stuff that you see here
is from one of those facilities. not for
like your brand new brand trying to do
50 of a piece. But if you're a brand
doing some quantities, trying to really
have that experience where you have
English speaking people that understand
trying to get the best materials, then
they they're a group that helps solve
that. And what we work on a lot together
is creative direction or creative
strategy for those projects where I'll
come in and work on ensuring the designs
are tight or line direction is great or
there's a visual concept on the other
side. We've had a relationship for the
last year or so, putting all those
things together and and just been in a
creative flow where we can build stuff
like this even in somewhere like China
and actually bring a creative vision to
life. All right, so today's video is
brought to you by my friends at Art
List. And I actually want to walk
through a new feature that they added
that we have been using a lot that is a
wonderful addition to your workflow if
you are using audio inside your videos,
especially for short form. So now when
you actually go into your art list
dashboard and you scroll down, you're
going to notice this find music that
matches the biggest hits of the week. So
what they've done is they've pulled in
YouTube, Spotify, and Tik Tok charts of
trending audio. You can actually sort
that by country cuz if you work on
multiple social accounts, you know that
there's a lot of nuance to trending
audio from there. You can pop over into
USA. It's going to give you a chart of
the most popular audios. Well, then not
only do you get this identified, so you
have an ability to actually find what
audios are trending now, they also have
matches for this from their royalty-free
library. So, if you are a brand or
you're a creator working on something
for a brand deal or overall you just
want to use original audio versus
trending audio, but you still want to
keep the sound and vibe that is popular
or use one of the trends with something
that's as close as you can get, Arlist
basically pulls from their library and
matches the closest audios to it. Just a
great workflow hack to get relevant
audio you need and have a bunch of
options versus kind of searching through
libraries to actually be able to find
them through this tool here. So overall,
if you are not familiar with Art List,
they have a ton of music, highdefinition
footage, sound effects, and templates
that you can use if you are making
videos. You can learn more about Art
List at the link in the description. And
big shout out to them for sponsoring
this video. All right, so let's take a
seat to talk about some of the things we
did this week on our various side
quests. So, the first thing we did
almost right away on landing is we went
with my boy Jason to Daloo Jewelry City.
I'm not making jewelry. I've made a few
things before. I'm not looking for it
for a brand, but just out of pure
curiosity, my boy was like, "Hey,
there's a city where they manufacture
all the lab diamonds where you can just
buy gold in the streets. There's gem
showrooms, natural lab, everyone and all
these brands all make their luxury
jewelry there. Do you want to go?" And
the answer is yes.
[Music]
So when we were there, we actually went
into this downtown. They have diamonds
like on the street lights, so you know,
it's a jewelry area. And literally when
my boy Jason lives here, and what he has
done is he just kind of went down there
and made friends and made relationships.
He has a business where he's helping
people get, you know, lab diamond
jewelry rings or like custom iced out
stuff at like that rock bottom cost here
in China. And so we just went to all of
his vendors and checked them out from
people that are hawking golds, these
places where locals are negotiating to
these spots where you can actually pick
out your own sapphire. And then we
actually sat down with a company that
specializes in lab, whether that's lab
sapphires, lab diamonds. They have a
huge catalog. It was just so cool to be
able to see that and dive into that
world and then go down the street to the
factory where they were doing all like
the iced out hip-hop chains. They only
let us film like half of it. There's
like a huge iced out like John Wick that
like I know is like some major rappers.
They were like, "You can't film. You
can't film." But we were like just in
the full experience of what jewelry
looks like there. But after that, the
next day, we actually headed out to the
furniture city. We're going to talk
about that in a second. I want to talk
about Fosan and the furniture city in
China, which is about an hour west of
Wangjo. These fixtures are a good
example cuz you can look at a big thing
like this and be like, "Oh, you paid
some big event company, some big
production." No, we got this all
fabricated. Yahoo worked on the majority
of like making this happen. Basically
just got people to produce all these
individual items. We worked on a layout
and people whipped it up and that's
everything from these racks to these big
steel boards that we're using for
everything that are magnetized to all
these kind of different furniture you've
seen around here. And that's because in
Fosan they make the world's furniture
crate and barrel restoration. Anytime
you order a piece of furniture overseas
and they're like in general and they're
like hey it's going to take 6 or 8 weeks
to get there. It is coming from Fosan.
And so down there they have what's
called the Lou and this is just a
fascinating concept. They basically
stuck a replica like a French some sort
of like ornate French area into this
massive mall and made it a destination.
Every one of these things that you see
out here is a different designer,
different showroom. They all have their
own cataloges. Most are original
designs. There are some replica designs.
There are some designs you see in very
common furniture places you can shop in
the west. You can order direct one piece
only or you can go out your whole bar,
your whole studio from here. They will
go make it and they will ship it to
wherever you are in the world. So what
were we doing there? I am very curious
about launching furniture for myself and
making my own designs is what I want to
do for valuable in the future. This is
just the start of it. But to do it
first, I actually want to redo my office
and a bunch of the things I have in my
house and bring it all over from China.
Now, originally, let's talk about cost
savings. I figured that would actually
be about 25% of the cost of buying it
new in the US and would be my own
designs. Now, with tariffs and shipping,
I think it's going to end up being like
60% of what the cost would have been.
Although costs will be going up for for
everything, still a deal to be able to
get all your own designs. We found all
these amazing showrooms. I found the
perfect one for me. A lot of it's about
finding those people you have a
connection with. You can order a one of
anything. Anything they have, you can
customize it. You want 2 in shorter, 2
in higher, this marble or that marble.
They will do whatever. And they have
immaculate design teams. It's just one
of those things that if you don't come
to China and see it in the flesh, you
would almost never believe it. But then
you're there next to all the racks of
like all modern and crate and barrel
stuff literally being made. and getting
to see that in the flesh was pretty
majestic. All right, before we go into
the rest of what's happening in Wong
Joe, I want to actually take you
upstairs to see the second floor of the
showroom and the event we put together
and some of what we got going on. So,
you
[Music]
coming? So, Wangjo and this area we're
in is particularly known for fabric.
It's basically the fabric capital of the
fashion world. There's all these amazing
places you can go to when you're down
here that will just give insight and
allow you to make like amazing things
for your brand. So, we actually did a
tour yesterday. Basically, we said,
"Hey, all those things that we had to
figure out our first few trips there,
what if we just took people directly to
all the spots we wish we knew about on
our first journey?" So, we hosted an
event here where people could meet up
with us. We actually had a ton of people
come, way more than I thought. It was
like 70 or 80 people. We thought there'd
be like 15. So, we were mobbing into
these places. But, we went to the trim
store. It's a massive store of examples
of every type of trim and tag you could
see from silicone to patches to anything
you could imagine. We actually went to
technical fabric places. We went to
Yutong, which is an amazing like street
wear fabric, and then took people to
Zangda, which is the massive fabric
market where all of the fabric you could
possibly be looking for in the world.
You can hunt through these stories and
stories of stuff. All right, so we are
here in the promised land. This is the
biggest textile market in the world.
Floor after floor of everything you
could imagine, every kind of fabric. Go
take a look inside.
[Music]
So, what do you actually do once you get
here? So, you're going to talk to these
vendors. You're going to want to be able
to get fabric that then goes to your
manufacturer. How does that work? So,
you get what's called a color card. So,
for example, if you like a particular
fabric, they're going to show you some
of the variations, washes, and just
colors that are available in that fabric
and its detail. This is what you're
going to pick from and be able to
actually give to your factory. Your
factory will call them up, order the
amount needed to make a sample, and then
eventually order the full amount.
they'll be negotiating with them through
the cost per meter and the kind of
minimum quantities that they need to
actually purchase fabric. So to actually
make the most of coming to a place like
this, you need a manufacturer who's
going to be a conduit between the things
that you find and what you actually want
to make. And so APM that we were just
in, they make some of the material for
some of the valuable shirts that I've
done and are just overall like an
incredible provider for 100% cotton and
for anything you want to do for sweats
or for shirts. You'll really notice when
you go get material from someone like
them versus when you get it from just a
vendor the difference in the quality and
how much a difference that makes even in
an item as simple as a t-shirt. So it's
awesome that we had so many people from
all over the world, Australia, Thailand,
United States, Europe actually come with
us and be able to experience that. It
was a super fun time and shows a lot of
the magic of a city like this. And that
is my itinerary. If you want to come to
here, I highly recommend you go to runi
which is the tag and trim store. Go to
Zangda which is the big market. I would
be wandering around this area where Utah
and a few of these other places are.
They have more premium fabric. YKK
zipper store and trim stores here. Just
go around and find anything you can and
you can really get into that fashion
experience. So, why would you actually
do that? Well, fabric is what makes some
of these brands stand out. It's what
makes your stuff better than others. And
you'll have suppliers that will show you
some of the options they have, but it's
rarely like the best option. So, if you
want to make things that stand out for
your brand, you want to go find the best
fabrics, hunt those down, bring them to
your manufacturer, be building that
lineup, and this is the place to come
for that. And along with that comes all
the inspiration. You walk into stores
like Runie, you get to see what modern
brands are doing for their tags and
trims, find something that might spark
an idea for you, and it is an amazing
trip to see. But now, what are we doing
up here? So, we actually decided to
showcase some of the amazing local
brands that are actually operating in
Wangjo as well. You can see there it's
its own fashion capital in China where
they burst lots of interesting brands.
So upstairs we actually have a few of
these showcased where later in the day
when people show up inside here they're
able to come shop some of that and
actually see what Chinese street wear
has to offer. But in addition to the
boutique experience, the coffee
experience I have to talk about. So we
this morning had Michelin Star coffee at
this place called Song Cafe. It's in
this Taiku mall. They had coffee that
went all the way up to like $80 a cup.
Most expensive coffee in China if if not
the world. Maybe I'll hook that with the
short form. We'll see. But we got to
experience that. It was amazing. And
there's actually a whole bunch of
amazing cafes there. There's another one
called I believe it was Lockchuck. By
butchering these names is what it is.
White guy America. #Trump. Uh, just
joking. Maybe. Take it out. Don't take
it out. Got to leave him guessing. But
Long Chuck has an amazing layout.
Amazing coffee there. Beautiful place.
You can tell they were big Japanophiles.
There's just stacks of Popeye magazines
of Monle magazine. Amazing place you
should also check out. Uh, and then
there's just coffee and kind of that
amazing boutique experience almost
everywhere we went. And to give you some
idea on prices when you're coming to a
place like China, like while they did
have $80 coffee. I think I had a $20 one
when we went to Song. Typically, you're
getting a latte for like $1 or $2. And
we actually went to a really boutique
pastry spot right next to Song. Got four
of the craziest pastries I had seen in
my life. And that was like $10. And
overall, there is some arbum pricing
when you're out here. Like hotels, like
really nice hotels are like $100 to $200
a night. So that's pretty much cheaper.
We were eating like incredible food this
entire time and like rarely even with
multiple people were having a meal above
$100 $200. So food is significantly
cheaper even the highest quality stuff.
Cars and cabs like getting a DDI which
is their Uber is super cheap. Two four
bucks I think it was maybe $30 for us to
get like the nice ass one an hour away
to Foschan which is like where has like
water is like the Uber black version but
then some things are like exactly the
same cost. Like even when you go to the
boutiques and buy clothes and some stuff
like that you're like everything is the
same. So, it's an odd and in real
estate, I went for a run with my friend
down in one of the really nice areas
where condos are only like $14 million,
$10 million. And so, it is kind of a
crapshoot as to what is more expensive
or not, but it's fun to kind of see that
cross-cultural experience. So, now we're
landing over here and actually showing
off a luxury packaging vendor called
Rapology that we work with. And this is
something that we also spend a lot of
time looking at whenever I'm in China is
finding packaging vendors. Actually
found a few at Canton Fair when we were
actually at the fair that had really
amazing high-end stuff. So you can see
this amazing Creed packaging. They even
brought out the molds that they're
working with. Totem like so. Rapology
does like that true high-end and they
are uh have production here but are not
based here. It's another one of these
like crease like an east west company
that has production like a forward
facing version and so we want to
showcase that as well. Something people
are always asking about. This is a
perfect addition to the event to be
like, "Hey, if you don't just want that
normal packaging, you want that
extremely high-end that can happen
here." And you got to come check this
guy's got the advent house, which is a
good example of what something creative
you can put together actually looks
like. And even fun here, we always try
to show the behind the scenes. If you
notice, all these boards, if you
actually see the actual tech pack for
the advent calendar uh sitting here, we
also had like a live screen printing
here with Unit 100, which is a screen
printer that Chris works with to do
amazing amazing work. I actually want to
show some of their work. So they have
these little cards are kind of like the
showcase of all they can do. So this
metallic one is absolutely crazy. Same
here. You got this, you know, the kind
of padded print. Some of these are heat
transfer, some are actual print. You can
see some of the texture when you get
into some of these. One of the most
amazing things about traveling to a
place like this and meeting a screen
printer. Like so, so these guys screen
print the valuable shirts. And now I can
actually see like, oh, they can do these
kind of embossed styles and what does
that actually look like? Do I want to
consider integrating that for my brand?
So seeing those capabilities in the
actual facilities gives you the ability
to generate things for your brand.
That's one of the best things about
working with Crease Group is I will have
this long list of things I'm interested
in seeing certain types of fabrics,
certain types of prints because even
though I don't have like the biggest
brands or anything like that, I'm always
fascinated with the most interesting
That's my whole premise. I'm going
to find the most interesting things that
either I can do or clients can do and
brands can do, but then all of that
basically just goes into their portfolio
that they can offer really easily to
clientele. been a big part of why our
relationship has worked so well. I want
to shout out my boy Yah who actually
designed the custom screens that can can
go for uh people can get while they are
here. Big big shout out to the plus 86
the China the China area code is a funny
one and he also did tariff goods was the
most popular one. U so John from crease
group came up with the concept and then
Ya did the design but people were
ripping this screen like almost the
entire time as the tariffs are quite a
point of conversation obviously with
anyone in China. And also a big part of
why like the group we had here, there's
like maybe one or two other guys from
the US. Even if like all those 70 80
people we saw, there was tons of people
from all over the world because even if
China ends up shipping less to the
United States, we'll still be ripping
worldwide. But this is the reminder of a
foundation of what makes a great event
is just make sure you have stuff every
day. So we have a panel. I'm speaking
with some other influencers here about
kind of like sourcing and building
brands for anyone coming to China. So
people have another reason to come
today. Had that screen printing set up
so people can leave with like a cool
unique shirt. Obviously we're showing
off a bunch of local vendors. for
showing off what we do. We're doing like
a walking tour. We had that big bag. We
have an amazing event takeaway bag. So
that's not a trade show bag. We have a
smaller version of as well. People can
walk away with a cool gift. There's
these metal invite cards everyone got.
You as you know, if you've seen any of
my event content, making every single
one of these things Instagrammable or a
Tik Tokable experience people can make
content about. Giving people artifacts
and things they actually want to keep
from these events they'll actually use
that are like real and good and not like
some shitty swag. getting you be able to
film the process of getting the screen
print, not just having the shirt. Like
all that, even just choosing this space
and saying, "Hey, we're gonna invest in
something that is incredible instead of
kind of trying to make it work in a
small spot downstairs." All those are
the things like in the modern era that
make a great event was super fun to work
on with the big team. Big shout out to
Yah and John and Jack and all the people
at Crease Group and putting this like
massive thing together.
[Music]
All right, so that was a glimpse of our
week in China. The one thing I did not
talk a bunch about was the stuff I
worked on for my own brand and hunting
down the fabric and things there, but
also the photo shoot we did. We took
over this place called The RAW. I'm
doing a whole separate video about that,
how you actually art direct a great
photo shoot. So, if you want to check
that out, I will link that at the end
here. But appreciate y'all so much for
watching. And anyone who came out in
China, thank you so much for coming to
the event. and I will see y'all in the
next video.
[Music]