In this video, we are going to talk
about the art direction of K-pop and
Korean fashion. This video centers
around the importance of references and
seeing new things because all of our
feeds look alike to help your creative
direction, your strategy, your artistry
find its own voice. We're going to talk
about concepts for your brand's products
and how the ultra competitive Korean
market uses these to stand out. We're
going to look at the art direction of
groups and how photos [music] of people
like K-pop stars can make your creative
direction stand out. We're going to take
some tips from some of the most refined
industry in the world with K beauty.
Look at some of the top creatives in
Korea and see how their work is kind of
translating into the internet. Talk
about how to elevate your brand and look
at the future of technology and ideas in
our global world. I'm super excited for
this video.
>> You know how long I've been waiting for
this? You're going to see a ton of my
mood boards and my references because
this is a market I look to a lot. I will
share a Cosmos board linked with all of
this down below. Let's lock in.
So, we are going to start with the world
of Korean fashion with a brand called
Postarchive Faction. There are a number
of Korean brands have crossed over into
full western pop culture. Gentle
Monster, Thug Club, but the most
interesting to me and the one I feel
like we can all learn the most from is
PAF. For any of you that watched my
Virgil Abau video a few weeks ago, one
of their interesting collabs and one of
the first times they got on my radar was
when they collaborated with Off-White. A
few years ago, they released this
collection. Really stand out art
direction. Obviously, look to the
clothes. This image itself is insane,
but also they had bas some sculptural
objects included as well. Backpack goes
crazy, but they reinterpreted
Victoriaox, which is a Swiss company
that makes Swiss Army knives into a
handful of objects. you'll see they have
this really interesting and robust Swiss
Army knife. They also have this
primitive tool, but to me it was a
really interesting aesthetic world I was
curious to learn more about. But when
you actually dive into the brand, they
have a concept behind their brand. This
is a really interesting thing I think a
lot of us can learn from. Every release
they have, every garment that they put
out, they make a left version of, a
center version of, and a right version
of. The right version is very
conservative. It's very wearable. It
looks almost like a typical garment. The
center version leans more experimental
and the left version goes completely
into its own interpretation. And as you
see, we have tons of streetear brands.
Everyone starting their own collection,
doing their own design. This isn't a bad
thing, but what it does mean is the
elevation of pattern, of form, of
concept is going to become a
differentiator when everyone can not
only just do the same screen printed
TE's, but everyone's getting good at
entrylevel clothing, right? Everyone's
able to do solid denim. Everyone's able
to do decent outerwear. People are
realizing that that has become extremely
accessible. Patterns are easier than
ever. Designers are more equipped than
ever. And so Elevation is going to look
a lot into pattern form materials and
then also a concept or an idea to the
brand. And this one in particular really
resonates cuz they make extremely
interesting garments. This brand has
gone on to collaborate with people like
on running and continue to reach
collection after collection of wearable
and experimental sidebyside garments.
And so it's worth thinking with your own
brand. Can you do a concept like this?
Can you have two sides of the same coin
or the dark and light, heaven and hell
version? What is that vision you can
have in your own head that brings a
concept worth looking at every time?
Because what this does is this makes you
when you hear there's a new release or a
new collection want to see what they've
done on those different ends of the
spectrum and really helps tie a reason
into the brand that gets people excited.
But moving on over into the world of
K-pop. Now, for many of you who have
watched my other videos where we've
talked about Stusy or Lee, but you
probably did not anticipate that K-pop
was next. But this is actually one that
I love personally to look at. This is
one of my Cosmos boards and I love it
because they take the essence of
capturing a group so seriously. The art
direction of basically multiple people.
If you are doing a shot or you're
working on a project with multiple
models and you're looking for some of
the best references that you can pull
from, K-pop is it. Look at this. This
image here is incredible. the lengths
that are gone to for the production and
for the standout in as competitive of a
pop culture environment as what happens
in Korean music and pop culture is this
breeding ground for just incredible
collaboration. And even the little
things that you would expect have this
deeper essence to them that's really
compelling and often borders on the
metaphysical. you'll see that recurring
trope of someone kind of rising above
these kind of collective moments and
even the basics of portraiture capturing
a single person and their essence.
There's just so much amazing work there.
And the importance of this, at least for
me, is I know whenever I show up to a
creative direction session or creative
strategy session, if I come with the
same stuff as everyone else, as someone
with a prolific personality on the
internet, that's going to get judged. I
have an even higher standard every time
I do creative now as I've begun to amass
a following that I am obsessed not just
with my own personal drive to make
interesting things but also knowing that
I have to come and compete at the
highest level. So I am always looking
for new references online and offline.
Buying books, buying zes, getting into
different cultures. And since I work a
lot on global projects, I spent a lot of
time in Asia. I'm always looking to
what's happening over there and
happening with my friends across the
world. And so if you are pulling
references or beginning to look for
these things, I would encourage you to
go outside of where everyone else is
looking. They're seeing the same
Pinterest things. They're all in the
same arena. Mood boards, the ones that
are so popular. You were able to find
some subcultures and lean into it and go
a level deeper. We'll talk a bit how
later in the video. You're going to find
that that mix of things that you're
taking inspiration from really leads you
to more interesting work. So why K
beauty? You might ask. Why would someone
look to that? What does it mean to be
advanced in an industry in this world?
So originally I looked a lot of Korea
because of their influencer mailers.
Their influencer culture is one of the
most developed. When you want to look at
where influencer culture is going, a lot
of people try to reference China.
There's a huge cultural differences
between China and how they consume
content, how they buy products, and
where they view influence and how the
Western world does. And actually, Korea
is way more aligned with almost step for
step how things have progressed in
influence culture, beauty culture, pop
culture in the United States, the
emergence of fandoms, the aesthetics
that we see, the product style. And so I
started looking at this for influencer
mailers. So, for those of you who don't
know the concept behind this, brands
send out thousands, sometimes tens of
thousands of mailers all the time. In my
typical set, you see behind my YouTube
videos, I have mailers I've either
gotten or with brands I've worked on.
They're actually behind me. It's a huge
compelling part of the marketing
process. But to make those successful,
you have basically what's called post
rate. You send out x amount of mailers.
How many people actually post them? And
not just post to story, post a feed. And
if you want to increase your post rate,
you need a mailer that is worth
showcasing where whoever opens it goes,
I can have a video that gets views
because of how cool this is. And Korea
is the inspiration for this. So this
company he's on their behance now has
done Korean beauty mailers that are just
incredible. Like this blush phone. The
first one I saw was these Maybelline
sticks of dynamite. Look at this. This
clear case they had here. They had
cardboard mini purses at one point,
which uh is one I've been trying to get
somebody to to replicate in the West uh
cuz it's affordable. They have like full
computers. They're like kind of made of
cardboard. Obviously, more intricate
opening items here. But this is if you
are taking inspiration for how to do an
amazing mailer in the US. Korea's
already done it. They've already hit the
pinnacle of it. So, being able to pull
from things they've done and apply your
own brand kit to it, uh is an amazing
way to look at it. and Heath is at the
top of their game, best of the best in
terms of creating these for these brands
and is an awesome person to look at.
That's H E A Z. And on that note,
shifting over closer into the actual
influencer culture, MLMA is an artist
from there. Me love me a lot. It's what
it's short for. who's at the tiptop of
the personality visual aesthetic
influencer game. Cutting these aesthetic
reels, styling, creating art, drawing on
top of Porsches, triggering some of the
fans in the meantime, creating really
interesting looks at your aesthetic
self. If you're an influencer that makes
this type of content, she is absolutely
on top. And this is important too if you
are looking for especially there's a lot
of influencers out there now in fashion,
etc. They're trying to make standout
content in a world that's obsessed with
editing and transitions. And it really
comes down to creative and creative
direction. much like anything else. And
these top influencers, especially those
that kind of in Korea, are operating on
a level with which US influencers are
barely beginning to compete with. So,
this is one of the examples I always go
to when I'm talking to someone about how
to elevate the visuals of their brand or
how to look at themselves and become
iconography to show their work and have
it travel on the global internet. She's
big obviously far beyond Korea. This is
an example that comes up and this was
the first time that I caught on to this
was I mean this may be a 3D viz it might
be AI but she basically become a robotic
version of herself for a series of posts
and that's where I began to look at
these like enhanced identities that come
from the modern visual style of today
and how you can begin to build that
world around yourself with editing
online I think is a fascinating and
relatively untapped mark that halfway
between a real person and little
Michaela. And speaking of references,
this week's video is brought to you by
Motion. This is the first time I'm
talking about Motion. This is a product
I use every day in the work I do in
cosmetics. It is an analytics tool,
creative strategy tool for working on
meta ads and it is excellent at we're
going to walk through a bit of how it
works. So you know, so what motion does
is it syncs to your ad account in meta,
whether you're running 10 ads or
thousands of ads, and brings in the data
and analytics and then they have AI
tools that actually identify different
parts of the process to group your ads
together. So for instance, it will
automatically call out the visual format
for your ads like a feature benefit
point out or an offer first banner. It
will note the messaging angle like a
Black Friday sale. It will break down
the hook tactic, basically applying auto
tags to every piece of creative you
have. But then what this also allows you
to do is then sort and see your return
on ad spend a by ads. You can go look at
what your click-through rate is by ad,
rowass by ad, and compare them in charts
like we're looking at here with whatever
metrics, but then also look at that by
the creative angle, the visual angle,
the hook rate, the actual creative
things that make ads move. And so when
you begin running more and more ads, so
as many of you know, if you're a company
that's scaling into high seven into
eight into nine figures, you are running
an absolute boat ton of ads. The work
that I do related to this is I am
briefing in for new campaigns and new
ads every month. Tons of variants,
existing winners where we're going
taking new styles, we're applying them
to new product launches and new
campaigns. You just see statics. You
just need lots of new fresh creative.
But you can actually go and see what are
our recurring winners, what are the hook
styles, what are the visual angles,
compare them, and then make an actual
strategy to brief for creative assets.
But it doesn't stop there. One of the
other interesting tools is their
inspiration section. You can go look at
what other brands are running for their
ads and get breakdowns of those as well.
What are the landing pages they're using
and what traffic is going to them?
What's the breakdown of video to image
to carousel in terms of what they're
running? What's the newest creative? And
then they have actually tools to
summarize and analyze this now. So I
used to do a lot of this manually. You
would go and you try to figure out what
are they doing? What are the new angles?
I'm going to create my summary. But now
I can go sit spot gaps and
opportunities. Tell me what this brand
is testing. What's new and what are they
what's getting spent? give me new hook
ideas based on actually get these recaps
to make that work quicker that you can
go through and make a strategy based on.
They have a new AI pulse report based on
how creative strategists are using
modern tools like this to do better with
ads. You can grab for free at the link
below. And I'm doing a webinar with
Motion coming up in December where we're
going through a lot of the creative
strategy trends that are happening right
now inside paid media. There's going to
be a link below where you can join that.
Thank you so much to Motion for
sponsoring this video. Moving over into
K-pop once more. People often ask, "How
do you find small accounts? How do you
find people to follow?" So, here I am on
Instagram where I found a production
designer and an art director in K-pop,
right? The other thing I look at for
visuals for campaigns is I'm looking at
music videos. The music videos had a
renaissance with Tik Tok. There's quick
ones and long ones, but K-pop still
takes the ultra high production
seriously. Things where you can learn
from shot types and aesthetic looks for
a campaign. And K-pop music videos are
taking this super seriously. And so I
found an art direction and production
designer in there. Now she has 10,000
followers is posting a lot of clips from
these carousels from these. Again, they
don't have any views or anything, but I
get to see the shot types, see some of
the environments that they're creating,
see how they're lighting things. But if
you click this little plus sign at the
top of the screen, this is the most
underused Instagram function ever. You
know what it gives me? 10 more Korean
K-pop production designers. You can
click through those accounts. That's how
I discovered people like Moon Lee, who
again, same amazing breakdown. You're
trying to create shot lists. you're
trying to look at what concepts can look
like. These people that are working on
these sets every day, like look at these
transitions that are inside some of
these videos. They're incredible. And
being able to find and go through those
is an excellent source of inspiration.
Whenever I find any subculture or niche,
and obviously K-pop is one that I go
back to a lot, but there are plenty.
We'll deep dive on some others in the
future. Explore using those functions.
But shifting over into brands and the
highest level, when people think of
Korean fashion, they think most often of
Gentle Monster, probably the most known
brand. huge installations, crazy
campaigns, but they have a brand also
run by basically a gentle monster
affiliate called Tim Burns is a
fragrance brand. They're really
interesting one to look at for a core
reason I think you could take a lot away
from a their art direction is
incredible. You can see them running the
gentle monster playbook. The form
factors of these fragrances, this foot
is insane. But here we go. When we come
to the chain, one of the things that
they are most known for is basically the
object and usability nature of their
products. Anyone who is designing,
especially a competitive category like
fragrance today, sunscreen, cosmetics,
whatever it is, could learn a lot from.
They're constantly elevating their
objects. So, a good call out there is
one of their more popular products is
this car diffuser for fragrances, right?
But look at the form factor on this and
the elegance of it. And then the ability
for them to leverage culture to promote
that becomes a lot easier when it's a
sculptural object. And how you stand out
in those crowded niches is with things
like that. Same thing with this lip
balm, right? every object becomes an
object of desire, but then they multiply
that by culture. So this is with Jenny
from Blackpink when they were debuting
one of the fragrances. And at the end
when she unveils that egglike design and
you kind of see the connections between
the production that happens and then
what's actually being sold, they're
combining that power of celebrity and
culture with these objects of desire
that people want to line up and get
because of their look. I think what a
lot of people confuse is they want that
celebrity endorsement, but their project
isn't a sculptural object of desire. And
they're also thinking that it has to be
at this level. You have to have Jenny
from Blackpink to have that level of
attention. And that's not what the case
is. The case in this world is there are
tons of micro influencers, celebrities,
actors, musicians who have a smaller
amount of that culture that as long as
you have an object of desire for that
culture and you're partnering with them,
you can do that on your level. And I
would highly recommend scrolling through
the Tambberans page to get some
inspiration there. But you will see
their products have endless accessory
options. One of their more famous ones
was this chain hand, which is a high-end
hand cream, but with the chain attached
to the product. They've then had this
innately social media friendly and
userfriendly addition to something
that's carried every day. We've now seen
them take to another level and really
elevate with the products on their
website today, like this chain wear we
see here, where literally you're having
your perfume bottle attached to these
really intricate, really greatlooking
chains that become an accessory and a
moment inside their own right. And
that's what I would encourage everyone
to think about in the categories you're
working in and especially also if you're
in fashion crossing that over to the
other side is how do you create these
things and become a signature in their
own right. How do you complement the
object that you're doing with something
that works in someone's outfit that
makes them want to wear that makes them
want to show it off? And Timber has done
an excellent job with that I feel has
rarely been circulated in the West. And
so to end this off I'm going to talk
about one of the best artists and
creative directors that I found coming
out of this Korean culture and we can
learn from them. not gonna try and
butcher this name. Let's take a look at
the art and creations here. And we are
in this era. We're in this really
interesting time where our use of tools,
the ability to bring any idea to life,
the technology that we have at our
fingertips, the ability to learn, the
ability for creatives to collaborate,
the accessibility we have to spaces is
just at an all-time high. And I feel
like the work is interesting. more and
more people make good work, but less and
less people make outstanding work, even
though we're in a era where that is
inherently more possible than ever. This
is something I think about a lot for
myself where I feel like I make a lot of
standard work, but what does it really
mean to break out of that shell? That's
something I'm really looking at as I go
into next year. And this artist is doing
it right at the highest level with the
best stuff using every piece of
technology and tool that's available.
Creating on a level that if you're not
exposed to this type of work, you have
no idea that this kind of stuff even
exists. And it's doing it with inherent
statements behind what's happening
inside the the the products. It's saying
stuff with deeper messages. It's
creating visuals that are ultra
compelling that stand out across
anything that you see on the internet.
And I would take inspiration from stuff
like this as to what the ceiling is of
if you're a creative now, what you could
begin looking like, have your work be in
5 years and 7 years, seeing that there
is really no limit to the levels of what
we can do today. And then going down the
rabbit hole into into their brand,
another scent brand with just like an
incredible unique visual look and
identity to just show you that even in
these extremely crowded markets, there
are people with kind of creative vision
who are still finding extremely
interesting ways and leveraging the fact
that production and new technology and
molding and all these things are easier,
more affordable and accessible than ever
to create stuff that is just amazing.
And so this is cgs_lab.
I will uh put a ton of stuff from all
these on that Cosmos board and link the
Cosmos in the bottom here. So you have
an easy time finding all these
references as well. Uh and to end off, I
know obviously one of the big access
points for a lot of people in into
Korean culture was the popularity of
K-pop demon hunters on Netflix. And to
give an example people are going deep
into that and this idea of going down
the rabbit hole under this. If you were
interested at or inspired by that, it's
easy enough to find the art director for
them on here and see their inspiration,
their process, what they're into, what
references they use. And then a couple
clicks later than that, you can actually
find the production designer who did the
Netflix animation. We have so much
access today to see those things. And I
[music] would just highly encourage you
to look at stuff outside of the normal
day-to-day, outside of what you normally
scroll. Find that one interesting hook
and go down the rabbit hole and begin to
explore new [music] worlds cuz
everything you consume forms what you
create. And I think the more interesting
and wide ranging that is, the more
excited you're going to be and the more
interesting work you're going to do. I
will link the boards below. All the
motion stuff that I mentioned will be
there as well. If you liked this, I have
enough brands to do another one of
these. I haven't even touched Thug Club.
We haven't even gone into uh any of the
food culture that's happening. This is
the tip of the iceberg. I can definitely
do the Korean aesthetics part two. So,
let me know if you want that or we can
just keep [music] it rolling. I
appreciate y'all so much for watching.
Let's go.