this is a video about telling brand
stories on the internet and curation as
a reflection of you I'm going to talk
about mood board Brands Aesthetics of
Storytelling using those as a social
media foundation for Branding and break
down brands that do this at a different
level and some of the mood boarding
tools that people actually roll with
they we're going to shift over to
individual this kind of idea of breaking
down the old version of you and creating
a new one online so first I'm going to
talk about the Giants of mbard brand and
one of the most dominant of which is
sporty and Rich after the Giants I'll
break down some smaller Brands doing
interesting things in a similar space
but from the beginning sporty and Rich
has basically put themselves out there
as a mood even in their latest campaigns
like new stuff in the last you know this
is August 13th right now it's August
31st They are promoting their next
launch by Cur pictures of Britney from
the start they always had the 80s 90s
University 2000 mood board items that
were on their page as part of their
content strategy before they released
any original content it was cure rated
content that basically set the vibe and
the reason that this one is interesting
is this is a relatively divisive brand
because there's plenty of people that
think it's undifferentiated or don't
like the name and then they have a huge
rapid customer base that buys out
everything they've ever done but even
here they have literally like they're
using Adidas iconography and Adidas
Vault items going into their Adidas
collaboration and then they've
supplemented it over time by making
their content their campaigns their
lookbooks look like this curated mood
board environment that they already
created for the brand what they are
doing is they are establishing lore that
they may not have individual when this
brand came out as the brainchild of
someone that was relatively known in the
Hy Beast Community em is the founder but
to tell their story and to tell people
what to expect from the brand they used
a mood board to create that have
continued to throughout their Brand
Story and the reason I want to talk
about this is it's actually a really
nuanced topic because these images
aren't theirs if you go consult some
type of attorney they'd be like yeah I
wouldn't post that as a brand but yet
they do and they're massive and plenty
of other big brands do and there's this
kind of line Happening Here of like okay
is someone going to get clamped out on
or not and then there's also Brands like
we'll talk about hidden next who
basically built their entire presence
before launching a brand on this
curation but the entire purpose of this
is it is the fastest way if you have
some if you are someone with taste or if
you have someone who has a particular
vision in mind to explain it to your
audience is to do it visually and brands
have been around forever you generally
know what you expect from them that can
change over time the way abber cromi has
kind of the same identity but it's moved
a little bit different in this era than
it did when you know I worked there 20
years ago but in the previous era you
had to be doing advertising campaigns
and putting things on TV and doing
lookbooks making sure they actually get
in front of somebody that they could
hunt down whereas now you can tell your
story on a grid on the internet and the
algorithm is getting increasingly good
at putting that content in front of
people I like to give two notes on the
Tik Tok and Instagram algorithm and for
context on why I can do that like
obviously I'm a pretty big Creator on
those algorithms myself and I've now
worked with like upwards of 30 40 brands
on their content plus almost a thousand
people now I think or maybe over a
thousand in Cut 30 and the way those
algorithms work that benefits mood board
items like this is Instagram has big
buckets if it is like hey you are into
street wear it will show you lots of
street wear if you are into this ivy
league aesthetic it will put you in this
ivy league aesthetic like the old money
if you like if you like luxury fashion
it will if you like Selene content like
it will show you product content it is
good at these big buckets and then Tik
Tok is ultra nuanced if you're like
really deep in like cat or mermaid core
or whatever it is it will keep giving
you to a level of nuance that like is
actually like almost shocking but that
means if you put aesthetic content out
around a brand the algorithm can
identify you're in one of those buckets
it is good at delivering it to the End
customer which is why this mood board
concept works this entire sporty and
Rich brand was built on establishing A
vibe and then establishing lore and then
selling things that are akin to that to
people starting off very basic like just
putting the words on a shirt all the way
now to collaborating with some of the
brands that they initially had on the
mood boards all the way to creating
items that are far more representative
and well executed that actually really
match that Vibe better than anyone else
is doing but then we have pool suite and
vacation so you may have heard of
vacation sunscreen they have this very
strong 80s Vibe excellent iconograph and
they spun out of this pool Suite account
which was an internet radio account and
basically a board Instagram account and
why I like to call them out and call it
sporty and Rich and call it hidden which
I'll do next is they all took these kind
of different approaches to how they
inevitably like launched a brand and
they're worth understanding as if you
want to build a visually inspired brand
and take advantage of like Aesthetics or
you want to be a Creator who leverages
this in your own way and I get to
personal later in the video like these
are worth understanding these methods so
pool Suite started with excellent
curation both on the music front and on
the visual front and they had some of
their own Graphics they kind of
obviously create these like Photoshop CD
Concepts when they dropped new playlists
but it is all curated Graphics all mood
board account graphics and they
basically selected those to create a
Vibe for the brand and one of the other
things they did really well is the tone
of voice that they wrote which is
something I think a lot of accounts
don't take into as much mind and part of
why they had a success is they built
they went from Vibes to Vibes and lore
lore basically being the storytelling
you're doing around the feeling the
characters like the World building that
becomes in addition to like the visual
feel that you're getting and so with
this they always had a certain tone of
voice they always had references to
positions inside the pool Suite company
um you know would it would address a lot
of things like a corporate memo they
have these really interesting
copyrighting techniques complemented
with the visuals that really built a
world but what you'll notice is that
they decide to spin out a company
separately and this is I think a lot
comes down to like the ownership of this
content right like this is not their
content you can post a move board
account on the internet you generally
don't get in trouble doing a thing like
that you may get into some sort of back
and forth which I know creators who have
but for the most part people just
generally do this all day without very
little repercussions at various extents
of things all the way from this to like
what maximize does which is like T
taking someone's art and making his own
amazing art out of it but they said hey
we're going to launch our own account
new account for this brand specifically
which is now the core Focus there's not
much posting on pool Suite there's a lot
of posting on vacation they made a a
they took a popular category they said
we're going to apply Aesthetics to a
popular category and I love that they
did it in this versus clothing right cuz
clothing in fashion is extremely hyper
saturated doesn't mean you can't succeed
but actually going and creating a thing
with a formulation with an aesthetic
feeli like if you're the only aesthetic
sunscreen brand is's a significantly
easier way to to succeed in that lane
and to present yourself than if you are
one of a million aesthetic clothing
brands and no matter if you think I have
this specific look you can go find 20
Brands online that probably have a very
similar they've also been around for a
Time curated an audience Etc but they're
still doing you know this idea of
curation as well there's images that pop
into this from like on their feed still
from the 80s and then they're recreating
that same style with their own ads which
is an amazing example I feel like of
taking your aesthetic basis taking your
mood board and then making the mood
board your own by basically that turning
that into like an aesthetic toolkit you
can use this is something I'm pretty
actively working on right now I'm at the
early stages of my brand which is like
more of a grand experiment you know uh
like everything I do and but like where
I'm taking these like vintage
advertising looks um I'll do a future
video where I break down how how we made
this but like basically like an old
magazine ad with video right like
there's an idea if you can take these
Aesthetics that people are expecting of
what like a 2000s catalog looks like and
then add your own twist to it and you
begin to have like a a visual
environment for yourself but to
summarize like sported Rich started with
mood board and brand at once from the
beginning and has kept it going the
whole time pool Suite started as pure
Vibes spun a brand off on it and keeps a
basically like a 9010 brand with those
same like Laur and imagery with a little
bit of like curation left on it and that
was like a transition between the two
and then we have hidden New York
basically the ultimate mood board
account and they post like an incredible
amount of content like I especially at
the beginning when I first saw they they
were posting it went from like a handful
to like 8 10 12 a day there was like an
unlimited amount of things that like
like they're posting like all these I
see here there's three a day four that
was just seven in a a day 3 in a day two
in a day five in a day like they post a
ton pure curation this entire like pop
culture Vibe spanning a number of things
they do and probably one of the biggest
if not the biggest mood board account
with like cultural resid and what they
did was cross poost a lot to them build
out their hidden past present future so
they've combined a couple things here
right interesting to talk about because
they also sell access to information you
can pay to be like on this substack and
get access to their deep Dives and the
cultural things they talk about
basically they have like a journalism
play and then also when you are
subscribed to that
I believe you get access to the drops
and things early as well so you
basically are able to kind of go into
buy the products but they built up
pretty large before launching those
products but now they are they've now
developed their own accounts for this
where they are dropping new stuff all
the time like is a steady stream of like
at least monthly like pretty significant
releases and collaborations where
they've kind of built their own
aesthetic on top of the cultural things
that made them popular for curating and
I'm going to talk about one more and
then we're going to get into like some
of the Core Concepts and like the tools
here so then we have Americana pipe
dream and if you haven't seen this this
is a like Oddball version of this right
because it is is a a very it's
interesting this they're essentially
like an army surplus store and they have
a series of like you they do a bunch of
their own informational videos and like
funny reels and have a lot of
entertainment content similar to how you
could be like a Creator Le brand would
look so they'll have all that going on
breaking down all these like Oddball
items that they're finding but then you
have a essentially like a constant
stream of faux military like quasi quasi
redneck Americana memes and curation of
all kinds like all related to like
military AR Surplus and history and
they're kind of combining all this at
once but the effect of that is you get
every type of content that someone in
their target market might like if
they're very meme driven if they like
more like Creator Style videos if they
like purely like curated mood board kind
of photos and carousels they are giving
it all all extremely particular around
this like Oddball Vibe of like German
armored vehicles who used what camo like
in the name of selling like Surplus
stuff and some some of their own
products and this is an excellent idea I
love bringing this up because it's that
right comment that shows like this isn't
just about fashion brands or cool cpg
Brands like they're selling like Oddball
camo and like tins and Tents and
whatever it is that comes from this like
MREs 2 a demographic that is like all
over the place there's all kinds of
different types of people of all ages
that are into that and they're using
that combination of like lore throughout
history and like fun facts and time and
like interesting stories plus their own
comedic like approaches like almost like
a YouTube style like prank Channel like
on one one corner and then just
weaponizing memes like absolutely
constantly like in a way that's like
like in cultural people like it will
Slither on my feet and I'll be like oh
like I understand exactly what they're
doing and the combination of like
weaponizing all of those is like a true
like lore driven brand to the point now
where they're like a reference point for
other people that that means something
if you say Americana pipe dream to
someone that knows it like there's a
whole bunch of implications that come
from that in their history and it's a
very like of the internet type thing so
this is a good time to talk about this
concept of it's a vend diagram product
Market fit and content market so you're
going to see a couple things here that
are worth there's a lot of curator
account people that just put like
amazing curation on the internet so my
hyper newsletter I do with another
Creator Clayton who runs this uh account
called spreza a newsletter that goes
with it that is very much like men's
wear curation and it'll be like Bruce
wills's Vibes for one he is very like
Men's Wear inspired does an excellent
job curating this like has a a
newsletter around it like isn't selling
like a product based on it but it's like
an excellent curator that's a good
example you he's one of like hundreds of
people that do this in their different
areas in niches but a lot of them can't
monetize or when they monetize the
products don't resonate and the same
thing goes for creators right like I
recognize I a creator that educates a
lot on design branding and marketing I
launched products that are like very
particularly niched and the vend diagram
with my audience is not necessarily
super large there's people in my
audience that will really enjoy a lot
some of those products but I'm not
expecting the majority to and I and
that's I think a good thing when you
understand like as a Creator to actually
not have your brand be super encumbered
to like who you are and so you can do
more interesting things with it have it
Go in different directions not have your
content be dominated by it but you'll
notice when creators fail or curator
accounts fail they may have content
Market fit where they've been able to
make content that works in the
algorithms that people like and love
that if you do that you have content
Market as a short form Video Creator I
have content Market fit long form we're
getting there but then product wise
product Market fits very different right
because do you have a product that just
whether or not you're a Creator no
matter what someone just buys it are
they going to recommend it to a friend
are people coming and getting sales from
you without you doing anything are
people like is is there a feeling where
people talk and are excited of your
brand without you being around it and is
that like continuing to bring you money
without having to spend marketing dollar
that's my Shady version of like what the
product Market fit description is and
sometimes those ven diagrams can be very
different right so someone like sporty
and Rich that vend diagram is a circle
to their female demographic that is
interested in that visual style they are
providing clothing that is exactly on
point for hidden there is a probably a
significant like a half and half overlap
where there's a lot of people that are
interested like the hype Beast
contingent of people that follow them
are understand what the clothes look
like there's a technical style of the
garments like there's a there's a chunk
of those people say it's even a quarter
they're like okay that is perfect for
them but Their audience is so big 2.6
million or whatever that that quarter is
like a huge demographic and someone like
Americana pipe Dre right if you're
interested in all this like weirdo
allball like military facts and like
like somewhat like intelligencia meets
redneck humor then you're probably going
to be interested in a good chunk of
their products there's a pretty
significant content overlap there but
you have to have both for these things
to work right because you can create an
aesthetic but if what you're selling
doesn't quite match the aesthetic or
people that are interested in it don't
want to buy it at that price point or
whatever it is then you can kind of miss
out there and that's why I like what
poolu did is like anyone who's in the
sun uses sunscreen a huge chunk of life
if you're choosing that you have some
level of brand affinity and then also
could stand out aesthetically on the
Shelf like I feel like they have product
Market fit purely from a okay there are
people that will just buy that Vibe
without knowing any of the history or
like any of The Branding being like Oh I
like the Retro One like they have this
an interesting like like visual product
Market fits probably like a separate
video but creating this aesthetic lore
for your brand and this history and
these stories that people roll with can
help you achieve content Market fit and
it can help like see expedite your
product Market fit and I feel like when
you add those two together and you have
both of them you're significantly better
than having one or the other it's not
like one plus one it is a multiple upon
that and that's what these like lore
driven accounts do so how do you
actually find imagery for stuff like
this so the the obvious is Pinterest but
like the funny part about Pinterest me
like most people don't know how to use
Pinterest probably my most used app um
when I use like one sec and brick which
are like little things I do that
basically help me not scroll and like
not consume on the internet when I don't
want to I leave Pinterest on it's an app
where I basically default to if I'm
going on social media I go on there it's
like an inspiration app but the nice
part ni part about Pinterest I'm just
going to go to a board here I'm working
on with like uh the team I have this
working on like our next shoe
silhouettes like we're just putting some
ideas on this board but see this anytime
you make a board and put some pins on it
so I literally pin stuff from Pinterest
and upload stuff from my computer onto
this board and then you see this section
here find some ideas for this board
click that they are basically taking the
visuals you put on there and their
algorithm is curating you a bunch more
that are hyper relevant and for instance
for this like shoe silhouette like I
mean man like one out every five of
these is kind of relevant for this board
they are very good at this and they do
this across demographics and visuals
let's take a look at another board with
a completely different feel so this is
one I was working on for um gel Blaster
as like an inperson video game thing
they're doing at family entertainment
centers it's like super sick and we were
doing bunch of visual planning for that
and for the photo shoots um this is
really like photo shoot based around
this we had like a bunch of like like
anime like cyber Punk stuff but like
same thing like this is literally giving
me like Photo and visual inspiration in
like these like aball futurist Styles
like same thing giving me a bunch there
and so what people don't realize is like
okay I actually have to go hunt down all
those like the algorithms on Pinterest
will help you hunt down specifically the
imagery that you're going for which is
which is a plus sign and they are
curating from a lot of the other mood
board apps too so if you've not used
that more like this function it is a
useful thing in whether just your
general creative career for this then we
have Cosmos so Cosmos is an interesting
stage right now so new mood boarding app
super interesting team they have a much
more curated version of Pinterest like
this is their featured feed they're
curating this feed that comes on which
is very well done so it's basically like
having a a tumbler that was like very
curated by some really visually in like
you know inspired people every day and
it has a For You algorithm based on the
things I'm already pinning but since it
is still relatively small and the people
that are using it are kind of the right
people and they are kind of forcing the
hand inside this featured section of a
lot of what is on the platform the
Aesthetics here are very very very good
and while this lasts like someday when
they get heavy adoption you're not going
to be able to fight for forever like
there I'm sure there will be a dir of
like mediocre content on there but until
then this is an excellent place with
which you are able to get that you know
basically work with inside the same
Pinterest framework that what's called
clusters which are boards they have a
couple other interesting tools but this
isn't a cosmos ad so we won't go too
deep into it but basically this is a
great place to find visual inspiration
in a similar way in a more curated
fashion if these visuals are the kind of
things that appeal to you inside what
you're building and then we have Arena
which is where art directors and
creative directors and designers who are
like serious actually works what I like
the most about the arena feed is that
actual working professionals use it and
share it a lot more than Pinterest in
the others it's not like just creative
professionals like the right creative
professionals like the difference
between like hey like I'm on a shoot and
I'm working with you know I'm trying to
think of like mainstream stuff like yeah
like I'm on the shoot I'm working with
the Pepsi team like I'm probably getting
like a Pinterest link or something from
their their their damn digital asset
management but uh if I'm working with
like a team and they're doing a shoe
with dazed or whatever it's going to be
like an arena board and I think that's
where like you can just tell by the
people who who have like that certain
like culture standard are working inside
this framework and the reason is because
like those other people are on it right
so the actual level of stuff you can get
and go down the rabbit hole on like this
is channels other otherwise feature of
this Channel and you can basically go
down the rabbit hole of like actual
amazing people that are working who are
kind of curating a bunch of these kind
of like like extremely well done like
thought looking feel the level that
other people aren't and then you can
actually go and be like all right I like
this visual Vibe oh here's all the other
boards that's It's featured in and be
like okay cool someone put all right
Eric has put 7.4 th000 pins on his type
design board like he's obviously taking
this [ __ ] seriously I'm I can go look at
this for my type inspiration and so
arena is like the ultimate Rabbit Hole
mood board brand so it's worth
understanding like the three apps the
kind of differences between them but
this is your toolkit if you are trying
to establish lore for your brand online
want to put visuals out there before you
release things or while you release
things to help tell a visual story
there's a lot that happens inside these
apps to help bring you the imagery that
does it and then we have like the more
expanded versions right if you actually
want to go and find things other people
don't have you're dealing with like
internet archives using the way back
machine which is where you can kind of
go down websites that used to exist and
try to find and like scrape images from
them because it has like a picture of
these images you can put in like look at
a website through time and how it
changed like or you're buying lots of
magazines off eBay or whatever there's a
Japanese version of it I forget the name
of that and you're basically buying big
chunks of magazines and like I have
grips inside my shelving of like I have
like all these Vintage High Times lots
and uh like even Newsweek was really
solid just for for for ads like even
things I got all the archives of like
the Chrome Hearts mags this is where you
can really like start to actually dig
into images other people don't have
right everything else that you've seen
I've gone through the internet like
someone else can ideally get to there's
a difference between that and like
imagery people have seen before imagery
that you're presenting in a new way and
then this like third party like
undiscovered imagery where you're
unearthing archives so I'm going to zip
through a few more of these real quick
just you can see some other examples
aren't like absolutely massive so metal
Wood's another good one like around 50k
where they are combining all this like
internet iconography in their products
like OB this is like a super famous ad
that they then you know recreated with a
metalwood golf ball instead of this used
to be like this was like a tennis ball
ad prior um if it was like Wilson or
cost or whoever that was back in the day
they are taking all this internet
iconography and building it into this
like amalgamation of their brand and
basically adding in golf and their
iconography on top of it in a way that
is excellent so I think they're a great
example of a brand kind of doing like
creating their own visual lore in an
interesting way have gum tree golf is
another one where they're doing a lot of
like presenting this like visual idea of
like being outside and the more like
existential side of golf birds and
whatnot and they're like kind of
applying the same mood board aesthetic
but they have like unique visual ideas
like this notification silenc idea and
like the their curating a carousel
around that like with their entire brand
Vibe whether these like these may all be
original pictures some might be original
or mve board not sure but it's just idea
of creating that visual idea that goes
with it so I'm going to end with talking
about like the role of an individual in
this as well is because I do think for a
lot of creative designers brand owners
now you are an extension of your brand
and I like the hidden example uh a lot
because it's basically like you have
them and they're Anonymous they sell
media they sell clothing all on the back
of their basically their taste level now
for a lot of creatives a lot of people
that put content out there on the
Internet or they're trying to do that or
that need to Showcase their taste in one
way I believe that you less so than
starting a major brand expecting huge
success from that I believe we're going
to see a lot more people that are like
amalgamations of this and I will likely
do a Studios video at some point I know
I always rattle off in these videos that
will come in the future but they slowly
trickle out but basically this idea that
you're going to be able to potentially
launch a brand at some point potentially
sell info products or templates or
subscriptions to your newsletter your
substack or whatever and then also offer
your freelance work and your services
and things that you do or just like want
to get a job we are now in this world
where like I basically like put having a
portfolio like isn't quite the right way
to story tell instead it's this combo of
like show your taste via curation like
these are the things I like this is how
I think and there's a certain degree of
people that are going to be really
connected to that and follow you for
that and like begin to associate things
with you around that and that can come
from like on your personal account like
posting the selects of the things you
like right like so Clayton's account I
showed earlier like he has an extremely
tasteful account that shows his Acumen
for identifying those things and when
work comes to him a lot of it comes from
people who recognize that or who think
in a similar way who go I want someone
that thinks like that to work on this
project even when we started
collaborating like I knew him lightly
but I could tell immediately by what was
on the feed that he thinks about things
in a really intentional way and it's a
different way than how I think and I
like that compliment but one exercise I
talk a lot about like with creatives I
run into like in the real world who are
stuck is like there's a this moment you
need to have of like a creative
reinvention and it's also a moment that
repeats right because I feel like
everyone needs to think that I have this
identity and I stick with it forever
when that's not the case right is like
at some point in time you're going to
need to reinvent and for some people
that might be every 6 months you open a
new chapter of your life or whatever and
like you need to go through like these
phases of reinvention where it's like
cool I'm going to clear my mood boards
I'm going to start something new I'm
going to add new things to my account
I'm going to begin to to find a vibe
that I want to present for myself that I
want to like use to inspire how I think
like the things on my wall or in my
environment or like around in my house
or on the background of my phone or
whatever or like is going to actually
influence how I think and act because
it's front of mind which is like a
really crucial thing that I think a lot
of creativ need to understand is like
the visual things around you are going
to then influence how you think and what
you create and then how you present that
forward facing right because I think
it's good to let people know what to
expect and to know what you're into and
to be able to take pride in the things
that you're interested in and
potentially like put your own spin on it
or make edit or curate your Carousel or
whatever that looks like and then
recurringly do that so that when someone
goes to your social media feed they can
see a combination of the work you've
done youve posted your portfolio stuff
the things that you're into and like and
presented in your own like interesting
way and you begin to have this like
offline and online Persona that kind of
ties together that's that moves in
Seasons or years or waves and I do think
it's worth like thinking like if you're
in a rut right like have I been in this
rut for a long time like would this rut
be changed if I had a more like of a
visual Focus or a like philosophical
Focus right now and how I think about
things or what I want to achieve and
like kind of identify a time frame for
that I think for a lot of people like
sometimes you need to make moves like
you need to change your visual look and
feel what you're into like every six
months you to clear the walls like clear
the mood boards like clear the Wardrobe
sell stuff on deop or grilled or
whatever like come back with like a new
visual sense of yourself and to like
keep things moving to keep yourself
stimulated there's a lot of people that
are like that who I think wait way too
long versus just doing it and like
finding your own way to like have a
ritual that like creatively resets
yourself I'm thinking about this a lot
like for for myself personally um like
as I make a lot of content start posting
a lot more Vlog content where I just
show the things like in and around my
world the things that I have the things
I'm into the places that I go um because
I'm trying to be more intentional about
like what that looks like and I'm trying
to Showcase this idea more of like
instead of just being purely a curator
of ideas that like there is a visual and
inspirational like lifestyle that goes
along with that that is not about like
money or like any like some degree of
success or whatever it is it's about
like curating the interesting visual
things like in your life and creating a
library of them and then sharing that
like with the Internet is that is a
Content I'm playing with I'm trying to
really double down on I'm looking at
being like okay cool I really want to do
that for this next six months heavily
and then decide if I want to continue
from there one of the best reasons to
have this kind of mood board sensibility
and aesthetic and the things that you're
putting out there to me is really around
like the things that you have around you
in your life the things that you post as
a reflection of yourself are the things
that like tend to come true and I'm not
saying that always happens but more
often than not the people that I know
that very seriously take the intentions
of I'm going to become this I'm going to
do X and Y or I have all these pictures
up on the vision board and I continually
think about like they're not just on the
board but how do I get to there how do I
make decisions around that like are the
people that actually achieve it and
we're this in this living breathing
experience now where we're on our phone
so much and we're required to do so much
work and we're having all these like new
experiences and this ability to like
shift your visual identity all the time
or to reinvent yourself or to put a out
a piece of content that could change
your life that I feel like it's almost
more important than ever and to have
those like really think through like
what is this visual theme and this
identity and this lore and history and
mystery that I have as a person of the
things I do and the things I choose to
do whether you're in LA or whether
you're in Kentucky like wherever you
choose to go put online what your
weekend looked like and your curated
version of that and what you printed out
from a mood board or how you looked or
like the vehicle you chose the places
you went or your unique spin on
capturing content of it really becomes
like a summation of your identity and I
know a lot of us don't want that we want
to be more than what we represent online
but the truth is the work that we get so
often comes from that or is reinforced
by that or opportunities that we get
come from people that talk about us when
we're not in the room based on things
that we put online that it just becomes
gradually more important than ever so
really the point of that this like last
chunk of this conversation was to be
intentional about that to know that that
is a factor in where you go creatively
or as a brand and to think about what
you want to achieve the phase you're in
and if you need a reset or if you need
longer time to do it