In this video, we are going to talk
about the seven stages of marketing and
brand building. This walks through
everything from what to focus on when
you're at a new brand or just starting
all the way to when you're a big brand
and trying to maintain relevance. What
are all these stages? It's really useful
to understand as a creative or as a
marketer to know where your toolkit best
applies and also to think about as a
brand owner if you're stuck or you feel
like you're concentrating on the wrong
things. So, no matter where you're at in
your journey, I think there's a lot you
can learn from this video, and I'm
excited to get into it. Let's lock in.
But first, let's talk about stage one.
What do you do at the very beginning of
your journey? What do you focus on?
We're inundated with all these
recommendations and all these different
strategies. And people often feel like
they're being pulled in so many
different directions or they need to do
something because someone says they
should do it. That's what everyone else
is doing. But here's what really is the
difference. At stage one of your
marketing, level one is one organic paid
strategy. You need to find one thing
that works. And you may test a few to
get there, but you need to be laser
focused on getting one thing that makes
money. This is the foundation from which
all the rest of your brand is made. And
honestly, nothing else matters. Not an
amazing brand kit, not awesome art
direction. It may be something different
than what you expect. And it also may
not be the most glamorous thing, but one
organic or paid strategy that makes you
money. This is important because you
need this to actually fund the next
stage of your growth. You need to
validate where your product is at. And
you need to be able to say, "Hey, I'm
making some money off this thing that
allows me to invest it further in the
business." And what you'll see happen is
a lot of businesses will start expanding
into other stuff without having a
profitable channel and they'll just get
further and further underwater. And if
you're in that scenario, which happens
to a lot of people, I just recommend
cutting back and going and focusing on
finding that one thing. And a few
examples kind of both small and large.
What I like to look at for a big brand
that I think is kind of underestimated
inside this was when David launched
their protein bars. They actually found
their channel inside Tik Tok shop, which
I don't even know if they expected, but
they had a product with a strong set of
USPS, unique selling points. Basically,
they offer the most protein to the least
amount of calories and the least amount
of sugar of any protein bar on the
market, which gives them a real leg up
to market on a network like Tik Tok
shop. And they sold a lot of bars on
commission with creators doing that that
would had far more efficacy than what
they did on social media and also help
them get lift and awareness as they went
into retail. Over in the organic world,
an example I absolutely love is Bad
Ombres. They are a frozen bean and
cheese burrito company that services
only Arizona and they have thrived on
organic Instagram where they were
continually told the story of how this
couple was starting a frozen bean and
cheese burrito company and all the
trials and tribulations that came from
that. But by focusing on carousels, on
videos, and on stories purely
organically, they've sold out every drop
again and again, knowing that that's the
key channel that helps drive their
story. But before anything else, before
you move on, before you think about
optimization or spending more money, get
to this one thing. And it may differ by
your skill set may take you some time to
find, but that is step one. Then step
two is the foundation. And if you're a
marketer and you're starting at a
company early or you're a freelancer,
you probably help a lot of companies in
this stage. That's someone who's gotten
this initial channel. They've made some
sales, they've done some things, but now
they need to move forward, build out
their team, begin to think bigger. And
so in this foundation stage, really what
you do is you lay all the foundation of
what you need to scale. You do these
things that are going to multiply the
efforts that come after it. And this is
why I don't want to ignore this stage.
You don't want to hop right to expanding
out to tons of channels. Dial in this
foundation first and it pays off
dividends. So what does this include?
This a includes landing pages. Where do
consumers land on your website and how
do they convert and how do you make sure
it's good? So there's software like
Replo that spins up multiple landing
pages and quick pages and different
experiences. And what you'll find is
that if you have different landing pages
for your different drops and your
campaigns that actually link to
specifics around them, different landing
pages for different influencers, for
different customer archetypes based on
the what you're emphasizing in the ad,
it makes a huge difference in your
overall conversion. And getting into the
habit of how do we do this? Do we do
this default in Shopify? If we are a
leadbased service, are we using
something like Clickfunnels or Lead
Pages? What are we doing there? All the
way to if you're e-commerce, you're
using something like Replo. How do you
make sure you are making the most out of
every visit you get? Related to that, we
talk about email. We talk about SMS. So,
I obviously use Omnisend for stuff like
this, but there's also pop-up software
and other things that can really help
improve it. But every time someone lands
on your site, the higher chances you get
their email, the more value that has to
you over time. And then once you have
that email or that SMS, what they're
educated with and how that works pays
off dividends as you add more and more
people to it. So, there's a software
called Aaliyah helps optimize pop-ups.
And in this stage, you're really
thinking through what am I giving people
when they sign up on my email list? What
is my offer? Am I testing discounts? Am
I putting it on every page? Am I leading
on the homepage or do I have guides?
What am I doing to make sure I get that
download? And then what technology am I
using to get it? That's one part of the
equation. Then the other part is what
does automation look like? And I have an
entire email marketing video you can
find on my profile where I dive deep
into this. But basically, how are you
educating people about your brand
automatically? How are you providing
education to new customers? The more of
those auto emails and automation flows,
that is then something that exists. If
you have a thousand more customers come
in, they automatically get into this
flow. their lifetime value increases and
it makes a huge difference. That's why
we recommend investing that time and
energy at this stage once you're making
a little money to set all this up to
then enable you to efficiently scale
after. And that leads us to the third
stage of brand building. That is the
multiplier. That's basically taking all
the things you're doing already and
putting them across as many places
before you think about something new.
So, for instance, if you're doing really
well with your Instagram organic
content, but you didn't put the time in
to cross post and Tik Tok all the time,
it's going back uploading all that old
content, putting the new content in, and
if it's not perfect, if it doesn't quite
work or you've been trying it, trying to
say, "Hey, how can I manually adjust
this? How can I build a workflow to
slightly update these existing assets
I'm already doing to get max value?" On
the advertising end, this can apply
where if you're running a bunch of those
ads on Meta, this is where you're
saying, "Hey, can I bring this over into
TikTok? Can I be using GMV Max? Do I
have additional places I can use these
assets I'm already investing in to make
money? And there's often not a ton of
room here, but it's worth doing this and
making sure you're in that habit of yes,
my Instagram stuff is going into my
email marketing. I'm actually pushing it
to Tik Tok and we make slight changes,
but it's worth the time to do that cuz
we're gaining traction there. And
thinking through what all those
multipliers look like when brands are
looking to find that breakout thing,
their unique special sauce or scale, a
topic that always comes up is brand
collaborations. And I'm actually going
to go inside Particle and look at the
actual data from a number of the most
popular brand collabs that we've seen
recently. And it's going to show you
some of the strategies behind what an
actual collab looks like. You're going
to find pretty interesting. So, I'm
going to start with Melbourne Golf and
their collaboration with Neighborhood.
So, Melbourne's been made a pretty big
name on collabs in general, but this is
typical of what you'll see when there's
brands that have an overlapping fan
base. They want to take advantage of
that. They want to sell out, but there's
not like a big commercial appeal in the
collab. So, looking here, you can
actually see the day this launch was
available. basically sold out within
like 3 or 4 days. There's not much
volume after this first week. They're
doing a low amount of units. 100 of each
of these shirts, 60 of these golf bags,
which is the marquee item. This is a
pretty typical collab that fits that
mold. Brand awareness for both. They're
not trying to move major units. Then we
can look at a collab that's about brand
awareness. So, this is the Kith Giorgio
Armani collab. And they aren't selling
much of this at all. They promoted the
hell out of it. Lookbooks, campaigns,
etc. And maybe they sell in store like a
decent amount more, but online they sold
22 of these $600 shirts. They're selling
like four of this short sleeve, 12 of
these shoes, like combined. This is
brand building. This is Kit saying, "We
want to be associated with Giorgio
Armani. We want their logo right next to
ours. We're going to pay a big fee for
that. We're going to promote that and we
don't really care if we make the money
back from it." It's about building brand
to sell our other stuff. And it's worth
understanding that strategy when you see
these bigname collapse. But on the other
end of this, you see what Ski did with
Roberto Kavali. So this is a milliondoll
plus collab launch and it's just
swimwear. So what they're doing is
they're making luxury more affordable.
So with the Kith Armani collab, it's as
expensive as buying an Armani item. It
just has a Kith logo on it. But this
you're basically the cheapest entry
point you're going to get into the
Kavali universe. $88 tops, $188 one
pieces. And they're selling an absolute
ton of them cuz Skiims has a huge
audience. you can buy into luxury and
they're doing 2,000 swimsuits, 1500
swimsuits. They're just hammering the
sales on these. And you'll see some of
the products they have that are more
unique. They only made a small volume.
But that's a strategy for a brand,
especially a brand like SKIMS to be able
to say, "Hey, we're going to pay a fee
to Kavali. We're going to do this
campaign that builds our brand with
luxury, and we're actually going to make
a lot of money back selling these units
because we know our customer wants to
buy into that luxury at our price point,
and we have them in our database, on our
list, in our social media." And then we
have Kai by Kylie Jenner. So she does a
lot of collabs with young and upand
cominging designers. It's actually a
good showcase point for those designers
to get exposure to like the Kardashian
industrial complex. But these are small
too. 160 units, 100 units. Again, this
is brand building for the new designer.
It's brand building for Kai to be
collaborating with these cool hot
people, but they're not doing massive
numbers. No one's making a ton of money.
It's exposure and brand building for
both of them. Also a good reminder when
you go talk to a manufacturer that like
yes, people are actually doing runs of a
hundred of this kind of stuff. maybe two
or 30 hund moved across colorways. You
can see all this data in particle.
You'll notice here that I have all this
cut to certain date ranges around when
these launches are. And we actually put
together a little collaborative project
based purely on collabs where you can
dive into this collab data and more. I
will link that down below. It's a little
resource report that particle has put
together to get you to understand
collabs and their data more. And if you
are looking to do market research,
whether it's to start a new brand, to
understand what people in your space do
as far as volume on stuff like this so
you know how much to produce, Particle
is an amazing tool to be able to use
stuff like that. And I appreciate them
for sponsoring this video. And then we
get to stage four, the most crucial
stage, the stage I've worked with the
most businesses on, and that is the
crossover stage. This is when you've
gotten some initial success, you're
making some money, you still have a
small team, but you've got to take it to
the next level. And this means you're
actually going to switch from just doing
what you did to start where, hey, I grew
an organic Instagram or I really
hammered Tik Tok shop. Whatever that one
thing is, now you're going to add in the
rest. You're going to say, "Hey,
methodically, case by case, without
sacrificing my profitability, but with
taking some risk, go from just organic
into organic and paid, or I'm going to
go from just paid to adding paid plus
Amazon and add organic on top of that."
You want to basically flesh out the
channels that you're sold in and having
that combo of ads and organic cuz if
you're not doing both super well, you're
going to have a hard time. The earlier
that you get into, yeah, I do both of
these, great. Once you've built your
foundation as a crucial part of brand
building and this is where if you're a
freelancer, you're a marketer, you're
going to be able to make a huge impact
inside this stage because if you're an
excellent at one of these things or the
crossover between them and you can find
efficiency, you can maximize value for a
brand. And in this to do this well, you
have to pick your channels. What are we
going to do? How similar are they? Are
there lift? One thing that's talked
about a lot inside this is when you
invest a lot in Tik Tok shop, you
naturally go up inside Amazon. If you're
already big on Tik Tok organic, adding
shop and adding Amazon makes a huge
difference. Similarly, if you're in a
service business and you're starting to
get a lot of leads from one channel, it
may be the time to say, "Hey, let's
really invest in Google search or some
of these places or SEO where people are
beginning to go for that same thing
we're already marketing where we can
reap the organic benefit." But you also
have to decide your metrics. What are
you measuring? Is it your return on ad
spend? Where are you doing brand
awareness? What does this team report in
every week? Often times when you've
built up to this level, you're measuring
some things, but if you're not creating
a culture of trackable accountability by
the time you hit this stage, you need to
get it in place. Then last is the
responsibilities. What can the people on
your team realistically handle? What can
get patched in and who is responsible
for what? Up until this stage of the
business, there's likely a handful of
people doing so much different stuff.
You have to really look at what is
outsourcable. Do people know what their
roles are? What's their day-to-day
responsibility? and how are they
reporting to each other? Because if
you're not actually sharing with each
other what you're working on, how it's
going, and how it's judged going into
this stage, you have a hard time going
to the next one. And for a lot of
brands, this takes a lot of time to
actually make that moment where you're
going, we're good at organic, and we're
good at ads. We've put some of these
metrics in place. We've brought in the
team and they're the right people.
Sometimes this can last years. They're
brands I've heard of over the last few
years, but they're not overnight. Some
have been around for 10 years, for 5
years, because this stuff takes time.
And I cannot emphasize enough that
especially in America, we're always in
such a rush to I need to have my brand
and be doing a million a month. And
sometimes this is a much longer journey.
That's how I look at it with the brands
I have. The women's wear brand I work
on, we working on for six plus years and
really only started to have traction the
last few. Even what I'm doing with the
brand stuff I sell basically as my merch
with my valuable stuff kind of and it's
interesting. It's a playground for me.
I'm not stressing the time and attention
and what it looks like. And maybe in a
few years it gets super laser focused on
one thing I see an opportunity of. But
in the meantime, it's about building a
foundation. But once you're there,
that's what leads us to number five. And
this is the funnest part of brand
building. Also one of the hardest is
that is getting your secret sauce. Every
brand who crosses from this level before
it into this next level, really begins
to enter the zeitgeist to get some
escape velocity has one secret sauce
thing. It could be a takeoff viral
series. It could be a funnel that's like
perfect and really nailed. It could be a
product, an advancement, something
that's like crazy and elevates the brand
to the next level that becomes your
signature. Collaborations also serve a
lot here. If there's a jumping off point
where you got to work with a major brand
in the category and they opened you up
to a huge awareness level or maybe
collabs become more frequent part of
what you work on or if you just have
real expertise in one thing that you
triple down on. And some quick examples
here on that last one, having real
expertise. I look at this brand Hollow
Alpaca. They are a socks brand. They
make alpaca socks. When you say socks
brand, how could that possibly be
glamorous? What should you double down
on there? They have ads expertise. They
are killer meta ads people. And you go
look at their account inside foreplay or
inside an ads transparency tool. You are
going to see in like a huge amount of
volume of ads and they're crazy. They're
utilizing every format. There's podcast
ads. There's AI hooks. There's full AI
videos, there's typical videos, UGC
statics. They are running every
conceivable thing. They are done to a
tea in the best-in-class execution
across everything. And they realize,
look, this is our secret sauce. We may
not know influencer. or you may not know
some of these other pieces, but we can
be the best at this thing. And that is
that brand secret sauce. It's allowed it
to achieve a way bigger market than you
ever would have expected in DTOC socks.
But by the same token, sometimes this
could be an understanding of modern
media and social media. So I look at
Cozy Earth. They did this thing called
the bedrock challenge. They basically
invited a bunch of influencers to a big
event. They covered it on TikTok. There
was lots of challenges. The influencers
posted, they posted, and they went
ultraviral by doing this unique, very
modern approach to event driven stuff on
Tik Tok. This is something that a lot of
other brands wouldn't sign up for, even
know how to do, was a risk for them.
They had to invest in it. And that's
what this stage is. This stage, you
might take some shots. You might be
spending 100K and it doesn't work. You
might have to take a few shots on goal.
But since you've built your foundation,
you scaled across channels, you have the
ability to do that. For someone like
Cozy Earth, they took advantage of the
modern internet. the fact they knew how
to use it created this massive viral
moment. Now they have a repeatable
framework. It's better than anyone else
in the betting category. And then once
you're there, once you have that one
secret item, it's about scale. Taking
every channel and going pedal to the
metal. And two brands I want to talk
about that are excellent examples of
this are Represent and Bridge Wallet. So
these are brands that got to that
previous stage, put the pedal to the
metal, and are both leaning towards nine
figure brands, if not nine figure brands
already. And their secret sauce is
interesting. So Represent for instance,
they found their secret sauce with the
personal brand building around George
and Michael and documenting that on
YouTube, having his Instagram blow up,
becoming like a true charismatic,
aspirational character for their target
demographic that was larger than life
that none of their competitors have. And
Ridgewall did it almost the opposite
way. They leaned into doing some unique
vehicles like they do contests, they've
given away cyber trucks and Lamborghinis
that was one. They leaned into all other
media. They're doing street interviews.
They kind of lean into every scalable
thing. But the real factor was they
recruited Maris Brownley, one of the
biggest YouTubers in the world, as a
member of their team, as a equied person
working with and around Ridge that put
them on the map to a much wider audience
in a much different way that no other
brand around them was doing. But you'll
know both of those brands had that big
marquee moment or concept that has
driven them and given them the ability.
They put the gas on everything else cuz
you have to be good at both that special
sauce and everything around it. And this
is the stage most brands live in for
years and years to continue to put that
pedal on the gas, keep their culture,
keep their metrics strong, keep their
responsibilities, and get to as large as
they can. It's kind of like a dream
framework to get to this. But then you
get to stage seven. And look, we live in
this world of disruptor and challenger
brands where when you get to a certain
level, all of a sudden you're competing
against the younger, leaner, smarter,
more modern team that you once were who
can take more risks, that's more savvy,
that can move faster. And it's harder
and harder to compete with them. that
cycle gets faster and faster. So for any
brand that's already at that scale, they
need to be laser focused on continuing
to execute without getting slow and a
methodology to stay interesting. It's
very similar to the secret sauce in
five, but more harder and more
conceptual to wrap your head around is
how do you continue to stay interesting
over time and have that
attention-grabbing thing. And one of my
favorite examples of this is SKIMS.
Skiim sells very undifferiated products
unlike any other lingerie or activewear
or basics brand. But they've done two
things that have really kept them in the
spotlight. And the first is using
product as marketing, introducing
conceptual products into their flow. So
even though they're selling you basics,
they're launching head wraps and nipple
bras, these things that grab attention
as part of their core process and then
people come to their pages, see the
other things, and convert. And it's now
a core part of their marketing kit. And
on top of that, they've done
collaboration and campaigns, but they do
it relentlessly. They do multiple a
month. They have celebrities behind
them. They've worked with everybody from
Kavali collabs to having Patrick
Schwarzenegger in their ads to Shay
Gilles Alexander huge athletes. Same
thing with models, male, female, WNBA.
They have they basically said we're
going to onslaught the amount of
campaigns and collaborations that we do
and the amount of people that are the
faces of them, what the art direction
looks like spans from everyone from Lana
Del Rey down to people we've never heard
of. And they're like, "Hey, this
velocity can keep us more relevant and
more on the internet than any brand
that's competing with us." And those are
the levels I think it's worth thinking
about with your toolkit. You as a
creative, you as a marketer, where can
you lend the most value? Where do you
need to improve? Working at companies at
these different stages to begin to add
stuff to your toolkit so you get this
kind of complete holistic understanding
of how brands work and operate. And if
you're an entrepreneur, thinking
critically about that I skip a stage and
that's why I'm flailing or where am I at
in this journey? And it's okay to be at
some of these stages for a few years and
think critically about what you need to
do to move forward. But hopefully this
serves as a road map for where you are
in this process. And look, in my journey
at this point in my life, having been
through many of these again and again
and seeing some fail and blow up because
they tried to scale too fast or didn't
have a foundation or they never got past
that one channel, I've seen the downside
of so many of these. And now at this
stage, I get to actually think back and
think critically about where can the
things that I know about and the skill
set lend the most value inside the
projects that I work on. But anyway,
I've hope you've enjoyed this video and
you'll see the whole series of all these
conversations we have with these London
businesses come out in the new series of
creative operations here in a few weeks.
Thanks for watching.
[Music]