In this video, we are going to talk
about the art and creative direction of
Ralph Lauren and Capitol, the
aspirational and the mythical. And this
is fresh in my mind because of the new
Olympics merchandise that we just saw
from Ralph highlighted on the ultimate
curator Outlander brings up a great
reason to talk about why Ralph is he
didn't just build a brand, he built the
aesthetic of aspirational America. Ralph
is one of the only designers whose world
is far bigger than their clothes. He's
defined the entire perception of a
country and that's happened through the
brand they built and also just
strategically through things like being
the Olympics partner for this for so
many years and many perceive the brand
as prep but the real story is that his
work is cinema.
>> It was perfect
perfect everything down to the last
minute details. We are going to talk
about the core of his brand, the art
direction and archetypes inside of it,
subbrands and strategies that got it to
where it is. But this came together in a
different world in a different time.
We're going to bridge into the Japanese
brand copy. Talk about what you can do,
what you can actually learn from a brand
like Ralph Lauren and apply yourself.
And I think there is almost no better
example of a brand than Capital. If
you're hung up on pronunciation, this
probably isn't going to be the video for
you.
There are so many lessons in how to
build on existing iconography, existing
brand concepts without just taking them.
And this is going to be a video where we
go through all of that. If you have a
brand, if you just love either of these
brands, if you're a student of fashion,
you are going to love this video. I
can't wait to go through this journey
with you. Let's lock in. Let's start
with a sense of purpose. Feel like
nowadays everyone glorifies selling a
brand, building something to make a ton
of money. But what if you make something
that could last for generations? So when
I was in the UK, you may have seen the
series I did with Air. We actually
talked to a lot of brands. We talked to
Earl Veast out there, talked to
Milwaukee. They both operate retail
stores, sell their own products and
other people's products. And they both
care so much about taste and the
lifestyle and the craft of the things
that they sell. And it became apparent
as we talked to a lot of these brands,
all of them were in London, it's very
different than what you see in America
where people are building to make money.
They're building to sell versus building
more for legacy or building because it's
their calling. I think it's what we've
seen with Ralph Lauren as well is it's
become a legacy for him as a person.
It's become so much greater and as
funding comes and goes or involvement or
whatever, you see an expression of
someone who realized it's not just their
vision but a vision greater than
themselves. And I want to encourage so
many young people to look at your brand
in that long-term perspective. Look at
whatever you do plan to build. really
think through the do I really want to
have an exit at some point or am I
creating a creative summary of not just
my life's work but perhaps a concept
that's greater than me that's embodying
the community and what I stand for and
what I create and with that part of why
Ralph got so big is he created a fantasy
that people wanted to live in he
presented not a real America a cinematic
America aspirational it wasn't fashion
it was lifestyle you're buying into the
family with the ranch the Hampton's
house the vacation to the Aspen Chalet
with friends. By wearing Ralph, you
could feel like you could go right along
on that journey, provided you're wearing
polo. Creating this aspiration is really
hard if you don't live it. And it's a
very different approach than modern
street wear and positioning. When I did
my video about Stucy, it was about
friends and what friends did together.
You often saw groups of people or
individuals living a life that was very
unglamorized or cinematic. It was still
really cool, but it was based on the
passions those people were choosing to
do. Or something you wanted to do, but
it's one step away. It's like your cool
friend who's adjacent. money didn't come
into the equation as much as the life
you chose. But Ralph chose a very
specific type of Americana, one that you
know exists, but you probably feel on
the outside of or tangential. And if you
are in, you need to make sure you have a
uniform that also signifies you know
what you're doing and are of belonging
and feels perfect for it. And it zones
in this idea of location as identity.
Ralph basically uses all these pieces of
America to form the core of what the
company stands for. Aspen in the ski
life, Colorado, Montalk in the Hamptons,
New England in the original style, the
playing of actual polo in the south.
They always represented their customer
in there as aspirational. They're
noticeably adult. Even the young people
in there, young people who want to
appear older. There's this desire for
maturity both in how they show
everybody, even the younger people, what
they want to be. Whereas someone like
Kif basically sells older people the
ability to feel young. Who really buys
the most expensive pieces they have?
It's guy's 40s and 50s. very different
than the casual t-shirt consumer who
want to still feel relevant, who still
have the Jordans. They're buying youth.
The Ralph Lauren customer is buying
maturity. And it became such a symbol of
that that a whole culture came out with
low lives and people racking polo to
co-opt the power of that for themselves.
That's its own video. But in addition to
location, the brand had clear archetypes
and archetypes that we knew in our
lives. rugged cowboy, the polished
Manhattanite, the collegiate sportsman
or sportswoman, the American child of
privilege, weathered rancher still feels
successful. These characters built the
narrative system. I talked about this in
my Balenciaga video. The idea of the
character study is something Dem is
doing at Gucci right now or really
putting a character on there, saying the
influencer, presenting them in their
model look. So what Gucci is doing is
taking hundreds of archetypes. There's
100 people that represent the Gucci
customer. We have so many customers.
We're all such individuals. But Ralph
Lauren was very particular. They had
more than just one or two archetypes.
They had maybe 10, but they were very
specific in how they went those across
and having other people want to be
inside of them. And now we're in this
world where people have fluid
identities, right? You may dress in one
style one day, another the next. Gen Z
and Gen Alpha have a whole basically how
they want to feel, how they dress or
what they engage with. Versus in my
generation and my my older brothers, for
instance, you were a skater. You grew up
as a skater and you stayed a skater
style afterwards. What I love about
Ralph Lauren is that they didn't just
have these archetypes, know who their
customer was. They literally developed
labels over time specifically to speak
to them. RRL, original Polo Country,
Speak to the Rancher, Polo Sports,
speaking to basically anyone athletic
with that more elevated or prep feel,
Purple Label, Black Label. There are so
many brands that flirted in and out of
the core of Ralph that when they saw an
angle, they could build an entire thing
around it. And we see that now, right?
One of the brands we talked to in the
UK, Perl had just released like their
athletic subline in addition to their
more standard men's wear. You'll see
brands break into this, but this is one
of the greats of how many they were able
to do and look at over time. More than
just a Rick Owens and a dark shadow. But
with these classic archetypes came
classic art direction. Eternal golden
hour lighting, relentless use of the
outdoors. The person and activity,
everything's a gathering. The brand is
worn together. groups of young people,
pairs of people, people competing,
people hanging out, clothes to impress
other guys, or let other girls know
where you are in life or that you
belong. This is what our group does.
You're either this or you're not. And
buying any piece of polo gear, that
logo, that style, immediately puts you
into a world could feel a bit like you
belong. Then he extended the brand as
well. This is even more relevant than
ever in the pop-up era where you can do
this and have it be ephemeral, have it
be 3 days. When we had talked about
blank in London, they had just run a
pop-up event, had a whole streak of
historical ones. And what I found
interesting, one of my favorite things
that Ralph did around these cafes that
they've launched, which became their
extension into the real world, is they
use that as the runway. This is a big
enough brand is still doing runway
shows. They opened these cafes in 2014.
2019 was the moment where like the
runway and the cafe as the runway really
took flight. You saw this whole world
come together. People wearing the
clothes to attend the physical location.
And this luxury co-ops food. It's
interesting to look at this as an
originator, right? This last summer, we
saw the Lacost cafe open up. We saw
Margella Tabby Cakes, Louis Vuitton
investing in more restaurants. Nothing
fits quite as well as the entire Ralph
experience. And much like we saw Kith
present itself as a new age alternative,
but positioned almost the opposite way,
you see ALD copying almost everything
Ralph has done down to the cafe itself
adjacent to its store and making that
such a significant part of what it does.
Doing collaborations. you could picture
Ralph doing being like we are a nimble,
younger, more relevant version of this
historic brand. In today's day and age,
you have to think, how can we represent
this world we're in? I love the Olympics
as just a cornerstone content piece cuz
they don't make money on that, right?
They probably pay money to do it. Ralph
is an ambassador of the USA, to the
world through the Olympics and a
reminder to the US of the brand that
represents them. And you have to ask
yourself as you put a brand together,
what culture do you represent? If you
make soccer jerseys or motocross culture
or represent a ethnic group or a place,
what are you doing to be able to put
that mascot front and forward? Maybe it
doesn't always make you money, but how
are you being known as that
representative is one of those core
anchor concepts to help a brand really
resonate over years and over time, but
for a new brand, you can't recreate
Ralph even in the aggregate, but you can
build on top of it what I'll call a
hybrid brand. I remember early on, for
those of you who you know Superline
Network and Eric and the guys over there
have seen their YouTube or their
Instagram. When they were first really
getting into media, they came to where I
worked. I worked at the surgeon at the
time and they'd asked about what people
can do to make their brand stand out. At
that time, I hadn't launched my like
merchandise line yet. I was still
working primarily on the women's wear
brand I work on, which is a western
theme brand. What's most interesting
about that brand is the founder, she's
Australian. I work on like the meta ads
and the email, etc. But you had her
Australian and fashion sensibilities.
She lived in Texas where we all had met
and where this brand came out of. and
she had a very New York fashion,
Australian fashion take on the western
world that she now lived in, which makes
that brand inherently interesting. And
when the Super Lion team asked, "How do
the brands stand out?" I said, "Hey, the
brands that stand out this next
generation aren't just going to be
redoing their new version of [ __ ] or
Supreme." They're going to be combining
things. They're could be combining Surf
and Metal, Southwest Colors, and New
England Money, whatever it ends up
being. It's taking things that are
actually part of your life and bringing
them together versus relying on an
existing aesthetic which now every
single one of has been done to death.
The contrast, the dissonance of those
topics together gets you to think. And
that's where I'm going to bridge this
video over into capital. What you can
learn from, in my mind, one of the most
impressive brands of this last
generation. So, as we get into that, I
want to take a second to go inside of
Particle, who have sponsored this video.
Particle is a platform for competitive
and market intelligence. Now, we're
going to look at Noah right here. We're
also going to take a brief look at
Ralph, but I want to show you if you
have a brand, how you actually look and
use things like this. So, no is a great
example of a brand that is that
combination, right? They took literally
the Ralph Lauren look and combined it
just enough with skate culture. A lot of
that's been kind of lost along the way
to now it really squarely lives in the
Ralph world, but at least at the
beginning, it was very much that
combination. But here, we can go through
and we can look at the last 90 days of
sales that they have. And the rough data
you can see there's like a range because
the numbers aren't the numbers aren't
exact. they're say within a 10 or 20%.
You can see what they actually sell. I
think this is really important for brand
people starting out beginning to look at
quantities. How do I determine how much
to buy? When your seller says, "We have
a 300 minimum or whatever." This is how
you push back. And this is how you
actually determine a real plan. You look
at this is one of the better, more known
consistent brands out there. They're not
as hype as they used to be, but they're
still excellent. I buy their stuff all
the time. These pants are Noah. But you
look at the volume of their expensive
stuff they have. They're selling 19 of
the $1,600 overcoat, right? Don't buy a
thousand. Don't buy a hundred units of
that, right? They're selling 200 of
their top SKs. Again, they have
storefronts and other ways to move this
brand, but online in e-commerce, 91 of a
zip. And again, this is over 90 days,
not even in a month. So, when you look
at investing in inventory, use services
like this to look at brands in your
niche. Look at people of comparative
size or one level up. Be like, what are
they buying? You can begin to forecast
what you think you can move and then
understand realistically what these
brands sell. And when manufacturers push
on you one way or the other, be like,
look, the biggest brands in the space
only sell a 100red belts online. How do
you expect me to get that many? You'll
begin to find people that will work with
you on that. And you'll notice that a
lot of these brands do purchase things
with minimums of 50 or 30, especially if
higher quality stuff. And again, you may
pay higher dollar for it. It's worth
thinking through as you begin to judge
your inventory. And some of you may find
sell way more than you expected. Same
thing. Look at what isn't selling. So,
for instance, going to this Ralph page
right here. You can see the most
discounted products like these rugs are
60% off, the mats, etc. Like the home
section of this is obviously a category
they're trying to liquidate right now.
So, begin to think through, okay, what's
on sale? What's moving? how much do they
do that? And you kind of come up with
your sales strategies as well. And you
can do all this while also seeing
insights into what emails they send in
their email marketing homepage changes
and what people will change on the
actual homepages of their website. And
being able to see trends of what people
are searching for and looking at over
time. I always like to look at this on a
2-year chart so you can see seasonality,
whether something spikes at Christmas
every year or not, which can kind of
give you a bit of a false positive
there. You can see how much the spikes
are. All this is tools you can use in
Particle to help you actually research
what you're going to launch or the next
campaign and what your competitors are
doing is an excellent part of the actual
strategy process. You can learn more in
the description and thanks to Particle
for sponsoring this video. What can you
learn from Capital? They're as much
fashion brand as they are physically
folklore. They feel mythical. They took
Americana, they took Levis's and Ralph
and then remixed it as like surreal
Japanese craftsman. They have some of
the strongest art direction in fashion
and the most unique design in fashion
while still being derivative, while
still being based on something. So much
so that the brand itself is a legend.
Three key things to talk about here.
Craft, iconography, and the references
of two worlds. So the capital universe
is Americana at its core combined with
Japan with a healthy dose of humor and
surrealism on top that's become
significantly more part of the brand as
time has gone on. So what do I mean by
craft? At the end of the day, this brand
is ultra focused on representing what
Japan does best when it comes to
production of fashion, which is
immaculate high quality garments. The
indigo dyes, the denim, the handstitched
sashiko surfaces, the patchwork jackets.
Obviously, heavily influenced by
Levis's, by Le by Wrangler, by Ralph.
They're using those core silhouettes
that you see, everything from denim to
fleece to jackets. They've gone and made
their own. and how they made it their
own was basically taking those and
applying immense craft to it, saying
we're going to do this in the most
intricate Japanese way possible. Also by
applying iconography to it. If you watch
all my videos, you hear me say this word
all the time, but it really matters for
a brand. These skeletal backgrounds of
jackets is perhaps one of Copy Doll's
best known items. Same thing with the
multi-eyed smiley. These are synonymous
with the brand, part of many pieces of
images that they have. and even their
style of illustration and the patches
and all these pieces that have become
really indicative and they're known for.
They apply to all these garments. They
take all these core silhouettes and add
their iconography on top of it in a very
over-the-top and obvious way. And that
combination of the core silhouette, the
craft of what they've done, the
iconography there makes it extremely
interesting. But then they add on top of
that the references of the two worlds
where you're just as likely to see a
cowboy or a racer, but it's positioned
in some incredibly Japanese world. Looks
like a still from a movie frame. The
garments are weathered. Everything has
this oddball spaghetti western feel to
it that seems like you're watching a
movie with which a story you've never
seen anything like before. And they've
done this in lookbook after lookbook
year over year. There's entire archive
of their lookbook on their sites is also
on internet archive or showing a bunch
of example pictures of these here. They
have so many campaigns that are so
amazing to look at that probably don't
pop into your Pinterest timeline or on
that curated Instagram feed that if you
want to dive into this world, this world
appeals to you. the cowboy land, the
Japanese craft world. They've done an
intricate way that has this combination
of western meets lone wolf and cub meets
all these different pieces where you can
kind of see the art direction happen.
That's really incredible. And you can
watch over time it get more symbolic and
surreal. It started off very literal,
very derivative of the initial things it
started with with its own twist. Then
they began to add these larger than life
motifs, these stranger and stranger
lookbooks. They found their groove over
time going farther and farther off the
beaten path. And so if you are looking
for your own brand, developing your own
aesthetic style, it's fine to start
somewhere that's been done before, but
really have to think about where you're
going. If you keep repeating that, are
you going to make something that stands
out? You look at the majority of these
popular brands here. Are they doing
anything new? But the ones that are
exciting continue to push that boundary.
How do you layer on top of that? And you
can take a surreal angle the way that
this does. You can take an angle
inspired by the culture that you're from
the way this does. Some combination of
both. You can make it even more literal.
find what that unique angle is. And
that's you need to think about what
that's the creative challenge that we
all face. And I don't want to act like I
am extremely deep in the lore here. But
from what I do understand, this came
together by people working together on
it by three family members. The founder
who knew denim manufacturing and was
inspired by vintage Americana, hero who
did the creative expansion, and the art
direction largely shaped by like a third
family member. That's interesting. I
think too when you have that combination
of things, often that comes from
collaborating with other people. We
always look at these brands as these
singular visions, right? that you
associate Ralph with Ralph, even if they
have a rotating cast of creative
directors. But Capital being really
formed by these three family members,
shows you how those styles can combine.
There's so much more to dive in there. I
encourage you to go into it yourself.
Dive into some of these cataloges, look
at that brand as inspiration, cuz I do
think that this in particular is the
blueprint for such a derivative age. So,
a few quick notes. I am going on tour
doing a whole bunch of events in
January. in Toronto, New York, believe
Miami. We are doing a bunch more after
that. So, we have the schedule down here
in the bio of stuff coming up. I'm
hosting a creative strategy webinar
diving into creative direction in 2026
that we are doing in early January. The
link to that will be down here as well
and doing a lot more to basically get
the community together online and in
person going in the new year. So, as
always, appreciate your support doing
that. Hope to see you either online, on
the webinar, in real life at one of the
events. If you want to see any other art
direction videos and topics, please let
me know. I appreciate y'all so much.
Thank you for watching.