what's good what's good y'all welcome
back you wanted more social media videos
here we are one of my personal focuses
on my profile since the start of this
year has been adding more carousels I've
making a point to do two plus a week and
I am working with brands on them
constantly as well and so in this video
I'm going to break down the carousel
Playbook both the types of carousels
that I do and what works and hasn't and
the types of carousels that Brands can
do because this is a super important
time if you are trying to grow on social
media or thinking about launching on
social media or have a brand to
understand multiple formats why is that
so first one thing I talk to Brands
about all the time is that if you have a
good idea or a good concept or a product
or a project you can usually dice it up
three ways I will use my own content as
an example so for instance this Stuy art
Direction video a lot of y'all would
have seen it it was a YouTube we used to
live in this world months and months ago
years now where everyone said oh you can
just chop a short from your YouTube
videos and turn that into 10 Tik toks
and turn that into blank BL blank and
you're going to blow up that's not how
this works anymore but what does work is
you take a good idea and you put it into
the formats that work so I had a Stuy
art Direction YouTube I took the four
top points of that I made it into a stui
art Direction short form video if you
want to learn more you go to the YouTube
I could take the 10 examples I use in
that YouTube I could probably make a
good Stuy art Direction Carousel and if
I want to break down a playbook in a
really short fashion I could turn it
into what's called a one shot which will
deserve its own video at one point but a
good example is this is a oneshot it's a
video mine there like 80 90,000 views
nothing crazy but all it is literally
breaking down a couple of strategies in
a single video shot and so that's what
we're going to dive into here today is
carousels are one of a format that
basically any good video idea you have
could be done in a carousel any product
you're launching anything happening as a
brand can be a carousel I'm going to
talk about different types of carousels
what makes carousels good and work on
social media show you tools I use to
make carousels how I actually do it
inside of Photoshop this tool visual
electric I use to generate images for
carousels get to the root of hooks and
calls to action so you have a Playbook
you can take to work on your brand or
your own personal brand for social media
without having to worry about video I'm
super excited for this one cuz as I
mentioned it has been a focus on my
personal social and I've built out a
pretty big playbook for this with the
brands I work with we're going to walk
through it all here today let's lock in
so first off why carousels why are we
talking about them so both Tik Tok and
Instagram wait carousels just as highly
if not sometimes more than they wait
videos their algorithms with some pretty
particular things around there this is
my explore page here you'll see there's
a mixture of reals and carousels I'm
pulling up literally a random one did
not have it selected before this video
and this is great cuz a lot of people
don't want to make video and they're
afraid of it to which I say especially
for creatives you should be making
carousels document the work you're doing
show the behind the scenes try out new
creative looks and feels curate things
you love and like share things you think
other people would enjoy and then if you
do make video and it's already in your
toolkit then you should basically do
what I'm doing as a personally as a
Creator and say hey I want to add
another thing because not everyone's
going to watch a minute or two minute
video of you talking or Vlogs but almost
everyone will scroll through carousels
when we talk about how they're using the
algorithm Tik Tok will share carousels
just like it shares Tik toks you're just
as likely to see them Instagram has
multiple placements so you get the
explore page like I just saw here you
get the actual feed and then you have
the reals feed this is important for a
note here is at Tik Tok you can have
carousels that are 9 by 16 they can be
other sizes and Instagram your Tik Tok
your Carousel should be 4x5 long ways
and if they are 4x5 with multiple images
and with music then they can also be
shown in the reals feed which means you
not only get the main feed you not only
get explore but you also get reals which
is a super helpful thing to think about
the potential reach of your Carousel now
while I encourage everyone to optimize
for the different social networks we'll
talk about that in this video if you do
make a 4x5 caros sare each you have the
most reach across both social networks
doing the least amount of changes to
your content well first we're going to
talk about the anatomy of a good
Carousel and I'm going to get into types
of them so what do I mean by Anatomy
let's click another completely random
Carousel this is the hook of your
Carousel you've heard about hooks for
videos the first couple seconds of your
video the combination of image text on
screen and what people hear those three
things together form the hook of a video
The Hook of a carousel is the same exact
principle slide one is 90% of the battle
if slide one stops people scrolling the
feet and then gets them to begin to
scroll sideways so they engage in it
you've already won your job is to get
get there once you get there optimizing
the rest is easy but you need to get
people into your content as a brand or
as a person and so this the hotter and
richer guide is a good example they are
calling out this is a playbook for which
you should get hotter and richer two
things that people want much like the
ultimate unfiltered guide to take social
media seriously another one a guide
everyone's algorithm is different but as
you can see a more meme focused one
manipulator starter pack getting ready
for a meme drop we'll do a meme video
later on idea Pokémon IS F favorite
Pokemon spons I'm in your job with the
hook is to get people into the actual
media the carousel then once they're
into it you want to keep people
scrolling so really easy format is if
you do something like this is you just
keep it going with more interesting
content or if you're telling a narrative
to leave a cliffhanger going on to the
next one but people once they've already
started scrolling if they like the
concept and it's good will keep
scrolling and you get to use both videos
and text to actually achieve your goals
with your carousels and Tik Tok it is
only text on Instagram you get video as
well same concept here gold say these
bends got it I'm in second slid of video
same format awesome sliding through I
get some still images doesn't have to do
that much right but we'll talk about
carousels that build value and don't
later but then one of the best benefits
of this is you get calls to action at
the end of your carousels what I mean by
that so this is my one of my marketing
cars I go to the end people Swip through
to the end I can ask them to do
something something that's a little bit
harder to do inside video obviously Etc
but you can get the general idea that
you can get them to go achieve a goal
and ask for something if they reach it
to the end as a a art in it itself those
are the three things to think about the
hook the core or the story of the
carousel the middle part and the CTA the
end 80% of the emphasis should be on
that intro on that first hook cuz if it
is not good it's not going to work and
this Carousel for instance of mine is I
don't like this hook personally doesn't
meet my standards of my Aesthetics isn't
what I want to be portraying myself but
it works it catches people it stops to
feed it has banging reach for me for a
carousel I'm a niche Creator right and I
am here at like 124,000 people reached a
ton of my existing followers you know
I'll take if I can get 78,000 people for
a carousel that I made in Adobe in 30
minutes with 1,00 saves I am winning but
the general idea is this pops out in the
feed it gets people interested enough
the best Marketing in history to see the
absolute bottle to see the dualingo owl
they're in that is a hook shot so this
leads us to the goal of a carousel
whether you are a brand or a person the
number one and two goals of your
Carousel are for people to share it and
save it we are not talking about likes
we're not talking about view time we're
not talking about comments saves and
shares just like video This is equally
as important if you don't want to get
lost in the numbers and virality game CU
those metrics show intention it shows
people taking an action or wanting to
save it for later to take an action on
your content but there are also big
signs to the algorithms and so you want
to design every piece of content if
you're a brand just saying here's our
new thing that's not savable and
sharable if it's here's how you style
our new thing to achieve X results that
is a more savable Carousel if you
present a scenario or a product in a
funny or more entertaining way then
maybe it might get shared but those are
the goals you're going to set out when
you go to make a carousel we're going to
walk through a ton of different ways to
achieve that here in a minute the first
is curations this is one of my most
popular carousels from last month
picture of me some books we are offb
brain rot instead consuming from The
Taste economy reading list so a curation
is literally you take a selection of
things that you like and love and put
them in one place for a niche so for
instance if I was just like marketing
book carousels probably wouldn't do as
good but having a hook like the taste
economy having it be something
interesting a little bit different a
little bit a different look and feel
there's not a lot like that that becomes
a little bit more applicable for people
so I am basically purely just putting in
a selection of the books that I like is
that simple I'm doing a curation the
second type of content a lot of the
examples I show when I just randomly
pull out my explor P is what we call a
Playbook how to do something my friend
Zach crushes it on these so he'll do how
to design a life you're obsessed with he
is giving you a Playbook these are all
pictures from his life he's saying
here's your steps toine your categories
for each category create an identity
here do this thing do this thing do this
thing a bunch of ideas where he's giving
so much value where it's like oh even if
you like one slide time block your day
you're going to save that because you're
be like I want to come back to this
later whenever I want to time block my
day whenever I want to go down and
actually do this you're giving you a
super savable Playbook and then the nice
part the sharable part about content
like this is if you're talking to
somebody else if you have your friend
group your group chat whatever it is and
you're into these kind of things you
will share this with other people be
like yo check this out we should do this
pop this with
Croy all right back to it and the next
type of Carousel is called a showcase a
good example from my boys's super line
something like this where it's like hey
here's this thing that happened here's a
bunch of examples of it you were just
taking an idea whether it's your product
or someone else's that Mercedes we saw
or saying it's a showcase hook title and
a bunch of examples of it that is a
showcase Carousel so we have curation we
have Playbook we have showcase and with
that framework I'm going to show a bunch
of different carousels of different
types that you should think about for
your brand but those are the three best
types I would focus on for almost all
content there's things like Photo dumps
and more lifestyle stuff if you want to
drive value for people focus on those
three get some examples for brand and
personal brand that kind of thing so
personal brand my boy alex this is a
great format where he is basically
saying here's a bunch of misconceived
Notions he's Crossing them out and
giving you a plan for how to replace
them so instead hey let's hire an intern
for social this needs to be a dedicated
team blah blah blah he is giving people
a set of resources and reasons but I
like this idea because it's more
inherently more interesting to cross
something out a misconception than say
something else versus just saying the
answer it's a more interesting format
this is another one from Grace Beverly
showing off her her podcast she's asking
experts about particular things and
she's giving a combination of the videos
from her podcast quotes things from
Twitter and pulling it together into one
Showcase of the various things that are
going on with her podcast around a
single idea and on the curation note
there's a lot of kind of marketing
accounts accounts in a niche this could
be car culture marketing women's fashion
Cosmetics Wellness whatever is are
people that just curate the news they're
saying here's are campaigns that
launched this week this is a useful
curation I always want to see the
campaigns that are happening this week
this is where I want to call out having
personality and not having personality
so this account you never see the person
that runs this just an account of these
curations which means that there just
isn't a bunch of affinity versus I want
to call out someone else who does this
uh Tatum who was in my my cut 30 program
she does this week in Fitness branding
and marketing very similar to the
campaigns that dropped this week done by
this other channel but the difference is
while you don't see her she besides her
her outro card here when you go to the
rest of her content she is talking in
all the content she's establishing a
personal brand and then using that
curation to add to the personal brand
for someone that never establishes
themselves there's just a lot less
resonance around that unless you just
have the utmost highest level of like
taste with which it doesn't matter if
you're shown or not like Outlander would
be a great example of that if you're not
familiar with Outlander where they are
establishing a brand by the power and
amazingness of their curation which I
will say for 99% of people who think
that they're that good you're not
there's an enigma to get to the level
that that he is at but you do that not
just by curating but by having a
perspective in how you curate and that's
a separate video in itself one of my
favorite examples for Brands brands are
always like how do we participating
carousels what do we do how do we tell a
story because all good content carousels
are the same as videos if you watch any
of my YouTubes about making good video
content you either make value content or
entertainment content or you fail those
are your two types of content value
content is something someone will save
or want to actually learn something from
entertainment content is something that
is competing with TV it is funny it is
super interesting to watch if you are
not creating either of those two then
your content is probably flopping but
for a brand like and they're saying hey
well we're doing stuff how do we show
that off this Carousel from juice tin I
think is a great example so so they are
basically going through their latest
photo shoot behind the scenes look at
the juice tint photo shoot again not the
most engaged biggest Carousel ever but a
good storytale here's the product that
we're shooting the photo on with with
some notes here's the Muse for the photo
shoot here's the outfits we used in the
photo shoot here's the looks they're
answering a bunch of questions the props
and showing people the world that they
are building and this is a good example
of a more middle bottom funnel Carousel
that's really educating their customer
base answering their questions getting
them more Affinity versus being designed
to go wide but an amazing format I'm
trying something like this out for my
brand minute another example from the
same brand where they're hosting an
event and they basically have a slide
for the space a slide for the guests
that they invited a slide for the spread
they are again they're showcasing the
things that they're doing and making it
a visual more entertaining way to to
show it and then using the caress format
to show a bunch of video clips versus
just making a standard video but a great
example for a brand is just actual
storytelling in the text format this is
a good one where we took our getting
robbed to New York Fashion Week and
they're literally telling a story in one
line with a photo or a video of exactly
what's happening for their brand now
this is a cool story it's all engaged
but there's a hundred stories like that
the story of why you started your brand
the story of the biggest challenge that
you fa as a brand the story of why you
picked your color story for this season
or how you know what went terribly wrong
in your photo shoot that cost you
$111,000 or the inspiration that you
spent 41 hours for when you determined
how you're going to approach your logo
those are all stories for a Carousel and
doesn't have to be crazy complicated
look at this this is literally there's
like 10 words maybe on each of these
slids same thing with a product showcase
just like you debut your product in a
video you could also debut in a Carousel
and I usually recomend for Brands to
consider doing both inside their
campaigns I'll do a whole campaign
strategy YouTube it's at some point this
is just a good example of if you're
going to debut a product this Carousel
format gives you a lot of stuff but
things you already have you already
built all this out for your product
detail page put it in a carousel run it
organic and test it as an ad product
combos is another one it's just an
aesthetic fun thing that people will
scroll through basically for
entertainment to see combinations of
products things people like various
displays there's something to visual
Beauty and aesthetic curation that is
entertainment in its own right and this
is one you can do with stuff you're
being packed in luggage or like looks or
things coming out of a purse beverages
in your fridge whatever there's a lot of
ways to approach a curation like that
sharing your reviews this is another
cool one I thought where they basically
combining a cool photo with the reviews
of the product and then there's
storytelling of things that happened
like this let's go on a trip Carousel
where obviously she's in the private jet
was a bit of Leverage but I love this
format in general I'm going to South by
Southwest here tomorrow recording this
video won't come out for a week or two
but that's where I'm headed if I was
like hey let's go South by Southwest I
maybe I don't have the PJ shot but I
need to find that Red Hook shot but I
can do the same thing what's in my bag
I'm bringing my osmo I'm bringing this
and that I pack these new shoes I got
here's where we're staying I'm staying
at a cool hotel here's some of the
people I met here's the events we go to
again I won't probably get the likes
that she has because this is a banging
Carousel with really cool stuff but I
will certainly get solid engagement for
what I do and that's what I'll be
thinking about for you as well same
thing with the brand hey we're going to
this Expo hey we're launching our first
retailer hey the team went to blank and
blank like just look at that
storytelling and say what do we need to
make that work we need a hook shot and
we need enough narrative and enough idea
to keep people scrolling through it then
we have these edits I look at this as
entertainment content too aesthetic
content cont is entertainment content
but people love aesthetic content so
this guy got popping off of doing these
edits that combined his hands and his
feet and his fits you as a creative if
you are a designer videographer whoever
it is should find an interesting format
for you that you can experiment with
another version this is like a design
guide how to be alone where she's
literally just providing some advice
like a value driven content in her own
kind of creative way same thing this is
more like a creative Carousel become
that girl in 14 days she giving you a
Playbook very much similar to what Zach
was doing about but in her own creative
style and I shared this to show you
there can be any kind of visuals for
this there's a wide range of that
another type of value Carousel is a
transformation Carousel these are short
carousels this is my boy JT's showing
off his 12 types of income and he's
breaking them down in this extended
thing and this is designed to be savable
people would be like I want to make 12
streams of income hell I want to make
three streams let me save this to think
about all the streams I could have as a
Creator another transformation one on
Tik Tok say this guy he was in Cut 30
this is a transformation where he's
basically describing a state he was in
at one point and then how much better it
got in like six years with this brand
and he has social proof it's a three
slide Carousel I love these two or three
slide form Maggie here has another one
everything you do on a long flight to
get your life together hook shot great
shot of her dressed up with like the
luggage great example something like a
lot of people could do right not in
front of a private jet but she picked a
good outfit it works and she's literally
just giving a plan if you have no Wi-fi
here's what to do if you have Wi-Fi
here's what to do it's super savable
Carousel but that's the toolkit you
curate you make a Playbook you showcase
or you entertain you can do it in a
couple slides and show a transformation
or a quick guide you can do an extended
narrative or an extended curation and
you focus on your hook I want take a
quick interlude and talk about visual
electric I use visual electric to
generate graphics for carousels and for
mockups all the time I want to show it
as a tool in this I'll talk about how I
use Photoshop later to make some of my
carousels visual electric is a tool very
similar to like a mid Journey but it is
made for designers look at this
interface we have here I have sketch
tools I have hand tools I have text and
I have imagery but most importantly I
have real workflow so for instance these
images are all variants of each other I
took this image I told it to change the
color of the packaging and change it to
White that's something that's capable of
doing here if I want so basically see
this art director function inside visual
electric any image I take into a board I
can use this edit function and I can go
change the color of the packaging to
Black lo and behold I have some dark
versions of this I can go select it and
say hey I'm going to remove the
background boom now I have the PNG
version of this I can go pull up retouch
say hey I don't like this Edge I can
apply retouch to it I basically get full
workflow similar to how you actually
design inside of a generative tool for
another example what I able to do there
I took this image I put them in a
concrete Studio environment I said that
head now I want it in an art studio you
begin to understand the power of
something like this you can go cool I
can move images through environments and
so again if I want to do the background
of a carousel or generate something I
can begin to get good interesting stuff
that fits in that it looks realistic in
this tool actually get it to where I
want it to go so I love I will roll
through they have this inspo section
here inside you can go bring stuff I can
go take this into my canvas I can say
grib and go edit make the bag longer go
make the bag taller and make it white
there there we go you will see I have a
slightly taller bag than is white I can
go in here and I can clean this up so
now is slightly less wrinkly but now you
never need to have a mockup that's the
same as everyone else's mockup ever
again and you can kind of change and
work around images in a pretty
straightforward workflow and even do
things like on this uh I I change this
billboard image from day to night right
want to tweak something for a campaign
mockup shift a nail color or an image
you can do all this in an interface you
can do it as a group with artboards and
collaborate on it you can resize and
make variations this is the kind of tool
that actually works how designers work
and again if you are looking to say hey
I need to fill in a bunch of images for
carousels and I want to be able to kind
of edit them and have a design eye on
them this is the ideal software that is
set up for it you can find out more
about them in the link below visual
electric I want to give them a big thank
you for sponsoring this video let's get
back to it so tactically it's break in a
little bit of this how do we actually do
it so I'm going to pull open my
Photoshop and you will see in Photoshop
this is an artboard Photoshop you can do
this in stobe Express as well most
design software literally you'll see I
have an artboard and all I am doing on
these is I made multiple carousels in
this artboard I am dropping a new photo
in behind it or a new image and I'm
adjusting the text and I have a very I
use the same fonts each time it's
usually helvetic a new M salt or caslon
or one of these options for a sand serif
and it's not even the most glamorous
thing it's a template I'm comfortable
enough with I have the images blurred
out and I make decent carousels not the
most amazing ones in the world but I
have a fan base that likes them but
literally is just an artboard is the
same layout on each of these I'm just
duplicating it and the only core
difference is the call to action one has
like a logo or I'll have a YouTube up
there and the front slide has more
design I hit this with a remove
background you can just go into select
subject and then you'll be able to
select inverse and it'll select anything
that's not to you and easily cut it out
and I put layers behind me CU that
effect that you've seen a lot of people
do where something is slightly behind
but still readable is an effect that
gets people to stop and scroll for
whatever reason you do not have to
overthink it begin to get a format and
some fonts for your hook slides get a
format for what you want to do for the
rest of this it does not even have to be
this complicated once you have a
template I have like two or three
variants of this and I use it for all
carousels and then all the brand stuff
that I have is just variants of that and
doing it on Express on your phone allows
you to like not make it hard for
yourself but this is your homework from
watching this video I want you to go
curate something make a hook of
something you think is worth sharing
books styling advice recipes places to
go in the area you live five best coffee
shops in rural Arkansas or South Africa
wherever ever you are things you need to
do when you visit whatever it is get a
hook image that catches do what I just
did get a picture of yourself cut
yourself out some text have a little bit
behind you nice big and bold big title
that gets people a little catchy get a
little edgy if you can the most hated
places on the west side of Austin you
know like have fun with it put images
together in that size and post do a
curation do a story whatever it is my
only other Pro tip that I will give you
is that if you I don't post those
carousels on Tik Tok if I was to do Tik
Tok I don't take the time to do I have a
little bit of a different Tik Tok
strategy but I would be using Tik tok's
default captions I would literally
export my images and stuff here and I
would go into Tik Tok and I would be
using this style white text black
outline and running the same text and
titles and all that using that style
without any of the fancy design you can
use the same images and everything but
literally be doing it in the default Tik
Tok style and Instagram using the more
designed ones or just use just copy
these text formats so everyone uses the
same stuff i' be using that instead of
doing a fancy design thing I've just
found they don't work as hard on on Tik
Tok and everyone goes aw another thing I
do is not that hard it'll take you like
10 15 minutes just stop scrolling and do
the work as your homework is to make and
release one of these carousels trust me
you can do it if you're like oh I want
to make videos okay fine you should
probably still make videos you can
definitely make carousels you can grow
your entire business your personal brand
Etc off carousels just as well I will
put the examples of these in my hyper
newsletter next week I'll put a bunch of
carousels linked all in there the link
to that is hyper studios. us and this
below if you want to sign up and I'll
make sure you can send out all these
links so you can get them easily that is
is it no excuses let's make some
carousels you or your Brands I
appreciate youall watching
[Music]