In this video, I'm going to talk about
the best marketing of 2025 so far, along
with a few campaigns that don't hit so
well. We're going to rank everything on
my arbitrary system of 1 to 10 based
entirely on my criteria and what I like
because it is my video. We're going to
cover everything from event activations
to actual ad campaigns to social media
content. Just highlight a bunch of
standout things in all kinds of
industries. Who am I to be able to talk
to you about this? I am a former CMO and
marketing leader across consumer
electronics and consumer package goods
companies. And now I make content on the
internet and help brands at the largest
level navigate how to do great on social
and make campaigns that culturally
resonate. This will be a fun one cuz
there's all kinds of interesting visuals
and exciting campaigns happening for
better or for worse. So let's lock in.
So, I'm going to start off with one of
the most interesting and culturally
relevant yet also particularly
controversial campaigns, and that is The
Ordinary releasing cheap eggs in New
York City at 337. So, if you aren't
familiar with The Ordinary, you're
probably not alone. They are a clinical
skincare company noted for their kind of
nononsense approach and branding and
being very focused on the science behind
their products. And they've grown to
quite an impressive size with that. But
what they've never had is anything
that's kind of gotten them outside of
the box or showed any really element of
personality for the brand. They've been
dead focused on the product, which makes
complete sense. You can scale to a
certain level as a brand with only
focusing on that. But they decided at
some point that we need to go bigger. We
need to be doing things that are more
interesting. And so they collaborated
with Mischief. Yes, the mischief of Big
Red Boots fame amongst others as a
beauty brand providing cheap groceries
when everyone is talking about the price
of eggs. So the conversation is what
does this actually do for them? So first
it enters them into a much bigger
conversation. This became a cultural
moment talked about from everything from
news media to social media influencers
where people could actually go and
capture it. They did it in New York
which is the epicenter of being able to
launch things like this. But they also
caught plenty of controversy as a
company that is notoriously vegan.
Offering eggs is something particularly
unvegan. and thus the comments on their
posts, as you can see here when you
scroll, absolutely went off with these
really complicated conversations around
aren't you cruelty-free and yet you're
selling eggs. I'm not going to dive into
the depths of people that care about
that kind of stuff on the internet. But
you will note that that controversy is
part of what propelled this to its
114,000 likes. And I do think for a
brand that is getting very little
attention inside the zeitgeist, inside
content, doing something like this is a
interesting way to spearhead becoming a
more interesting brand. And on that
note, I'm going to touch on the next
campaign which is by a brand with a
similar strategy who has done this at at
the highest level now for years and that
is Sarah V. So most people know from
Sarah Vee or became a household name
with their Michael Sarah campaign where
there's all the speculation around
whether it was his brand and it was a
celebrity endorsement. But they also
this year announced their heads of
Caravee with a couple famous and
prolific athletes. One of whom being
Anthony Davis who was in this paparazzi
moment carrying around massive tubs of
Caravee anti-dandruff shampoo. Now why
is this relevant to the ordinary? Cuz
Carave is another company clinically
focused scientific products or basically
advertising on basketball sites to debut
this. They actually got WO to debut the
news of Anthony Davis scientist Sarah
Vee like it was a trade and brought him
out of retirement. But they as a company
have leaned into this over-the-top
performative marketing inside these
niches at culturally relevant moments to
help give them an identity beyond just
being like a clinical brand while their
actual branding stays completely true to
what you'd expect from like a
traditional shampoo. And this is the
route that something like the ordinary
goes on. By doing this egg program opens
the doors for them to be a more
interesting, talked about brand with
whatever they do next. They enter into a
category where they become a little more
cultural versus purely just a product
choice. Now, I always find these arcs
fascinating. So, next up, this is
Anthony Davis and his sneakers with
Adidas. So, right after Anthony Davis
threw down a poster dunk, those you not
familiar with basketball is when someone
gets humiliated on the dunk so much that
you'd want to have the dunk on a poster
and the pierce would be like cowering
blow and got hit. Adidas releases this
commercial basically right away, like
right after this in-game dunk where
they're replicating with iced tea your
Law and Order style recap of a crime
scene of how bad this dude got dunked
on. In the signature Anthony Davis
style, if you haven't seen his other
ads, you will see the same background
with the orange, etc. is within all of
these. and then they find the actual
shoes like evidence. Uh, and you see
Anthony Davis pop up here at the end.
So, this is a great example of kind of
this cultural relevance idea that we
started with the ordinary saying, "Hey,
eggs is a topic of conversation. Let's
give people cheap eggs. Let's enter the
conversation that way." Or Sarah Vee
being like, "Hey, we're announcing
Anthony Davis. He just got traded. we're
going to leverage all that conversation
around him to actually have basketball
outlets debut the marketing campaign for
us versus just putting it on television
to something like this where they have
made this ad. They probably have a
multiple ads in this campaign sitting in
their queue and have said, "Hey, when he
does something impressive, we're going
to drop another one." And they're using
cultural figures that people recognize
and scenarios they recognize to cut
these ads with a branded kind of
dramatic background. And once we see ad
15 like this, you're going to
automatically associate with Anthony
Davis campaigns. So giving some rankings
on these and what do they mean? Actually
scoring some of them. So that ordinary
campaign I'm going to give like a seven.
And I give it a seven because I think
for for them and for the impact it has
on getting their brand into the
conversation, it is extremely high. But
to the point of like, hey, there
actually are like a vegan cruelty-free
brand. Their audience seemed to be a
little bit dissuaded by it. I will knock
it down a few pegs. it didn't make sense
in the greater context what the brand's
trying to do. Whereas that Sarah Vee
Anthony Davis campaign where they
announce the heads of Sarah Vee, they do
it on social media. They bring in all
these orgs and things you wouldn't
expect like it's being debuted through
basketball media. It's part of a
multi-step campaign where they're
announcing these heads. Community gets
involved. You can kind of see the full
span of a way to a group that really
understands marketing. I would give that
a 10. And then this Anthony Davis style
on this, I would also be giving what
they are doing, putting out his shoes
and the marketing around it. I would
give that a 10 as well. All right. I'm
going to teach you about a piece of
software you can add to your marketing
toolkit that is super useful if you are
trying to stay relevant with everything
that's going on right now. So, this is
Particle, who is the sponsor of this
video. But why they're really
interesting for marketers is you can go
into any brand that's on the platform,
which is the majority of the brands that
are on Shopify. And you can actually see
the data like I look at here, which will
show you things like rate sold and
average discount and see what people are
doing for sales. They also have this
events tab in here where they basically
summarize changes that get made from the
brand. So, for instance, Glossier
launches this new merch item on April
11th. It tells you the revenue. They saw
sales revenue of $3.1,000. That merch
item generated 6.7K in sales and 5.8 the
following day. It notes when they put
launches on their homepage. You can go
back and get historicals about where
brands did what. And right over here, I
can click into assets and I can see
things like meta ads and emails that
they're running and the styles that
they're using. For instance, now I can
go through I'm on the Playplace site. I
can go look at all the emails that
they've sent and when. Show you more
emails from the company. I can scroll
through a whole bunch below if you're
trying to basically competitively audit
what's going on with companies. You can
see the direct sales numbers of what
they're doing per product. You can see
the average discounts on those products
in case you were curious about that. But
really, this event summary is actually
one of the most useful ones because you
really want to understand what has a
company been doing, how frequently do
they make changes. This here where you
can look at basically every new product
arrival, their this launch, and then how
well the launch actually did. And having
that all in a summary that you can have
is a really great way to just keep up
with everything happening in your brand
and landscape. If you want to learn more
about Particle, which is a tool I use
constantly for everything from
researching niches to launch products in
to just diving into competitive data, it
is the link that is in the description
of this and I've also pinned it as a
comment. So, next up comes this IKEA you
up campaign where IKEA slid into
Canadian DMs and I believe text messages
by asking them if you are up. Anyone who
responded, I don't know how they chose
them between 10:00 p.m. and 5:00 a.m.
was rewarded with a free mattress. And
this is one of those where it's like
that fine line between like ad agency
[ __ ] and stuff that might actually
resonate, right? Where so any brand that
has SMS knows that like SMS is a really
rough channel. Even DMs is a rough
channel. No one wants to receive a bunch
of extra stuff from a brand. I feel bad
enough sending stuff into my broadcast
channel on Instagram. Nonetheless,
sending text messages to people's phones
to buy your [ __ ] And someone like IKEA,
same thing. What are they really going
to announce? Someone's going to go, I
really have to open this IKEA text
message. developing a sense of humor and
a personality with that I think is a
really really interesting concept and
then doing it like in a way that again
is is sort of culturally relevant and
like the you up after the club way and
then actually giving someone a reward if
they respond within time frame utilizing
this time component of marketing I think
is a really interesting idea. Now this
wasn't a campaign that I feel like
really grabbed the zeitgeist or tons of
people talked about it definitely has
that like hey the ad agency that put it
out if you like you search for it it's
like they're all talking about it but
not a lot of actual people are. So, I
will give this a seven. I do think is a
strong concept. And I think what we're
going to see in the SMS channel is that
how do you get like nuanced and
interesting and get cool enough that
people are actually going to open your
text messages, which as a brand is a
pretty hard proposition. Moving down the
list into event marketing. This
Pinterest campaign was an interesting
one. To kick off Coachella, they invited
Chappelle Ron's creative director to
create an installation where people
could collage together. You could remix
yourself at Coachella. Now, I do love
this idea. They're connecting to the
brand and they're giving people
something they can leave the event with.
And I'm a massive fan of this for
events. Events where you actually get to
create something where you get to leave
with a thing that you are proud of from
a creative standpoint where people get
to participate in something maybe learn
skills beyond them. I absolutely love.
Uh I spent some time working with a
group called the shoe surgeon. We used
to do these workshops. We had like the
NFL would come to a workshop or a brand
would come to a workshop. They'd
customize sneakers at the actual spot.
You could see anything from like the NFL
events were with like disenfranchised
kids or whatever it is. and they would
leave so stoked and happy that they got
to go create this thing. But also, even
when you did a corporate workshop,
people would like put a lot of care and
intense like making something
interesting for them and be like, "Wow,
I'm capable more than I expected." So, I
love that for brands. Was an amazing way
to have it resonate. Arcterics did
something like this back in the day too
where they partnered with artists. You
could bring your Arcterics and they
would like screen print it or do
customization. Love that. And this is a
fun idea too for Pinterest at Coachella.
I am curious to see what the social
element of this is. Are they going to be
able to get a bunch of people here? Are
people going to be posting these really
sick collages? Can they get them sent to
their house? Whatever it looks like. But
it was a creative and interesting
campaign to do for a festival activation
more so than just having a house that
people can hang out at. So, I'm going to
go ahead and give Pinterest an eight
here. We'll follow up once the actual
campaign is finished. So, speaking of
campaigns that have interest or
attention, I think that's like half the
battle, right? You can come up with
these interesting campaign ideas. IKEA
can do this UP campaign, but the only
people that talk about it are other
advertising people, advertising
executives. Does it actually matter?
It's like a tree falls in the woods, but
only ad executives are talking about it.
Yeah. All right. Anyway, metaphor
doesn't quite work, but you understand
the point. This is another example of
that. So, Frazzia, I believe that's how
you pronounce it, have a really popular
bag at the moment, this butter bag, and
they were gifting it to influencers in
Los Angeles on a platter with engraved
butter, which I actually thought was a
really interesting concept. It looks
really cool. It's naturally viral. I had
actually seen some of the debut images
of this bag. They had the person holding
it like with baguettes as they like
entered an apartment. They were kind of
bringing this butter theme into it,
which I love from an art direction
perspective. I did a food and art
direction video a while back if you want
to dive deeper on that. But something
like this is I only know about this
because it's on an aggregator Instagram.
I've never seen this. You actually go
search for it. I looked up a bunch more
stuff about this. I was like, "Hey, it's
actually a cool idea. I wonder if that's
popular. Is it going viral anywhere?
It's on the brand's page. It's nowhere
to be found." And so I will say that
this is a really cool concept. They
should be making content about it on
their feed that hits. It should be
easier to find the influencer content
about it. And because it is good, like
do a bunch of it. Like get it out there.
So this is one where a good concept I
feel like is poor execution. I had to
give that a four. And speaking of
interesting concept poor execution,
California Pizza Kitchen, CPK, they
launched a fake rebrand. They basically
did a Malibu's Most Wanted style CPK
rebrand where they put out this really,
you know, like corny, unexpected lights,
etc. type content, but then kind of
saying, hey, it's sort of all of a funny
like in the PR review, it's like one
might have assumed these were new liquid
death or mischief launch. Like no, no
one was assuming that. And here's what I
want to talk about something with this
false flag. This is one of those things
that happened like when the Jaguar
campaign came out and everyone was
talking about it be like wow they're
getting a lot of attention for how bad
this is immediately a bunch of like
agencies and marketers like we're going
to do that we're going to take advantage
of that same thing but the hard part is
like if it's not actually bad enough
that people really get into talking
about it you're not going to get that
same value like this isn't just like
it's like some stuff if you're going to
do something really bad needs to be like
really bad and like attention getting
and you need to stick with it and like
run with the game. This is too much of a
like here's this campaign, haha, it's a
joke. No one quite understands what's
happening and it's not interesting
enough to be relevant enough to get that
huge level of attention. And so if they
had dialed this campaign up
significantly and then run with the joke
for a longer piece of time or like
debuted one of the stores being like
completely redone or like really just
leaned into the side of this, you may
have gotten people talking about like
what is going on with CPK? But it never
got to the point to have that moment. I
think that's kind of too bad. CPK is a
brand that I love and have a long
history with and I don't think they
managed to pull this one off. And nor do
I think anyone is using this to then
contemplate eating more CPK pizza. We're
going to go with the two. Speaking of
relatively out of touch campaigns, Kors
with this misspelling campaign. I talked
a bit about this and uh on the
grandfather's podcast, but they launched
all these ads at Mountain Cold
refreshment. So refreshment people
correcting them. They all these big
billboards and out of home and then they
basically said, "Oh, uh this is a case
of the Mondays." It's like a case of the
Mondays campaign and LinkedIn and all
this other stuff they're doing. This is
like classic ad agency slop. This is the
stuff that you just cannot be doing in
this day and age. Like this is not
inherently viral. No one cares if
something is spelled wrong. It's not
encouraging people to get more corsite.
No one understands the this through line
into a case of the Mondays into this
other campaign. We are doing too much
here. This is why you can't have these
old school ad agencies trying to do
stuff that resonates for your brands.
You need to get younger, more
interesting creatives and smaller firms
giving you ideas that might actually
work. We go with the one for young
corors light. You're not tapping the
Rockies. Speaking of unique ideas, I'm
going to pull this one from Reformation.
So, Reformation did a collab post with
Letterboxed where they're actually
showing off all the wedding dress, like
dress related content from brides on
like certain letter boxed movies as part
of a promotion for Reformation Bridal
Dresses. And I thought this was really
fun. It ties in a culturally relevant
fandom and people that really like
letter boxed. It attaches to those
movies. It gives them the ability to
access some of these moments. It fits
Restoration's kind of fun voice. Lets
them tap into culture in a different way
without merely just like posting those
pictures and having a connection to it.
I think they had a little more in-depth
stuff that was happening on the in
actual letter box itself. I like it's a
fun and interesting different way to do
it a content collab. Fun way to leverage
a fandom on social media. I'll go ahead
and give that an over in the world of
celebrity. Javiana's is trying to bring
flip flops back. I think we are actually
in the natural order of things in the
hey trends come back every 9 years or 13
years. Whoever the cycle is, we are at
the time where flip flops may just come
back this summer. If it's not this
summer, it's probably next summer. I say
this for better or for worse. But
Javianas has a vested interest in
wanting to make that as aggressive a
campaign as possible that we are going
to bring back Javiana's. So look this
summer Javianas eyeshadow god knows what
we're going to have come hit but like
this is what's happening and they said
Gigi Hadid is the person we're
announced this over the limit and she's
an ad campaigns. She's saying talking
about her love for Javiana's and how
this is coming back. It's a good-looking
campaign. But my biggest question
something like this is like she had the
influence level to push Javiana's over
the edge into being something everyone
wears or would they have been better off
just sending like 5,000 pairs of
Javianos to every conceivable influencer
and then sponsoring several Tik Tockers
for the same rate that comes up to it
and probably gotten a bigger and better
cultural response. Someone I've seen do
some stuff like that really well as
coach. I definitely think so. And if you
are going to do all this work to have GG
and just having like a photo shoot
without having some like more clever
instances of content or a full campaign,
which maybe we'll see later, I think
they are not doing enough with what they
are given. Go ahead and give that a
four. Speaking of relevant celebrity, we
have Patrick Schwarzenegger from White
Lotus and his wife or fiance, I forget
which for Skiims, which they debuted
right after one of his popular White
Lotus episodes where his character is
quite the talking point. Every time I
talk about Skiims on short form, I'll
lose like a thousand followers. People
just hate hearing about their
Kardashians in any way, but The Skiims
just executes at a absolutely legendary
speed of which they do releases, how
they do campaigns, the quality of their
art direction. Can't speak for the
quality of the product, but they do an
excellent job with marketing. And this
is one of those examples where they're
like, "Hey, who are we going to have to
debut our collection? We're going to get
someone relevant." He's not huge. He's
having a moment right now as part of
this thing that's happening. We're
putting him with his significant other
in a very Skiims way with little pieces
of Skims iconography kind of spread
throughout to promote Skiim's bridal
exactly the right cultural time. Touche.
I'm going to give them an 8 and a half
nine here. They probably could have done
a little bit more with this campaign,
but uh it doesn't matter cuz they
crushed it. But they were not the only
brand leveraging the White Lotus. Also,
the Gap with Parker Posie, another kind
of of the many viral characters
happening from there. And this is a Gap,
like a classic Gap dance campaign. So
Gap is always known for these kind of
big dance routines. She is a very viral
person, very relevant to the older Gap
demographic. I feel like Gap is trying
to split how they're doing their sales,
half towards like, can we get the Tyler
crowd, half towards, hey, can we just
maintain these like millennial Gap
people who have some Gen X who have some
favorable thoughts on our brand and they
are definitely going for the higher end
of that here uh in a kind of fun way.
You'll notice they try to circumvent it
while having some youthful people around
her, but they're staying true to the
brand. They're using a culturally
relevant person in a culturally relevant
moment who might actually wear their
clothes. And for Gap, this is an
excellent job. I will give it a nine. I
did ask my wife if this would be
convincing her to buy some khakis. The
answer was no. Over to the wide world of
events. Hero Cosmetics uh was doing a
human claw inside their actual event. To
that note of getting people to leave
with something from event activation
like we talked about with Pinterest. Uh
this is another fun idea. I think we're
only going to see brands doing more and
more at these events to make it work. I
thought this was a fun application. But
perhaps one of my favorite event
campaigns is this from Merit, another
cosmetics company. So, at Paris Fashion
Week, they had these Merit branded
Vespas, and they were driving them
around, giving deliveries to editors of
these different cosmetics packs. This is
the Merit Merit has a their own kind of
branded bag as part of their marketing
and their giveaways. They would actually
be delivering and giving these Vespa uh
deliveries to all the editors around
Fashion Week with this fun branded Vesa.
And this is why when I talk about, hey,
how do you do something also as a
content resonance? Like, they're making
these fun little videos with this cute
little object. It didn't cost them that
much to wrap. They're just doing seating
with this. This isn't like some huge
expensive campaign, but it's extremely
fun. It's very social friendly. It's
clever, and it's something they'll
probably do anyway, trying to go ahead
and get these kits in the hands of
editors and celebrities at one of these
shows. Why not do it with a little bit
of style style and perhaps some
virality? And the last campaign that I
want to talk about was this one. It was
April Fools related. I typically am not
an April Fool's fan, you may have
gathered, but I did enjoy this from my
friends at Ladder who had uh talking
about basically gym bodyguards or ladder
guards available through the app for
people that are tired of getting looked
at in the gym. I like this because it's
so social friendly because it's such a
funny skit. Now, I don't know if you all
had seen there was that video of like
there's these girls traveling somewhere
and they were having their bodyguards
like bring them matcha, which I imagine
was part of the inspiration for this,
but that whole concept of like
bodyguards doing something for somebody
is like always, I think, a fun social
vehicle. and the fact that they were
able to kind of do this. They put out
kind of two videos around it, but it
works so well for like funny social
stuff and they're able to throw the
ladder branding and show the app in
there in a way that doesn't hurt their
virality with the concept whatsoever.
Uh, and I think that is a a great note
as well. So, I want to shout out to them
for like a native first, making one
piece of content to get their entire
piece. I guess there's two videos, one
concept to get this like quick campaign
out there. I think they did an excellent
job with this um good software marketing
for social media. But that is all my
favorite and some less favorite
campaigns that have happened so far this
year in marketing. Ones that you've seen
that you've liked that I haven't talked
about or didn't cover in my Super Bowl
video. Please feel free to drop them
below. I'm going to do another kind of
like end of year recap. I'm sure if some
increasingly poor things come out, I
will definitely hop in and talk a bit
about the moment. But I always find it
interesting to actually break down a bit
like why I feel something is resonant,
how you see it works, how brands can do
different things, and what the budgets
are. I hope you enjoy it. you're trying
to learn about marketing for the first
time and dive into deeper how these
things happen. I do have this video
about all the different types of
marketing explained. It is a like
amazing deep dive video that is so much
knowledge I wish I'd have when I was
like 21. And you can watch and I will
link here. Thank you all so much for
watching.
[Music]