Today we are going to talk about the
downfall of luxury brands and what you
should be buying instead, plus the
tactics that these new age brands are
using to stand out. I'm dropping this on
Black Friday weekend as it is a great
time to support some of the independent
brands that I'm going to be highlighting
while saving a few dollars. But really,
this is a guide for how to think about
how you consume and for premium brands
trying to decide how to position in the
future. And this isn't just fashion. We
are going to break down bags, towels,
sheets, fragrance, candles, rugs, and
homegoods. and have a blast doing it. I
absolutely love this conversation. As
many of you know the brands I work in
like Morphe or cosmetics and if you're
in the lore, you've seen all the other
brands that I've supported. I love the
mastige price point. So below that
luxury, above mass market is I feel the
real sweet spot for brand opportunity.
Right now we're going to break down
production and supply chain,
positioning, story, form factor and
design, and art direction and creative
direction through a wide swath. Let's
lock in. And so, first off, this is my
first video since we hit 100K. My play
button comes Saturday. So, I want to
thank everyone who's watched this
channel. I appreciate y'all tapping in.
And I do have a new set that we're going
to be rolling in starting next week. So,
something to look forward to there as
well. We're going to do some exciting
things with the channel and only happen
with y'all support watching. But first,
we are going to talk about production. I
have been around the world. You've
watched this channel. You've seen me in
China. You've seen me in Italy. You've
seen me and all of these far-reaching
places actually produce garments,
electronics, etc. My background is wells
marketing was in supply chain and
product design. And what's interesting
about this is this is now more available
than ever. When I did these big videos
walking through the fabric halls of
Zonga or going to the luxury shows in
Milan and showing people this is where
you get your materials, this is how you
get your fabrics. This is how you find a
provider who can make you electronics or
rugs or whatever it is. That is part of
a greater trend of ungatekeeping access
to the providers that make things all
around the world. And at the same time,
postcoid and with the Instagram era, we
saw stunting go up, right? Where
everyone wanted to show off their
luxury. You had to have the Goyard
wallet on the Hermes tray inside the
photo dump. And that led to the
prevalence of dupes, right? Cuz a lot of
people can't actually afford it. They
are buying it. They're doing it with
trust fund wealth or they're doing it
with CLA. And plenty of people are just
buying what looks the same but isn't
actually it. And there's a massive
subculture doing that to show things off
and create personas on the internet. But
with that and with that untapped demand
for this, those factories got much
better. If you go around Wangjo and you
begin to actually spend time with the
luxury dupe manufacturers, they have,
let's say, 20% of their goods that are
at the quality level of real luxury. We
did a comparison with a YSL bag I got
there and the same YSL real bag my
wife's had. And we compared a few
different ones. Like the Gucci ones
weren't quite as good, but you couldn't
tell. the YSL one was better. And I
don't say that to say you should
purchase luxury dupes. I say that to say
that quality is no longer something that
luxury brands have a monopoly on. And so
when they charge the prices they charge
because with this popularity, with this
Instagram generation, prices have gone
through the roof. I called out in a
short form video the other day, Prada
sells $390 polyester socks. And you can
go get Darn Tough or Anonymous from
Japan. any number of these like great
alternative brands for like 2030 bucks
if even and while all of this quality
has been democratized look there's still
artisans and supply chain and I'll bring
up Bautga as the best example where they
are buying leather and monopolizing the
highest quality of leather that will be
hard to get your hands on at that level
they're using a lot of capital to do it
and they have real artisans there that
are producing some of their things that
allow it to be at a certain quality
level that people aren't going to be
able to get off the jump but for a lot
of products and I love to call out Prada
for this and we'll look at products data
in particle later you simply could
recreate it, right? Prona sells a lot of
bags that are nylon for egregious sums
of money. And at the same time as this
is happening, as we've realized this, as
people realize there's alternatives,
we've also seen this rise of taste. Tik
Tok, Instagram, and YouTube have given a
massive amount of people access to
developing their own style and learning
a lot more about design. You see really
interesting accounts that break down
different design eras. Here's art noo or
here's art deco or here's this
particular style of craft that the
Japanese used to do this denim or create
this brass table wear. We're learning
about that all the time. We're
developing our own sense of aesthetics.
Guys have learned how to dress for the
FIRST TIME.
>> LORD, IT'S a miracle.
>> And along the way, we're making
relationships, developing real
relationships with brands who are
telling their story in a way that
educates and entertains and we can learn
about and with founders who are doing
the same thing or providing themselves
as role models for this like higher
quality culture. the playing field has
leveled. And one thing I love to call
out as an example for that is this paint
company, Tonster Paints, 2.3 million
followers. They're competing against
Pharaoh and Ball and the highest end
paint companies in the world with these
big entrenched things. But this guy has
a format on Tik Tok and it's a small
company, handful of people, but 6.6 6
million views on this video of Black
Orange, their bestselling color, inside
his facility, just him on camera filming
it, getting more views than the entire
paint industry competing with him in the
single thing from understanding the
power of social. And this is what's
really disruptive to that luxury end is
that advantage they had from dollars and
infrastructure etc. is actually a
negative. We'll get more to that in a
minute. What's happening now is we're
seeing this constant changing of the
guard. I'll use Arcterix as an example.
So Arcterix as a brand has really fallen
off. It had a big hypebeast moment where
enthusiasts were like, "Cool, we don't
really want to mess with this brand
anymore. It stands for the wrong thing."
Then they got acquired by a big Chinese
conglomerate. There were complaints of
quality failing. And then they did this
really divisive campaign where they set
off fireworks and like destroyed a bunch
of endangered climate in Tibet, angering
not only the Asian consumer, but also
the woke western consumer. And overall
has basically been dethroned from being
a marquee brand. I won't ever say they
were like a luxury, per se. opening the
door for people who are considering that
category now to think a lot more of an
wander or claim mucusen or goldwin or
some of these incumbents that are coming
into that space and to the point of what
I mentioned with the paint video
companies like Merchra. So, Merchum
makes jackets, right? Jackets with
unique designs, but they are excellent
at viral emphasis where all of their
videos are made to succeed on the
internet. And they use product with
glow-in-the-dark and heat sensitive and
all these other things that come with
it, but to be able to gain way more
attention online than any of the
competitors are out there. They as a new
brand can move into an entrenched space
and through thoughtful design easily
stand out and then with content get more
eyeballs than their entire luxury
competitors were doing with all the
millions they spent on campaigns. Almost
everyone on the internet has seen this
video. 22.5 million views for a heat
reflective. I'm not even saying this the
quality is on par with something like an
arctic or even the same category, but it
shows the potential of people that know
the internet and how they can change
basically the sea tide here. So now
let's talk about positioning. So, if
you're new to marketing and branding,
positioning is how you choose to appeal
to consumers in your niche. How you want
to set yourself apart comparative to the
rest of the landscape. Positioning looks
at your brand relative to the other
brands. How do you set yourself up to
stand apart from your pricing, your
product decisions to your aesthetics to
your look. And so, there's a whole
category of what I'll call anti-luxury
that are offering you the non-brand name
at the same quality. And it is an
excellent example of this. So, their
whole spiel, life is luxury. They will
get you the same factories, the same
quality without the brand name and
label. And they've been around for a
while, but they've recently kind of
revamped their look and approach. If you
follow me on Short Form, you know one of
my most popular series I do is called
product versus brand, where I compare a
large number of items we will buy or we
will test against each other to
determine what is you being marketing
to, it's being oversold, you're buying
because it's popular versus what
actually has high quality product. And
so, I was doing homegoods, we were doing
sheets, we were doing towels. Metallic
is one of the brands that we purchased a
lot of for that. And sheets was an
interesting one. People really are
invested in their sheets and care about
them. And there's brands like Fret and
Spa or Fret, I want to pronounce it.
Sphera, really high-end sheets brands.
It cost like $2,000 a sheet. And we had
a lot of friends. We live in a really
nice part of town. We're in a luxury
neighborhood. We have a lot of wealthy
friends. We get into these conversations
about are these things worth the money?
And a lot of people are consumers of
these brands. And we're literally
testing these sheets and having
conversations with about them and
ordering this. And we compared this
whole grip of these options. And of all
of them, the italic sheets, why I'm
calling them out here, were the ones
where like this is hands down as good as
the luxury that's up there. And the
price is like a fraction. And so they're
delivering on that promise. And what's
interesting about this is they do this
from a category perspective. I'm going
to talk about Kint in a second does the
same thing. So my initial reaction from
there, I was like, cool, I want to try
the towels next. So I did the big towel
comparison. Their towels are right there
like higherend, middle of the pack,
excellent for the price. Whereas then
the sheets are crushing it. So I'm
looking at, okay, what else do they
sell? where is that quality there? So,
we recently got one of the Japanese like
steel chef knives to compare to some of
the other quality knives that we have.
But, I'm testing across their product
line now because I'm seeing that the
value is there. I don't care what logos
on my sheets. I care that the sheets are
amazing. And that is a positioning thing
they're able to say by basically being
like, look, it doesn't matter what name
is on it. It's we will give you that
quality at that price and have that pay
off. And K is a very similar approach.
They're doing this across a lot of
categories, a lot of different products
where they're saying, hey, we are
offering something. I think they are
basically positioning a slightly lower
tier than where it talic. Talica is
saying you're going to get luxury.
They're saying you're going to get
premium. You're going to get it at a
better price. They're doing it across a
lot of things because once your customer
trusts you to deliver on that value prop
on one thing, they become a keyn
shopper. They say, "Cool, what else can
I get? The same experience I have with a
talent." And K gives them a whole world
to buy into where they feel like they're
getting real value at an excellent
price. And look, you're getting your
your Birkenstock competitor right at a
fraction. And it's also water repellent.
They're really thinking through the
consumer experience here and they're
going wide to sell more to that
consumer. And that is a real positioning
opportunity that comes from this world
we're in where supply chain has
basically been ungatekept where they can
have their teams in China and Portugal
and wherever else continuing to hunt
down people that make the best stuff and
working out the economics of how they
can offer that and then leveraging all
the customers they get from any one of
these categories to cross-ell into other
categories. And it's a massive
opportunity and they're doing things
that are worth it. You can find amazing
value in both these brands. But the most
important thing they're fighting
against, which is really important for
any of you building brands, is they're
fighting against entrenched
infrastructure debt on the part of
existing companies. What do I mean by
that? As many of you know, I work for a
firm that owns companies and looks at
buying companies. So, we're doing due
diligence on companies a lot. And so, we
will look at some of these brands that
are are for sale. And look, most brands
that are for sale are not at the top of
their game. Sometimes they are, but most
aren't. You look at where are they going
wrong? And a lot of them, if they've
been around for a while, have a good
marquee brand name, you're like, how did
this go wrong? and it went wrong because
they have way too many employees now for
how the modern world works but they
don't want to fire them and get rid of
them or it's unnatural. These people
know X or Y and they've also got all
these commercial buildings, all these
factories, all these things that in the
modern world that is more of distributed
workforce where people own more key
things in categories where younger
people are savvier inside marketing than
larger older orgs. There's a lot of
disruption that can happen from a small
group who's able to do the same thing as
people who are used to doing it with a
lot of people. Cuz once you work in a
company that's used to doing a thing a
certain way, it's really hard to get it
to change. Especially when you get to
that 300 person plus mark inside an or
makes it almost impossible to move it
nimly. And this is an opportunity for
any new brand to look at guess what we
can actually replicate a lot of this
with 10 people with 20 people and use
that remaining margin to offer better
deals to our customers. And that's what
you see here. And the key of positioning
from these brands is they're telling
that story. They're saying you get this
quality at this price and they are
actually paying off on it. But while
that is more of an executionbased
tactic, there's also the storytelling.
So, a brand I love to call out as an
example of kind of new luxury is Benny
Rugs. I am a Benny Rugs consumer and
Maximalist. They sell expensive
products. These aren't cheap rugs. But
look at this video that we're starting
with. They sell authentic Moroccan rugs.
Their social media is like this, too.
They are You are watching guys in
Morocco hanging out these rugs. The
designs are incredible, but they are in
a constant storytelling mode. Every
picture here, Benny rugs feel like this.
When you step on it, you can see the
texture inside of this. This is not a
ruggable. Well, I will give the benefit
of the doubt. I want to keep I know a
lot of these companies are working to
improve. They have so many quality
products with amazing designs, but
they're using it by telling the story
from every environment you see them in
here to everything you see the photo
shoots on to their collaborations like
doing it with Studio Co. or Studio KO, I
don't know. this whole memory from
Casablanca where you can break down this
entire history of how they came up with
the designs based on redacted documents
like inside the labs. The storytelling
that goes into a Benny and then the
experience you get when you get it and
the design quality of when you get it is
incredible and eight acts of postcards
from Portugal and their whole journal of
the world behind rugs and the world
behind design. This is an excellent
example of a brand who can position
against the highest quality things in
the industry and pay off it by telling
their story really well online and
making that a constant focus of the
brand. It's analog. It's beautiful.
Another brand I like to call it that's
doing this at a lower price point is
Slow Tide. So Slow Tide's doing this and
they're a bit after my own heart as
someone who lives in Orange County and
who grew up in Hawaii. They're
positioned this as a beach brand, right?
But they are selling quality goods the
same quality of any of the mid-tier
luxury towel and outdoors companies with
a certain aesthetic with a certain
lifestyle and moving it across all
related products, right? Blankets,
ponchos, towels, positioning it based on
a specific lifestyle. And that's where
the like the fractional nature of every
brand in the world right now is going.
Nike's biggest competitors are
independent running brands. Big textiles
biggest competitors are the
individualization of we're going to
specialize in on a certain look and feel
of a product. We're going to dive in
there and they're doing it here. But I
want to talk about form factor in
design. We talked about positioning. We
talked a bit about story especially in
consumer electronics. We're seeing this
form factor and design revolution,
right? Where back to like that
entrenched like infrastructure debt. So
many of these companies that you
purchase on, if you want something like
a blender or a coffee machine are so
caught in their ways and their molds and
their infrastructure and their product
rollout, it's very hard for them to
create new things that look interesting
and intriguing. And so someone like
Beast, who's come out with a blender,
which I always think looks amazing and
is probably slightly overrated, slightly
overpriced, but they're really trying to
create a better experience to have it be
easy to use, really working on doing
something different, which you can
appreciate, but most importantly,
they're making an object which appeals
to our new aesthetic lives, which is a
strong angle for that. And you have this
comparison. You have performance to look
to cost and what matters to each
consumer. For a lot of consumers,
performance being at a B+, but look
being at an A is amazing for them.
They're not thorough everyday. my
blender needs to be perfect. Users, they
actually want the aesthetic thing. It
makes them happy. It looks good in their
home. That's that's important. Whereas
some have that mixture of they want the
best thing, the lowest cost and the
highest value. They're buying purely for
the value of the product. Everyone has
that scale and you can decide which of
those three levers you want to pull on
anything you position and it will help
you price and see where you want to work
in. And [snorts] another example of a
similar thing in the category is Fellow
making really nice tea kettles, coffee
machines, all these kind of things at
very reasonable prices with excellent
design that perform really well as well.
They actually have some real design
acumen that's gone into the decisions
they've made there. But they're
positioning against these entire
categories of brands that have come
before them and branching out quick. But
this doesn't happen just in electronics.
Another interesting category for this is
in bags. One of the biggest money sucks
I feel like in life is the designer
purse industry. the godforsaken Chanel
double flap, the money invested to have
to work your way up to Hermes to be able
to have the luxury of being able to buy
a Birkin. And meanwhile, there are all
these amazing brands like Marne who
offers bags that are in the hundreds of
dollars that look excellent, have a
really unique vibe and feel all the way
up to the low thousands to Sevet being
another kind of luxury competitive
choice. what to if you want to buy a bag
that has that same impact and feel and
looks and is luxury in comparison to
those fold brands. This is an excellent
one to brands like Capernie who have
built out their own unique shape that
kind of defines their brand and has
allowed them to create their own kind of
designer version working their way up
into luxury. These are better purchases
overall than spending that extra money
on that full luxury bag. Develop your
own sense of taste, your own sense of
style. And it's interesting. I'm going
to go into the particle data here. I
want to spend a moment on some of this.
And so Capern is an interesting one
where they sell those core bags. Most of
their top sellers are in that bag. They
also sell apparel and a few other
things. But they're also using that as a
basis to then hop on interesting trends
in product design. So for instance,
these are like five finger socks or five
toe socks. It's a really popular thing
right now. Toes spreading and its impact
on your spine is a really popular thing.
They are on that. They are selling a lot
of units, like a significant amount of
units and they're spiking and people are
buying them now for Black Friday. Same
thing like the knitted horn beanie.
They're able to play on trends and have
a core. And it's interesting to see how
brands are navigating that and playing
that savvier than these huge catalogs of
what you see traditional luxury have
opportunities and moments to buy into a
brand that's then surrounded by
relatively affordable staples, right?
Like this is a $800 bag. That's one of
their cores. And this why this why I
love using Particle. You get to like
find you see, oh, I thought they were
primarily a bag company, but really they
sell more apparel. Like you look at
Colga inside here and they bags is what
they're known for, but they really sell
more apparel. But you go inside Prada's
data. So look at Prada's last four weeks
142 million online. Just to give you a
comparison, the idea reason that number
is important, look back on $100 million
plus in sales and look the particle data
has some like like ceiling and floor of
accuracy, but still we're looking at
nine figures in sales in the last month
on there. Is that that is all market
share that is available for new brands.
This is all stuff that you can take your
1% of and have a viable business. You
get 1% of that month. That's a million
dollars a month as a consumer that is
worth fighting for. Something to note,
you look at these top products. That's
why I love to call out product. A,000 in
the last month of this medium nylon
backpack for $2,400. The smaller nylon
bag. That's a $3,000 bag for 1.2
million. Someone like Crease Group in
China can make bags of that same
quality, the highest quality of nylon
and stitching and all that for you. If
you have a design and a marketing plan
that can stand out, that problem can be
solved for you by manufacturing. The
product is commoditized. Look, there are
luxury companies that make higherend
stuff than that. Prada is not one of
them. You can solve that. And it's just
kind of worth looking at and seeing the
size of the prize. So anyway, one of the
reasons I love Particle, who are
sponsoring this video, thanks y'all for
so much. Is cuz we can literally stumble
into things like the Capernie insight of
like they're selling a lot of five to
socks right now. I wouldn't have
expected that. And understand how
they're building across their base to
seeing the real size of the prize of
thing like luxury brands. What do they
really sell? What people really buy from
them. You can learn more about Particle
at the link in the description. And the
last thing I'm going to talk about here
is we're going to go into the fragrance
and scent category. I want to talk about
this brand DS and Durgga. You look at
luxury fragrance, etc. How do you stand
out? How do you compete in that
category? And where they've done a
really amazing job is they are an art
direction driven brand. I know a lot of
people watch my channel for art
direction, creative direction, something
I'm extremely passionate about. That's
what they have thought through inside
their photography, even their product
photography and the angles on it are
incredible to everything and how they
present the brand. All of this is
incredible. So these imagery, they have
so much incredible imagery that they've
shot. all these campaigns truly a leader
in art direction inside of this where
they have presented their scent with
just incredible art in every portion of
it and it's begun to sell the identity
of a brand that's intriguing that's
mysterious that you want to tap into and
look inside. They have complemented that
with music. They have playlists that go
with every one of these scents to find
the vibes and the moods and they're
serious. They go through all of these
that you see that they release. They've
built this real world around a fragrance
in a way that I think is as interesting,
in fact more immersive and interesting
than any luxury brand has done and then
complemented that with product. So in
addition to like doing things like these
holiday candles and releases, one of the
things I found most interesting for them
is they did this murder mystery set.
They do layering sets. I have it sitting
on my my shelf over here where you can
layer these fragrances on top of each
other to create different feels,
different sensations, and they have
basically like a game with suspects and
all that where you put out to be able to
they're selling it in a really
intriguing way, but also getting people
immersed in the idea of scent and how do
they play off each other and the fact
that all of these can be a combo and
making something unique to you is a
really thoughtful and interesting
approach to fragrance. And people are
always like, "How do you stand out in a
market like fragrance or candles, which
we're going to get to last?" And it is
by really genuinely committing to
everything. and they use their expertise
in fragrance to be able to sell this
really interesting thing that I would
rather you purchase and invest in than
any luxury scent. And last, I want to
end up with Hotel Lobby Candle. We're
going to take another look at Particle
on this, too, cuz that's the other
question. Everyone's like, "Oh, I have a
candle company. How can a candle stand
out?" Look, you got to commit to the
bit. So, Hotel Lobby sells a hotel
themed candle set. Again, amazing art
direction, interesting looks and feels
of the content, but they work really
hard at marketing this at creating this
world around it. And they invested a lot
in marketing. I found this company
because they rented a not a PJ is the
wrong word, but they rented like a King
Air, a private plane to go from New York
to the Hamptons with a bunch of
influencers at a big influencer weekend.
And all these people were like, "This
candle company got a PJ for the
influencers." And it's an interesting
thing to talk about cuz look, they're
creating this vibe, the idea of
Hampton's and that jet setting lifestyle
and all the things that come with that.
And they're selling into it. You have to
sell if you want to stand out. If you
don't do anything, it's going to be hard
to get any attention. But that's a
pretty easy one actually. That's a short
plane ride. If you put influencers on a
PJ, how much do you think they're going
to post? Probably a lot more than
they're contracted for. And it begins to
tell this immersive story of all the
things that they did on that weekend. It
sets the stage for people to pay
attention to the influencer content that
comes after that when people are doing
multiple posts with you. It was a very
savvy move to get attention for this
brand. But you have to do that. You have
to invest in the real marketing and
storytelling. It doesn't necessarily
have to be to that level, but it has to
be to a level that gets people to pay
attention. And you can solve that either
with doing things on a higher budget end
that really impact or on a really
creative end. And to call out the
results of that, like let's look at
these candle sales. I'm in particle
until lobby's in there. In the last uh
30 days, 1,000 plus of just this holiday
in New York candle, another 900 of this
other the holiday candle variant, the
big candle, 120 of the $325 uh city
candle collection set, right? They are
moving units of candles, like no joke
amounts of candles, and they're driving
this through, I'm sure, any number of
channels. This is a candle company that
came essentially out of nowhere.
Probably heard of it first time 6 months
ago, maybe. Maybe they've been around
for significantly longer. But getting on
the radar of new consumers, moving units
like this and being something I imagine
many of you have never heard of. This is
where the opportunity is. It really does
lie that you can break out in any of
these. You have to think through one of
these things we talked about. So going
back through what we all mentioned
positioning, the democratization of
production, the storytelling aspect of
this design and the form factor, this
art direction and creative direction,
really thinking through the themes of
the brand, which is akin to the
storytelling aspect. This is the
playbook we have to to work with. I do a
lot of videos where we get tactically
into it. Sometimes it's good to just
take a step back and look at the people
that are doing it. And this exciting
time to be in and look at all these
brands that are genuinely worth
consuming. They're working really hard
to tell a story, to do more than just do
a product, to be genuinely interesting,
to create things that have real value.
And I love looking at this and thinking
about why we consume what we do, what
brings meaning into our lives, and
what's worth investing our time in as
designers or marketers or creatives to
to bring to life. I hope you enjoyed
this video. Learn more about Particle in
the description. And my next video, I
believe, is going to be the art
direction of Korean fashion and street
wear. We're branching out a bit. It's
going to be on the new set. I'm super uh
excited for [music] it. We'll be trying
to up the ante going into 2026. And as
always, I appreciate it so much for
watching. Happy that y'all are so as
passionate about these things as I am.
Thank you so much.