all right so today we are a bit outside
of our normal environment we are here in
London I'm en route to Paris I'm
actually giving a talk tomorrow here in
London about art Direction and social
content I want to take some of my art
Direction thoughts I've been preparing
for this and then give youall a really
interesting case study of one of my
favorite Brands Stuy so in some of my
previous art Direction videos we covered
the core of what art direction is we've
gone in depth into how you can apply
some of its Concepts to things like a
white background shoot but in this video
I want to use Stu's pretty incredible
canvas of all their various ads and
campaigns over the years talk about a
couple crucial Concepts that any art
director or any brand making art
directed content should think about
we're going to cover text and treatments
and building the iconography of your
brand into art direction we're going to
talk about using your logo as a core
portion of how your brand comes across
visually we're going to talk about the
lifestyle of a brand and how that
extends into art direction we're going
to talk about the people of your brand
the original stucy and the rise of what
influencers call the homie lookbook and
then we're going to talk about
developing Brands signatures and through
lines and using them over time all with
tons of examples let's lock in so first
why Stuy so as many of you know I
actually grew up in Hawaii in Honolulu
and the first shirt that I ever got was
actually the stucy and I remember being
in the surf shops with all the brands
you'd think of quicksilver bong Etc but
there was something about this brand and
the designs and what was around it that
was just immediately special was the
first thing I'd ever bought with my own
money that was like a fashion piece and
it's crazy seeing that brand still today
like here on the Streets of London
you'll see the logos like like all
around all the way to where I live in
Orange County which is now where the
stui office is and seeing a brand that
has maintained its cool like throughout
that time it's had some dips and erors
but the fact it's been able to go there
and survive from when I got that first
t-shirt 20 years ago to today is a
pretty incredible run but also you'll
see their content permeate mood boards
throughout all those arrows because they
are a campaign first brand when you
really look at Stu's marketing it comes
down to the product itself and who wears
it and it comes down to visual photo art
directed campaigns that were run as ads
and magazines that are now put out
across their social media and into the
kind of network of blogs and news that
we put out but really every single thing
at the core of its marketing they do
very little else besides put out
incredible art directed shoots and it's
funny where I live now in Orange County
in Santa Ana Stuy has an archive store
it's one of the best pieces of marketing
and kind of like secret lore I feel like
a company can have where you go to this
old downtown like Arts area there's not
a tongue going down on there but it's
like buring for where we are and they
have stuff from stucy collections for
the last decade they basically like
slowly roll out things from anywhere
from 10 years ago to 5 years ago to a
year or so ago you can basically access
a very careful collection of things that
would otherwise be sold out online in
like a tiny shop in this you know really
fun area and seeing a brand that's so
intentional about its access about its
art is something I feel like a lot of
Brands whether fashion or not can learn
a lot from and aspire to be like let's
get into some of these campaigns I'm
going to start with this Birkenstock
campaign stui does extensive
collaborations and are always anchored
in art Direction and this campaign in
particular they are doing a lot of hedge
trimming gardening all with their logo
and iconography at the center and this
is a great way to talk about iconography
as a centerpiece for art Direction and
why your iconography matters as a brand
let's look at it this way say you have
iconography for your brand it goes on
your t-shirts Etc Great that's step one
but when you're able to permeate that
into what you actually put inside the
concepts of your campaigns you're taking
it to another level so in this
Birkenstock campaign you can see they
have Hedges trimmed to look like the
Stuy eightball to look like some of
their key iconography and when you think
about art Direction your team sits down
and come up with a campaign and you have
a concept saying hey we want to work
with gardening we want to be able to do
something on a beach want to do X and Y
usually you're basically throwing on the
board people you have access to and
locations you have access to now when
you have a really strong iconography set
all of a sudden this becomes much more
inherently ownable as a brand so for
instance duy can go okay on this you
know in the selection of people we have
maybe for this shoot we could either get
a fire eater or we could go work in this
garden with someone who has Immaculate
ability to cut various trees they say
okay let's now apply our iconography to
that they can cut the trees into
whatever but if that's actually our c
aall that becomes a much more
interesting visual thing immediately
conative of the brand and this is
something you'll see they've done
through generations I highly encourage
any brand with iconography to do and if
you don't have iconography how can you
begin to develop those symbols that go
with it obviously they've been around
long enough to be associated with kind
of legendary versions of these but when
you begin thinking about your
iconography you want to think the same
way and a brand I think has run this
Playbook really well is this brand 2js I
believe it's from Spain where you'll see
they will have their kind of logo
iconography and they'll be running it
like in huge metal sculpture it'll be on
fire in the desert and they're kind of
taking that same Playbook applied to
their iconography this ties really well
into this next segment which is building
the cult of your logo we've talked so
much about art Direction and just like
making interesting photos making content
that will stand out and this video
really hinges on like how do you
incorporate your brand correctly how
does branding really tie into what you
do from an art Direction perspective so
there's this iconic shot of the stucy
logo in treatment in a sunburn and you
see it has multiple variations of their
logo and iconography I also love this
shot which is a drone shot of the stucy
logo basically mapped in the sand on a
beach and in our era now people will be
asking oh is this AI is this CGI but
like you know that this is the kind of
brand that will go and actually execute
this kind of thing we actually create a
real sunburn we'll actually employ an
artist to do this from the air on a
beach it's part of the lore of the brand
that these are things that are real and
if you're in this kind of time now and
you want to do that same thing you now
have the ability to add behind the
scenes content that helps tell that
story and show the depths with which
you're willing to take your brand lore
but you'll notice that front and center
inside not all these campaigns but
plenty of them is that logo and
iconography even this awesome campaign
we'll get to the people and the people
of stucy in a minute when they're
playing dominoes they're spelling out
the Stuy s and this is tied over into
print for them for decades so st's most
recognizable initial art Direction was
they would take these shots lifestyle
shots of people in their Community often
in black and white and they'd have the
hand styles of the kind of graffiti
roots of the brand that would be all
around in a border and eventually those
would turn into just kind of like
additions on the page but you're
basically building a toolkit from there
if you look at your Brand's toolkit you
go we have iconography and then we have
typography in this case you know with
with the graffiti tie and they have
pretty extensive typography they can use
with it and then you have the actual
logo itself like that is a visual
toolkit for post application and
something like this is interesting when
done over time and especially this isn't
just like a cool type treatment it ties
into the lifestyle and culture that the
brand was embracing as well but that
becomes your basically visual like
postprocessing toolkit or toolkit of
what you can incorporate into the shoot
and no one has done that better than
what Stuy has next we're going to talk
about the lifestyle tie in and we're
going to get into people so stui started
as a surf brand with a significant
amount of like hip-hop skate Associated
Roots but really has that Association of
lagona beach of places like Hawaii where
I grew up and they've built that pretty
significantly into the FI of the brand
but they've done it with like the
wideness of any action sport right one
of the most iconic shoots they've done
was this racing shoot with their branded
car with the helmet coming coming out of
it with the motion that's happened and
they've embraced that action throughout
their kind of brand history and this is
when we talk about when we say lifestyle
adjacent there's a lot of Brands now
whose lifestyle is basically being
fashionable or being street wear but was
was important to think about suy as
adjacent to basically anything action
related any Motorsport any kind of surf
sport that has the right connotation for
them they've shown within these
campaigns it's often not some like big
sponsored writer or famous person either
it's just people partaking in the
activity but it's that sense of motion
it's that sense of action it's an
extension of the lifestyle and again
when you have your art Direction toolkit
as a brand you now have okay here's my
iconography how could we incorporate
that who we have access to okay and
here's our lifestyle we're looking for
an idea for a shoot we're action
adjacent all right we want to make sure
we can incorporate Motocross or racing
like that now is all things when you
look at the board you begin to have
you've honed in on the choices that you
have you can make interesting decisions
within all right so in these videos I
don't want to just give case studies I
want to actually show you what
actionable work with some of these same
Concepts look like for someone like me
day-to-day so I use milillo to organize
my creative workflow Mill node is a tool
for Creative organization and it
graciously agreed to partner on this
video so I'm going to show you how I use
my art Direction Master boards like this
one you see here inside Mill note so I
do a lot of work in multi categories
Cosmetics apparel consumer package KS I
have one master board for each and I'll
do what I did here anytime I take a
project and want to present it or talk
about it with the team so this is a
bunch of Concepts I've pulled from my
various boards and put into one now how
is this different from a mood board and
what makes this workflow special so
inside Millan note here what I will do
is I will take between three and let's
say eight or nine images or videos and I
can embed Instagram and Tik Tok in here
one of my favorite things about mm I
will put them in these big boards each
one of these Concepts will have a title
it will have a couple example shots I
don't want to go too far I don't want a
whole mood board I just want to be able
to visually show an idea so anyone can
look at it and be like okay I get what
you're going for and then I will note
about what would make this special or
ideas that I have so for instance like
this same kind of lap shot style but we
use an ultra wide to show more of the
surroundings or we have a series where
there's dogs and cats on the lap as well
or odd pets going down to these vending
machine shots I have't note about how
much it costs and how long it would take
to actually get a custom vending machine
I have some of these shot ideas for
reels like a person buying it or shaking
it to get it out or some models tipping
it over or a day in the life of someone
restocking like an oddball like a
Cosmetics vending machine then what I
will do is in presentations and in
brainstorm sessions we actually go
through a bunch of these ideas sometimes
it's just a handful sometimes it can be
like 20 or 30 to gauge what people like
and don't like add some notes on here
and I can literally just grab a note and
drag it on screen and be able to put
notes while conversations are happening
and then what I'll do is I'll take
everything that people like from the
brainstorm session I will make a new
board and I'll put those in there we can
collaborate on that one add comments
people can begin to add their own
imagery and really take advantage of the
power of a creative tool like mill note
so if you're looking for an exercise you
can do for art Direction ideas for your
brand or to get the creative Wheels
spinning for your own work I would
suggest making a lot of these little
idea boards so basically taking a
masterboard getting three or four images
that attached to a concept think about
how you can make it different and just
laying a lot of those out so you begin
to have a framework you can go back to
because too often we'll have those
visual ideas not put them anywhere and
then forget about them and this is a
really useful form format you can do to
quickly review your own workflow or to
go through something with a team so you
can sign up for mote for free with no
time limit at the link down below highly
recommend it it's a tool I use every day
now I want to talk about the stucy tribe
and how that ties to this idea of the
homey lookbook that's really popular now
so from the beginning stusy has taken
portraits of people in their Community
they were known as the tribe early and
it's funny I actually worked with
someone from that like original stusy
team a previous brand I worked out who
would talk about like the Heyday of like
those people and being invited to it and
being like a member of that Community is
like like a really awesome part of his
life and something has continued now
where you see that inside all these
campaigns whether it's collaboration or
not they're featuring these interesting
people and people that are significantly
real and was that something like when
they did their campaign with Dre van
noton where they have like flea from Red
Hot Chili Peppers like in his element
you know showing like the photos of that
to various artists that they've been
connected to over time to just the
models they have there is an integration
of people that are in a very real sense
throughout the brand but the the real
the hey this is part of our community
these are the people we know is like an
extremely important concept cuz you've
seen this now from Al who shot with all
their like friends and family out inside
New York City to people like Brigade in
New York who have all their kind of
friends the center pieces of their
campaigns there's this really important
concept of replacing models with just
people you know with real people because
how closes fit on models isn't how
closes fit on actual consumers and the
same thing goes for how Cosmetics look
on people or really any of the aspects
like if you put some piece of furniture
inside a gorgeous home that's a
significantly different than what's
reality and and consumers Embrace
reality more and those stories tend to
be more real and stusy from the
beginning was showing hey these are the
people inside our community the people
that we mess with and by extension you
can look at that as a community you
basically buying into by buying into the
brand and I would encourage Brands now
to really think about that too and it's
not just hey I'm going to use my friends
in my photos versus like employing a
real model it's more of is there a story
that we can tell underneath that because
that becomes the more interest of the
art Direction before I came here to
London I was in New York and we talk to
the team from Brigade and they would be
having this conversation like oh well my
friend does this really interesting
thing uh and so actually designed a
piece of clothing they kind of inspired
by that we want to do a lookbook around
this really interesting thing he does it
wasn't just like hey I wanted to put
Carl in the lookbook cuz he looks a
certain way it had to do with his story
and the things that like Inspire them
and do that that's a really great way as
a brand to again look at that toolkit
cuz now when you say I have my
iconography I have this lifestyle Jason
2 now I have all these people that are
coming in and out of my life that maybe
their stories can hinge into the art
direction of the campaigns that we're
trying to do and now your world is
starting to build out if you're kind of
cataloging that on a whiteboard or a
notion dock or whatever it is you're
really beginning to build so companies
are World building by taking all this
together like what we're talking about
here is really like World building for a
brand and how art Direction plays into
that and I think every brand should have
you know its range of people that are a
part of that Universe they're building
and understand the power of the portrait
of those people what is their angle
going back to Brigade they have a series
where it's like medium format photos of
basically all their friends but theyve
Incorporated the portrait idea like into
their brand sty had this original idea
hey we're going to have photos of people
like out and about together and then
we're going to have our handstyle design
around it and they're going to be black
and white right there's very different
approaches they have I'd encourage you
to think for the people that you know
that are engaged with your brand what is
that kind of portrait what is that style
you can Embrace over time to Showcase
those people and there could obviously
be more than one or you can do any
campaigns another way I do think an
important part is how you're capturing
the people your community and
incorporating that into your content so
next I'm going to walk through some of
the concepts as Stu's used that are
recurring themes in their content and
then we're going to go summarize all
this into a playbook for kind of brand
art Direction so one of the other themes
you've seen deep within what Stu's done
is surrealism so they'll do things like
incorporating this dinosaur into the
shots and you'll notice again
iconography like the eightball logo is
the back of this tire wheel cover but
for a significant amount of time there
was a like kind of Oddball dinosaur
inside a number of of these campaigns
right it's kind of thing where if you're
flipping through a magazine if you're
stoned in whatever era that was it's
like oh like sick dinosaur like they are
kind of incorporating this like thing
that makes everything seem just a little
bit more strange and that's a great
theme and I think Brands all need a
couple of these themes they can go into
and back to and recurring things they
don't have to be serious what I like
about this is there's a lot of really
serious stucy shoots there's a lot of
really community-driven ones and there's
just this like fun era that like again
doesn't match perfectly didn't last
forever but like was a a part of the
brand and showed it you its other side
then they have this other segment they
have of like Urban action and people and
who is wearing the brand and showcasing
that from these like Street side shots
of like this girl flicking off the
camera in New York to these guys playing
dominoes which I feel like is one of the
most iconic Stuy shoots of like recent
memory but what you're doing with shoots
like these is you are showing people
that aspire to be in these places or
look like this like who wears the brand
who they are adjacent to when they wear
it and you're creating that story and
again it's not models that's why I think
this is really important and how to
think in art Direction where you can
think in art Direction terms of what
what story does a model tell but you can
also think of what does this scene and
setting and people like in a location
tell and for brands that are from a
place or want to Aspire be related to a
place things is a really important
concept to have as you think about
shoots and the last is the car signature
you'll notice that in so many of these
shoots do uses vehicles and there's a
lot of brands that use vehicles in one
way or another but they basically use
them for framing like this shot that
goes like through a car door or someone
sitting in the truck bed or this entire
campaign they did where there's really
interesting cars on either side you
actually can't even see the full amount
you kind have to wonder oh I think
that's a whatever or I think this is
this vehicle you actually get the whole
picture it makes you want to learn more
about the shoot it it's like a really
engaging way but they're basically using
it like not as a primary not as this
photo is cool because it has a car but
as a a set in setting that brings depth
into what they're are directing so if
you now look at this whole toolkit that
we described this surrealism this
capturing of like the friends and
community and the family these like
Urban settings this idea of like the
vehicles and then their iconography
that's kind of stretched across not all
but many of these the treatments of
their logos and the handstyles on top of
them that is their art Direction world
every campaign you see from them
operates Within These boundaries and
with these through lines and if all this
is on a board and you are a brand
preparing for to doing campaigns you
have a really solid sandbox with which
you're able to play in and so your job
as an art director when you're working
with some somebody is to basically
outline this sandbox like what are these
things and your job as a brand is to be
able to have a world where you actually
created this so to run that back into a
Playbook like the first thing I think
about is what is your iconography and
how can it last like for my brand I have
this really big V that's almost you know
it's almost a check mark you know it has
that like you the idea was hey let's
let's you create something we could make
big we could fabricate then same thing
with like you know the folders and this
archives idea and you've seen it complex
con I had like a massive folder and
there's like some of these kind of ideas
of like archives and like the archival
or design Department Focus brand that's
how I'm kind of thinking about that is
how can I build that iconography into
many things and the second thing is are
you building logo worship right are you
making your logo a centerpiece that
makes people want to have it on them and
this is hard because for a lot of people
when you really look at your logo you
may not have that and you may not have
that ability also to be easily
integrated into campaigns or or easily
kind of like put on it and like the
treatments might not be there it it
makes you really think about what your
iconography looks like and the power of
it then there's what lifestyles are you
adjacent to right now think about this
with my brand where I'm working with
Garrett who's like a rodeo photographer
aspiring Rodeo photographer and the
connections to kind of that world for
the brand same thing for the like the
Ultra Car Enthusiast like mine's not
just like any car it's people that he
say hey I'm going to take this time and
dedication and money out of my life to
be the guy with a '90s Ferrari to be the
person who's restored like X or Y like
some of these adjacent pieces that you
begin to to put together and like making
gear that is exciting for those folks
like so I I sell car mats at valuable
and like car accessories right and the
people that get them are the people who
have like this project car or this thing
that they're really proud of or got that
you know hey I went and got this
specific thing and now I want to have my
person personalization on it they want
to have that like attachment to it
they'll go grab the car mats and like
you'll see it like time and time again
the people that end up getting it are
people either like with this really
specific vehicle they aspired to have or
who are like have a project they've
undertook where this kind of adds
another layer of depth and lore to that
project and then what is your portrait
philosophy you're going to have all
these people around you whether it's
your customers your community whatever
how are you capturing them what is your
photo and art Direction style for that
is worthwhile exercise to think about
and then last what are those additional
themes what are those recurring things
that are going to be able to kind of
work through that for example in my
brand I do some of these like
storytelling carousels it's like
captions where they're almost movie like
there like a recurring theme where I can
connect things together this kind of
like Heist almost like intelligent crime
adjacent thing that can kind of
continually perpetuate we're adding this
other visual layer on of like you can
always think about okay if we have a
horse there's something that like
immediately ties the brand into it by
just being in all these traditional
Street Wear scenarios or working with an
existing photographer art director in
their look but immediately we kind of
added this like equ factor it's like an
interesting idea I'm playing with but
this is a what you can learn from the
Stuy brand from their execution and the
last point I'll note is that the
campaigns are Relentless every single
thing they do there's a thought through
ART directed campaign every release
every collaboration every season without
fail and it's something that where
people say hey maybe this time we're
just doing the standard lookbook or
whatever like they never do that it just
always something that has intention and
I think that's the same level what you
should be bringing to your brand and how
art directors should be thinking and
laying out their ideas so I appreciate
yall watching I'm excited to see what
this inspires for you and your Brands
let's go
h