This is how to successfully build a
luxury brand. I'm using a case study on
this concept of heritage maximalism.
It's a widely used term, but one I
actually made up on TikTok like 2 years
ago. And we're in an interesting era
where brands aren't trying to pop out
and look brand new anymore. They're not
yassifying, but instead they're trying
to invent a brand identity and find a
legacy that may or may not exist that
makes them feel like they've been around
forever. And you see this in fashion
with brands like ALD doing their best
Ralph Lauren impression. you couldn't
tell if that brand is 30 years old, 50
years old, or 5 years old. You're also
seeing the same thing in packaged goods.
So, my friend Andrea at the snackshot
had a recent post about this where she's
actually calling out, I think she called
it Nau Artal, which actually calling out
some of the brands who are taking this
strategy where they're saying, "Hey, we
actually want to look like we've been
around for 100 years inside our
packaging with some really interesting
examples of kind of how that's being
merged into a combination of of modern
aesthetics as well. This briska olive
oil is a great example of like it's a
full period piece. But in this video,
I'm going to go through a whole variety
of things. I'm going to talk about the
state of aesthetics and the aesthetics
that were like the millennial defining
era into where we're at today and how
we've moving from '90s nostalgia to like
nightcore nostalgia. We talk about my
recent trip to Paris and seeing how
people are embracing some of these older
aesthetics. We're going to dive deep
into a brand called 1803 Bully who are
the poster childs of basically creating
a luxury house out of thin air and how
they've done it and why I think it's a
really interesting playbook for other
brands to look at and replicate. I'm
going to share some other examples from
inside the food industry. We're going to
talk about luxury toothpaste, how
technology is embracing this new look
and feel, and overall what the tools,
ideas, and recipes are to make something
seem like it's been around forever to
help justify these higher price points,
and what a holistic luxury experience
looks like for a brand being built for
the next decade. So, first, we lived in
this era. If you're a millennial, you
lived through this, if you're Gen Z, you
may likely remember it, where all these
new brands were coming out, and they
were all being branded by these agencies
like Jin Lane and Red Antler to look
like these new millennial brands. There
was these cartoon characters, these very
primary colors, these millennial
pastels, very simple logos. Everything
was becoming very millennial, for lack
of a better term. And you'll recognize
brand after brand that was basically
done by these same handful of agencies
who were just known for cranking out
these like simple, successful millennial
forward brands. And what we're seeing
now is a reaction to that because many
people were kind of taken advantage of
by those brands. We've seen a lot of
those brands go from darlings to
bankrupt or had founder issues. There's
a lot of kind of glorified issues that
happened inside that era. And also just
consumer taste switches over time. And
none of those band brands positioned as
luxury. They positioned in this middle
tier where it said, "Hey, we're going to
cost more than the traditional thing.
We're going to look a little better. Our
marketing is going to be a little bit
better. We're not going to go up to the
full era of luxury. We're going to
charge a premium for our aesthetics."
And what we found is that people don't
want to buy the premium for those
aesthetics purely anymore. or in fact
they feel like they're kind of getting a
raw deal for that and have been educated
enough by the internet to understand it.
They actually do want to feel like they
are buying history, luxury, and an
experience with what they get. This
comes with a bigger idea, this shift
into maximalism away from minimalism
that a lot of brands should be super
aware of where you'll see now the
aspirational apartment isn't an ultra
minimalist millennial. It has gold
frames and splashes of color. The looks
inside architectural digest have
shifted. There's amorphous shapes.
There's plants. Things are extra versus
simple. And it was interesting. I went
to Paris a few months ago. I made a
handful of videos that went pretty
viral. And one of them was just about
the experiences you can do in in Paris
if you are into maximalism. And one of
the ones I called out was from this
artist group, Ex Libras, who I stumbled
into inside of a like these luxury pet
stores I was around. Above them on one
of the floors was basically like a
little booth where they would make
crests. They will like basically
handdraw and come up with crests for
you. And they have this business I'm
scrolling through here where they have
just have all these gorgeous like very
intricate very traditional crests you
can get like with a stamp for a fee from
this group. And it was it went extremely
popular like everyone was commenting and
asking about them. They got a bunch of
followers and inquiries and it was just
a reminder of like what people are
looking for when it comes to aesthetics
which ties really much into where the
foundation of luxury is today. That they
want this kind of legacy look and
approach. And I think this is in a large
part due to how easy aesthetics have
become to replicate, especially with AI
where anything that's relatively modern
or simple can be replicated very easily
using all these basic tools that we are
basically proliferated with how easy it
is with creative market and a few stock
assets and a little bit of chat GPT and
midjourney to make any basic modern
brand that people see so much of that
and are inundated so much with that that
really when they think of aspirational
or something that they want something
that represents them they want something
that's handmade that has more care that
is more intricate and something like
exaborist is an amazing ability to go
have that kind of level of experience
onetoone with an artisan versus
everything we deal with in this internet
era and I bring this up because this is
what I think the foundation of luxury
looks like for these next decades is
that it is really historicalbased even
if you are creating something new the
experience needs to be that craftsman
focused that artisan that ornate in that
way and I've talked about the pillars of
luxury before talked about how luxury
needs to last over time talked about how
the quality needs to be there. The
difference between something that's
bespoke, something that's designer, and
something that's luxury. Save that for
another video. I'll link at the end. But
in this video, I want to focus on that
heritage maximalism aesthetic and how
people can basically create a legacy
brand out of thin air. And to do that, I
want to talk about Bully 1803 cuz they
are someone who's done it. They are not
a brand that has been around forever.
This was a company formed in 2014,
acquired by LVMH. It's a decade and
change old that references an ancient
brand that pulls on all the tropes you'd
expect from a brand that has legacy in
terms of how it presents itself, what
the packaging looks like, what's on the
website, the experience inside their
stores, positions it very much as a
brand from 1803, as well as it being in
the name even though it is something
new. And it's actually became quite
controversial. There's a lawsuit out
there from a perfumery or fragrance
house that says that they took their
imagery and use a lot of their imagery
inside the intricate packaging that they
present. As of me making this video or
at least writing this, that remained
unresolved. But the point is they have
created a brand identity around
positioning themselves as legacy and
done it successfully cuz at the end of
the day, the consumer doesn't really
care what that actual history is there.
They care about the quality of the
product they're getting, the look and
feel of what's happening. if they feel
like they're buying into a movement, if
they get the results, and if they can
have the experience. We're going to go
through those one by one. So, first is
presentation. They have immaculately
designed packaging in the most ornate
levels possible in ways that is kind of
even hard to comprehend how one goes
about making something like that. These
are mainly skin products and body
products, but there is intricate
illustration on essentially everything.
There are labels that beget it to being
an older time. Same thing with the
ingredients, with everything about how
this is positioned. There is at no point
do you doubt for a second that they are
not all in on this identity of some
vintage luxury of this heritage
maximalism idea and this carries through
to the experience in store. If you go
into the store is a time capsule
intricate presentation and they have
leveraged that to also provide an
experience and this is one of the
biggest things I think is crucial for
any luxury branding being done in this
modern era is if you want to take that
shortcut to time you need to have this
experience element. I'll call out ALD
around this as well because part of what
has cemented them was when they launched
the ALD cafes which became a destination
which had a look and feel which felt
like luxury that are done better than
the Ralph Lauren cafes that they are
replicating in terms of design and
experience and present them as a artisan
thing you can go do even if you're not
actually purchasing an ALD jacket you
can go buy in on your ALD coffee and
where Bully has done this in a genius
perspective is when you go to Paris one
of the most crowded experiences that you
can do is to actually go get in any of
those locations you can get engraved
combs and brushes from them. It is an
extremely popular thing to do. Is
relatively affordable. It's like a €50,
say 30 to 100 depending on the model
that you choose. And you get it engraved
there. You exit with an absolutely like
ornate bag. The whole thing because the
way the stores look and the way the
brand looks and the experience in there
is perfect for making video content. And
you can buy your little piece of Paris
as part of that experience, which is
something everyone wants to do. They
want to be able to have that video of
going to a thing that's they know is
going to look great on the internet.
They want that memoir that's not like
some random thing. It's a brush or
something useful they'll have in their
life dayto-day. And Bully nailed this by
saying not only do we have this product
lineup, this brand, this intricacy, we
have this physical real life experience
that is worth seeking out that becomes
part of someone's plan inside their
journey. much as stopping and getting a
coffee when you are in the lees or
wherever the ALD store is has become a
part of the day of their target consumer
or visitors into the city knowing they
have a destination to go there. All
right, so in this segment I'm going to
talk about the email marketing that some
of these heritage maximalist luxury
brands do and I'm going to show you a
bit inside of Omniscent, which is the
email software I use for the brands I
work with, how to actually set some of
it up. So this segment is sponsored by
Omnisense, but as always, I don't want
to just talk about a software. or I want
to show you how to do something you can
use in your career with it. So, first
I'm going to start inside of Mil. Mil is
a free tool that you can use to see
brands email marketing. So, I'm going to
pop in here and I'm going to look at
Bully 1803 and the actual emails that
they use. And one thing I want to call
out and why I like to do this is you can
see how Luxury actually does email. So,
here, you know, beautiful title at the
top, all the graphics we've talked
about, but look at they're writing a
novel inside of this email. There's so
much text, there's history, there is
context. This is kind of the opposite of
the email marketing playbook a lot of
brands do who say, "Hey, we're just have
one graphic and a little button says
call to action." They're literally
educating you on all kinds of stuff. It
is in French. As you can tell, I'm here
in Europe. So, some of the default
language is French and Italian on things
I look up. But you can see inside here,
we got like a whole history of Maria
Antuinette going into a Victor Hugo
quote, then going into them talking
about their products. And so I just want
to call this out to note that you should
feel okay putting lore and history and
thought into your email if you are a
luxury brand. Now heading over into
omniscent I want to talk about
automations. So I'm going to go here to
automation. I'm going to hit create
workflow. A lot of people get I guess
spooked by the concept of automations.
Sounds like it's something that's really
complicated but it's actually really
easy and it's a core part of selling for
your brand. So here they have a bunch of
pre-built automations you can just click
and get into. Something like a welcome
automation which we'll talk about here.
So automation has a few things you
should know about. They have triggers,
so based on something that people does,
an action gets created. Then they have
actions, so things like a delay or an AB
test or splitting people by some
parameters they have. And they have
actual emails you can put in there. So,
one of the things I love to do if a
brand has no automation already is
actually just go through their best
performing emails, save them as a
template, and then load them into a flow
like this. I'm going to start a new flow
to show you how. So, create from
scratch. Define how a person enters a
workflow. So, I'm put enter a segment.
Segments are basically lists and
portions of list inside of Omnisend. I
can select that. I'm going select my
pre-release segment I have inside this
account just for relevancy. I can choose
to trigger that workflow for people that
already exist when I when I set it up or
I can just have it for new people that
come in. I'm just going to set this for
new people that come in. And you'll see
these actions. I'm going to delay pop in
here. Also may want to tag them. So I
say, "Hey, let's wait for 1 minute after
they signed up before we send that
email. I want to add them to a new tag."
Pop that in there. And then I can put an
email or an SMS. Literally, you're just
dragging it. And then that email, I can
either set that up right here. I can
save this content. This will allow me
when I go into edit content. I can
actually go and I can change the
template to any template I already have.
So, I will save other emails as
templates or usually set it up before I
drop it in. Or you can just go custom
design it. But then once I create this,
I can do the same thing. I can delay
again, say, hey, I want to delay this
for another 2 days. I can drop in
another email. I can do another delay.
Hey, I want you to actually get this 7
days later. And that gives you the
basics of how to put together a flow.
So, what I will typically do here for a
brand is I will have an auto email, not
just like behind the brand, be like,
"Hey, here's all our top performing
videos. Here's our bestselling products
and why. Here's frequently asked
questions about styling or sizing or how
it works kind of thrown in there with
some content." And to the point of the
bullet emails we looked at earlier,
don't be afraid to like really go in
depth about what makes your brand
special inside of email. So, I'm doing
all this inside of Omnisend. Omnisend is
a great choice for brands who want to
send email. It links direct to your
Shopify. You can actually segment and
send emails and tag and stuff based on
what products people purchase. It'll do
your cart abandonment workflow and you
can add more emails and triggers to
that. You can do back in stock
notifications and they do all this at a
greater value. So, it has a cheaper cost
overall for the amount of emails in your
system than a lot of the popular
alternative email marketing softwares.
You can learn more about them in the
link to Omnisend in my description. That
is an affiliate link. So, if you do join
or use them, then that helps me as well.
hopefully learned a little bit about
email automation and how it is not an
intimidating thing to set up and just
adds so much more value over time as you
get subscribers to have them
automatically being onboarded to your
brand. Let's go. What's most interesting
to me is this is based on a house, but
they just took it, right? Whether the
allegations of the lawsuit are real or
not, they took an identity of something
or created and fabricated an identity
and made it their own. And we live in
this worldbuilding time where you can do
that. If you have the creative vision,
you can actually come up with your own
complete history of something. It's a
fascinating exercise. and go fully into
it. If you are a creative, I have seen
no idea why you wouldn't want to do
something like that and build something
wholly interesting and immersive to that
level with all the tools we have
available today to be creative. Like
that is a differentiator of kind of true
luxury. I don't talk about some of those
other videos is the ability to create
something so magnificent that people are
drawn to it, which is something they've
done here. I feel like that's something
every creative should be able to aspire
to. And related, I want to talk about a
chef. I think he's a French chef called
Yanver. He has a store in Miami, but
they've done like a light version of
this where they have iconography. They
have this fox, this kind of very like a
playful, whimsical, very French-based
identity, a former identity. And they've
played it out extensively over their
packaging and the different things that
they have for their brand in terms of
how they display everything, how
intricate everything is, how everything
feels like a long time historical
bakery, even though it is kind of a new
look from a French chef. A lot of this
is in positioning, is in packaging, is
in embracing that maximalist ideal. And
if you uphold the standard, both of your
product and of the cost that you sell it
at and the premium there and the
aesthetics that come with it, you over
time can begin to establish yourself as
to a feeling of a luxury. And the
experience really adds a lot to that.
The ability to go somewhere in person
and experience it adds this degree that
really works so well in the modern era
where we all make content where people
are looking for those like little relief
and treats. It's why you see everything
from Louis Vuitton cafes to Margella
pop-ups. Why these luxury brands are
leaning into this. They're almost going
downstream and saying, "Hey, cool. You
can go buy a cheaper thing from us at
our Prada Flower pop-up." But if you are
a new brand, you can go upstream into
that same thing. That's a much cheaper
and easier than opening massive stores.
And one interesting tool, if you're a
creative kind of diving a little bit
more into this world, is this tool,
Public Works. It's by the same team
behind Cosmos where they've actually
taken all this imagery that you can get
from public domain and they've scanned
all these like intricate libraries and
they've put all this image where public
domain basically means is past the
trademark limitations where you can
actually use it royalty-free and it's
all like old school stuff of different
ways. They have a searchable incredible
database of things which I think can get
people going down this rabbit hole of
what these visual ideas look like. As
you see I can kind of scroll around this
page here. there is no limitation to how
indepth that goes. And so I do feel like
we have all of these tools here for
people to create these much more
intricate brands and experiences. And I
feel like that's where it's going. If
even if your brand's been around for
four or five years, it needs to feel and
look and have the intricacy of if it's
been around for decades. That's the new
differentiator for aesthetic versus like
a sleek presentation. It's an
interesting concept to think about if
you care about luxury and its
positioning. And if you think it's
vapid, so is any amount of buying luxury
in the first place. This is more I
actually really like and I'm into this
because you are creating a world, you
are creating lore, you're creating
history, you're letting artistic
expression go extremely far versus
refining it into the particularities of
like something modern, which I think is
an interesting exercise and involves
more interaction with artisans. It
involves more interaction with history.
It makes it more interesting by default,
at least to me. We've seen this play out
in any number of ways in terms of how
brands are positioned over time. And one
I always love to call out in a similar
aesthetic is Marvis toothpaste where
they position themselves as a more
expensive higher quality but far more
interesting. Just look at the experience
of this website approach to toothpaste
with the same heritage maximalism look
that you see so much in kind of the
examples that I've given that when you
look at visual positioning how different
things compare to each other. This is
one I think every aesthetics driven
person should understand. You have your
kind of yassified product positioning.
You have your minimalist product
positioning, your millennial product
positioning, your counterculture, your
liquid deaths, your death wish, your
extreme positioning, and then you also
have now this kind of heritage maximal
position. Any product or any shelf the
products are sold on, there could be an
angle to take this with it. And it's
funny to see this even go over into
technology where this is a little bit
more of a kind of art deco grecian
approach, but A16Z's recent rebrand
where they have gone allin on golden
coins and maximalism of a different kind
is I think you will see that same ornate
branding come to a very traditionally
modernist tech as well. Anyway, I know
this is a little bit different of an
approach to how I do these like kind of
more tactical luxury videos. I feel like
this aesthetic is really important to
talk about. It's one that's going to
dominate for a while to come. It's an
interesting playground to work within
and something that everyone who's
building a perspective of the luxury
world and the aesthetic world should
understand. So, I appreciate y'all
watching and more videos I have here
about luxury if you want to get more
into the tactics of that. Thank you all
so much.
[Music]