So, this is a day in the life art
directing shoots in
Wangjo. This is how we go to a Chinese
hospital. You know what I'm saying?
Today, we're continuing my art direction
series with how to build and manage a
photo shoot. This is actually my
favorite one that we've done so far cuz
we're going to go behind the scenes on a
real photo shoot that I am doing in
Wangjo, China, both for my brand and for
a client project. We're going to walk
through all the variables you need on
your checklist to make a good photo
shoot. The order to go in to actually
effectively put it together. We're going
to talk through concepts, props,
lighting, how to actually mood board and
set up structure to do it effectively,
and then what kind of team you have in
place to make it work. And all the
while, we'll show you some examples,
actually walk through it. I think you're
going to find a ton of value in this
video. This is Ora meets World Live in
China edition. Let's lock in.
[Music]
It should be illegal for this to be
this type.
So, in this first section, I'm going to
talk about variables. Whenever you plan
a photo shoot, I actually don't start
with like some highbrow concept and then
figure out how to execute it. When
you're doing things on a smaller budget,
especially, it's better to kind of start
with what is the actual options that we
have, what is the toolkit that we can
put together, and then make something
from there. I'm going to talk about this
all from that perspective. So to me,
variables include location, the models
and talent that you can have, and then
the people you're shooting with and
their capabilities. When you get a good
idea of what's happening there, that can
inform the level of concepts that you
can execute. So, first I'm going to talk
about location. This is probably the
most important. And if you're doing
studio shoots, you're doing kind of more
photo shoots of with all different kinds
of variety or certain types of art
direction. You could do a lot within a
studio. If you're doing an on
locationation shoot, it really comes
down to what you can get. And so, here
in China, we got this location called
The Raw. And this is an ideal location
to do photo shoots because it's not one
environment. It's actually six
environments. They have this whole
tennis court. They have an outside area.
They have these red canyons. They have
this like majestic house. There's an
interior. This is like black lava look.
This means when we go here, we can
actually pull off a couple looks and
ideas and concepts in one place. And
that's something I always look for,
especially with a smaller brand, is how
do you get that bang for your buck where
you're not just going to get one look or
one thing. But once you've established
your location, then the next thing
usually comes into models or if you're
not shooting with people, kind of visual
merchandising. What do you have inside
the shoot here? Especially if you're
traveling abroad, it's usually hard to
find people and connect with people.
You're going to go through agencies. And
most of the models you want to get are
either going to be influencers or
they're going to go through agencies.
I'm going to link to some software below
inside the description of this video
that actually is helpful in finding
models or some services that do that.
But we went through some modeling
agencies and some friends here in China
to find two models with a really
specific look. And usually what we're
going through that something I want to
remind everyone when they're looking at
this is you have a look and idea you're
going for but you're not always going to
have the things available right like in
my ideal world for this shoot I'd have
like some people with some like facial
scars or like eyeball Russian prison
tattoos but that's not available from
the Chinese modeling agencies. And so
instead we're kind of working with what
we have. But we basically decided to go
with this more like Fast and Furious
look based on the two people we really
like that we could find from the
options. And this is why I like to think
of this as variables because you may
have some perfect vision but if you
can't put it together, you only have so
much budget. It's about kind of building
a concept on what you have and then it
comes down to shooters and capabilities.
If you ask one person to shoot all the
video and all the photo and the behind
the scenes, it's probably not going to
happen. And then if you understand the
styles and the capabilities of the
people that you have, you can work
through it really well. So on this shoot
that we're doing here, we had two
people. We had Eric who was concentrated
on handling photo and then we had Brody
who's concentrated on handling video.
These are guys I work with relatively
frequently so we understand each other.
They're social savvy. They work for the
agency DMG that I'm signed to as an
influencer. So, I know they know social
content and I have a trust level on the
social side of it. I'm going to get the
video clips because I know they know
what they're doing and they shoot that
kind of stuff. Whereas, if you get more
like a medium formatted traditional
photographer, you're trying to get them
to shoot for social, they're going to
need a lot of help. On the shoots that I
do now, no matter what, as a client
project and my projects, wherever the
industry is, we're always going for
both. We're going for lookbooks and
especially because carousel ads do so
well on Meta right now. Great photo,
marquee photo. We're always building out
landing pages, trying to do things with
like really like leading photo, putting
those into carousels, but social video
is still the most important part. So, it
comes down to how do we capture the most
of that content. We'll get to that in
organization a little bit later in the
video. So, once you have your variables,
who's going to shoot it, what the
location looks like, who are the people
that can be in the shoot, then we can
get into concepts. So, based on this
look that we had, some of these
futuristic environments, uh, I was
trying to do two shoots here. One was
for a client project that's a little
more formal. They're like an e-commerce
software company. And so, we had a
concept there we wanted to execute.
We're doing like a resort hotel
collection. So, we want to do this out
of office concept. I saw that tennis
court in the location. I saw the beach
in the location. And I thought the idea
we could roll with was, hey, there's
professionals on vacation. They're
trying to get away with not having to
work or they're trying to act like
they're working, but they're actually on
vacation. They're doing both at the same
time. So, we got a bunch of props
related to that concept. This whole idea
is kind of like you're out of office,
but you're not really out of office.
Like, she's on vacation. She's called
vacation gear. They were just doing
tennis over there. They're laying out in
the beach over here, but you're never
really offline. We said, "Hey, we have a
tennis court. Let's get tennis rackets.
Let's get tennis balls. Let's get beach
chairs and then let's have them
working." So, not only did we get your
kind of typical lounging model resort
shots, we also got all these conceptual
shots where the guy's trying to play
tennis, he's holding his computer up or
someone's, you know, trying to be at the
beach, but they're like arguing on their
phone. It adds this dimension and this
concept to the shoot that is fun and
ties into the company and is largely
based on the models, the props, and the
location that we had. And at the same
time, we were shooting a bunch for My
Brand on some of the other locations.
And I saw those kind of more futuristic
environments. I saw the areas. I was
like, "Hey, it actually be really sick
if we went a little Fast and Furious,
kind of had this east meets west of like
the look and feel of my brand with
what's going on there. And we wanted to
get some dirt bikes in it. We had a last
minute twist. This happens on shoots all
the time where the people we wanted to
get the dirt bikes from canceled in the
in the same morning. Had some prop
failure earlier today. supposed to have
a dirt bike, but luckily we reached out
to the Chinese community and we were
able to receive the low rider the
support of our low rider brethren of
Asia. We got these in house and with
that we got some other props as well. We
got some like auto tools we can use for
some skits. But having those concepts
and having all the props to help support
those concepts, what we call visual
merchandising is how you put together
the core of a shoot like this. And then
the last piece is lighting. This is how
we get into where mood boards really
play into and then the structure of the
shoot, which is the second part of this
video. So, we put together a Cosmos
board full of lighting examples, brought
that over into Millanote to the main
board once we agreed on some things. We
wanted this like big dramatic lighting.
The location actually offered some
lighting support and had some lights for
us that we could rent. They also had the
ability to get us a grip who assisted
with the shoot, and I'll go through the
full team a little bit later. We want
casual lighting on the first shoot,
dramatic on the second. Means we're
going to need external lights. So, the
photographer could go in like knowing
what the actual look and feel of the
shoot is. This is something I see happen
a lot is you'll have a vision for it.
you don't actually show any lighting
examples and it will look really
different than what people who will go
into a shoot actually think they're
going to get. And so I always think it's
super crucial, my biggest pro tip is to
have a lighting board literally no
matter what you're doing from product
shots to any level of photo shoot so you
can understand, you know, how that
changes what you're looking at. We'll
show I'll do a whole section on
Millanote in here and we will actually
show in those boards what our lighting
references were for this shoot and some
of the results. So, I'm going to
actually walk through the board that we
use to organize the shoot so you can see
a bit of the background of what that
flow likes before we actually get on
location. So, this is in a Millanote
board. Shout out to Millanote for
sponsoring this video. This is the
software I use to help me stay
creatively organized. And so, here on
the board, we can take a look and see
how we actually structure it. So, first
I'm using the note style of Millanote.
Put these titles on here for the
location. You can actually embed videos
here from social. So, we actually have
an embed of the Instagram video that
walks through the location. Uh, I'm
using the comment tool. I actually have
some notes on my comments about the
location cuz there's six different looks
inside this actual location spot. They
have like six environments. So, I'm
noting which ones go with which outfits.
We also have a test shot of a light that
we dropped in here so people can see
what the light looks like naturally
since outdoors. Uh, and over here I'm
using the columns feature in Milanote
for the actual styling. So, you'll see
down here we have the actual models, a
male and female model. Some references
there. And then we have outfits for each
of them, color codes for the outfits. So
the photographers can plan a bit around
lighting, etc. And they know the basic
idea of what we're trying to work with
cuz we're trying to match some of the
outfits to the environments and how we
style them together. So we're doing that
in these columns. I like the columns.
You can get like a nice organized look
at what you're putting together. There
are actually templates that have a lot
of this already built out if you want to
find things like these columns, etc.
already in use when you start a new
millode board. And over here I actually
have my mood board reference of all the
shots kind to get where we want both of
them on a bike or a vehicle. We want
some of these kind of pose ideas that we
can get because our props do include
like these low rider bikes, all that
there. So, the photographer has some
reference to shots we do. We're going to
use this to build the full shot list.
And same thing with lighting. We have
some really specific references to kind
of more dramatic lighting styles we'd
like to try to achieve so they know what
they do and the equipment they need to
use there. Uh, and then starting to
build out a bit of what the
post-processing board looks like as well
of like ideas we may want to use as we
take these all into carousel. So I like
Millano because I can look at all this
in one place. We organize it into
columns when needed. We can drop it in
like a mood board. Actually leave
comments and notes on all of these. Do
things like pull colors. We have that
reference there. And then link boards in
between it. You know, for instance, this
board is actually a subboard inside my
master kind of valuable planning board I
have for the brand. So I can easily go
back, look at and pull other references
and just have everything I'm working on
for the brand kind of in one easy place
with everything from colors to comments
and a team that can work together to
access. Anyway, that's what we use to
actually plan the shoot and take the
visual inspiration, put it in one place
we can all look at and then turn that to
a shot. So thank you to Milanote for
sponsoring this video. You can give them
a try at the link down below in the
description. It is free to try with no
time restrictions. So, if you do want to
give it a shot, highly recommend. All
right. So, now we're going to talk about
building a shot list and a plan for the
shoot and we're talk about the team to
execute the shoot and we'll have gone
through a full range of this video. So,
the first thing that I build shot list
around, I build shot lists around
scenarios. Shout out my guy. I mean,
they'll deliver anything in China. 30
minutes. Yeah, I mean, you matcha Molly
T. They need a Home Depot for China,
though. I need to be able to pick up
guys to fix things. Anyway, so I
actually built my shot list around
scenarios. So, I want to have a scenario
of like a guy and a girl on a bike or a
guy and a girl in an argument. That's a
scenario to me. people lounging, people
playing tennis. So, I will build a
scenarios list as you can kind of see on
the millote board and then build a shot
list within all that saying, hey, when
we actually are on the tennis court, I
want to have a shot uh with a reference
of someone with a tennis racket over the
shoulder holding one of the items from
the photo shoot. And basically, if you
have a list of all the items you want to
shoot and you have a list of all your
scenarios, you can begin to mix and
match. So, that second part after all
the scenarios is what are the actual
looks? What are they wearing completely
within it? Because styling is often
overlooked. Even on this shoe, we
communicated the styling we wanted, but
since everyone was speaking Chinese,
they didn't actually arrive with a bunch
of the items. So, I had to adopt some of
the things we wanted to shoot because
one model only had a black shirt versus
a white shirt, and we picked up one that
wasn't the right size and someone didn't
have socks, so we had to adapt. They
couldn't wear the sneaker. Their shoe
sizing was actually different than the
US shoe sizing. These are all things you
deal with, but styling is important. Not
just the items you want to shoot,
whether that's your own product or
whether it's clothing, but also all the
things that go around it that you need
to have to complete it. I like to have a
nice big list of this, big list of the
scenarios. In each scenario, write down,
you know, this shirt, this top, this
pants, this bottom, this prop, this
thing in the background for this look,
how does that change going into the next
one? So, you actually cycle through all
your product and literally check it off
on that list to say, "Yeah, I made sure
we're actually shooting this shirt in
this one, or we're shooting this product
in this one." And so, that merchandising
idea of what is in the shoot, what's all
working around this is super important.
And that checklist is another just great
pro tip I feel like everyone should do
when they're art directing. Then,
there's a BTS plan. My standard BTS plan
I like to do on every shoot is I want to
plan to get one kind of vlog where
someone like me is talking through it.
Basically have enough footage to do a
voice over of the shoot and what
happened. Get enough photos and things
are happening to do a carousel. One of
my favorite carousel formats is this
format actually breaks down. It'll be
like the guests, the people, the hosts.
I feel like you can do that for events.
You can do that for photo shoots and
really allows you to break down
different elements. So we tried to
capture all the stuff where we could get
that. And then last one to two either
funny pieces or concept to reality
pieces where you kind of have some crazy
thing happening and then you show the
results. And so for one of these we're
working on, we actually had this guy
using a torque wrench on a bike which
you would never do so I could do this
kind of like what is bro doing like why
is bro doing that and it's like to get
the shot and then show a bunch of the
shots something like that. Ideas we had
to have it in the background. So I found
that everyone will shoot BTS. If you
don't have a plan for BTS then you
actually don't do anything with it. I'll
walk into all these companies that I
consult with who be like, "We shot BTS
in this last shoot. We do this." Well,
that doesn't actually matter. You can
have as many hard drives as you want. If
your idea was, I'm going to actually
have this type of video, so I need this
shot and that shot. That's when BTS
becomes useful. Plan your BTS. How you
plan your actual shoots, cuz especially
now on social media, that BTS might rip
harder than your actual lookbook. Now,
we're going to talk about the team we
used to put this all together. It's kind
of a typical shoot team for a smaller
shoot. These obviously go way bigger.
And then we will wrap it up. So, first
uh on this shoot, we had one
photographer, one videographer. We had a
grip that came from the photo shoot
place, which basically just the guy
holding the lights, which is more
crucial than you might think, actually
makes the shoot go really well when
they're there and can dial things in.
So, that was three. Then we had an art
director, producer, my friend Ya, who
you've seen a bunch of these videos,
noted cut 30 graduate, he was there
actually being the one helping, oh, we
need to get bikes, we need to talk to
these models. He's from Wangjo, has a
lot of the relationships, was helping
produce the entire event. And then
myself as like the career director and
the lead, someone to be like, we're
moving this environment. We're getting
this outfit. You know, sometimes people
won't wear all those hats. You'll have
separate people for all this, but since
I was there, I was trying to both shoot
content, make sure everyone had the
fits, make sure everything's getting
done, moving thing to thing, and just
being kind of like the lead on that,
ensuring we're getting what we need. So,
I was a fivep person team for a shoot
like this, plus we had two models that
came into it. And what's nice is doing
this in China was actually relatively
affordable. So, that location for 4
hours was about $500. Renting those
bikes was about 100 other props. We got
another like 10020, 200. And the models
were pretty close to LA normal pricing.
I think it was 1,000 R&B which is like
130 40 bucks an hour for them. So that
was kind of the most expensive part of
this and that's pretty relatively normal
to what we paying in LA or similar but
you can get get to see like the more
conceptual you get the better the
location the more the props those
budgets can kind of go up and obviously
the cost of your photographers
videographers fluctuate but you can
start to see the core of like what a
shoot cost to produce but on the plus
side of that we shot in multiple
environments for multiple projects video
and stills with all these concepts and
got an absolute ton of deliverables. And
so the last thing I'm mention here is
that for all this, you need to prepare
to be ad hoc. Things are going to happen
on the fly. People are going to cancel
the drop off. This model's not going to
have shoes. This person's going to have
a club foot. Whatever it is, and you
need to work through it, and you can't
be married to those lists. I walk on
these shoots where people are rolling
through the content list. They see it.
They know it's not good or something's
wrong. They just want to finish the
list. You've got to roll with the
punches. If someone has a funny idea,
you've got to go with it. And the other
note is someone has to be in charge.
This person calls the shots. When
there's a decision, you have to
designate the person who at the end of
the day who makes that final decision
cuz you start going by committee in the
middle of these shoots. That's how
things get mid. And so someone with a
vision needs to be the person that locks
it down. Anyway, I know it's a bit of a
different video than my normal art
direction videos where we're kind of
showing a bunch of examples, but I want
to show you some real life stuff, show
you what I'm actually working on, what
it looks like to be in the mix of this
and just get you hands-on. Hope you
enjoy this thing. Comment, let me know
if you do. I will link one of my other
art direction videos here so you can
dive in more into that world overall.
And thank you all so much for watching
and to Milanote for sponsoring this
video. You can check them out in the
description.