In this video, I'm going to explain
every type of marketing. This video is
for you if you are an entrepreneur or a
brand owner and just want to understand
the full scope of your toolkit or if you
work in marketing, you want to be a
director of marketing, a VP of marketing
and know how this all works. So, from
positioning to funnels to email to SEO,
I'm going to go through what each of
these is, the role it plays in the brand
ecosystem, and chat about it. By the end
of this video, you're going to have a
complete idea of the whole marketing
toolkit and how it all works together.
I'm stoked to talk through it with you.
Let's lock it in. So, for some
background, prior to becoming a
full-time creator, I was the SVP of
marketing at a brand called Gelb
Blaster. Before that, I was the head of
product and marketing at a CPG company
here in California that had several
brands. I was the VP of marketing at a
consumer electronics company called 3DR
and ran sales and marketing prior to
that, an outdoors company. So, I've been
through the ringer of marketing of all
times, from supporting retail to things
that are purely online to big brands
that are doing everything. And as part
of that, I've had to learn a bit of each
of these and think about what works and
what doesn't in different types of
businesses. And there isn't a lot of
education around this kind of modern
marketing. So, if you do want to learn
about it, just going to walk through
each piece and what it is, some
examples, and see what we can build. And
I'm going to start with the most
important one, the most important thing
that I feel like every business needs to
consider and every marketer needs to
have a grasp on and that is positioning.
So what is positioning? Positioning is
how you take your product to market and
how you compare it or put it in the
market compared to your competitors.
There are a couple different types of
positioning. So for instance, when you
walk into a Best Buy, you will see
shelves that have three types of
products. Best Buy merchandises their
products with a good, better, best
strategy. So, they will have a best,
like a best-in-class item. Say if you
were in action cameras, it might be a
GoPro. And that's going to be expensive.
That's going to be sold on brand or on
really high-end stuff. And you're going
to have a better, the core category
where they make the majority of the
sales, like your average product. And
you're going to have a good, which is a
product that positions itself basically
purely on price that isn't as good as
everything else. So in headphones, you
might have a Bose or a Beats at the top,
more in the middle company, and then
something on the cheaper end, say a
Skull Candy or someone like that who
tries to present a premium experience,
but does it at a lower price point. But
positioning is more than price. It's
about who is your product appealing to
and how and how does it differentiate
from the market. And it's a moving
target because your positioning depends
on the other offerings that are
happening around it. So if you sell
computers, then other people are selling
computers with similar specs. Are you
positioning it as a gaming PC or as a
thing for work? It's about thinking
through what the angles are for your
product. And I like to look at an
exercise I think every brand owner and
marketer should be able to do for the
project they work on as a comparison
between yourself and any other products.
So if you are in an elevator an elevator
pitch scenario and you say oh I work in
the headphones industry or I have a
fashion brand etc. and someone says oh
like this brand and they call out one of
the big brands in the space. You need to
be able to respond and say oh we
actually do this. Here's our difference.
Here's how we compare. here's you would
why you would buy our product and that
is going to be your kind of positioning
statement and that quick synopsis is
going to be kind of a big driving force
in your product and so a few things I
want to call out as tactics for this
that are worth considering so obviously
there is price you can always look at a
market that has some success and say
we're going to do something cheaper as
an easy positioning strategy on the far
end a much harder positioning strategies
you can always charge more by having a
lifestyle product something that people
aspire to and want that has that brand
technique but that is going to be
something that has a lot of intangibles
that are hard to describe within
companies and hard to achieve with
marketing. There's also a few other
techniques. One of my favorites is
called position against. This is when
you take a big item or a popular item
and you pick something bad about it and
you say we are not this. Our main
characteristic is that we are not the
enemy here. I like to think about the
whole prebiotic soda category, the
lollipops and poppies. Their main
position is we are not Coke. We are not
bad for you. We are the same thing just
not evil. And there are a lot of
companies that present that in a certain
way. Similar to this, but not exactly
the same, is what I'll call
counterculture positioning. Liquid death
is a perfect example of this. Deathwish
coffee and black rifle coffee are a
perfect example of this where you say
the mainstream of culture consumers
inside a category, whatever it is, do a
thing. They have a certain lifestyle.
They have certain things they like.
We're going to be the exact opposite of
this. And usually you will see it is
synonymous with a more gothic look, a
more extreme look. And there's room for
kind of an extreme vertical in basically
every category saying we're going to
take all the things around the branding,
even around the product, and max it out.
I like to bring up DeathWish coffee a
lot because basically they said we're
going to have more caffeine than any
other coffee. We're going to put a skull
and crossbones on the logo. It's not
going to be some fun picture of a
Colombian farm or this these beans were
grown. It is going to be like a skull
and crossbones. That is a good example
of like a counterculture positioning.
But enough about how you actually put
your brand out there in the universe.
Let's talk about some of the other
factors. So, the next thing I want to
talk about is what's called a funnel.
You may have heard this term before, but
really what a funnel is is your web
presence, your online web presence,
combining websites and where people land
and engage with your product and email.
And I will hit those one at a time.
Email being a separate section. So, in
your marketing, you need to consider the
web experience you have. And why it's
considered a funnel is because people
drop off along it. You start at the top.
All this traffic comes in. They see you
on social media. They watch your videos.
they see your ads, whatever it is, that
is your top of funnel. And then people
get to your website, your funnel is cut
down a little bit more. And then from
there, you get people that explore more.
They go to the product page, funnel gets
cut down more, add to your cart, finally
check out, customer. You have basically
seen your funnel shrink until it gets to
the very end. And what good marketers do
is they analyze every part of this
funnel in two ways. The first is what
are they doing from a marketing
perspective at each level? What do you
do to generate brand awareness with big
campaigns or influencers or ads? What do
you do once you actually get that
customer? That's what we're going to
zone in on here. When a customer comes
to your website, what is their
experience? How do you basically lose as
few of those people as possible or get
as many people to actually purchase with
the highest value by the end of their
website experience? This is a really
important one for every marketing team
to think through because if you are
getting any level of traffic, that
traffic is precious. You are paying
money in some regard to get those people
to your website. And if you get them
naturally because your brand has a big
name or good SEO, we'll get to SEO
later. That is a huge value that you are
getting that you need to make the most
of. So there's a lot about optimizing
your funnel about taking all the pages
people land on in your website and
ensuring there's the right message for
them, the right imagery, you have the
right call to actions that you're
retaining them. One of the most common
funnel things I end up working on when I
talk to businesses is you'll see they're
pushing all this traffic to their
websites, but they don't actually ask
anyone for their phone number or their
email on the site. It's all about the
purchase. And one thing that most
marketers will learn the hard way is
that soft call to actions help enable
strong call to actions. So actually
asking people for their email, getting
people to sign up, getting them to take
step one gets you closer to step two and
get you retain more people through your
funnel over time versus just saying your
only option is to buy. And so I always
encourage people to basically have those
opt-in areas. Now, when we really talk
about optimizing the funnel, what do you
do to encourage people to buy, right? Or
encourage people to engage in that
secondary call to action. So in that
example I had of, hey, we want people to
give you your email. I'm putting a
section on every page, get your email or
your phone number. If I just put it out
there saying sign up for our news, that
gets me some interest. If you say sign
up and you're actually going to get
this, you know, seven video bundle to
show you exactly like how to optimize
your fitness journey or whatever it is.
Give them free content, give them like
some value discount code, whatever it
is, you're going to get a higher rate.
And so your optimization as a marketer
is going through all those decisions and
being like, how do I improve it? Same
thing with purchases. This is where it
comes down to things like issues your
customers have that prevent you to buy.
How do I put them on page on your
website? For instance, if people don't
know how your clothes fit, they don't
want to buy a $100 hoodie without
knowing how it fits. Showing that on the
web page and having pictures of a couple
different body types so people can see
it. That's an example of optimizing your
funnel for any type of brand. After we
get to the funnel, we get to the second
end. This is email marketing. This is
one of my favorites because many
businesses don't do it well. It's an
easy thing marketers can add to your
toolkit, and I've done whole videos
about this as well. But there are a
couple types of email worth considering.
So the first is just the campaigns that
you send for email. So you have an email
list to email out to them regularly. So
a couple things I encourage when you're
doing this is not always be selling when
you do this. You can share your best
content. You can share ideas and
journeys. You can have your
communication not always be so
salesfocused and then it will encourage
people to be more likely to open it if
they get some value. Second thing is to
assign a personality to this. If your
emails come from a person, a CEO or a
representative, it begins to get over
time a little bit more of a some actual
connection to the brand and to people.
There's your email campaigns and your
email automation. This is emails that
send automatically when someone makes a
purchase. When someone leaves something
in their cart, when someone signs up on
your website, they get a welcome
sequence or purchase a certain product,
it encourages you to cross-ell to
another. And you're able to at all these
platforms, Omnisend, Mailchimp, Clavio,
schedule those emails to happen
automatically. And those journeys matter
a lot because the more and more traffic
you get, the more that happens
automatically with information sharing,
the more sales happen automatically. And
the better that journey is, much like
your funnel, and the better the content
is and the more of the questions that
are answered by you as a marketer inside
their journey, the better it goes. And
so a core thing to think about,
especially for new brand owners, because
a lot of them kind of ignore email to
start, is how am I optimizing my
campaigns? And then what am I doing for
my retention and my automation over
time? And you'll see the through line
I'll talk about throughout this that is
what can you answer for the customer
journey? What can you answer for your
customer inside your website or your
email or your positioning or what you do
in retail? Like what are those questions
that prevent them from buying? How does
this hoodie fit? Is this thing made of
100% cotton? Oh, can I take this if I
have a heart condition? Whatever those
questions are, how can you put those in
your landing pages, in your emails, in
your content to help make that journey
easier? Now, we're going to talk about
retention. So, sometimes retention falls
under email, but it's a whole
conversation. Retention is when someone
is a customer, they become they buy from
you. How do you keep them? How do you
get them to buy again and raise your
average order value? And this is a huge
thing because a lot of brands will have
a starter product. So, for instance,
even in my brand, I sell a lot of shoe
bags. Shoe bags is my entry-level
product. The majority of people start
with a $40 to $70 purchase of one to two
shoe bags. Once I have them in there, my
goal is to get them to purchase other
things from my brand. There's a
retention program designed to get them
educated on the other things I offer and
get them to participate in higher ticket
products and get to like the brand over
time. This is the case for the majority
of products. Even if you buy a car, if
you buy a Toyota, Toyota's job is to get
you to buy more Toyotas over time and
not switch to Honda or upgrade
eventually to like a Mercedes. There's a
lot of tactics and things around this,
but it's a key principle that's one of
the most ignored in marketing, right?
Everyone focuses on that first sale on
performance marketing or your emails,
but then they don't really think about
the customers once you have them. And
that's where we're going to talk about
CX or customer support and the role in
there. So, most people don't put
customer support under marketing, but I
100% do. Their customer experience you
get in support of what happens when they
have a problem or how you engage with
people is a big part of the word of
mouth they spread to their friends and
whether they're likely to return to your
brand even if you had a bad experience.
I feel like marketing and customer
service should be handinand. Customer
service should be letting marketing know
exactly what questions they're dealing
with so we can try and solve that
upfront with content and messaging. They
should be letting them know what
advocates and positive things they have
you can begin to put as testimonials.
And marketing should be looking to
customer support and to customer
connections for new people to make
content and for ideas to put inside all
the things that they are producing from
a content perspective. And one thing I
want to call out here is as many of you
know I worked for a while with a women's
wear brand I still work with. And one
thing that was big for us is when we
started googling customers, right? It's
part of the retention strategy. When we
would just look at everyone that comes
through, we're just going to look up who
you are. And we began to notice some
patterns inside our customer that helped
engage with retention. A lot of people
were buying and using our clothes to
attend festivals and you could go online
and see them wearing the clothes and
tacking them in festivals and we
realized we should incentivize that
build collections around that and also
we realized that a lot of our customers
were influencers like way more than we
thought and so then there's a whole
program around that and how do you seed
them maybe we send people stuff and this
idea of retention can sometimes be very
manual as well. So now let's pivot to
some more technical elements of
marketing. All right today I'm going to
walk a bit through workflows of using
art list to help with creative scale. So
first what is creative scale? So there's
now this desire by brands content
creators to make more content in
particular content for different
languages, different regions, different
social media accounts and then lots of
variance for ads. If you're doing any
work inside meta ads in particular this
year, you know that there is just a
burning desire for more creative at all
times. So in art list, which is a
platform I use for music, footage, and
SFX for my content, my brand content,
they have a couple key tools for this I
want to talk through. So, first there is
an extension where you can basically use
artlist within Premiere Pro. So, if your
team is using LUTs to achieve a specific
look and you want everyone to have the
same thing, you're able to pull those
all up in app. I want to talk about this
voiceover tool cuz this is useful for
brands that are trying to go and
actually have varants appeal to
different people. So, for instance, if
you filmed a POV video, you can test a
male voiceover versus a female
voiceover. You're going to run an ad in
Australia or in England, then you can
actually go set the tone of the ad
you're running and generate a variant
from it. It allows you to get content
that's going to move across, especially
regions, but also just testing for
creative ads pretty well. You can
control the speed of the voice over, the
inflection of the voiceover, and what
you create will automatically be
available inside of your workflow like
Premiere Pro. And the last thing I'll
hit there is these artboards that they
have. So basically, if you're kind if
your team is trying to work from one
place and organize your music, organize
your SFX, use the same things in
different videos, organize lots, you can
create an artboard here where you all
have a shared workflow. And what's nice
is also give you tailored content
suggestions. And so basically I'm
working on a project for a restaurant.
It's going to then give me sound
effects, footage, etc. that's relevant
to that kind of generated by them to
kick it off. And I can add any of that
to the artboard. And you can see
immediately there's like ambiance
footage for restaurants, cutting and
sizzling sounds. Like they actually have
useful content that I can just add to
the artboard right away. Anyway, thank
you so much for ArtLos for sponsoring
this video. Is an excellent tool. Both
of you are a creator or if you are a
brand looking to work on creative scale.
You can learn more at the link in my
description. We're going to talk about
SEO or search engine optimization. I'll
shout out some software that will help
you for this. So, search engine
optimization is are the pages on your
website getting traffic organically from
people searching on Google or god forbid
Bing and finding your website. And so,
this is a major component of a lot of
brands and is a complicated place right
now. As more and more people use things
like Perplexity or use AI to search for
their questions, the the pool of the
results that you get from Google is kind
of shrinking. But, it's certainly not
dead and it's certainly still an
important part of marketing. And so what
I would encourage people to do if you
want to learn this toolkit because it's
complicated is there is software.
There's HFS ah REF and SEM Rush. Those
are two websites and software that will
basically analyze your website and tell
you what keywords you're already ranking
for and where. When it comes to
importance of this, being on top is
really what matters. First couple
results for a term. If someone's
searching leather belts, you don't want
to show up on p number 12. You're either
basically number one to three or it
doesn't really matter. You also want to
consider things like your brand name. I
know plenty of brands that have a very
similar brand name with someone else in
a big category. Look at road clothing
and road skin and who that's SEO is
always a battle of someone clicking on
the wrong website and then you're
running an ad to get your own brand name
and then you're that's a money suck you
have every day. So there's a lot to be
thought around like you're naming an SEO
as well. You'll begin to look at all
these opportunities and what you'll
begin seeing is there's usually two
opportunities for brands. One is on
singular terms. So for instance, if you
sell a certain type of sunglass, you
have a like, you know, Japanese acetate
sunglass, whatever that is, and people
look for that thing. people search for
it and you'll see volume on those tools
I mentioned before and you say, "Oh,
wow. There's actually not a lot of
competition for this because the other
thing you'll see in that software is a
is a difficulty ranking of how hard it
is to rank on the first page for that."
There'll be a number between zero and
100 and they have their proprietary
systems and it'll tell you if it's good
or bad. And if as long as it's like
moderately easy, you'll say, "Oh, this
is a opportunity for me to own that
search." So then what do you do from
there? So you're you mean to make good
content about it. So you' make a
dedicated page or a collection page of
all the products you have that are
Japanese acetate sunglasses. You put a
write up about Japanese acetate
sunglasses on that page. Why your brand
does it, what makes it special. Doesn't
hurt to embed a video about that on
there as well. And have your collection.
Now you have a page where you are
focused on making it SEO optimized. You
are putting your description in the
header of the page. You're going to put
that term in it. You're going to give it
some value to people that do it. And
then you're going to get traffic to it
and link to it. And this is important
because the way Google works for SEO is
it weights how people what people do
when they're on the page and if they
enjoy it and get a good experience from
it and stay on it, whether people click
the link when it shows up in search to
people and then also how much is
directed to it from the rest of the
internet. So the more websites and
social media etc that actually links to
that page and references it the better
it does. There's a whole science both
black hat and white hat to how to do
that that I won't dive into in this
video but that becomes the the world,
right? make an optimized page for
whatever it is and then drive your links
and traffic to it so it begins to
generate inside of Google. And this is a
war of attrition. It's a war of time.
I'll give an anecdote on that in a
second before I move on from SEO. But it
can really make or break your business
if you actually pay attention to it over
the course of years because that traffic
eventually becomes just a big free
generator that kind of lasts forever. So
example there, my friend Matt was
launching a brand called Chlorophyll
Water. Many of you may have heard me
talk about this before. And I was
encouraging him. He had asked for help
when he did that to help kind of
optimize his website. I had the agency
at the time and to work on some of his
launch strategy and I was like, "Hey,
the word chlorophyll and the word
chlorophyll water are attainable. You
can actually get to the results like
number one or two on this in a couple
months. No one's competing in it. It's
pretty easy on Google, but it's going to
take months like where it might take us
four to six and he wants to launch right
now." And I'm like, "Just let us do this
SEO campaign. invest in some money
building these links, building these
pages, get you on there. So when you
have this launch, you take advantage of
all the traffic versus if you generate
all this attention at launch and you
don't show up when someone searches for
chlorophyll water, then you're not going
to win. And so this is exactly what
happened. We built up this SEO. We got
him to I think he was like number one on
chlorophyll water, number two on just
like chlorophyll. He did a massive
launch. He was a a master of seating
before seating was even a thing. He had
something like a billion impressions on
Tik Tok from celebrity and influencer
seating of his water and then was able
to generate all that demand, get all
those people to his website because he
had locked in SEO prior. And this is one
of those things why I encourage
marketers to learn things like this. So,
moving on, we are going to talk about
retail support. Eventually, your brand
is going to get into stores. And this is
a key one to think about because stores
are going to ask, "What's in it for me?
Why should I put your product in there
versus any other product?" And then once
you're actually in the stores, you're
going to have to perform. people are
going to need to buy it and you're going
to have to support that. It doesn't just
automatically happen. So what do we do
there? So the first is when you actually
go into retail bringing some data and
info and generating some support first.
So for instance in that previous
scenario where we talked about
chlorophyll water if he was able to say
hey look I own all this SEO traffic.
People don't really buy water online.
I'm getting all this traffic in Wyoming
and here's a big retailer in Wyoming.
Look at how much traffic we have. These
people don't have any place to buy. I'd
love for you to direct them to buy from
you. That is a compelling conversation
to have with a retailer. Same thing if
you have a big marketing program. So for
instance, when I was at Jel Blaster, we
had a ton of influencer marketing. And
so we' be able to say, "Hey, we actually
can dedicate some influencers to
specifically support your retail chain
where they're actually make content
about it." And you can begin to put a
specific campaign to attach to the
retailer. And then for other people,
it's going to be, hey, you actually need
a position on your shelf. Right now you
only have expensive items. We're going
to offer you a cheaper alternative your
customers want. You can you basically
get into retail based on positioning. So
there are all kind of things to think
about. But then once you're actually in
retail, what do you do? The first thing
is merchandising. So merchandising is
how your product is presented there. You
will notice things like products that
have little tearback boxes like protein
bars you can stick on a shelf that have
some branding on them. That's like
entry- level merchandising. You'll see
little tags are called aisle
interruptors. When you're walking down a
retail aisle that someone has placed
there that promote a product that call
out that you should go look at it. These
things work. Same thing with displays
you may have. You go into an Ulta or
Sephora and you look at how crazy the
display is for a different brand. they
are getting people to consider a brand
because retail psychology is basically
if someone actually takes the time to
look and consider and look at your
product you have a high chance that they
are going to buy it is about getting
that first look and if you get that
first look it is your job of your
product to lose that you have the
opportunity to lose it most of the time
you're going to be able to win it so you
need to be thinking about not only how
do you support traffic and interest at
the store level but then once they're in
the store how do you make sure you are
called out as an option and then you're
going to get to the last part which is
retail training some retails have
trained sales floors some don't if they
do like the outdoor stores industry, REI
and Dick Sporting Goods and stuff. Train
those people as much as they can. The
more training they have, the more
incentive those employees have, the
better they are going to be able to sell
your products. And a big part of what I
did when I worked as a marketer in
retail support was that training. Online
programs, inerson programs, field teams
to basically make sure every person who
was selling that product had it in their
hands, had experienced it, would
recommend it, and as much education on
all the key questions. Now, we're going
to get to the fun part, content,
influencers, and then we'll end on
events and partnerships, and you'll have
the complete picture of what modern
marketing looks like. So, content,
everything now is becoming content. What
do I mean by that? I mean that used to
think of content as just what you put on
your social media page. But all the ads
you run on meta, that's content. Ads you
run on your out of home or on TV, that's
content. The training that you're going
to end up doing for those retail
employees I mentioned is content. Events
and partnerships you do, even if someone
shows up to a physical thing, guess
what? They're making content. They're
making videos about it. just sending
pictures to their friends. Same thing
with your packaging experience. Almost
all roads lead to content. And so it is
a critical thing to be thinking through
from your business perspective. And so
this goes from actually testing your
videos to designed assets, etc. And so
what I'll say here, I have lots of other
videos around content as a whole, is
your job as a marketer to be as in-depth
on this as possible. The most useful
marketers understand social media
networks. They know to tag related
videos for shorts on YouTube for a
longer length. They know how to label a
tutorial as something that's searchable
when you actually put it on YouTube.
They understand that Tik Tok brand
accounts are not going to perform as
well as creator accounts. They should
probably have a multi-account strategy.
They're gonna know how to use trial
reel. It's your job as a marketing
leader not just to rely on your social
media person, but to have at least one
person, including you, in the trenches
knowing how this works and thinking like
a creator as to what should succeed.
Then shifting over into influencer
marketing, which is nice and tangential.
So there are two key types of influencer
marketing to understand. The first is
seeding and the second is paid
influencer marketing. So seeding is
sending out your product for free to
people to post. This is still a
fantastic technique in this year of our
lord 2025. I would be sending out as
much stuff as you can afford to
especially if you have a cheaper
product. And this involves building a
system to find influencers that are
useful or people that are up and coming.
Contact them friendly actually send them
things. check and monitor that someone
actually posted this or not and begin to
build a system where you graduate some
of those people into doing paid work and
where you kind of monitor what gets
posted or not and make sure your product
is getting out there in the world. That
is kind of initiative one. Initiative
two is finding people you can pay to
promote your product that generate sales
and interest that is worth their amount
of dollars. And the key thing I want to
iterate there is I really feel like
long-term partnerships, doing multiple
posts with influencers, building out
longer things versus one post for x
amount of dollars is the way to think
about a lot of this. Now, what you as a
marketer need to have is a way to track
this like a CRM system, a way to monitor
this, and a way to find people. And
identifying those three things is a
complicated step and a difference for a
lot of businesses between success and
not. And the more you outsource that to
agencies, which there are plenty of good
ones, the more it is costing you, right?
There's going to be an upcharge on all
that, the harder it is to justify the
value. And the closer you have it to the
chest, the more useful it is. And as a
marketer, there are so many marketers I
see hired now because they say, "Hey,
you know, I have a 2,000 person seating
list. I have the addresses for all of
them. I know all of them open the
packages and I can do that day one when
I come in your company. That is a hard
thing to turn down when you are hiring.
So worth considering. And you go
business to business, collection to
collection with that same one too. All
right. So last topics. We're going to
talk about events. We're going to talk
about partnerships. So a few different
types of events. There's consumerf
facing events where you basically have
your consumers come and experience
something. There's B2B events where you
are putting your product in front of
retailers and trying to sell to them.
And there's selling events. So let's
break it down. So selling events first.
I actually really encourage brands to do
selling events. So for instance for my
valuables brand I went to Complex Con.
Complex Con is a selling event. Kids
come to buy clothes there. I sold a lot
of clothes there. We came about break
even on attending that show. That is a
very big net positive to generate
awareness, generate enough money to
justify going there. But also you'll see
things like whether it's a farmers
market or a car show or whatever it is.
There are probably places where your
audience gets together that it'd be
great to build a repeatable format with
which you can generate money at because
selling in real life is still an amazing
thing if you have a good extroverted
person versus purely selling online.
Those are consumer shows like that. I
would highly consider what that looks
like. Then you have B2B shows are more
expensive. These are shows like the
Magic Convention in Fashion where you
can actually go there and have a booth
and retail buyers come. Same thing for a
lot of these shows like even like EPA in
Berlin, consumer electronics buyers come
there to buy for Europe. There's all
kinds of shows to have like buying,
selling. Now Expo West is a CPG show for
food and natural organic products that
buyers come to to find brands to carry
on their shelves. So a couple things
worth noting for that is to succeed at
shows like that, they cost more money
and you have to take it into your own
hands. You need to be scheduling
meetings with buyers, filling it up,
following up, and actively selling at
those shows. And for a lot of people,
it's a good way to get in front of
people, but you need to have your ducks
in a row. Understand your distribution,
understand where you can send product,
know how to get meetings with people, be
reaching out on LinkedIn, reaching out
on cold email, trying to get people by
your booth and attracting it. And have a
goal, whether it's for a consumer show
or a B2B show of it cost us this much
money, we need to write this much in
POS, or we need to get this much in
direct sales. Because a lot of times
people will begin to do these events,
they won't have that figured out and
they'll start to realize there is not
real brand ROI in doing this if you are
not trying to get to a number. And that
ties to the first thing I mentioned,
which is these more consumerf facing
events to basically appreciate customers
and do interesting things. And in the
social media era, if one of those takes
off and people make a lot of content,
it's kind of more value to these than
ever. But this is a slippery slope where
if you do do those kind of events, you
need to basically activate your
customer, make sure they have a great
experience, make sure it's social media
friendly, and use it to create your own
content. you're going to have a very
hard time justifying ROI. So last, we're
going to hit on partnerships,
influencers, and collaborations, and you
are going to have a complete picture of
kind of modern marketing. So in
partnerships, this is what you are doing
with others. Basically, 1 plus 1 equals
2.5 to push your brand out there. So a
couple things we can talk about there.
The first is collaborations, like we've
all seen, people coming together to
create a product. Second is licensing.
It's a partnership type where you
basically say, "Hey, I'm going to pay a
royalty on a product to be able to sell
a version of it." I'll talk about
licensing first. So, you may have seen
the brand Warren Lotus, popular fashion
brand. He licenses the NBA and the NFL,
makes versions of his clothing for every
single team. He pays a fee. He pays a
percentage, and you'll see they'll have
like little logos and things on on some
of them, and he's able to use this
really popular iconography to sell to an
existing fan base. This is a genius
marketing thing for him, but he's able
to take his his iconography he's
established, and sell a thing to a
passionate fan base who is more likely
to say, "Oh, I don't want to support
that. I want to support that and the
Celtics or and the Cowboys at the same
time." And this is something everyone
from Simple Modern to Represent, there's
all kinds of brands that do this. And
that is a paid partnership. A paid
partnership should 100% be on the table
for your brand when you have the volume
to support it. And then collaborations
is really about a structure. And I'll do
a whole collaborations video. I want to
bring one of my friends on who's a
specialist in this at one point, but
this is about how can you create a
product and then co-arket it together.
And usually where this comes down to is
logistics. Who's paying for the product?
How much does each person get? Who's
selling it? Who's responsible for what
assets? like you really breaking down
responsibility and agreeing to it and
then having something come out. But this
is just another good example I think a
lot of brands should be doing as long as
you can create something interesting and
unique. And the best way to think about
this as a marketer is a collaboration
schedule where you go, we have all of
our normal releases. We have our spring
release and our fall release. We do new
product once a year. You know, if
there's big spaces in there, can we do a
collaboration that fits that's a new
product to fill that space? Is a great
entry- level way to look at it without
having do overkill. Another way to look
at is a whole program the way Monontlair
does with Genius where you may say,
"Hey, we actually want to do a a a
branded program over time where a bunch
of people fill these slots." This is
great for a bigger brand to work with
smaller brands. Uh those are just
different ways to think about it. So
anyway, I know we covered a lot of
ground inside of this. If you like this
kind of conversation around marketing
and brand strategy, my newsletter called
Hyper is at
mail.hyperstudios. I'll link it down
here. I talk about stuff like this every
week. I didn't hit on some like kind of
a little more nuance stuff like PR and
communications things that kind of don't
matter as much. And there's a whole
chunk of this that is performance
marketing and spending money on ads that
is probably worthy of its own video.
Another one I'll try to bring an expert
in on. But just defining all these
categories and just thinking through
what they can do for your brand, I feel
like is an important thing to learn. And
thanks for bearing with me.
[Music]