Everyone you know has been brainwashed
into wanting to go to Japan. Do you
notice a massive influx on your feed of
baggy pants girls and selvage denim guys
roaming the streets of Tokyo? You're not
alone. The yen has depreciated 44%
against the US dollar since 2019, making
Japan one of the best value destinations
on Earth. In 2024, they welcomed a
record high 36 million visitors, 53%
over the prior year, and their goals
were actually set much higher. But in
one of the most interesting signals,
typically in tourism, visitors prefer
experiences, but Japan's become a
shopping destination first. People are
going to buy things. And in this video,
we're going to explore that arc. Cuz if
you want to learn about brand, you want
to learn about quality, but all of the
dynamics happening on a global scale
around marketing, there are so many fun
and interesting topics. So, I'm fresh
back after a week and change out in
Tokyo with my family, seeing and
observing a lot of this in person,
participating in the shopping economy.
And in this video, we're going to talk
about everything from the creative
directors of convenience stores, their
department store culture, the
opportunities in branding and
duplicates, the oddball scenarios around
licensing that are playing out globally.
Let's lock in. In Japan, they don't just
consume brands, they obsess over them.
And the consumer experience is treated
like real hospitality. And there's no
place to better call this out and start
this video than with convenience store
culture. You will see again and again on
your feed there are viral 7-Eleven Japan
videos. You can get an egg salad
sandwich. I went there with my son, he
can pick out a bowl of frozen fruit and
then make a smoothie right there in a
7-Eleven for like $2.50. But 7-Eleven
and their culture there isn't the story
as much as Family Mart. One of the big
competitors, in Japan, there are three
primary convenience stores. You have
Lawsons, you have Family Mart, and you
have 7-Eleven. But why Family Mart
stands out is they actually announced
NIGO as their creative director last
year. If you're not familiar with NIGO,
he founded A Bathing Ape, the BAPE
brand, in 1993. He opened a store called
Nowhere with one of the founders of
Undercover. The name is an idiom for
overindulgence and complacency. It
almost poked fun at itself and Japanese
youth living off their parents' wealth.
So, there's an interesting kind of
streetwear dynamic and culturism from
its start. And a huge component of the
scarcity model. This initially started
partly by accident. The brand had a
limited budget when they dropped 50
t-shirts, it's all they had. And they
famously really worked this ever since,
including canceling wholesale outlets,
focusing on their own flagship stores,
and being a great global representation
of hypebeast culture overall. And they
continue style. Their Kids Super collab
this year was hot and in demand 30-plus
years later. Nigo has taken that across
many industries ever, including probably
the most prolific position he's had,
which has been at the artistic director
of fashion brand Kenzo. A true high-end
designer brand. In between, he has
collaborated and been part of showcasing
streetwear culture, art culture,
worldwide. So, how does someone like
this end up as the creative director of
a convenience store? And then, what does
that mean for brand and consumer culture
going forward? So, if you walk into
Family Mart, it's almost identical to
what you would see in 7-Eleven or
Lawson's, except for one thing. They
have their own line of branded products
called convenience wear. Where they have
small towels, shirts, socks,
well-priced, lightly branded items that
will remind you more of a Muji or an
IKEA, but it's almost out of place in
the other store with everything else
that's in the aisles and your snacks and
your beverages. Then you have this
Helvetica laid out, very well-priced
product. But in this competitive world
that they're in, where there's some
convenience stores everywhere, right?
Major brands they're competing with. And
there's all this tourism culture, where
people are choosing to much I want to
experience extra wide." People make
their lists
from the internet. All of a sudden, this
becomes much more competitive and
interesting. And so, with someone like
Nigo, you can see that he is tasked with
a few things. One is redoing the
interiors of those stores. How does that
become different over time?
He's going to be getting rolling out new
store experiences going forward. And
then, second is how does that product
experience become more than just Family
Mart the convenience store, but
convenience wear and these convenience
items become their own brand, their own
tool to be able to attract attention and
to be able to get customers to spend
money in different ways. And these two
actually merge together. So, I visited a
concept store they had in basically a
high-end office building where it was
just a convenience wear showcase where
they had joggers, umbrellas, socks,
towels, pants conveniently laid out. You
just grab them, scan, and go with
nice-looking stanchions, interesting
merchandising. It's basically an
extension of your average convenience
store, but played out in an
untraditional environment. And begins to
show you a bit of how the brand is
thinking and where they're going. I
think this is interesting. I think this
is ahead of what's happening in Western
culture where you've seen things like
high-end specialty groceries, you've
seen the Erewhons of the world focus on
collaboration, bring in things like
merchandise and drops to make it into an
experience and a tourism destination in
LA. But that's operating at the highest
end, at the luxury end. That's a given.
That's going to happen. Well, how do you
engineer this in the rest of the world?
How do you differentiate when everything
becomes commoditized? And this is part
of a bigger topic, right? And one that I
feel like Japan is most close to. Is
that everything can be copied so easily
now. You've seen my videos about this.
You can go on Import Yeti and you can
look up any brand and see what factory
they're importing from. That goes for
beauty, that goes for apparel. You can
hack your way down to who someone's
supplier is. You can go to China and
find them yourself. You can duplicate
almost any good. The gates have been
broken to be able to make almost
anything you want and in quantities
lower than ever. And so, if you decide
to make something niche or marketed or
presented in a different way, even if
it's successful and mainstream,
you're able to take some of that market.
We see the same thing in software now
with people being able to just quickly
replicate things with AI coding. But
Japan has always seen that directly
because China's right next door, right?
There's still a barrier to entry that
you had the US pre-Alibaba, pre-the
internet and TikTok culture where you
actually have to go hunt a bunch of that
down. That was happening in Japan
constantly. Anything nice would
potentially be bootlegged by China and
easily imported. And so, there's just a
proliferation of extremely well-made
things, extremely cheap things all
throughout. And so, in this lowest end
culture and the things you buy most
quickly and as a convenience the
branding and competition of that is
ahead of where you consider something
like that in the US. And the creative
director is one of the last tools that
people have, right? If you have the
equal ability to buy anything, I can go
to any grocery store, I can go to any
convenience store. There's a Quick Trip
next to a 7-Eleven next to a Casey's.
How do you pick what you're going to do?
Does one of them represent your values
better? Does one of them have a more
interesting experience you can pick up?
Does one of them have an item that
they're known for? When everything is
the same, the identity becomes more
important than ever. So thinking about
how in any normal business can you
differentiate yourself through what a
creative director would do? How could
they design the experience to be more
shareable and more compelling and more
interesting than the surroundings? That
might take time. May want to not run
that right away. Whenever you're doing
your redesign, can you begin to bring
that creativity in? Can you begin to
collaborate and have exclusives that
people want to show up and buy and
participate in, which you'll see NijiGo
doing through a series of collaborations
inside Family Mart. Can you develop your
own specific products and lines that
give people an interesting reason to
have demand or want to get something and
pick something up because you know they
have a superior item. And so if I was in
any of those businesses, those more
traditional businesses here in the US,
I'd be thinking about that, right?
Grocery, convenience, what is that
creative director path to enable
product, to enable distribution and
content and to enable experience in a
world where basically everything else
including your proximity and
availability becomes commoditized. And
one interesting thing that I feel ties
really well into marketing and brand
building in general is the next level of
experience in Japanese shopping, which
is the department store. So when you
think of department store in the US, you
think of Macy's, Nordstrom, Saks, and
pretty antiquated models. They feel
nothing like they used to, even Neiman
Marcus the high end. In the UK you have
Harrods and Selfridges and more of a
culture that's built around that. So
they've been, you know, kept some of
that experience at a higher degree of
quality than the US. Whereas in Japan
it's still a primary mode of
consumption. You're still going to a
department store versus individual store
for lots of experiences. And some of the
best brands themselves function both as
a brand and as a department store. The
most interesting one to me is Beams. So
if you hadn't heard of Beams, the story
basically starts with Japan's
reproduction of American garments. So,
there's an obsession in Japanese design
with the heyday of Western craft. The
most authentic American garments of
denim, some of the process that were
used for high-end American workwear are
now really only continued in Japan at
that level of quality. There are brands,
Beams being one of them, that have made
entire businesses off of making the
highest quality versions of kind of
classic American garments. There's a
book on this, Amatora: How Japan Saved
American Style, that you could dive
into. But, American traditional is a
style in Japan that's basically based on
Ivy League style of the US. And what
started as imitation basically became
far more elevated over time. Rather than
importing stuff from the US, Japanese
companies like Beams basically did a
much better version of it locally and
took the craft more seriously. And you
see if you've seen my video on Ralph
Lauren and Kapital, it's another example
of someone who basically took what Ralph
Lauren was doing, but didn't just say,
"Hey, we're going to replicate this."
They made it better and more interesting
and their own over time, which is, for a
lot of brand builders, how to think
about it. I don't want to just make
another T-shirt, I'll make another pair
of pants. How do I elevate the craft?
How do I elevate the story? And so, as
Beams began to develop these originals
at a higher quality standard, they had a
store that would sell imported American
goods. They would curate. They sold
Japan's first Nike trainers and
eventually developed into their own
lines. And this brand blossomed that's
now collaborated with a lot of the
American brands used to base its
products on or be inspired by or carry,
Red Wing, Timberland, Levi's, LL Bean.
And they've created these multi-floor
experiences where you go there and on
the bottom floor of the one I went to,
there was a Ziploc bag collab with
Coquette bows on them. It was like hot
and in demand and people were there to
shop. It was like a standout
collaboration I hadn't seen. It would
you know, rival any collaboration you've
seen in America. With an iconic brand as
a Ziploc bag is. Kind of an outrageous
collab, but one nonetheless and they did
a good job with it. But then there's
curated goods and levels of product,
right? Where they have a lot of products
they're selling of local Japanese and
American, everything from ceramics to
food products to watches. And then it
kind of goes layer by layer through the
store where you have streetwear and
curation around that and the things
you'd expect and toys and vinyl all the
way up to more traditional menswear to
home goods. And it's all looked on
through this lens of Americana, but also
being really true to also finding its
own through lines into Japanese culture
and curation and the merging of the two.
And I think as we see everything in our
world and so much product so come out of
ties where everyone will have a brand
that looks like anyone else's brand.
Everyone makes elevated streetwear.
People who are really passionate about
the same two things, three really, will
find their way to stand out, right? So
first is the craft saying, "Hey, we're
not going to make a crew neck. We're
going to make the best crew neck." And
here's why. "We're going to use
alternative materials." That's why you
see it all the things that I'm so
obsessed with texture. You know when you
get something from me, it's going to be
similar to I've never seen before, but
the texture is going to be unique. And
then there's this idea of history and
the portrayal and where can you spin
from and how do you combine multiple
backgrounds? Yeah, I'm going to take an
Ivy League style with a medieval twist
or a Kapital's Americana mixed with
almost a rural Japanese style. And then
lastly is that experience. How do people
actually engage with this? Cuz doing it
like online and in e-commerce versus
having a world is interesting. That
world doesn't have to just be your own
things you sell. I found when I visited
the UK, a lot of these brands, Earl of
East, had their own products and also
curated others. You bring into an
experience of the brand's world. And in
a world where everything is so ephemeral
and then a new store pops up online
overnight, there's something interesting
about that permanence. You can take a
lot of inspiration from from brands like
Beams. What's also interesting to see
how a brand can be interpreted in a
country. So I'm wearing stuff that I
bought at North Face Japan, North Face
Purple Label, which is an interesting
story. There is a distributor called
Goldwin and they're also a brand, maybe
familiar with them, who used to
distribute North Face. So for those who
don't know, in the '90s North Face was
having a rough time and they almost
faced bankruptcy. They were cooking the
books and a series of deals that they
did, this being one of them, helped kind
of save the company from bankruptcy at
that point. And one of them was they
sold the complete trademark rights to
the name to Goldwin. Not just like a
license that they have or they pay, but
like perpetual ownership of the brand in
Korea and Japan. Goldwin was really
interesting steward of this. They spun
off a sub-brand, I don't want to butcher
the name, where they had really
excellent takes at design and other
branding underneath it. And now
basically 95% of the North Face products
sold in Japan are unique to that market,
and they are excellent. They have
basically a dozen sub-labels. They have
North Face Ultra, they have Purple Label
that I got. There's White Label in South
Korea. There's Standard, there's Sphere.
They have a 141 Custom Service that will
3D scan you to make perfect things to
your body. Really taking the ethos of
The North Face brand and doing what that
brand basically has insisted it won't
do. I poked fun the other year at North
Face launching this new manifesto the
other year that was like AI-written and
completely out of touch with their
customer versus their kind of
traditional tagline that Never Stop
Exploring means a lot to people. But
it's interesting to see in a vacuum as
someone who takes the craft and the
presentation and the elevation of a
brand seriously versus what happens in a
company kind of lumbers on under their
huge holdco ownership and ends up in
like weird corporate stewardship where
that line goes. And I think what's been
done with The North Face in Japan is a
tremendous example of the more
uninhibited creative vision that can
come forth. So much so that I spent a
awful lot of money on clothes there. And
North Face did 1.7 billion in the US
revenue, but 670 million in Japan. It's
a huge business. They coexist. And
there's other stories like this, like
oddball stories of brand ownership. But
Weiser doesn't own its own name in
Germany. Brothers who in like a faux
family feud split up the Aldi grocery
chain in the UK, and then one of those
brothers owns Trader Joe's in the US. So
you have all these little interesting
scenarios that come up around that. I
always just find it interesting to to
look at and think about. And those are
the kind of things that intrigue me a
lot. What's funny when you look at how
do you, you know, look at brands, how do
you find brands that you want to
reference or look from if you're in
fashion, or you want to build your own
unique style, a lot of that comes from,
okay, being unique is what are garments
that other people don't have. you want
to have your reference garments, how can
you reference things that are different
from what other people do? And so if
everyone's looking at the same brands
that are in the US when they basically
copy things or are inspired by things,
and you're looking at a completely
different set of brands that are only
available if you go somewhere in person,
that's a very It's an interesting
concept, a way to base what you're doing
around something unique. So related to
some of these conversations around brand
positioning, I'm working on a new
project. We'll see if it comes to
fruition. Those of you who know, those
of you who follow like my lab diamond
journey and a few others, I try a lot of
things, and we'll if they come or not.
Some have worked well, some continue on.
I obviously have the fashion brand.
We've been selling more and more of the
car accessories, which is interesting.
I'm debating whether I restock that or
not. A lot of this is just for me to
enjoy the experience and make a little
money along the way. But one of them I'm
looking at is I'm looking closer and
closer at interior and exterior objects.
And I have some ideas for how I could
make some furniture and interiors
products my own. And so I've been
researching a bunch on Particle, who are
the sponsor of this video. Relevant
because it's something I'm using for
this exact process. And what's
interesting here is I like to look at
some of the people in the space to find
what are what are things you would be
unexpected that they're selling. So I've
been in the furniture world, I've been
researching what sells. And one of the
things that interested me is I went on
Two Modern. I've been looking at all
these kind of dupe brands, brands that
like sell a lot of common designer stuff
and slightly redo it. So I'm thinking of
putting my own twist on on some of that
and have it be tongue and cheek. What
was interesting to me is looking at Two
Modern this spring, their all their top
products are umbrellas, like outdoor
umbrellas is a top seller. Then two of
the other ones are ceiling fans. I
thought that was interesting cuz I have
these unique ceiling fans in my house
cuz there's just not many options. We
got you know two of the only ones who
could get on the internet back when we
moved in here cuz I was like cool, I
don't want like I don't like the look of
the standard ones. There's only so many
that look interesting. And it was
interesting to me to see that like their
volume sellers. I can see here on
Particle, 700 units in the last four
weeks of the Irene ceiling fan, 557 of
of this other variations, the three
versus fives. Like two of their seven
top selling products. This is like a
massive firm. Like I can go look at
their overall. Obviously these numbers
are like directionally correct, but
yeah, we're looking at tens of millions
of dollars a month. And they sell lots
of a lot of different things. This is a
wide catalog. It was interesting seeing
the million dollar a month are coming
from the umbrellas. And this is kind of
one of the reasons you look at and kind
of take a look what's happening in these
categories. You don't really know what
people are selling. Like in the same way
I want to look at Interior Icons. So
they're like a classic kind of gray
market dupe brand. What was interesting
to me looking at them was there is no
like big top seller, right? There's lots
of little sellers. So it's funny this On
the Rocks sofa is a product I've I've
been looking at the house, which is
funny. But again they sell four, but
it's their highest revenue generator.
They're They're a lot, four to 15 across
so many of these. This is why you see
furniture brands operate the way they
do. Where it's like, "Oh, it's 6 to 10
weeks for delivery." They're making it
when you buy it, right? And this makes
sense cuz why would you want to stock
something you're selling four of every
month? And you need a wide catalog to do
that. Um you'll also notice, this is
something I hate and is uh borderline
illegal, constant average discount of
60%, right? And so you'll see when
you're playing in that arena, the
perceived value of something versus the
discounted value. Whether that's your
always price or not, you have to Is
something worth entertaining? It's like,
cool, do I want to play in that gray
area? If I was to compete in this space
as a brand, can you make it work if
you're not perpetually discounting? It's
one of the reasons I like to look at
data like this. And you can see what
that looks like. I'm just wondering, in
Particle, you get to do that. You can
look at their various assets. So I not
only can see the price and average value
and how that changed over time and how
much they're discounting it. I can see
when their homepage changes. I can see
what they posted on Instagram. You can
see their SMS. Can check into their meta
ads all in one place. See how much they
post, what their average likes are.
People do not mess around with Interior
Icons' Instagram. And you're able to
look, actually look at a competitive set
for any industry that you're diving
into. If you want to learn more about
Particle, you can check them out at the
link in the description. And thanks to
them, as always, my first and original
YouTube sponsor for staying with me. And
all of this kind of culminates in a
conversation around Muji, one of the
most interesting brands in the world. If
you're not familiar with Muji, I'm
liking them a bit to an IKEA, but they
don't make furniture, they make
everything. Furniture included, but
every category. From grocery to luggage
to bed and bath products. At the Muji I
went to in Japan, they have a Muji
hotel. There's a Muji cafe inside. They
have a diner. They have every type of
experience. They basically have
positioned themselves of being the
anti-brand. Their slogan in general and
their belief system is the absence of a
logo, the absence of a brand. The idea
that it's good enough. There's a
philosophy around, instead of this is
exactly what I want, it's this will do.
That's the entire philosophy of the
brand. Which is interesting that that
philosophy has become a brand in itself
because it's so much of what people
want. They want a standardization. They
want to know a certain standard of
quality across anything that they can go
and get and feel that they're getting a
good price and something that's worth
the money and interest. They've elevated
this idea of this will do into something
that has clarity and confidence behind
it. Where I walk in, I'll buy basically
any Muji product sight unseen and know
that it's going to be fine. I can't
really say that about any of the other
generic experiences you have or even any
of the other value experiences. You
don't know if it's going to be fine.
It's probably going to be mid. And it's
funny that like the No Brand now sells
you a hotel you can sleep like
underneath that branding. And what I
think is interesting here is that trust
level that you see for modern brands
now. Like who's going to sell you what
in the future? If you have an
overarching idea We see this more in
Japan than anywhere. If you sell me one
thing and I trust it and you start
selling me another and I trust that, I'm
only going to trust more of those things
in the future. And that's why you see
now everything from, you know, Satisfy
launched a marathon a marathon protein
bar. Or so like an energy bar. Graza
isn't really an olive oil brand. They're
also selling chips and hummus and
mayonnaise. They are a food brand. And
if they were to move into Graza home
goods, you kind of know what to expect.
I think that's what we're going to see
here is trust and distribution. This
idea that there is brand love. And the
brand hasn't messed up and it keeps
going. And you have a huge email list.
You look at this is the Kin's phenomenon
too, right? Where I start to like one
thing or I get one dupe, all of a sudden
I want to get more and more. I'm be you
become obsessed with the value. As
brands get more and more own
distribution and more brand trust and
understand the internet more and more,
they have more opportunities to move
across these categories. To not be
limited at all. And in Japan this is in
action. Because people are doing this
from a physical experience standpoint. I
go to the Muji store to get groceries
and snacks for my flight home and then I
also find that there's luggage. Now I
want to try this candle for my house and
why don't we eat at the diner next time?
Look at how nice these rooms are for the
value. Let's stay at the hotel. You're
putting yourself in that experience. The
same thing I went to I went to Beams.
Where I went there to look at some of
the curation they have, the interesting
package CPG products on the bottom floor
and then I got the Ziploc collab. And
then, hey, the streetwear is actually
pretty good. Oh, the men's tailoring is
excellent. And you begin to get
introduced to this entire world of a
brand. I say that to say that I would I
think from a product perspective, anyone
who's in that battle now, who's having
any level of success, who has that brand
love, I wouldn't be underestimating what
you're going to be capable of in the
future. And I think we are going to see
these big overarching brands, the way
you'd see these kind of massive key
companies, but now composed of kind of
these smaller entities, become something
really prevalent in the next decade. And
that ties into kind of two final
sections I have here. One is about this
kind of like the new world of branding
and clones, and the one is about the
experience and kind of some
recommendations I have if you travel to
Japan. Everyone's really with Gentle
Monster, right? You see my video on
Gentle Monster, maybe I'll link it here
at the end. Incredible architecture,
incredible brand presentation, really
popular, but extremely expensive. I know
a lot of people that like Gentle
Monster. I know very few that have ever
bought anything from Gentle Monster. And
so, there was a brand in Tokyo. I always
like to look when I'm traveling
anywhere, you know, I'm I'm a brand
cultural anthropologist for lack of a
better term. I'm building as much of my
vernacular as humanly possible across
everything I do always to bring
decisions I can bring into creative
strategy, creative direction, product
development, and marketing. And I like
to look at where are the actual youth
shopping? What's What have I not heard
of that's packed? And in Japan, there
was a store called Blue Elephant, which
is another Korean brand, similar to
Gentle Monster, that also sells eyewear.
But, it is just literally a knockoff of
Gentle Monster. When I looked it up, I
believe they have been in lawsuits and
just at a cheaper price. And this is
interesting and damn near genius in that
there is so much brand equity that's
gone into building Gentle Monster for
something that most people simply do not
want to buy at that price point. And
people will not necessarily care. They
know what they're getting if they get a
dupe that's trying to do a lot of the
same exact things, but at a price they
can afford cuz we know now every
consumer, every one of you watching
knows or is about to know in 20 seconds
that we know everything is an upcharge.
We know what things cost. The internet
and TikTok has democratized what things
are worth. And so, we know we're buying
the brand. You know, for Gentle Monster,
you're paying an egregious upcharge for
their marketing and for maybe an ABG to
recognize you. What brand is this? Ask
you a question. Probably not. And that
is a premium that is not worth it for
most consumers, and brands can fit in
that middle ground. I had my entire
product versus brand series on this,
right? Where it's like you can buy the
Frette towel or sheets for thousands and
thousands of dollars, and guess what?
The Italic ones, who pride themselves on
being an anti-brand like Muji, are just
as good, and they're a fraction of the
price and we now know that the
information's been democratized. You
know you are wasting money on brand and
signal and that signal on your sheets
doesn't really matter anymore. And for a
generation that did, those little
signals meant everything. But now as
Rolex makes a million watches a year, as
Porsche has a million 911s on the road,
you may like those things, may enjoy
those things, but they're not the
signalers they were. Signals have been
ubiquitous. And so you might as well
take the thing that looks like it, that
functions like it at the lower price
point and there are brands to be built
specifically doing those things. I know
a lot of you say, "Oh, I'm going to
start a dupe brand." But you'll find
that most of the successful things that
we're looking at now are kind of doing
that. And so I thought it was
interesting that Blue Elephant was
playing there. It gave me a few ideas of
experiences I want to have and there's
probably a whole separate dupe and
shitification video coming where I'll
talk about that more. But last, I did
want to give you some tips for things if
you do go to Tokyo in Japan you can dive
into. So first, there's an awesome
listening room culture where the thing
from going to Yoyogi play vinyl to these
experiences. I went to Karamoku Research
Center. They had all these Devon
Turnbull designed listening room. They
had speakers, they had special furniture
just for listening and you could
experience the rooms and they had all
the items laid out on the bottom floor
and it's really interesting design and
and look and whole brutalist facility
you you can just go to for free. Team
Lab's Planets, they had this amazing
exhibit that's basically like a complete
interactive playground, kind of like
those photo exhibits you go to in LA
where it's like take pictures where
everything's actually interactive and
useful, almost like an amusement park.
Amazing if you have kids and they have
Michelin green star vegan ramen there as
well. And then there's a special
separate kitchen town and fabric town.
So I always got I'm always looking for
more fabric. If you've seen the pants I
have that I sell a lot of it in white
and black. We've restocked it a few
times. It's a specific Japanese fabric
even though we we make them in Wonju
specifically cuz I found something I
love from a mill that just does this
particular thing and so I'm always
hunting for fabric in there. Same thing
in the kitchen town. It was really
interesting. They had like all these
really unique molds. Any questions
you've ever had about what knife is
worth it or what cuts you can kind of
resolve right there right then and
they'll ship it to you. Pans, like
anything like that. And then last,
there's so many custom examples. I'm
going to do a whole post on this on on
Instagram, but you can do everything
from making your own ceramics to making
the fake food that they use in photos.
There's so much custom experiences
there, which I find for creative people
to really fun to be able to like
participate in your own souvenirs. So,
now we had our art direction of K-pop
and Korean fashion videos. This is a
little bit of a different approach. We
want to talk about those branding
concepts in general. And this is what
I'm going to I'm going to focus on in
the April community call. When this
comes out, I'll have just done the March
one where we focused on social brand
strategy. I'm going to focus on brand
creative direction that like at a macro
level. What does creative direction even
mean in this kind of day and age? And
then how do you decide what to base
things on in this kind of complicated
world? So, all of info on that live
event uh will be down below. I hope you
enjoyed this video. I'm at ShopTalk in
Las Vegas this week uh getting into a
lot of e-com. We'll see if I end up
recapping that. If this comes out before
it's done and you're there, don't
hesitate to say hi. I appreciate y'all
so much for watching.