In this video, we are going to talk
about a term that I hate, but that is
very important. The taste economy. Say,
what does this even mean? What are the
factors that led to it existing? And
what does it mean for commerce? Both how
we buy and how you market and sell and
brand your own products. We're going to
talk about the educated consumer. How
consumers now have way more knowledge of
everything in the world than ever. And
then how you actually consume based on
that. Then we're going to talk about the
archetypes of the premium buyer. Who
overpays for luxury today? Why do they
do it? and how do you understand them?
If you are in marketing and branding,
make sure to stay to the end because I
have some specifics and some tactics
there from my experience selling premium
items. But the goal of this video is to
have you think about why we consume what
we consume, the factors that are at play
on social media, in media in general,
and in brand building that make us buy,
how luxury actually works, why our
brains think the way they do, and how
this changes the world around us. Let's
lock in. So, I'm going to start with an
analogy from food, a flavor analogy.
>> Welcome to flavor time. You may have
noticed in recent life everything has
started to taste amazing. Raising Canes,
Sweet Green, Goop Kitchen. There's a new
generation of food that's basically
engineered so that our taste buds just
love it. It's like when you first had a
Dorito as a kid. You never had a chip
that tasted that intense before. And all
of a sudden, this feeling came over you.
You're like, "Why have I never had
anything that tasted this good?" We had
those hyper strong flavors, at least in
my childhood. Mountain Dew, Doritos,
like the high sugar candy before this
whole natural food movement. you would
just be shocked by the efficacy of
flavor of this. But now we have all this
really refined flavor all around us. Way
more global flavors, all these hot
sauces, everything in the world. Why do
I bring this analogy up? Because in that
world where now if you want to have like
a piece of white bread or like a single
vegetable, it feels like life with the
volume off because everything around it
has become so amazing. This is why so
many people will get an Uber Eats now or
do the easy thing because it's also that
much better. And this ties into the
nonliteral taste economy. And let's
start with what does the taste economy
even mean? So we used to buy what we
need. I might need a new jacket once
every couple years. I you buy whatever
hand soap is at the grocery store. If
you really wanted a candle, you get
something normal. If you wanted a car,
you got your Corolla. But a paradigm
shift happened and it happened for a
couple reasons. The first being the
democratization of supply chain. So
Alibaba in China, the whole concept
behind Alibaba was that all these
factories used to have to go to China to
find an app now gave you access to any
person in the world could look online
and see what someone made and get it.
And the same exact thing happened
whether it was from import Yeti or
global trade shows, Thomas Net, whatever
it is, all of a sudden anything you want
to make anywhere in the world from
Turkey to the Middle East to Italy to
Portugal to the US, more people can make
than ever. So more and more brands
popped up. And at first they started to
compete on price. You would see all
these Chinese brands pop up on Amazon
with just cheaper versions of what was
successful. So there became a whole
economy around cheap. But for people
that still wanted something good, all of
a sudden the competition stepped up. The
nice thing all of a sudden became
cheaper as well. Things that used to be
a luxury that people could upcharge for
and they had to go hunt or was only made
in Italy. All of a sudden was being
duped all around the world at extremely
similar quality. So the nice thing
became not that much more. And that's
factor one. Factor two, you used to have
to dig to care. If you wanted to know
what an amazing fragrance was, you had
to go research. You had to go hunt it
down. Now with the internet, with
Instagram, with Tik Tok, you are
presented so much more information about
your options. Far more people in the age
of 14 to 16 know what a gourmand is than
ever before. People understand
materials. They know of brands that they
wouldn't have heard of any other way. It
is given to us, shown to us in how we
consume. On social media, we are
presented with brands, luxury
experiences, and high-end items in our
feed right next to everything else we
would never have seen on a TV ad in the
early 2000s. So, caring has become easy.
And those two factors of the nice thing
not being that much more expensive
because of competition. And the fact
that nice things we never would have
known are being shown to us has made it
easy to care, has made it easy to have
taste, to see apartments that look nicer
than your average apartment and go, "Oh,
I could do that or I could buy that."
And you know what? That's not that much
more expensive than what I was going to
do already to get the designed version,
the little luxury. The espresso machine
that might be $150 more than what you
were going to get, but actually produces
real craft macchiatas. And at that same
time, people have developed affinity for
brands and experiences and beautiful
things and are able to express that
through what they like online, what they
consume, and what they buy. We've had a
cottage industry of amazing brands pop
up. You've heard me talk a lot about
Flamingo Estate. It was a b a brand that
was founded in the pandemic, but they
have a beautiful estate the brand is
based in. feels like it's been around
for a long time. They sold vegetable
organic local vegetable pickup to people
in LA and then they began to add on hand
wash and hand soap and honey and treats
and now it's curated boxes from around
the world. Extremely high-end versions
of strawberries or olive oils or
whatever it is for people that have
begun to go down the rabbit hole of yes,
I like organic vegetables. Yes, I love
what this brand stands for and their
care about it and how they go into these
things around the world and create this
amazing iconography. And now I can buy
in. And guess what? buying in is just a
couple dollars more than whatever I
spent on my soap. And we've democratized
quality. I made a a really viral video
about rugs, right? Which rugs should you
buy? Because you always buy crappy rugs.
There are tons of crappy rug companies
out there. All the big DTOC rug
companies don't make great product. Then
you have companies like Nordic Knots or
Benny that make really good rugs. Benny
in particular makes an incredible like
life-changing rug. Now, without the
ability for a creator to be like, "Hey,
here's this amazing thing. Here's this
amazing brand. Look, they show their
craft. Look what the quality looks
like." You may have spent a similar
amount of money or decide to spend more
on this new tasteful thing and you enter
the world of that brand and the
algorithms know that you buy the Benny.
They now know that you are often a
luxury consumer and they show you more
content around that. If you just browse,
they show you more content. So taste is
brought to us. This is an important
transformation to understand for how we
consume and how to sell. Fragrance is
perhaps the best example. You will see
boys 14 to 18 are obsessed with
fragrances. They have whole fragrance
setups and they're learning all this
from Tik Tok and they're learning more
about the notes and the samples and
making it part of their identity, who
they are, how a sense gives them a bit
of happiness. All this education, all
this taste, for lack of a better term,
gives us identity. And there's an
economy around it where people are
participating in buying things they
didn't buy before, spending more on
traditional things than what they spent
prior. And the industry is so massive.
There's so much dollars that have come
into this in different ways. And then so
many people that are paid to promote it
or influence in it or develop branding
around it that it is worthy of a title
like the taste economy. Now we're going
to talk about what that means for the
consumer because the consumer is
educated with all this content. What
does this mean for you? How are things
sold in this world? Then we're going to
go into the archetypes of the luxury
buyer who buys the really expensive
stuff. And then we're going to go into
the new economy to sell them. So
consumers are more educated than ever.
You know this. You are on YouTube. You
consume more educational content if
you're watching a video like this than
anyone in generations prior simply
because of its availability. If you want
to go learn about how the best soap is
made or you want to learn about this
drone versus that drone or camera
equipment, whatever it is, you can
simply go down a rabbit hole of amazing
experts willing to educate you. So, your
average consumer now knows about
incredible things. Look at the female
skincare consumer. I'm going to butcher
this pronunciation, but nioinomide is
basically something that people are
buying now versus sunscreen. They buy
the ingredient. They know about the
activives. Brands like The Ordinary just
listed nioinomide 6%, zinc 1% on the
package. People Googled it. People went
down the rabbit hole of what am I
putting on my body? Same thing. You see
the conversation around polyester versus
natural fibers versus cotton. What does
that mean for my skin? What's in
polyester? Why should I not buy bamboo?
Oh, bamboo is treated a certain way. You
start to get into it. More content comes
to you around it. Prebiotics,
probiotics, yogurt, soda. We know way
more about the ingredients than ever
before. That is from education. So, how
do you sell to a consumer who has
content brought to them, who now expects
a slightly better thing, who can follow
the journey, who's educated, and there's
three key tactics here. So, the first is
the best thing. You will see an endless
storm of videos online of like, I quit
my job in private equity to fulfill my
life's dream of creating the perfect
prebiotic yogurt. You've all seen videos
like that, people going on a quest to
solve a problem as a content type that
works really well on social media and in
brand stores. And a lot of the reason
this works is about consumer habits. So
when you go into Google, I used to do
SEO as one of the core things I did when
I worked in marketing. And one thing I
would always look at is you search it,
search the terms. So for instance, I
used to do this in surf. You would
search for best foil surfboard, worst
foil surfboard, reviews for soil foil
surfboard, the different brand names.
Those are all search targets that people
would be putting into Google cuz that's
what people actually type. I want the
best thing. I want the cheapest thing.
Which one should I avoid? What do people
recommend? That is a habit of how people
search. That habit hasn't changed. they
will type the same thing now into Tik
Tok or into Instagram and the algorithms
now know if you type it into Google they
send signals to each other so that if
you're looking for the best thing it
gives it to you so brands now build
around that story comfort is a amazing
example of this so comfort hoodies have
built a huge brand they have thousands
and thousands of creators making content
and it's all around the softest hoodie
cuz they recognize when people are
buying hoodies that might be oh I want
the heaviest I want the cheapest I want
the coolest I want the softest guess
what the softest is a huge market
whether you were searching for it or not
do you in your mind want the softest
hoodie ever. I'm intrigued. So this
concept for the educated consumer of the
best and then we can show them why are
we the best? How did we make that
process? We can have hundreds if not
thousands of creators and ads telling
the story of that this is the best, the
softest. That becomes a really
compelling way to sell. The second one
is then focusing on the ingredients.
Ingredients will become popular. You
need to get your greens of a company
like Gruns. People are really into
creatine. So that's all of a sudden
being everywhere. Prebiotics. People
care about gut health. They understand
the gut way more than ever. or you I
talk to anyone 15 years ago only a 2% of
people into their health were talking
about the gut microbiome, prebiotics,
probiotics. Now it's a huge swath that's
lightly educated on that. So the ability
to say I do this thing with this
ingredient becomes compelling. And then
the third thing is the transformation
when everything is just a little bit
more tasteful or different than the
other. What is the thing that is going
to change my life? It's going to really
tie the room together. It's going to
help me achieve X or Y goal. How can I
tell the story of how this product helps
participate in the life-changing
experience, the transformation? So those
three tactics, the best thing, the
superpowered ingredient or ingredients,
and the transformation of your life
become ultra effective ways to sell in
something like a taste economy where
everything looks cool, everything looks
good. And you'll notice the throughine
for all three of those things is
enthusiasm, right? People give a
Yeah, I want the best thing. If I'm
going to put my dollars out there, I
don't want to go buy something else in
two years. I want the best one. Yeah, I
care what I put in my body. I'm going to
care about what I consume, this
ingredient or that material. They're
enthusiastic. They care about it. And
the transformation, I want to actually
get a result. I want to know if I commit
to my 30-day program or I get this thing
or I decide to get this Pelaton, I'm
gonna have a transformation. Enthusiasm
is the byproduct of education. The more
people learn, the more into it they get,
the more excited they are to participate
in it. And this is a huge thing to
understand around the taste economy is
people love participating in it. In my
house, in my home, we've gotten into
fragrance. My son, my wife and I, we get
interesting candles. We talk about it.
We'll go visit a fragrance store when
we're traveling abroad and try new stuff
out. I was in a store in I believe it
was Barcelona, may have been Florence, I
forget which one, but my son was really
interested in finding he had been
searching and he's he's nine for like
the wildest fragrances and there was a
store there that had something called
like the blood note that like smelled
like blood. There was another and there
was ones that were literally uh it was
like almost offensive smells that were
kind of out there in the world. We
visited this shop of like rare
curiosities cuz he's enthusiastic about
the learning behind it. It's new. It's
exciting. It's a sensory experience. But
then if you really want to get
scientific, you want to think about
where you live in the consumer process
or where you can market to in the
consumer process, we need to talk about
the archetypes of who buys luxury. This
week, Swap launched something worth
paying attention to, their Agentic
storefronts are live. The Aentic
storefront is its own dedicated shopping
experience. It's not a widget or an
add-on to your existing site. It runs a
fully branded experience separate from
your.com where a shopper can go from
product discovery to virtual tryon to
checkout inside a single uninterrupted
flow. Simkai, Retrofret, Omuse, Studio
Nicholson, and Manners Golf are already
on board alongside 20 plus more global
brands. And here's the problem it's
solving. LLM are building their own
commerce layers right now, and their
incentives are not your incentives as a
brand owner or marketer. They want the
shopper to stay inside the LLM. You want
them to convert, come back, and belong
to you. Every purchase that runs through
a third party AI layer is a customer
relationship that you don't own. So,
swap flips that. The storefront lives on
your domain with your brand voice, your
data, and your customer history. AI is
trained on your catalog, sounds like
you, and every customer interaction,
purchase, and preference stays with the
merchant versus a thirdparty platform.
The numbers from launch have customers
seeing up to 2x conversion rates, 3x
longer time on site, and returns down up
to 20%. So, pretty impressive data, and
this is the window to be ahead and be
working on these things before Aented
Commerce becomes table stakes. You can
check out what swap is building at the
link in the description, and thank you
so much to them for sponsoring this
video. So, in the taste economy, we talk
a lot about things that cost a similar
price to what you would normally buy to
a medium product, but that are a little
nicer or more interesting or have more
interesting branding. That is a separate
economy in my opinion than the luxury
economy where things are radically
overpriced in the name of some obscure
quality metric or selling you the story
of luxury and the luxury brand. This is
when we talk about the Roiana, we talk
about Louis Vuitton, we talk about
Hermes, talk about Reova. These are
luxury brands that really if you are not
in the 1% of consumers, you have no
right buying. But more people consume
than ever. So let's talk about why and
the archetypes behind it. So I've sold a
lot in the category right below this.
And now over the last few years, I've
spoken a lot at luxury companies,
including like at the source in Italy
about how the new world interacts with
this. So I am uh I've firmly been
implanted in how these work and how they
translate into purchase decisions. And
I'm sure the luxury brands wouldn't love
this, but I call it the four archetypes
of people that waste money on luxury
because it is truly you're overpaying
for something. Why? So, first is this
new era customer, the cultural omnivore.
We now have this class of educated
people in the taste economy who
understand and like everything. They are
just as likely to know a bit about wine
and enjoy and be able to participate in
a fine wine while still appreciating a
Miller high life because it's the
champagne of beers. They are fine and
capable of going and sitting and
experiencing the best caviar possible.
and then they might still be hungry and
go get a taco from a taco truck after
and enjoy them in the same amount. They
consume across classes. They like
everything around the world. This is a
huge this whole idea of the millennial
craft movement and millennial food was
largely a precursor to this, right? This
customer comes a lot from that where you
began to say, "Yeah, that little cut
pepperoni is a lot better than the
standard pepperoni. I want only pizzas
that have that." This was a whole
generation that came from this. And that
cultural omnivore is a really important
consumer. They love everything in the
world. Why wouldn't I want to try it, be
interested in it? a generation of people
raised on Bourdain and they're
interesting because they're smart. They
would never spend money on entry-level
luxury, right? That consumer isn't
getting a Gucci wallet. They are a
luxury spender, but their taste has been
built through exposure, through actually
experiencing a bunch of these. So, they
become a great person to sell to if you
sell something worth buying. If you
charge a premium because of the quality,
because the experience is that much
better. This is an amazing target. But
if you charge just for the sake of
charging, this person can go back and
forth between them. And this is a huge
millennial taste demographic. Then we
have a second archetype, the petite
bgeoisi. This is someone who's trying to
be an omnivore. They're reading a bunch
of the substacks. They're watching the
videos. They consume what creators and
influencers are telling them to consume.
This is the person who reads like a man
repeller substack, who will participate
in something like the strategist. They
are trying hard and they're spending
above the money they have. They've begun
to have a little of it and they want to
spend it on a luxury purchase. This is
who buys a Lopeia hat. This is who buys
ESOP hand soap. Who buys Kate denim?
They are overspending in the name of
being educated on it. They're signaling
that they've arrived into money. This is
typically really bad decision-making on
their part. They should be saving that
money. These are all the wrong
purchases, but they're learning on their
way to a different journey. But this is
a really important demographic to
consider because this is the demographic
for the entry-level luxury products. And
if you're this person, I would highly
encourage you in your decisions, don't
spend that money on these things. Try to
get the education, the experience
without buying the overly expensive hat.
Save that money for the more informed
purchase. But if you're selling to this
demographic, it's really about entering
them into something better from there.
About saying, "Okay, you're going to be
able to purchase into our brand. What
does that mean? What do you get? How do
they feel? Do they get the recognition
or things that they desire? And how does
that start them along our brand
journey?" And because of the dichotomy
we deal with as marketers, something I
think about all the time. How do I
consume versus how I sell to people? You
begin to struggle a lot with the natures
of business and commerce and having to
deal with that duality, which we won't
wrestle with too much in this video. And
then we have the true elite, people that
function purely in wealth. To them,
buying a $3,000 luxury item is just
buying a coat. It is normal. It's
participated in. These are really hard
people to market to. People were always
complaining about, "Oh, Gucci is using
AI on Instagram." Guess what? The true
elite luxury consumer does not follow
Gucci on Instagram. Aspiring consumers,
we'll get to in a second, they follow
Gucci on Instagram. Truly does not has
not seen a Gucci AI ad campaign. And if
they did, they have a different feeling
about that, but most of the time they
don't. You can't reach that consumer in
the same way. It's not a consumer you
can easily market to. They are
participating in these luxury economies
because they've been around for a long
enough time. It's simply built into what
they consume and where they consume. And
this is why when people talk about I
want to start a luxury brand or a
premium brand, it's like okay, if you
want to start one, your kids are going
to finish it off. It is a generational
play to be able to get to luxury. And
you have to be able to work your way
through craft through creating an
amazing experience maybe not at that
price point for a long time to be able
to get that recognition that comes from
generations having consumed it. And
that's how you end up in the true elite
consumer. And very few things actually
crack through that wall quickly. And the
last archetype is the aspiring. The
person who doesn't know any, they're not
educated. The difference between them
and the petite bajgeois is they've
started to get money. They're starting
to be educated. They're purchasing their
way to understanding to becoming an
omnivore. But the aspiring don't know
anything about this, but they just see
the Gucci logo. They say, "I want that.
I want a signal. I want a big logo tea."
Whatever it is, whether they have the
money for it or not. These are people
that will buy the cheapest item that's
available to them purely to work as a
signaler. And this is a really hard
thing for premium businesses to work
through. If you do too much of this, you
lose your luxury. If you don't do any of
it, you miss this basically a generation
of people who will maybe over their
consumption time become more luxury
consumers. I think it's really important
to understand those four about expensive
purchases and where do you fit on that
scale and then where does your customers
fit on that scale and then what items do
you have to sell to them and how do you
fix your value proposition and I would
zone in if you sell a premium good on
one or two of those at a time and think
about what is your product and marketing
roadmap look like for them and to give
you an example of this when I worked in
the surf industry we sold really
high-end surf stuff and our ability to
get to the true elite was a lot through
like demo days and showcases in things
like luxury country clubs and boat shows
and places where they already bought in
person. We weren't able to reach them
through like the meta ads or the
influencers etc. It was through long-
form documentary. We did a really long
form documentary with Lar Hamilton about
foiling and NASA that was shared through
the type of people that spend their time
and hobbies and money doing intense
things around the world like that. It
reached the consumer through
storytelling. That's a very different
way than reaching the people we were
able to reach online with content. And
I'll end this section before we go into
this kind of new economy and how it
works to sell to people with just
discussing sociology and psychology for
a second. So, if you've been watching my
short form content and you've followed
me for any amount of time, if you're new
to this, I'll explain a bit my strategy
here. You'll notice it's shifted. I talk
a lot now about insights. I will notice
something happening in culture and I
will create a position around it. I will
take a stance. I will say, I see this
insight. People are doing a certain
thing. They are buying a certain type of
home. Men and women are interacting with
each other differently than they did 10
years ago. Brands are leaning into the
fact that people are increasingly
lonely. Whatever it is, I will take a
stance. I will say I believe a certain
thing. Here's my thesis. And you'll see
in the comments, people either agree
with it or don't agree with it. And this
is because I'm sharpening my blade for
basically how marketing now works
because there's two types of sociology
psychology insights here. And this is
really important to understand. One is
there's insights people know about
themselves. They say, "Yes, I bought
this thing because I want to make
friends. I'm lonely." But you have to
realize there's a conflict in inside
everybody inside their self where
they'll be like, "Oh, I don't want to
believe that about myself. So of course
I'm going to say it's wrong. Of course,
I like my house at the size that it
actually is even if it's too big or too
small for me." I've convinced myself. We
do a lot of convincing of ourselves as
human beings. It's completely natural.
But your job as someone in marketing or
in sales or in social media or
developing a product, working on any
brand is you need to begin to decipher
this. You need to go, is this a real
insight or is this what someone says
about themselves and develop conviction
in your stances and take opinions that
you can then back up with content or
advertising. And I've noticed that more
and more, um, I used to be a very
operational marketer. I can set up a
certain number of ads. We can do a
certain amount of content. We will test
different messages and landing pages and
we will hammer our way to making money
online or supporting our retail partners
through those decisions and messages we
test. Now, I've noticed more and more of
this has become commoditized, right?
Making the landing pages, doing the
media buying, creating the content.
There are more and more and more people
that can do that. It would never be
worth my time to dollar ratio to do any
of that work. The only thing that's left
that's important is the insight is the
idea that can be outperform all these
different things that people can do. It
can make a creator make great content.
It can get a person to convert from a
landing page. It gets someone actually
pay attention to an ad. And so I'm
hyperfocused now on what all those ideas
are and building basically a compendium
of them. And that is a important way if
you are in this world at all or you care
how people think to catalog the things
that are happening to you in your life.
And so I will end this last point. This
is very focused on marketing and brand
people. What is this new economy like to
sell to this premium buyer, this taste
economy? Cuz it's completely different
than the previous world. So marketing
used to work like you would have your
own social media accounts. You have your
Meta account, your Tik Tok account, and
you would have paid ads. You'd run ads
on Meta. You could run ads on banner
ads. You could put billboards up, buy
things in magazines, your newspapers,
and then maybe you would have like some
celebrity endorsement or a few
influencers, right? But that would be
the marketing stack. The last time I had
an SVP of marketing job was basically at
the peak of this when this new world was
being formed. And we were participating
in this new world I'm about to describe
where it's like you have your own
account. You are doing paid media to
promote those owned accounts. But then
you have in what we call enabled
account. People that you seed product
with for free. People that are creating.
You may have 20, 30 creators, hundreds
of creators that are making content
about your message. You have influencers
that you're paying for campaigns. You're
doing experiences or events, but you're
doing it to help enable people to create
content. When you put the billboard up
in Times Square, it's not just about
having people see. It's about having
people take a photo of it and share it.
It's the enabled economy. And this goes
side by side with the taste economy. we
talked about the in the beginning where
taste be comes from this multiplying
factor. It can't just come from your
brand has to come from the world of
people talking about things. And then
the multiplier of that is you can take
any of those things you can put money
behind it. You can boost it. You can
whitelist the ads. You can push that
message out further using your dollars.
So your organic plus you're enabled plus
dollars gives you this much bigger piece
of the pie for marketing. And on top of
that it leads to a more organic
conversation. You execute all of those
well there's even more conversation
around your brand going out in the
world. And a great example from this is
when I was at Coachella the other week.
There was a Gap booth there. I'm wearing
a Gap sweater today. Um unrelated, no
affiliation with Gap, but maybe there's
a psychological connection here. They
had a booth. They were selling Coachella
Gap merch. They had a really popular
Coachella hoodie that they were putting
out. There's a line, just massive line.
My wife was interested in getting one.
Lines were too big the entire time. VIP
line, regular line. Now, you would say,
okay, say Gap spent a million dollars to
do that Coachella activation. Are they
going to make that back in hoodies?
Maybe Bieber did 5 million in merch or
whatever there. Are they going to get an
impressions for the Gap brand because of
people attending that and seeing that?
Maybe what they're really buying is the
fact that there are tens of thousands of
people, not just anybody, people that
post on social media overindex and being
influential, even micro influencers to
major influencers are the people at that
at Coachella. They are making videos
about being in line. They're making
videos once they get the hoodie. If they
buy the hoodie, they're wearing it in
Coachella content, which is
significantly more popular than regular
content. It's a huge content consumption
moment. So, they buy this enabling
ripple effect that is way bigger than
just buying that same event presence
somewhere else. And that is a bit of how
to think in this new economy. So, I'll
leave more of this for kind of the
future. I know there's probably a lot of
questions you have, whether it's around
tactics, whether it's around brands,
drop any of those questions. I'm happy
to get into it. I think our next
community call, which I'll link below,
the one that comes up in June, is going
to be about luxury. It's going to be
about premium positioning and like the
taste economy. And so, um, if you have
questions about that or things to
tackle, feel free to sign up for that
call below where we'll do the big
workshop. We had 300 people on the one
that we did, the last one more. It was
almost 400 as peeking out. That's
simultaneously. There was just tons of
people in there chatting and talking.
So, it's a great time to actually talk
about these and I'm going to keep diving
into the psychology of why we buy and
how to sell in those places. And [music]
as always, thank you all so much for
watching.
>> [music]