In this video, we're going to talk about
the psychology of why people buy. Every
single day, whether you shop online or
shop in real life, you are inundated
with tricks from $9.99 as a dollar value
to sample packs to marketing tailored
specifically to you without you even
knowing it. And all these are tools in
any brand or marketer's toolkit that
they can use to better perform in their
business. It's also things that every
consumer should be aware of so you
understand how you're being sold to and
more about why you make the decisions
you make when consuming. In this video,
we're going to walk through pricing
strategies that will help your products
sell more and give examples of how
pricing and product tie together to form
brand strategy in all kinds of different
niches. And then we're going to dive
into personas, how to break your
customers into specific segments and
give value propositions right to them.
And look at the technology stack to do
that effectively. This is a super
tactical video you can actually apply in
your marketing career as a brand or
really in any business. But as always,
my video's really rooted in the
sociology and psychology of why we buy,
why we think, why we consume, why we
love the brands we do. I hope you'll
have fun no matter what your background
is. There is a super comprehensive free
download that comes with this you can
grab below. It includes how to build
personas, all the pricing tactics, even
info on things like how to connect in
your social strategy. And in the first
week of May, our next community call,
any questions you have, you can come
dive in. There's a link to that below as
well. Let's lock in. So first, I'm going
to speed run through five pricing
psychology techniques. Then we're going
to get into some examples of how brands
structure their product mix to take
advantage of these. So the first concept
is anchoring. The first number that
someone sees on a page reframes every
number they see after it. This is why
you will always see when someone sells
you something in software or similar
that they will have tiers of a high
anchor on the right, a mid-tier in the
middle, and a low option that often
mostly exists to make the center feel
justified or to get someone to buy in to
later upsell them into the other tiers.
This is all about making the product
feel reasonable by strategically pricing
all three. And then retail does the same
thing. Luxury stores don't stock a $900
candle cuz they think you're going to
buy it. They do it to make the $200
candle seem affordable. And the anchor
doesn't have to be your product. It just
needs to be in the frame. In a bit of a
great tactic, Keens does this by
actually listing the typical retail
price that they position against with
their lower price. And you'll see retail
structures a lot like this. Best Buy
will go in, you'll see almost every
category they have, headphones, washers,
TVs have a good, better, and a best.
Someone just wants the price option can
get the good, the best sells a lot
rarer, but helps anchor the price of the
middle, and the middle tends to be a big
selling category. Now, let's talk about
price as a quality signal cuz this is a
big one and one I've had a hard time
learning in my career. But people don't
have perfect information about product
quality. If you saw my videos in prior
weeks where I talk about cashmere,
you'll know that 100% cashmere can mean
completely different things, but still
have the same label. And so on
e-commerce, it's almost impossible to
tell. This is why brands will use price
as a proxy. You may think that your
brand you want to offer people a deal.
You're going to give them an excellent
product at an excellent price. But the
problem is the perception based on price
maybe that your product isn't actually
excellent. So a lot less people even
make the choice of buying it to
understand. I look at this in
streetwear. People always ask, "How do
these brands sell $400, $500 shirts?" In
fact, as someone who sells $80 shirts,
I'll get a lot of people that will say,
"That seems too expensive, $80, $100
shipped." But they're better quality
shirts than the 500. But the boutique
owners and the buyers especially will
go, "Is a sign that something is of a
specific level of designer or a specific
level of value just to be priced in that
range? Of course it's a telltale. Of
course it's not a blank." And if you're
positioning any lower than that, you're
actually lowering the customer
expectation, and you may never even get
a chance to exceed it. This makes sense.
This is a reasonable heuristic in a
world where people can't try everything
before buying. Price things in an
expected way, and know that underpricing
is a brand problem, not just a margin
problem. Then we have charm pricing and
rounded pricing. So $9.99 versus $10.
The difference is 1 cent, but the
psychological difference is actually
much bigger. Prices ending in nine
consistently drive higher volume. This
is true in mass and value categories.
But in premium and luxury categories,
the opposite is true. The rounded
number. Basically, the $10 says we're
not trying to trick you into thinking
that $9.99 is a good deal. We know
you're smarter than that. You will see
that play out in a lot of luxury versus
value brands. And at the same time, you
have what we call lost price points.
$69. There's a reason why everything is
59 or 99. If you go all the way up to
79, you might as well be 99. 69 is so
much more than 50, you're looking for a
49. There's little things in there we
will notice that people gravitationally
pull towards some of these price points
that make sense for them. So now let's
get advanced and let's talk about
pricing as it relates to product and
what different products do to fill in
the consumer experience as a full
product mix or how all the products in a
brand work together. We'll get some
concrete examples. So for instance, when
you go into an Aesop, you'll notice they
have affordable products, $27. You can
get a hand soap in the store. It's
really expensive for a hand soap, but
it's cheap for Aesop overall. This is
what we call an entry-level product. It
gets you into the ecosystem. It's low
risk, it's high trial. They want to make
sure you have a banger for that low that
low price product. So that they want to
then buy more cuz they had a good
experience with it. And then you'll get
the core product. The thing most people
actually buy, the real business. So for
Aesop, a lot of that is 60 to $100 skin
care, expensive premium skin care. And
actual repeat business that people buy
into. And then you have aspirational
SKUs. Dream pieces that sell very little
but help anchor the brand and move
everything else. So if you've ever gone
to a brand page and it's a lot of denim
and shirts but they have a $2,000
jacket, that's an aspirational SKU. And
then for Aesop, they have $200 kits and
fragrances, position Aesop as a luxury,
not just a nice soap by really getting
into higher price points. And they don't
even take full advantage of this the way
some of the brands that we're going to
talk about too. And with them, that
store experience kind of helps close the
deal, right? And then we'll go into Halo
products. These might not even be for
sale. So, for instance, Palace had a car
that they put inside their shoot they
listed for I think it was like 40 grand
or something. You actually buy the car.
District Vision when they launched
cycling had a $10,000 bike. It'll be
like a one-of-one. No one may even buy
it, but it exists to define the ceiling
of what the brand could be. And all of
these work in concert to build an
effective product mix. And you'll notice
if you build out your core product and
you have success with it, you begin
playing in some of those other
categories and they'll drive more sales
to the core. One of the perhaps
legendary examples is this when
Oreo started doing all these legendary
collabs, right? Where they were doing
Swedish Fish Oreos, crazy flavors, Lady
Gaga Oreos. And what they found from the
data is those collabs sell like a little
bit and the flavors sell like a little
bit, but they drive way more sales of
the main line Oreo. They bring people
over to the shelf, they get people
talking about the brand, and they might
laugh and buy a vanity product once, but
they buy more Oreo overall. Apple, they
execute this to a T as you would expect.
Entry-level iPhone SE, the AirPods, low
barrier and you're in the ecosystem. And
you have the core, their iPhones, the
MacBooks, the Airs, the majority of the
product. The Neo, for instance, is a new
entry-level for them. And you have
aspirational, the MacBook Pro, the Pro
Displays. People buy a lot of the
aspirational products, but they're not
for everybody. It positions Apple as a
professional tool you're buying into
even if you get your Air. And then the
Halo is stuff like the Vision Pro. It
exists to say that this is the future
and they're investing in it. It makes a
$1,600 phone feel reasonable. Whether
the Vision Pro works or not. Over at
luxury, we got Loro Piana. Entry-level
$400 to $600 cashmere accessories,
scarves, beanies, small leather goods.
They sell a lot of these cuz people want
to buy into the brand, but they can't
afford the core. The core is frankly
ridiculous. $1,500 to $3,000 sweaters
and outerwear, it's for very few people.
But there's a lot of people that will
flex their way up to that one beanie or
scarf, a pair of shoes even. And then
aspirational, you have to gift the
King's Wool, a $12,000 jacket. That just
exists to help anchor the $3,000
products. You don't need luxury prices
to do this. Glossier is another great
example. Their brow product at $18 gets
someone in. Skin care at $35 keeps you,
and then they upsell into fragrances at
75. Makes them a brand. They do many
things. You can live their experience.
And so, a lot of brands make one of two
mistakes. One is they build too many too
quick. First, you need to build your
core. Get something people want to buy,
and then hit some walls before you start
thinking through all these other things.
Or the second is they only build the
middle. They only build that core.
There's no entry point to help easily
acquire new customers, or they only do
that entry point with sale on core. And
there's no aspirational tier. Nothing to
anchor your prices against. Nothing to
for people to believe there's something
bigger. And if you take this approach in
any level, whether you're a designer,
whether you're a marketer, you work at a
brand, you're launching your own
products, you and whether you're just
consuming, you now understand the
ladders of how you engage. But now to
really put this into impactful tactical
stuff that will help you crush it at
work, I want to talk about personas. So,
what do I mean by that? I mean by the
customers of your brand fall into
categories. They fall into groups based
on similarities of their demographics,
like their age, their race, their
location, and their habits. How they
buy, how they consume online, what they
listen to, what they follow. By
understanding those personas, you can
better craft messaging, you can better
design products, you can better look at
collaborations and marketing and
content. It informs everything. And so,
traditionally, what would happen inside
marketing companies, I've been a part of
this process a hundred times, people
would map those personas out on like a
whiteboard, list them out with a
marketing agency, do this big exercise,
but they would mostly be made up. If
they did get data, they would go and
they'd pay for surveys, right? got to
understand, the only people that would
actually do a paid survey for a brand
are generally one type of customer. And
even if you got those couple thousand,
it's just so heavily skewed. And people
really rely on that data, and you'll see
people that are really in touch with the
consumer, the street team, or the
marketing, or people on social, or
customer support be like, "That's not
quite right." But now you can get way
more tactical. So, one of my absolute
favorite pieces of software, not a
sponsored video, just something that I
use and believe in that I'm trying to
get them to let me invest in, is called
Outer Signal. So, what this does it goes
through your customer base in Shopify or
your email list and basically builds
your personas for you based on the
actual data. So, when I found this, I
was using it for something different.
So, one of the other things that they
do, they just analyze your customers as
they come in. So, for instance, if I got
133 orders like you'll see inside the
screenshot in the last 7 days, it will
tell me, "Okay, seven of them are ultra
high net worth, six of them are
influencers, three are industry experts,
two are relationships to me or the team
somehow, two of media or content
businesses." And it'll actually give me
their information. So, this is a great
tool for actually hunting down
influencers to represent your brand or
to make your UGC content cuz they
probably already have them in their
customers. That's how I found the tool,
but now what we use it for a lot more is
these segments. So, for instance, this
brand is broken down into
high-performance executive, affluent
health investor, wellness professional,
athlete biohacker as a key personas. And
it shows the percent of their customer
base. 14% of their customers are
high-performance executives, 10.8 are
affluent health investors, et cetera. It
also shows the difference in their LTV,
their lifetime value, how much they buy
for you. This matters. This is where you
start to get into the sweet spot where
you can do with messaging. How often do
they repeat? That all gets put inside
this data set. You can actually build
your real personas out. You can say,
"This is the real data from our
customers online or from our email
list." So, related to Claude workflow, I
want to talk about Granola who I've
partnered with on this video. If you're
in a lot of meetings, you probably use
your AI note taker or have someone on
the team that does. And a lot of times
you'll find that what you've actually
done with that goes nowhere. So, I use
Granola to connect my meeting notes to
my real workflow and it's been
invaluable. So, let's talk about it.
Granola's an AI notepad that transcribes
your meetings in the background without
a bot joining the call, no weird robot
participant in Zoom. If you've been in
my Cut 30 chat, you've heard plenty
jokes about that. But listens directly
off your computer audio across every
platform or on your phone for in person.
You can jot a few notes if you want it,
fill in everything around them or you do
nothing. You come out with clean
structured notes, action items, and a
searchable record of the whole
conversation. But the part that changes
my workflow does the MCP integration
with Claude. Granola connects directly
in Claude, which means your meeting
notes become live context inside of it
that you can ask in any chat. You can
reference it or you can just pull up the
notes. You're not hunting for it. You
don't switch tabs, you don't hunt down a
transcript and copy-paste it. It is
there. Claude knows what's discussed and
there's an app there's a connector there
and there's a ChatGPT app. I just happen
to use Claude more and they're both for
Granola. Once you set this up and give
it permission, which is a super easy
process, you can just query your chat,
bring up the date or just the topic that
was discussed and it's going to find it.
It's super useful for bringing up things
in the past you only have light context
for. Remember when we were talking about
that photo shoot or what was the plan
for the social post? I even use it to
suggest video ideas for me personally
based on conversations I've had
throughout the week. What were
interesting topics? What did I talk
about? What were questions people had
inside my Zoom calls? The meeting feeds
the work instead of just sitting in a
folder somewhere. So, somewhat unrelated
but I want to shout out their use of a
spoon as corporate merchandise. It's
clever. You can try Granola for free at
the link below and thanks to them for
sponsoring this video. And so now, what
do you do with that in the modern era?
So, a couple things. Because this is
based on email, you can segment your
email and SMS communications in software
like Clavio or whatever you use to
actually send different messages to
those people based on what they do,
especially based on the lifetime value.
If you have a category that only buys
once and doesn't buy again, specifically
work on targeting them to increase that
LTV over time. If you have people that
buy from you all the time but you're not
marketing to them a lot, market to them
more. Can you build that LTV out way
higher by being more active? Those are
the kind of things you can test. And
used to be with personas you have to
then brainstorm what the angles are. One
thing I love and I include in the guide
that you can get in the free download, I
have my prompt for this. Bring this into
Claude. Bring all the information from
your persona. It's this person, they
have this income, they're from these
places. All the information you can
download or get, put it into Claude
project. Use the prompt that I have that
basically describes how to create
marketing copy. It's designed to create
marketing copy. And what you do with
this, with this specific project, which
again is a collection of the information
about the persona, any brand or product
materials you can add in, and then the
core of this this prompt is basically
the project description. That you're a
copywriter who thinks a certain way,
like a certain marketer. You can adjust
any way you want. Now, you can do three
things. You can write copy for your
landing pages, your emails, and SMS, and
your ads based on this. That's number
one. Number two, you can design the
messaging for your products overall to
be in tune with your customers. And then
three, you can decide how to segment
because just because you have four or
five personas doesn't mean you need four
or five messages. Ask the all-seeing
claw oracle what message would appeal to
multiple. What messages should we
segment when we're launching a product
that has this value proposition? How
does this message stack up against
competition? And it will research it.
Now you're able to do just like actual
interesting marketing. And so what do I
mean by the copy that we get to in the
front? So every e-commerce experience
and also every experience of buying a
high-ticket product or a service or from
an agency or a piece of software comes
down to the ad that gets the person
there. So what is the content you put in
front of them? What are the messages you
can test? What are the pain points
people have? Ask that claw project for
these people's pain points relative to
your product. That's going to give you
ad ideas. But most important is the
landing page. They land somewhere where
you have to sell them with the copy. A
headline, a sub-headline, some bullet
points on why they buy, some frequently
asked questions, maybe a video. And
doing that by persona is going to work
way better because guess what? The
wellness professional that we saw inside
this here who's buying something for
their job is very different than the
biohacker who's trying that same
wellness product because they want to
work on themselves. If you have two
separate landing pages for those and the
messages are great, your conversion
rate's going to raise. And guess what?
Writing that copy with something like
this, putting it into a platform, you
can do landing pages inside of most
email providers, you can do your landing
pages directly in Shopify. There's
software like Replo and Fermat. You can
do it in like InFramer if you have an
agency website, whatever it is. Just
spin up another lander. It's a quick
thing. Once you build one lander, you
can and you already have your
placeholders for your copy and for your
images, just duplicate it and swap it
out with the new ones and you will raise
your conversion rate. And the last one
is the emails. You're sending out a new
campaign, you're doing an automation
sequence. You can build segments based
on these personas automatically. And so
you may have someone who needs more
touches. They need more touch points to
sell or someone who needs a longer form
message. Again, the professional versus
individual consumer is one of the most
blatant ones. That's not even that's a
that's a huge persona rift of I'm buying
this for work versus I'm buying this for
me. If you can segment your email
communications with different messages
around that, it's going to perform
better. This combination of all the
pricing and all the techniques you can
use to price a product, how those
products stack in a mix, whether that's
software, whether that's a consumer good
or food, even a service offering, it's
the same exact thing. What's your
entry-level $99 audit? Really, I want
you to end up buying the $1,000 monthly
package. Then, do I know who my customer
is and do I make messages for them? This
is the time in our world where you used
to have such deep expertise in research
and copy and messaging and marketing to
do this. And you can do an amazing B+
job with a combination of software tools
and some basic street smarts that will
accelerate your career or accelerate
your brand. I would not lose that
opportunity. So, again, this is all
broken down inside a really thorough doc
that you can get for free below. And
there'll be a webinar at the end of the
month to discuss all of it. I would be
stoked to have you there. Uh any
questions you have on brand building,
etc., we can dive into. I appreciate
y'all watching and there's a guide to
yapping coming next week.