how long does it actually take to
concept prepare sample products and
start your brand it is longer than a lot
of people think but it's also one of
those things where if you start now
whether you're fully invested in your
brand Journey or still working on it or
looking for the future you can actually
knock quite a lot out in part-time and
in chunks until you actually get to
bringing your vision to life in this
video we're going to walk through that
entire journey through what you do when
you're first starting out through your
actual sampling process through
production and the time that that takes
to getting ready for launch and I'm
going to break down as much as I can
inside there so you can have all the
tips on things I think you can execute
simultaneously and all the tools I'd
help use to make sure you're successful
I've been in the middle of sampling and
creating a bunch of things myself for
the new valuables brand that uh I'm
putting together that I'm using to
leverage a bit of my Creator audience to
put some cool Visions I think are really
interesting into life and so I'll show
off a bit of that on the way as well so
we can actually kick off there so I do
have some new samples so first starting
off is these bags which I plan to put
all the hats we put in all the small
Goods uh put some decent time into
making sure it was a nice premium bag
reusable I really always love those old
Crown Royal bags I used to keep them so
we did that here uh it only took one
sample to get this we we designed it
they' sent me a bunch of fabric options
let's see what's inside pulling out uh
so as many of you know the brand I'm
working on is car themed uh these are
leather versions of the classic fuzzy
dice uh some studs on them put together
by a chain we went back and forth and
sampled these the sampling process and
getting everything done with the factory
probably took about 30 days uh we'll
dive into that in the sampling section
but stok to put these together try out
some different leather try out some
different studs and uh make something
cool going all the way back to the
beginning if you want to start a brand
someday where do you begin so step one
and I can't recommend this highly enough
is that you need to build an audience
now there's a couple ways to go about
this doesn't mean you have to go be a
Creator and talk to the camera like I'm
doing that is way number one become a
Creator in your nich become an
influencer of some kind P yourself out
there and get a following enough you may
be able to bring them into the products
that you're creating number two is you
can actually document the brand journey
and do what's called building in public
and cover all the things that go into
the decisions you're making and there's
a number of good strategies for doing
that but the third is just curating
content in your Niche so uh my friend
Sam for instance has a really awesome uh
Instagram account and blog that's based
on cars and he has a car themed brand
that's been born out of that but to
start it really was just curating cool
imagery news and things happening within
that space that is an amazing way to
bridge audience into being able to
launch a brand without having to
actually put your face out there or tell
everyone the story of what you're
building but no matter what whether you
are 3 months away from creating your
brand or 3 years away from creating your
brand start with audience and why do I
say this because there's a there's a few
things at some point you're going to
have to get social media right anyway
there's very few businesses aren't able
to succeed with that in our current
world and for a lot of people the
ability to create that content or have
their story if you start that once your
whole brand is developed and all your
products are already created you're
starting it too late if you end up not
being good at it you're going to be in a
world of hurt and so being able to
figure that out and actually be like hey
I got this even though that might take
30 days 100 days a year is going to show
you that you have the potential to do
that business it will validate for you
your ability to be an entrepreneur by
your ability to navigate and either work
with others or by yourself to understand
and Excel on social media and then
number two is once you have it it's an
eternal source of organic sales if
you're in a business where you either
have to rely on retail to make sales for
you or you have to pay via advertising
to get the sales you want you're always
going to be in have your future in
someone else's hands but if you have
organic attention and you have some sort
of following whether it's any of the
ones I described you have the ability to
continuously just put out more content
connect to the people that you were
trying to sell to and sell products and
being able to do that at the price of
merely creating content or merely just
putting a story on Instagram that is a
huge leg up that I cannot even begin to
describe how much of an advantage it is
versus basically generations of
launching products prior and you should
take advantage and keep this going and
keep that following building up
throughout the entire process that I'm
about to break down now comes phase two
and I typically would say is about 90
days now I'm going to give a lot of time
frames here time frames definitely vary
brand to Brand industry to Industry it
will take more time sampling something
really complex with long production time
overseas versus will doing something
domestically it also could be more
complicated formulating like a beverage
than it will be to get a shirt design
there's all kinds of caveats ifs and
buts but I'm just going to give a
generic time frame that shows you kind
of how long it takes to put together and
for context it is now March of 2024 no
when you'll be watching this video but
if you wanted to get a brand live for
this holiday season peak selling you
need to be starting today in my opinion
to have that done and well executed
without kind of hacking the system with
any like easy you know we using someone
else's product or Drop Shipping or
whatever you want to build something
well architected if you want to be Live
for November December next year you are
doing that now back to the beginning
brief and research your product that is
the first thing to work on so what do I
mean by brief and research I'll do a
whole video on comprehensive briefs uh
coming up um as some of you may know I'm
working on a bag product with my friends
at shift uh they have a really cool
design and manufacturing business and
we're actually going to run through
their entire brief process and brief I
put together for this bag in a future
but a brief and a design is really what
you want to come out with and this is
what you're going to give to your
manufacturer this is a description of
your product and all the guidelines with
which they need to produce it so if you
are creating a candy bar you're going to
need to have some sort of recipe or at
least a list of things you're going to
want to get to work with your factory to
get to a certain taste or volume uh if
you're creating a shirt you're going to
want to have your Tech pack and all the
things that make that special if you're
creating a lamp you're going to want
your various diagrams or models you you
need to be able to create the exact
picture of what you are going to want
produced and you're going to be able
want to describe it and walk through
what makes it different how is it better
than its competition how are you going
to sell it actually go through the steps
and process of what exists in the market
today and how you're making something
better and just to give it a quick
overview ways to make something better
are can you make it cheaper than what's
currently offered on the market and
offer a value can you make it more
premium and a significantly better
experience and charge more than what's
on the market do you solve some crucial
usability issue or have some like
amazing upgrade versus what already
exists does it taste better it feel
better would you like to use it more and
then last does it appeal to some
particular Niche to some people better
than others hey I'm going to make soccer
shorts for people who have really skinny
thighs whatever the right thing is that
you say hey I'm zoned in on this really
specific thing and I'm going to make
something for them those are beginnings
of the different ways you can
differentiate your product inside this
process and to do it you need to
research you should be looking at every
product on the market how do they list
their specs what does their stuff made
of how do they sell versus the
competition how do they come up how many
iterations it take to get there what
have they changed from previous
generations of their product to now take
the time to understand it while you're
developing that brief and getting
designs done and whatnot you want to be
working on your brand as well I covered
naming in my previous video but here you
want to be thinking about what is my
actual brand name what is my logo what
are the different things fonts colors
that represent my brand what does design
look like and then doing that process
hand inand with the product creation
because a lot of those same questions
about who am I selling this to how is it
better are going to end end up being
things that are important to reflect in
The Branding you do people always ask
how do I find people to work on these
things um there's always the like very
cheap route of going to upwork or Fiverr
some of these folks and finding somebody
overseas that can work on it I'm more of
a favor of finding people on social
media people that are putting their
portfolios out there on Twitter and
Instagram in particular and saying oh
I'm making beautiful work and you know
they're trying to promote it and being
able to see that and engage with them
there and understanding they have some
social Savvy and hiring people that way
obviously you can work within your
network and Google but it's worth
finding like other professionals like at
your level or who are working on
something together that especially
people that are already on social media
cuz I think that's there's something
important to actually Bridging the Gap
between those and then the last part of
what happens in phase one is researching
vendors how do I find someone to make my
product I'll do a whole video video on
how do you find factories but the short
version of it right now is I really like
Petra who I work with extensively I
found the provider that's making the
shoes that I am creating in Pietra I'll
grab those real quick if you haven't
seen these These are the sneakers that
I'm working on like a skull from the
side and Top This rope lace this is just
V1 V2 is actually going to be quite a
bit different uh but I found this vendor
that I'm making this with on Petra what
I like about them is they have prev
vetted products uh suppliers so
basically they've already talked to all
the factories on there versus someone
like Alibaba which just anyone could be
on and so all these people you know have
already at least been through some level
of vetting process with the Petra team
and also if you pay for the more premium
version they have uh you get like a
concierge who will help connect you to a
vendor and communicate with the vendor
and like honestly for a couple hundred
bucks if you don't have experience in
this process getting a pro in there and
shout out to Alex who's helped me again
and again on there then like you can
actually navigate that process really
well a good example of this is I was
creating a cleaning product for a client
a year or two ago I don't know how to
create a cleaning product I know a lot
about sourcing and brand development and
packaging but they were able to connect
me to someone who had done a similar
project for another client they knew
exactly what I was looking for made the
process really streamlined and I really
appreciated it and beyond that I think
Google's another place to go uh
especially if you're looking for local
things if you're trying to produce in
the US they doing things industrial
there's Thomas net there's obviously
always Alibaba and you know there'll be
referrals for people that you know and
find but really Petra and Google are a
great place to go start and if you're
looking for beverage you can search for
term co-packer um there's a lot of like
kind Nuance there but you spend time on
Google and YouTube you'll find out what
you actually need to search for what I
recommend doing in that phase is getting
a list so having multiple options there
that you then go and bring your brief
and your designs to and you're going to
be able to say hey I want to create this
what does that process look like how
long will it take what will the cost be
what's the benefits of working with you
and you can compare those vendors to one
another to see who you want to work with
and I'd recommend probably trying or
sampling with two because you always
want to have redundancy and if you just
take the first quote that comes apart
you're not going to know if there's some
huge disparity in what's being created
and that brings us to the next phase you
have your product brief and your design
you have your brand identity you found
some factories now you're going to get
into sampling so for sampling so if
you're a new brand you're going to pay
some money to get a V1 of your product
done then you're going to likely want to
change what you see in the V1 and then
get a V2 done and you'll also pay for
this over time if you have relationships
or you spend a bunch of money with
factories a lot of your sampling will
end up being free so a good example for
some things on work work on doing some
some valuable belts this is one of the
first samples I got I was basically
comparing Hardware uh and the actual
style I ended up really liking the belt
style liking this hardware for the
future but not really into it for this
first one I I got this style with this
hardware and really liked that I ended
up going with this belt with a different
piece of hardware and then in its final
iteration I ended up with this
particular hardware on uh with this belt
in a different color and one of those
other options and took a few iterations
but they sent me these samples i' work
with the fact a bunch before so this was
one where I wasn't paying for the
sampling but if I was I'd be expecting
to pay you know 30 40 bucks for
something like this all the way up to 40
or 100 for more complicated garment and
you know even up way higher if you're
doing something that's really special
but so you're going to need a budget for
sampling expected to take multiple
rounds and what you're really going to
want to do is get your sample and then
detail back what you want to be improved
and what you want to see different and
then make sure that they're taking that
into account and you're communicating
well together during the process there
is a lot of dead time in the sampling
process you send your design they put in
in Q to be produced they it they send
you some pictures then they mail it to
you then you go get your feedback and
then you do it all again and so this is
why I recommend doing a lot of your
setup while you're sampling set up your
Shopify store set up your email
marketing I'm using brevo for mine I
have no relationship or affiliation with
them they were just like a cheap option
I actually looked at who had the most
features for the cheapest thing most
people use clavo for for what they're uh
working on with this register your
social media accounts you don't have
them already take care of all the
logistics you need in your business
while you're sampling it's also a great
time if you want to be submitting
trademarks some of the things I talk
about within the naming video I did and
just making sure all of your ducks are
in a row for when you're done sampling
cuz after this you're going into
production so once you have something
that you want to make and everything is
good to go you actually are going to Get
It produced now a couple things that
happen here sometimes you'll be
producing and they going be packaging
everything and getting it ready for
production in the one place sometimes
you're going to be making something
somewhere else it's going to get cased
or finished at like another facility
just Logistics we're going to assume
that everything's getting done in one
place it's going to get produced that
takes x amount of time let's say 30 to
45 days for a soft good and then it's
going to need to get shipped and
shipping you save money if it can you
can take longer time so for instance you
can ship by boat there's what's called a
fast boat and then there's air uh and
you kind of have the cheapest option
which is the regular boat to the most
expensive option which is shipping it
via air I would always recommend
building in the time to try to ship by
boat it saves a significant amount of
money especially if you have like a
heavy item if you're making small things
your jewelry or whatever just air it
it'll get there right away but let's
assume that it's going to take your 45
days for production and another 45 days
for shipping by boat and you know back
in the height of the pandemic sometimes
that was 60 days if you're on a fast
boat sometimes you can end up in 30 days
varies a bit but you'll work get through
with your either your manufacturer or
your Freight forwarder which is a term
for a logistics agent you can work with
if you're looking for somebody like that
feel free to DM me anywhere I'll help
connect you to people I've work and also
know that Petra when you work through
them they also have a freight forwarder
option that you can just use while
production is happening again more
downtime so usually what I recommend
doing is using your samples because you
should have a couple things that are
mocked up and close to right from the
sampling process if not completely right
or get them to produce a thing and shend
to quick and use that to make all of
your content and do all of your launch
prep while you are waiting for your
stuff to be produced so basically build
out your content plan make sure you have
a bunch of stuff shot your e-commerce
images are ready you have teasers online
you've you gotten picked out your
influencers done all the things you want
to do for launch and you're ready to go
you also want to set up your fulfillment
if you're going to be shipping your own
orders or you going to be then uh you
know make sure you're set up and Shopify
with something like ship station how are
you printing your postage do I call a
carrier does USPS pick up from my house
whatever your your Solutions will end up
being going through all that or finding
a 3pl I'm using the Petra 3pl on mine
they have a warehousing service that um
addition to the factory it makes it
really easy um I'm just starting with
them so I can't critique it super
thoroughly but once I do I'll make a
video breaking down the process and then
when you're product arrives you're going
into launch making sure everything's
ready to go actually QC checking
everything that you see uh you can ask
them before shipment to send you a nice
list of Okay can send me these pictures
show me these things make sure
everything's to your spec before it gets
shipped uh and then you actually want to
make sure youve seated your product out
everything's ready to roll and then you
actually launch put all that social
media you have into uh and all the
presents and things you have together
into creating one great moment and we'll
do a whole video on launch strategies
and drops and pre-orders and stuff um at
a later time but if you add all those
times together we're going to say cool
you're going to establish your social
media for a bit curate in your Niche we
won't even count that time on here but
you have your designing branding time
let say that's 90 days so 3 months your
sampling time about 60 days now we're
about 5 months our production time and
shipping at about another 60 days now
we're about 7 months um so that would
you know then you say hey my launch
period at least a couple weeks getting
everything right and ready and or about
eight months that is a real realistic
timeline for most Industries to go from
I have a good idea and some resources
and I'm starting today to I am ready to
go and sell my stuff again there's
faster ways to do it there will be
products that take much slower I would
say all the things that I'm working on
um which I've been taking my time on and
obviously do like kind of part-time
additionally all the other things I do
you though I have a team to help is you
know we have been probably eight nine
months in to to get to where we are
about to start selling stuff in the next
few weeks so that is a just a good
guideline to have we have those phases
um it's a great road map to actually
just really practically look at the time
commitments and when you go and then
think about when it's going to hit so
holiday is an amazing period right if
you are your stuff is done in October so
you're selling in November and December
everyone's shopping depending on the
seasonality of your product if people
use it Outdoors whatever it is you can
adapt a bit January February is rough
everyone just spent in the holidays it's
cold short months people tend to be out
of money that's not the best most ideal
time to launch but overall is we're
think about when those months will be
when might resonate most with your
audience if you're selling something
that might be really useful for
Valentine's Day or people are going to
be you know spending their time with in
their summer um think about what the
seasonality of that looks like and begin
timing what you do accordingly so you
can always push pieces of this and say
you know what I want to do it but I
don't want to go into production until a
month later or or oh man I need to speed
up this process because otherwise I
won't make holiday which kind of means I
have to wait another six months for my
product will resonate these are
important things to consider we're going
to hit tons more in all these videos
that are going to come up next about all
the different parts of this process I'll
probably do a video on every single step
inside of this uh so please like And
subscribe those are all going to be on
the 30 days of building a brand playlist
list that you'll see and any questions
you have anything you want to see more
information on please drop below and I'm
stoked to
share