we are living in a world that does not
want you to lock in everything around us
is designed to distract from our
creative talents being brought into the
world if you want to take the things
that are in your mind and bring them
into reality you need to relentlessly
rip them out while everything in the
world focuses on distracting you and the
creative mind whether it's the ADHD mind
the introverted mind that needs its
space the extroverted mind that needs
people is just not designed to deal with
all the things that we deal with in the
modern world but locking in or not right
now is the difference between living in
that constant world of Never Enough of
chasing other people's dreams versus
beginning to unlock having it all and by
having it all I'm never the person that
said this is a million dollars a year or
you do X and you make y having it all is
about bringing your Visions into reality
about living a fulfilling creative life
about being a kind of person who can act
on ideas and who can work on ideas with
others and get immense fulfillment out
of it that is much more powerful than
money is much more interesting and when
pursued in the right way whatever
abundance that you want in your life
generally comes with it so in this video
we're going to hit how do you lock in
I'll start with why the time is now
because we are in this era of creators
social media and marketing Acumen that
is very unique and if you have any of
the skills of that group you are just
ultimately qualified to be massively
successful in this era and then I'm
going to hit how to shift your mind
because it is a battle it is hard but
there are tactics that work to actually
get there and then I'm going to shift a
bit to tactics to operate for those who
watch a lot of my YouTube videos you'll
see I have like extensive notion docs on
all the things I talk about I'm go a
little through the process and the
organization that you use for things
like that and the process and
organization you use to scale creative
it'll be an introduction to it and help
you develop some creative process and
what I like to call rituals help you
engage all those parts of your brain of
your ideas the people around you and
begin to actually scale some Vision to
reality it's going to be an interesting
ride so first who am I to talk to you
about any of this I work on a lot of
creative businesses and I work on only
businesses I find are interesting that
ranges from a women's wear business I've
worked on for years to an engineering
agency I've had for even longer to if
you follow some my more recent videos a
wellness business we just launched my
own kind of personal brand and then a
brand derivative of that I'm launching
off of it multiple Brands I advise for
and then just over a long period of time
I've been able to work on just
interesting project after interesting
project but the thing that has kept me
both successful on social media and
successful in this work is that I just
continually ship if I have an idea for a
product I know how to bring it into the
physical world if I have an idea for a
design I know how to get it on screen I
then know how to get teams to scale
those things from there how to create
content after it it moves how to launch
a product from it and take money and
we've just refined those over just
repetition and repetition project over
project and over that time as a CMO a
vpa marketing a director of marketing a
creative director I've just managed
large creative teams and even now my
whole life is run by a freelance network
of people that I work with on some
capacity to do X or Y and so a lot of
optimizing that life has just been about
how do you make sure creatives are in
their Zone because it's not traditional
management it's not like the same
one-on-one structure there's just a lot
of things that are just Nuance to people
that have ideas versus people that
produce constantly but I've been doing
it year over year now almost decade over
decade and I think we can really break
it down to what will work and just have
a great basis for so many of you all
right that takes us to chapter one why
the time is now why do we need to lock
in cuz it almost seems like a good time
not to lock in everything is in chaos in
the world we have so many distractions
such just sit there on the phone on
social media we have amazing
entertainment we have a whole world of
swiping left or right on dating at our
fingertips why do we want to Zone in
right now and my content is for Creative
what I mean by creative you might be in
any kind of job if you're an idea person
if you're a design person if you you
know like to create visual thing if you
like to write if you like to bring ideas
to life that is a creative person and
you may find that in almost any field
but a couple things make this period in
time right now particularly special the
first is the creator era a lot has been
talked about this but you can literally
transform your life in 6 months a year
by participating in the online social
experience why do I say that because I
did it I started making content on short
form maybe about 20 months ago now
within 6 months I was making money off
it and my life had transformed within a
year and a half my life now has
everything I've ever wanted from it and
then working through cut 30 I've seen it
happen again and again with people
person after person who begin to pursue
that passion it works for them they have
that right fit of the content they're
making in the internet and they're able
to blossom into a lot more than they
ever thought they could do and this is a
unique error it wasn't always like this
if you were trying to grow on Instagram
like this six or seven years ago that
wasn't there there wasn't Tik Tok there
wasn't all the same things it was just
significantly more complicated to do it
and at the same time there's this
infinite demand level because not
everyone is destined to want to be a
personal be a personal brand but if you
get the skill set for it there's also
this other side of it that's that every
brand right now needs a Creator and I'm
going to touch on things that aren't
specifically related to social media so
don't worry this video isn't all about
that the marketplace for people that can
create content for brands that will work
on social media is like ridiculously
massive uh my friend JT has a whole
service Creator X where he helps match
Brands and creatives and if I was to
tell him I have 100 creatives here that
make content that's good enough for
Brands I think he would be ecstatically
over the moon to be able to have that
much Supply to be able to bring to all
the brands that and that's happening on
short form they need creators to be
their face creators to contribute to the
ongoing efforts of the brand to help
tell their story and their narrative in
a way that gets that eventually gets
sales that's not even touching on what's
Happening from a long form perspective
or an awareness perspective or the more
interesting ways to approach these
platforms because you can't just start a
brand Channel on YouTube expected to
succeed talking about your product you
have to treat a brand channel the way
I'm treating this if my channel was a
long-term scop for a designed software
company that probably their best
marketing approach to go give a ton of
value for free around a personality but
that's something that Brands can't
engineer in house you need to go find
people who have the desire to go create
like that the skill set to do it and
some level of knowhow and experience on
how it gets done and it's one of those
things that if you are somewhat creative
tangential and you begin to look at the
tools you start to pick up cap cut and
learn how to edit use the green screen
effects Etc you begin to edit your
background social media graphics and
titles and whatnot in combo or adobe you
understand a bit of the distribution
mechanisms you can YouTube enough design
and make good thumbnails you can write
some provocative captions you can
research hooks you can archive you can
mood board you have some of these
tangential skills even if few and you
lean into it you become oh this is
actually a formula it's easy it's
something that you can lean into and you
can get some degree of success right
away if you're any what creative
tangential but if you're not near any of
those things you've never edited or
tried to edit a video before you've
never captured something Crea if you've
never written something for the purpose
of getting a response from someone else
this is entirely foreign they can't do
it and all these archetypes of old like
the adage CMO World they don't get it
they won't figure it out and they are
doomed to obscurity to be replaced by
the people that get this era so that is
0 one you can capitalize on this not
only could you build something for
yourself but you are now employable in a
way that you have never been before and
absolutely critical to Brand success in
any industry you want to place it into
and that ties very well into Point
number number two which is the marketing
toolkit you'll notice that there is not
a ton of great performance marketers out
there that are available for brands
people that can help scale your meta ads
people that can help crush it on social
media and if you ever wondered why that
is it's because at some point everyone
who's making money for other people
whether you're at an agency or at a
brand you're in the meta account and
you're like wait I'm getting 3xtra
return on ad spend on these campaigns
because we've done X and Y and I'm
helping put these creatives together and
you you look at the numbers the numbers
are right there you we're spending $600
we're making $1,800 we're spending
$60,000 we're making $180,000 whatever
that derivative is and you go that's not
money I'm making that's money someone
else is making and guess what making
that product that's a commoditized thing
plus it's some amazing idea and all
those marketers at one point go I can do
that myself or I can partner with
someone else and do it and have a huge
ownership chunk and that is why there
are so few good people and if you are in
the skill set and you're still left in
that bucket there's a lot of young
performance and growth marketers out
there who begin to get the skill set the
faster you shift over into using that
skill set to making the dollars for you
the better is setting the stage for one
of the most important jumps in your life
you have the hardest tool kit figured
out succeeding in our current ERA in the
way ads and organic social work you have
either of those you are at the peak of
your powers and you combine that with
the ability for a brand to come out of
nowhere and grow on social media
significantly and this overall Zeitgeist
that whole Generations have where they
distrust the corporations we grew up
with they don't necessarily want to buy
old school brand names they're
interested in new things they want to
build Affinity to smaller Brands they're
struck by interesting content and you
basically have this massive incumbent
Market of everything we've ever bought
from any major brand you can Chip Away
dollar after dollar at and make that
dollar for yourself in anything from
water bottles to clothing to snacks to
electronics almost any dollar that we
spend in our lives that opportunity is
like too much to pass up whether you
want to play a major role in it and you
know bring all of your own ideas and
Entrepreneurship to reality or you just
want to say I want to leverage myself to
be the most interesting scenario I could
possibly be in doing work that is
fulfilling for me as a part of a larger
team this is the best ERA for that so
that's the stage I'm going to set before
going into so how do you lock in there's
a really important book by an author
named Steven pressfield go on a quick
Steven pressfield Rabbit Hole one of the
things I like most about him is that he
has a series of historical fiction uh he
includes Gates of Fire which 300 is
based on a whole series on Alexander the
Great including one of my favorites
which is the Afghan Campaign which is
about how Alexander the Great Lost in
Afghanistan which is very relevant to
how the US lost in Afghanistan kind of
the nature of the world and he also
wrote a some some non-fiction books
including one that every creative should
read called The War of art this is a
fundamental book for me in me locking in
at the point I did in my life and in
this book he breaks down very
practically the reason I talk about the
what he's written before is I love to
see someone who's obviously churned out
so many amazing pieces of his own art
then put out a book where he's actually
describing the process I love The
Duality of that something that I
obviously do in my own content and so in
the war of art he breaks down this
concept called the resistance and the
resistance is every single thing going
on in your life that's pulling you away
from what you should be doing and you
can categorize it and you can view it as
an end it comes down to this innate
human instinct that we've all been
battered against that we can't have
anything be good or bad we can't hate
anything we can't love anything too much
we have to make sure our opinions are
appropriately whitewashed for the
internet when in reality there's
something that we should be fighting
against every day and it's in human
nature to want to have an enemy to
position against something to be
combative but if you put that energy
that's kind of within you and you say I
am combative against everything that is
holding me back that is a massive
foundational Concept in your head that
can take you a long way no matter who
you are I would highly recommend reading
that book I'm going to use that concept
of the resistance which I'm going to
play to you every single thing that's in
our lives every app that's on this phone
we've seen this transition I feel like
it's a good transition in content where
a lot of people are consuming less I'm
going to laugh stupid content and more
value content they're bookmarking it I'm
a I've Had My Success because of the
value market value content marketing era
where people are saying I want to save
tips I want to learn I'm going to
repurpose some of my screen time to
things that are beneficial that's a good
thing but just step one because we spend
these hours in a day all the success
that we could have is locked in our
screen time whether it's on the phone or
whether it's on Netflix or whether
people around us are sucking it out of
us or jobs are going too far and taking
it from we have 24 hours in a day that
are basically being nipped from us piece
by piece by all these people that want
our attention and our attitude so the
first thing you need to do is fight
against us in every way you can some
exact tactics that worked for me
Hardware advice I I am trying called a
brick that helps shut your phone down I
had a case I was using until recently
that was a weapon of Mass distraction I
have on the back of my phone it's a
mental reminder there's an app called
one sec where you can basically limit
your social media time or force you to
take a breath before you go into your
social media time any tool that you can
get anything you can spend money on $20
$40 $10 that reduces any amount of time
that you spend doing [ __ ] is is
worth it run all of them force yourself
to be on all of them but you need to add
that factor of you being conscious of
where your time is going and I would
just write it out look in a day to
catalog your next two days how long do
you spend watching Netflix on your phone
doing things that didn't matter be
conscious of it as option one segment
one and then segment two is apply
constraints I'm going to show these
Graphics from visualized value which
really sum up the points where I make
here is that you have all these ideas
you want to bring to life so many people
do and if you don't you at least know
that you do want to bring some idea to
life you just haven't defined it but
what's happening is it's too big of a
thing it's easier to go just open and
scroll again versus saying I need to
Define this and so constraints are
massively important this visualized
value graphic basically has this idea
that hasn't come to fruition on one side
versus I'm going to finish one thing a
day and people ask me all the time how
do I do so many business how am I
involved in so many things and is
because I am relentlessly focused on the
one thing a day Ru every one of my
projects I do one thing a day they all
move slower than I want them to I wish
some of them were scaling to the Moon I
wish I had more time for an ex or Y but
no matter what for each one of them
every single day I move one ball forward
I complete one task one thing pushes
this closer to completion and if you
look at that same thing for whatever it
is you're trying to do decide on it
build a better portfolio make a video on
social media launch your brand learn how
to be an illustrator become amazing at
Tech packs learn how to sew Master Excel
become a 3D artist whatever one thing a
day ideally creating and finishing of
things you're you're applying repetition
to the idea of getting better this is
how I got huge on short form video One
video a day and I just never stopped I
started making it in the first few
months I got a bunch of videos out there
it weren't that great eventually they
started to crack through a bunch of my
friends started joining and working with
me I'm the only one that just never
stopped that's the difference between me
and everyone from that era is I'm the
only person that's stuck to a video a
day throughout the entire thing and
that's why I'm the biggest of all those
folks not because I'm any better or had
any better content or any better ideas
but Sheely because of the repetition to
take it there so now we have we're
fighting every ounce of where is our
time wasted we have constraints to act
on what we need to act on the last thing
is establishing a contract with yourself
cuz this is the big thing right we all
try to do [ __ ] every month I try to go
you know what I'm going to eat less
carbs I'm going to really dial in my
diet this month yeah and I'm going to
get to X and Y and guess what I I never
hit and that's because I'm violating a
contract to myself I don't ever take it
seriously enough to be like I'm going to
sign a piece of paper to me or whatever
or whatever physical Incarnation that I
want to actually put out there lock in
the world says this is important enough
for me to do it it is obvious that that
is not important enough for me to
actually do because there are plenty of
things that are important enough for me
to do is get the [ __ ] for my brand
shipped make sure my content comes out
every day make sure my weekly YouTube is
live those things are important to me I
have made a contract with myself I'm not
going to let that [ __ ] Fall by the
wayside and I'm executing on it and
there's some things where I just haven't
gotten there yet and you need to decide
of the things you want to do I just them
out what do you want to do the next 5
years where do you want to go decide
which of those are important enough that
you don't want to violate the contract
with yourself that you want to lock in
and you want to say this is a thing I'm
doing and then now is the thing that you
put your word on that is more important
than your health that is probably more
important than things that you enjoy and
fun you decide where that scale is you
need to basically say this is more
important than most of the things in my
life to ensure I do this thing and they
need to break it down to what do you do
every day because there is no I'm going
to do it once a week I'm going to do it
whatsoever there is how do I achieve
this goal and move the ball forward
every day and you either commit to doing
it at that level or you don't so
wherever you are right now again you
want to start posting on social media
you want to build your portfolio you
want to become a better illustrator what
do I do every day do one t-shirt design
every day one 3D piece of art every day
I add one thing to the portfolio I write
one personal essay give yourself these
blocks of I'm going to do 20 of these
I'm going to do 100 of X I'm going to do
90 of X I'm going to build it into a
habit and I'm going a habit stack I'm
going add another thing on top of it
once I have one make the list of what
those things are act on them and for
people that are in these unique
positions like hey I'm a performance
marketer I'm at a company right now I
have a pretty good job I know I've been
making a lot more for myself your goal
is like you're never going to make a
change while you're comfortable you need
to put a plan into action or else you're
going to keep working at a place forever
if you go I want to have my own brand to
take advantage of this or I want to be
you know I want to move from being a
social media assistant place it doesn't
matter to a Creator where it's somewhere
great like what is your 90day plan I
would just break it down to my goal is
to do X I list that out I backlist what
are all the things that have to get done
for me to do that and then you kind of
list that breakdown in the tasks to ask
this person do this you massive list and
you go and you say all right how many
things are on this list 65 90 101 one
thing per day list that out I've believe
in myself that I'm going to do it cross
it off until it's done this is locking
in and for creatives we are taught in so
many ways that we need to wait for the
ideas to come that we need to put the
art before the algorithm or that we
shouldn't be thinking with the that part
of our brain or we shouldn't be Alpha in
one way or the other you are for La of
better term the [ __ ] wolf in this
scenario and you need to do these things
to get yourself where you want to go and
the last piece that we're going to hit
on here is the how I live my life in
notion dot I have an example here and
the important thing to do when you're
doing something like this is to have a
place to put your tasks and your
references in your project so for every
project I do I put everything in one
place put all my references into a place
I put all the working ideas I have all
the written things that are actually
happening and then at the top this is
where it's crucial we actually have the
things that are going on in the project
in a table with what the responsibility
is what the next step is what we're
waiting on and some level of tracking
and accountability for who does what
next and then right below that every
single one of these is just a checklist
just a to-do list of what are we
Crossing off you can do this in any
software you want but if you literally
have all of your references all your
working ideas a table of the things with
some accountability and what the next
steps are and then a to-do checklist
you're going to be able to accomplish an
awful lot add a calendar on top of that
of what's actually happening day by day
so you can go look at Thursday or prep
for tomorrow or whatever to know what
the actions are and then you can start
color coding things by person if you
have a bigger team you can tag and all
that that's why I like notion for this
or reference other documents you are
beginning to build a command center for
how you tactically execute a thing so
for instance if you were saying I'm
going to build a social media presence
for my brand you're building this out I
begin to scour the internet for
references what are other brands what's
content they make I'm I would have a
goal of putting 50 references of videos
of styles you'd like to do inside of
this Doc and I look one step further how
do I actually do that I don't know how
to do this I'm going get what are the
things I need to have tutorials for I
need to be able to make this effect I
need to be able to use cap cut to do
that how do I do this punching how do I
light my videos what mic do I need I
would put all those questions in there
and then begin to add in resources it's
now a to-do list for me to watch when I
add in those to-dos I'll go out to my
checklist and I'm going to go all right
each one of these I to learn how to do
Blank That's now a thing I can check off
then you're going to go to all right I'm
going to make a plan I and be able to
start making this video by this time
this video by that time and begin to
think of what are the realistic dates
with which you can learn the things that
you want to learn begin to do some
drafts and to actually publish and begin
to Overlay that on a calendar and every
video that you're going to do becomes a
line in your table where are you at does
it need a script do you not know enough
to do it what is your next step and you
can look at that from anything building
a design portfolio launching a brand
signing t-shirts begin to have this
framework here we can go look at your
entire project and this is a great
framework to apply to client work cuz
they can see exactly where you're at all
the things are in one place they can
look at Calenders they can look at who's
doing what what's waiting on them versus
what's waiting on you so you can use
this format in a lot of different ways
and you can begin to build it in your
life and the last thing I like to look
at is like what's repeatable do want to
put a segment in somewhere you're saying
hey every Monday I do this every Tuesday
I do this begin to build I like to call
rituals CU I want to be like a schedule
creativity is not about schedule it's
about a thing that you do like Sundays I
always prep my week ahead Saturdays I
always shoot these YouTube videos
Mondays I'm usually putting together a
all the written work I do for the week
and like organizing it out these are
things where you know you need to get in
the right frame of mind to make sure all
certain things are prepared and that's
why I like that ritual concept for like
yeah you know what I'm going to do first
I'm going to get my sparkling water I'm
going to get my cold brew take this
supplement I'm going to do whatever I'm
going to make sure I exercise first and
I'm going to create the environment
where my head is in the place to execute
this I'm going to put that in the
calendar so it happens every week so
that my creativity falls on some type of
schedule and there will always be time
where you can have open time or things
will come to you or not but aren't able
to just free will it having those
structures in place is critical I know
this is a little bit of a different
video than many that I've done but I do
feel like if you're at that point in
transition in your life you just haven't
hav't been able to lock in where you're
just continuing to lose it and Pock away
this is the kind of thing you should
save and come back to to remind yourself
this is a once in a-lifetime Opportunity
from a timing perspective to be able to
leverage creative skills to then know
that hey I have some tools I can go to
block my screen time to make a contract
with myself to remind myself why I need
to win and C there's a framework with
that I can go set up and manage my time
begin to execute on some of my goals
this dude on the internet has literally
just given me a format to be able to go
put those things together and all I got
to do is open whatever doc you have
Google doc notion doc money day click up
[ __ ] doesn't matter I can go do that
I can begin to put my plan in place
follow a structure and I can begin to
act on it and get better and if you just
do that one thing a day you are so much
more locked in than so many people out
there and you are that step closer to
chasing down whatever it is you wanted
thank you for watching