Does it seem like everything we buy kind
of sucks now? The portions are smaller,
the average price of basic things is
ridiculous, and the quality of things we
used to like is significantly worse.
Brands that used to stand for something
are the same as everyone else, and it's
hard to actually navigate the web of
lies about what's made where, what
quality, and what's going on. This is
the age of enshittification, and you are
not alone. It is happening to all of us.
In this video, we're going to talk about
why. We're going to talk about the lies
of what's made where around the world.
We're going to talk about the quality of
cashmere and leather. We're going to
talk about the education of the consumer
and how that will helps and hurts the
scenario. We're going to talk about
everyone starting brands and what that
has actually meant for the products we
consume, mass production, internet
advertising, what you can learn to be
educated both as a consumer and if
you're someone that partakes in this
economy as a marketer or a brand owner.
I am fascinated by this topic, the
culture of dupes, design, who owns what
ideas, who makes what where, and what
this means for our collective taste or
lack thereof. I'm excited for y'all to
explore with me. Let's lock in. So,
first, I want to start with this idea of
provenance. We used to be able to know
what we'd get from buying something a
lot based on where it was made. Used to
assume if something came from China that
it was some sort of kind of crappy
mass-produced good, and by contrast, if
it was made in Italy that it would be
something amazing. But along the line,
we began to get sold lies. So, let's
start with the luxury brands and the
lies that they've been telling. So, a
few years back, outside of Milan,
Italian authorities raided a Dior
factory, and they found basically
terrible conditions. Migrants were
living there, safety guards have been
taken off against the machines, and
people were working far against Italian
labor laws who were not people from
Italy to produce goods that are made in
Italy. Similar things have happened to
Valentino, to Armani. You can read about
the charges for these people online. In
some cases, it may be, "Oh, this is a
rogue member of our supply chain." If
it's an Italian factory coming from an
Italian company, it's only so rogue. At
some points it's actually part of that
company's infrastructure. And it
highlights this idea of made in Italy as
luxury. So there's the concept of
something made in a country, and there's
the concept of how and who makes it. So
for instance, when you are bringing in
migrants from countries like China or
Vietnam or Burma who make those things
for the rest of the world, and you're
simply having them do business inside
your factory, and then removing all of
the safety guards for what is allowable
by regulation to work, and that good is
still legally made in Italy, are you
buying that artisan experience that gets
suggested? This is what the luxury
brands are selling you. Now, if you
remember last year when there was a bit
of a tiff in the trade war between China
and the US, and the TikTok Illuminati
made sure, forced into our feeds on
TikTok and in the response videos, there
was all of these conversations about the
factories that really make your goods,
that make luxury, that make Hermes.
There was a lot of conversation around
that. And I, as someone who spent a lot
of time in China, you've probably seen
lots of my China content, I've also
spent time in Italy at the shows and
textile and sourcing there, been in
factories in Portugal, across the world.
I had a few thoughts on this, right?
Because I have been in factories where I
have seen products from European
manufacturers, Givenchy, Rimowa, brand
after brand being made there. And I
don't say that to say that it is a bad
thing. The places where I saw those
things being made are artisans. They are
places where I make extremely high
quality stuff on projects. I don't, as a
consumer, feel bad for a second about
buying an item from those brands made in
those places. Because there's a wide
gamut of production in China. I will
tell you the tale of two people I know.
They're two brothers, both of whom run
factories. One of whom runs a smaller,
artisan-based factory where the people
execute truly excellent work, best in
class, you could put it up against
anyone in Portugal or Italy. His
brother, by contrast, is a little less
on his luck. And when we visited that
factory, purely because I wanted to see,
because they were producing for Shein.
Once I heard that, I was like, "Cool,
I've heard about those factories and
their conditions and all. Let's actually
see what that looks like." And that
factory, not pretty, not some massive
abuse, people chained to tables, child
labor, anything like that. It just
happens to be chaotic, filled with
people don't have a lot of expertise,
with not a lot of management, in
crowded, hot areas, doing crappy work.
And they take those gigs, the factories
take the production they need there, buy
the cheapest items because that's the
business that they have. But that gambit
from the highest end to the lowest end
can exist within miles of each other.
And the problem was people didn't
understand the upper bounds of what
China was capable of. Feel like until
recently. People also didn't understand
the lower bounds of the rest of the
world. You can get something crappy made
wherever you want. And the problem is
the brands have decided to lie to us in
the middle. It began when Italy was
outsourcing more and more production to
Portugal. And it's ended with this kind
of obfuscated global supply chain, a lot
of which functions on the fact that you
only need to have a good that's made in
Italy if the last real procedure done on
the product is done there. You can,
quite literally, legally just finish a
good assembled and produced somewhere
else. This is not the case in the US.
You need to have the majority produced
with the majority of materials in the
US, and brands get in trouble for this.
Shinola, who used to have, I believe it
was made in Detroit on their products,
had to stop doing that. There's
significantly more protections than
Italy has. Italy actually has a 100%
made in Italy designation that you never
see because no one does it. And so this
leads to this time we're in now that's
really interesting, where the consumers
are actually really educated. When I
started sharing videos inside China, uh,
in the big factory mills at Zongda,
inside the factory, showing what the
textile outsourcing was like. been one
other video ever filmed inside that
environment. Now there's hundreds.
Consumers understand how things are
made. People realize they can start a
brand. But this happens purely from a
consumption standpoint as well. Let's
take this idea of natural materials.
Lululemon, Alo, and their ilk blew up,
created clothes a lot of us wore, and
didn't feel great in. You don't feel
great running wrapped in plastic, and it
became a huge conversation around
natural materials. Can we work out in
linen or cotton and moisture-wicking and
the popularity of merino wool now as
kind of like an in-between. But really,
the point is consumers care about the
products that they're buying a lot more
than ever. You basically have your
low-cost consumer, they'll get Temu or
Shein, or whatever, they don't care. And
then everybody else above that lowest
common denominator has more education
than ever, is making more decisions, and
guess what? If you're choosing between
$70 and $90 leggings, and you have the
full internet to internet to help you
research and hunt down the thing you
want, you actually have kind of a lot of
options. And so as consumers think about
what they want and why, they're more
enabled around that than ever. Plus, we
have this social media-driven desire for
luxury. People want to post hot stuff,
they are influenced. We have all the
knockoff Goyard in the world making
everyone want a Goyard wallet. It seems
like everyone has everything when you
see that B that was on reality TV, and
now you have this combination of does it
look like that, did they actually buy it
with real money, are they just renting
it on a service like Nuuly, is it a
dupe, and no one can ever tell, but
they're participating in the game in one
way or another. And even if you aren't
participating in the label chasing,
etc., you're still looking for
interesting things that represent you
like any consumer is. And you have more
choices than ever, and you're more aware
of luxury in the higher end of this than
ever. And because of this popularity,
the biggest brands in the world have put
their foot on the gas of mass
production. I remember growing up and
working, and my boss at one point bought
a Porsche 911 Turbo S, and it was the
coolest thing in the world. It was
extremely sick. It was the only car of
that kind I'd ever seen. Fast forward to
today, if you actually tally up how many
Porsche 911s are on the road, it is more
than a million. There are more Porsches
on the road than adult residents of San
Francisco. And I don't mean Cayennes and
Macans and all the other like striver
wannabe cars, I mean 911s. So while you
may enjoy that experience of having a
car like that, it's not rare. It's not a
luxury per se, cuz there is some degree
of scarcity that has to come with that.
It is as available as anything could be.
Rolex, the same. They make over 1
million Rolex watches every single year.
There is no rarity. There is no
scarcity. There is just mass-produced
psychologically influenced demand. If
someone says they're buying it because
it's a good watch, sick. You really need
to read the time that closely in 2006.
It is purely an influenced choice. And
while there are many other luxury watch
brands that make immaculate products
that take a significant amount of time,
and may be worth the money for whatever
reason is reflecting artisanship, Rolex
is not one of those. But with this
demand comes this idea of
insipidification, where if they have to
make more than ever, if the luxury
brands are saying, "We're selling more
Louis Vuitton and Loro Piana", another
one that's been hit at the center of
scandal of where they're manufactured,
now they're abusing migrant workers and
things like that. If you have more
demand than ever for these ultra-rare
things, you begin to mass-produce them,
they are going to get worse. And that's
what we've seen happen across luxury.
While they've kept raising the prices.
And so we basically established this
ridiculous standard where nothing is
worth it. At the same time, you have the
rise of every brand. Creators like
myself have shared factory links. I used
to share factory links at the start when
I worked much more in supply chain. I
would share, "Oh, okay, this is a
factory that makes this or that. These
are just these people I found. Here's
where we made this merch." And encourage
people to start brands, cuz guess what?
Those other brands are taking advantage
of you from a margin perspective of an
uneducated consumer. Now we know what
things cost. Businesses can survive on a
four to five x markup. It's different in
luxury when that becomes 200. That's an
exaggeration, but not by much. So as
these people began to develop all of
their own brands, they have also began
to democratize the economics building a
brand looks like. So you didn't know
more about what's real. Also, all these
new brands are figuring it out as they
go. You buy from something off an
Instagram ad. You support a new creator
brand. They're figuring it out. They
don't know the difference between this
weight of t-shirt and that weight or
what this wash looks like or why certain
people do blue tooth componentry this
way or that way. You have more people
than ever learning and figuring it out
basically at the consumer's expense,
which makes the quality of everything
worse. This began really in full in the
Amazon marketplace economics, right?
Where it's like, "Cool, I'm searching
for a bar of soap or pasta or whatever
and I get a brand, I get a brand that
kind of looks like it, I get some kind
of knockoff, I get all these Chinese
versions, I can't tell what and I just
buy it and it's kind of whack. And
people are just competing over the
arbitrage of demand for the lowest cost
that they can execute on. So, this
entrepreneurial opportunity and this
education about what they buy leads us
to this really interesting place.
Whereas, especially cuz we're buying on
the internet and some of these
nomenclatures like made in Italy or 100%
cashmere, which I'm about to get to,
mean nothing, where does it go? Let's
just talk about material for a moment.
100% cashmere is an extremely misleading
label because based on the microns, the
type of sheep, the way the yarn is spun,
full cashmere can mean length of hairs.
It can mean so much different things. A
really high-end sweater versus a low-end
sweater. You can buy a Loro Piana gift
of kings wool $12,000 sweater and a Zara
$95 sweater that are both 100% cashmere.
And you as a consumer have no idea how
to judge that. Same thing when people
are really into weights of t-shirts. I'm
going to buy a 300 GSM t-shirt. All of a
sudden everyone on the internet knew GSM
and knew what a weight meant. But then,
for instance, when I launched t-shirts
with my Valuables brand, people would be
like, "I've never felt something like
this." And yeah, it was a certain
weight, they were super heavy, but
there's a special finish on it. We had a
finish on the shirt. No one talks about
finishes. Consumers don't even know what
If I was to describe it, they wouldn't
even know what they're buying. But the
feel is actually different. And at the
same time, you see the rise of what I
call polyester smut. Brands like
Comfort, right? Who sell tons and tons
of blankets and upcharge, basically
provide a mystique experience. So, a
level below luxury, a level above
average. But they're doing it with
really cheap materials that are designed
to feel as good as possible. So, the
consumer feels like they're getting
something they love, but they're
actually doing it while inhaling stuff
that's terrible for them, for lack of a
better way. And this happens a lot.
Prada is the king of this material
arbitrage, right? Prada sells stuff
that's mostly in nylon at the prices
that other people are doing leather. It
costs them truly fractions of what it
is. At least Bottega uses incredible
leather that's really hard to get. I've
been at sourcing places where people
have brought out the leather that
Bottega buys from them I can't even get
access to because Bottega buys
everything and just feels
extraordinarily better than what I'm
allowed to buy from those tanneries.
That's operating a certain level that
does not exist with nylon. If there is
one brand that is the largest amount of
scam of the luxury charging, it is the
Prada nylon. And so within that world
where we can't feel it, we can't
describe it, how do you even know what
to buy? And that's led to people taking
advantage of that brings us more to
inchidification. So the new discovery
stack for a website isn't just Google
search and the results that come up one
to 10. It's happening on chat GPT,
Claude, especially on the Gemini recaps
that come up at the start of search and
perplexity. And every business I work
with and most of the ones I talk to are
making a plan to get ahead of this. So
one of my favorite tools for actual
traditional SEO is Ahrefs. And they just
launched something called brand radar
specifically for this problem. So this
is a quick look at the tool and how we
have used it for traditional SEO. So I
can see this is a website I used to work
on. It shows me my organic traffic, how
it's changed over time, the ranking of
all my pages, the back links that are
going to those individual pages, how
that traffic changes over time. But now
with brand radar, you can track your AI
share of voice across chat GPT and
Google AI and see where your brand shows
up in Reddit discussions, YouTube
videos, comments. Because in chat GPT's
own words, Reddit and YouTube is what
builds results, not traditional PR or
back links. So brand radar is built on
millions of real search queries. So
you're seeing what people actually ask
and what AI answers back. You can
research brands, products, competitors,
regions, even people. There's unlimited
projects. And you can benchmark against
competitors to see who exactly who's
gaining attention via AI and who's
losing it. So if I was making a plan
right now, I always want to give you
something educational. I want to uplift
my brand's AI presence, I would start on
brand radar to monitor competition and
my progress and build baselines. I would
write descriptions of my products, the
headers, their titles, and everything on
my site because AI doesn't read clever
names. It wants like actual descriptive
information of the content you have and
what you're selling. Agents look for
solutions to questions, not vibes. And
I'd write really thorough info guides,
knowledge bases for my products and via
text on product pages, category pages.
So, that way I make sure that the site
is optimized to tell what needs to be
told and explain why you want to buy.
And I focus on entering the conversation
on Reddit and YouTube organically with
partners, seeding, and owned content
because that's getting so highly
weighted and what the actual results are
that are getting shown. There's a link
in the description of this video to
learn more about Ahrefs Brand Radar. And
thanks so much to Ahrefs for sponsoring
this content. Now, let's roll over into
internet advertising. So, one of the
other reasons why we end up with
products that aren't good essentially
inside our hands, is it really the
internet is less a game of product and
more a game of who can sell that product
best via these new tools we have. You
hear me talk about this endlessly on
this channel. If you are good at Meta
Ads, creative strategy, and organic, if
you were to think about what these more
traditional companies are doing to be
able to buy anything, the fact that they
have eight figures in programmatic
spends with agencies that are getting
like backdoored to be able to sell them
trash traffic from websites or banner
ads, you are competing against such
antiquated old agency graph, that's no
wonder so many young brands are winning
online. But, it really comes down to you
know how to make a good ad, you know how
to make a compelling product that people
want about it, you can move units and
people will consume those units. We've
seen this in drop shipping culture for a
long time. And now with AI content
especially, drop shippers are getting
crazy. There's this example of this
lobster handbag where people were act
acting like they're artisans making this
ridiculous bag and getting drop shipped
like some trash, right? For a low price.
Because there's so many people that want
to quick, they want their e-com brand to
hit quick. How many channels and people
on there are being like, you can hit 10K
or 100K a month with your clothing line
or whatever. But, what they don't teach
people is the weights and finishes and
the product quality and making patterns
that fit and refining everything. This
goes for clothing, it goes for bags, it
goes for candy. We got influencers doing
like drop ship candy out there, right?
Like they What do they know about the
food science of it, right? Typically,
when you started a brand before, like I
remember I invested in a beauty brand a
while back, Experiment, where it's like
they're two chemists, organic chemists,
who had some really interesting ideas
for products to serve Gen Z. But note
the first part, organic chemists. The
expertise level to go into a world where
product differentiation, in terms of how
it shows up on AI or what people's
experience is like that gets them to buy
more, is extremely important is the
differentiator. In the world where
everyone's starting those brands where
has that helps to get to the next level.
But the question is, are you willing to
pursue that? The guru that taught you to
get the $10,000 a month selling your
products via Meta ads, are they the ones
who are going to teach you about the
weights and finishes and cashmere and
going to China and putting all that
together? And that's something that
brand owners really need to think about,
cuz this next level, this next
generation that pulls you out of the
insipidification era is going to be
brands that take this really seriously
and master the craft. But one of those
other product-related topics is this
idea of design and copies, cuz we deal
with that on the internet, too. You see
all these things, you probably see the
shopping where it looks slightly
familiar. I got some shoes other day
that look like the Bottega pattern, they
look like they're Bottega shoes, but
they're not quite Bottega shoes. And you
know what? That was fine with me. I'm
never going to buy Bottega shoes, I like
the way that the woven thing looked, it
was going to work with a particular
outfit, bought it. But it got my eye
because it looks like something that
already exists. But then play this a
step further. Furniture is the key
category of this, right? Look at like
Interior Icons. This is a brand that
dupes other designs. They basically work
through the legal loopholes of the US,
sometimes brazenly, sometimes not, but
they'll just copy any design that
exists. So, let me explain to you a bit
of how this works and why you see it so
much in furniture in particular. So, in
the US, furniture is treated as a
functional object, not a creative work.
So, copyright protection is pretty weak.
Whereas in the EU, it actually lasts
like 70 years from the death of the
designer, it's really well protected.
Basically, what it means is it's really
hard if you have a table or a chair
design of any kind, even if it is from
the last 15 years or whatever other
protections look like, but especially if
it's older, to not just allow it to be
copied. It is fully legal for for to be
copied. It cannot just be represented as
the name. You can't call it an Herman
Miller chair or an Eames chair or
whatever when you do it. If you just
present it in that look and form, that's
why you see a million Togo sofas, the
Ultra Fragola mirror, all these things
just reproduced indefinitely. So, if you
don't call it that, you can basically
with very little recourse sell it.
That's the difference between a
counterfeit and a replica. A counterfeit
pretends to be the original. It's
pretending to sell you an Eames chair,
illegal. A replica, they're just taking
that design, maybe there's a couple
minor changes, maybe not even, but
they're not calling it an Eames chair,
replica. This is all fully allowed.
There's some complexity here. This is
not necessarily a bad thing. People act
like, "Oh, the designers aren't getting
paid." The designers aren't exactly done
particularly cleanly by a lot of these
furniture companies, either. Sometimes
they'll pay estate fees and things to
the designer or to their estate after
they pass away to continue producing
those or pay out licenses, but in the
majority, much like we go back to the
luxury conversation, they are charging a
ridiculous amount. DWR, whoever it is,
is charging you an outlandish amount,
all of which is profit. Versus the dupe
companies who are who are making things
that are sometimes less quality, a lot
of times just as good for a fraction of
the price. And I've been there. I've
been there. So, my content last year, I
went to Foshan in China, which is where
all of the furniture is made. We saw
CB2. We saw high-end stuff. So much of
the world's furniture is made in this
one region, and then there are an
infinite amount of you basically go to
these massive malls, look at all the
things they have, and just order one-off
and custom whatever you want. We got a
lot of stuff for our house and office
space. I originally learned about this
when I was furnishing retail stores we
used to own. You have this entire
economy of one-off. You can fill up a
container or a half container. And then
you get to learn the quality of which
and what things actually cost. And you
realize that those brands, again, much
like the luxury brands, have just been
surviving off this massive markup, which
doesn't pay the designer or the creative
a ton of money. Maybe it gets them a
little. It gives the executives private
jets. Pays for massive corporate
offices. And so, we're in this kind of
awkward place today where maybe you
would say, "Okay, if the designer's
living and they're getting paid really
well from their designs, they're selling
it themselves, I wouldn't buy the copy."
Completely understood. I wouldn't,
either. But for something that existed a
long time ago, now you're offering a
newer version of it, or putting your own
spin on it, or you're just purchasing it
for your house. You need to feel bad
about purchasing it from one of the dupe
brands. This leads to the complications
of the instification, because on one
hand, you buy it from the real source,
you're getting ripped off, they're
overcharging you. You buy it from the
dupe, you're participating in this
oddball economy. I've been thinking a
lot about this, cuz I I've seen a few
items in real life that are vintage that
I like, I'd like to produce a version of
that I know I can produce in like a
Foshan. If I was to introduce a couch,
for example, where's that line? And
where's the line as a consumer versus as
a a brand owner versus as a creative?
And while I may have that in the back of
my head being like, what's the right
thing here, the vast majority of
consumers and business people won't
think about it at all. And we're
watching this game play out in real time
now, cuz it's happening with the big
brands, too. You see me do videos on
Gentle Monster. I talked to briefly
about this in my Tokyo video as well.
Gentle Monster commands a massive
margin. They overcharge massively for
their sunglasses. The markup is in
completely insane, but they do that to
be able to do these cool marketing and
activations and pop-up. Blue Elephant
exists, and it's been sued by Gentle
Monster literally to reclaim that
margin. Most kids, like myself included,
I wouldn't buy a Gentle Monster, it's
just too expensive. There's just no
reason I'm ever going to spend that kind
of money on that. Doesn't say anything
to me. But if someone makes something
that looks kind of just as cool as one
of the ones I want, and it's in that
middle range, and you know that they're
just keeping that margin, where does
that line become for you as a consumer?
And as a Blue Elephant is that brand.
And they're one of the things that's one
of those things that's happening right
now that's going to happen across
everything. Every reason where someone's
overcharging these. The other brand,
Alohas, the shoe brand. They basically
just said, "Cool, you can't get the Mew
Mew New Mew New Balances and the other
Mew Mew popular sneakers, we're just
going to make variants of them, and
they're going to be at a more reasonable
price, and they're going to be great,
and we're going to have a big ecosystem
around it." And that is a rock with
which a brand can grow. And it's funny
that that is, and Keents, and all this
other products that basically say, "We
are going to de-middleman and take that
margin back and give you a great
experience." are thriving. And a lot of
them make good product. And it makes
sense, cuz we're in what I'll call a
distrust economy. Reddit is game. Reddit
is most gamed social network on the
internet. We used to go there and be
able to trust the people on it were
regular people. Now, even the regular
people I know are taking payments to
post on there. Everything is bought in
because of the power of the SEO search,
and it is now the least trustworthy
place on the internet. Influence is
gamed. The expectations are are almost
ridiculous. I have Mountain Valley water
in a lot of my videos. I also have
beverages in a lot of my videos. Now, I
have people in the comments asking, "Is
there a reason you put the beverage on
there? Is it like a psychological hack?"
Or people will be like, "This video is
sponsored by Mountain Valley." My
brothers in Christ, I just want to have
a beverage when I sit here and talk for
45 minutes. But, people are assuming
commerce in anything even minorly
influencer-related, and they're probably
right to do so, even if wrong in that
scenario. And if people are doing this,
if if younger entrepreneurs or creatives
are doing any of these things, is that
better than these ivory tower companies
making all this money and not paying
creatives? That That's That's the life
that we were in the previous 30 years.
So, I don't look back and look at what
happened previously as better than this
whatsoever. This is the age where if
you're a creative person, you have more
opportunity to make money related to
doing something you love, you have more
of an upside to make total money overall
than any time in history. This is the
best time for you ever. If you don't
believe that and you're worried about
all the other things happening in the
world and this or that, they've gotten
to you. Time to end this with what do
brands learn from this? What do you need
to do in this era? So, I think you have
to show it. Cuz whether you're made in
Italy or made in China, you need to show
it one way or the other. If you're made
in Italy, show the artisanship, triple
down, show that it is actual artisan
people making this and it is not a bunch
of migrants in a factory with the wheels
falling off. Prove it. And if you're
making in China, don't be afraid of it.
I mean, there's those gorgeous luxury
Fromanteau bags in China and silk
scarves at a quality level any luxury
brand from the highest end Chinese
factories. And I've shown those
factories in content, and I'm proud of
representing that, but I can also show
it because I remember there was the
brand What was the brand? It's like a
popular streetwear brand, Tricko, where
they went to China and did the China
factory content, and the factories were
like pretty dark, not the kind of
factories we go to. And they were making
the content there, and people were kind
of commenting like, you know, like, "Bro
went to the sweatshop." But, like, hey,
they're showing the reality of it. So I
will at least give them kudos to that.
It was an interesting like microcosm in
that influencer like new age streetwear
brand moment where we're actually seeing
what that looks like. But you need to
know what your experience is and show it
and prove it. And even that learning
experience, like maybe they moved on to
nicer factories now, right? But give
people the full resolve. If you're
selling 100% cashmere, explain it. Don't
make them feel ripped off if you told
them it was better than it is. And don't
undersell it if it's not good enough.
You read the descriptions on some of the
products I have. I'm calling out
specifically, this is going to be one of
the most intense things you've ever
worn. This amount of weight, this
texture is a feeling that like is is
completely different than what you wear
before and has this upside and this
downside. This is the area to explain
that in text and in video. And most of
all, you have to feel it. You have to
give a We had this whole era.
Look, I'm just as much a part of the
problem as anybody. I've encouraged
thousands and thousands of people to
make brands. I was tallying the other
day DMs of people that said they've
actually made brands. There's 176 I
could find. You think about all the ones
beyond that. We're encouraging people to
start that entrepreneurial journey, to
be getting working on that. Now, there's
going to be levels of those people.
There's people that did it cuz they can
make money, they did it cuz they thought
it would be cool, they did it cuz other
people were doing it. And maybe they
find a way there. But for some of them,
maybe they're making like kind of crappy
products. All of the difference between
where you're at there and the next level
that you can be proud of is just giving
a It's just really caring about
everything and probably caring about it
over the economics. Because when you
really give a about anything,
whether it's your content, whether it's
a product, whether it's the things you
choose to consume, people feel it. A
convoluted topic, but one I have a lot
of thoughts on. I appreciate y'all
bearing through it with me. I have a
really solid video coming up about
pricing, archetypes, personas, like the
really in-depth tactical marketing I
know you guys love, so that is coming
shortly. Examples, questions, thoughts
on the insidification of everything in
these brands. There's a lot of nuanced
topics here. Definitely drop below and
I'll chime in on all of them. As always,
I appreciate y'all watching and I hope
it inspires you to think a bit about how
you consume.