So, this last week I was in London
speaking at Vervant Pulse to hundreds of
brands about how to use creators. And it
got me thinking about the creator
economy and how misunderstood it is. I
want to make a video to discuss how are
there so many creators and then how are
they all making money? And this is a
particularly poignant subject because I
met with a lot of brands in the UK and
they're still really focused there on
old school brand strategy. Less have
kind of come over to the new modern
marketing than we see in the US. And it
was just a reminder of how early we
still are on the bell curve of this. In
this video, I'm going to break down all
of the ways that creators make money.
Affiliate, influence, UGC, working for
brands, info products, payouts. I'm
going to talk about the best niches for
creators to make money and I'm going to
rank them because not all niches are
created equal. And then I'm going to go
into how brands are leveraging creators
and how they can all those different
ways so both brands can understand how
they take advantage of this and creators
can also understand how brands actually
want to pay them and how it works. It'll
be a complete A to Z of the creator
economy. If you want to leverage
influence online to make money, I'm
going to drop an enormous amount of info
on you right here. Let's stroll through
sunny London and lock it.
So, first, why do we even care? Who
cares about all these creators, all
these influencers? Well, 82% of
individuals 18 to 44 have posted content
online in the last month. 64% of Gen Z
consider themselves to be content
creators. It is a different world.
However many creators you think there
are, there are more. And however much
money you think they're making, it's
more. So, let's start with how creators
actually make dollars. There's a few
different ways. So, the first, obviously
the most known is brand deals. Brands
want to buy advertising and sponsorships
on a creator's channel, whether that's
YouTube, TikTok, Instagram, for a few
reasons. One, to reach their audience
and then two, to leverage how good they
are as creators to make better content
and better ads about their brand that
they can then use to promote. And while
this is the most talked about, this is
actually the one of the least common
ways to make money. And we will rank
niches for brand deals later, but only
some of the best creators are able to do
this. It is not a game for everyone. You
need a lot of things to fall in your
favor for that to work. So, I'm going to
focus on some of the other ways first.
So, first, the worst paying, but
available to everybody is the platform
payouts. So, Instagram pays out a very
small amount occasionally for you
posting on their platform. Slightly more
if you're posting on Facebook. You get
this based on the performance of your
videos, but it is a pretty negligible
amount. But, it's great if you are
basically creating for fun of it or
getting started, you get some money
along the way. TikTok has the creator
fund that does the same thing, but it
pays out pretty well. It specialized in
different niches, so there is education,
there is automobile, there is beauty.
And this actually, if you are putting up
videos that make pretty good views,
you're getting hundreds of thousands to
millions of views every month, you could
start getting a couple thousand dollars
a month off of this. All the way up to,
you know, lots of creators who get 7,500
to 10K all the time just off the creator
fund. And they're doing 10 million views
plus in good niches. And with this comes
an incentive to post. TikTok only
rewards you on content that's longer
than 1 minute. But, entire economies are
made on this. You've ever wondered, how
do brands send out all this free
product? Why do people still post about
it on TikTok? Well, because if you make
a video about a product over a minute
and it gets any little of views, TikTok
pays you for it. And if you're sent
something good or interesting, that's
now a thing for you to make content
about. If you already made that content
on TikTok and it's done, why wouldn't
you post it to the other networks to
take advantage of the content you made?
There is a massive economy around this.
You've probably heard me tell the
anecdote before of working with beauty
brands last year. I had so radically
underestimated how many of those mailers
you could send out. Oh, a couple
hundred, maybe we can get up to a
thousand. No, it's thousands. 5,000,
8,000 a month. That is how many creators
are participating in that ecosystem in
beauty. Whatever the scale you think it
is, it's more. And this is funded in a
large part by TikTok. And if you look at
it as an average person, when you talk
about what are all those Gen Z making
that percent of content, what are they
doing? Well, look, if you are a hostess,
or you work in retail, or you're in
college, or you have an entry-level job,
getting an extra $500 a month, or $1,000
a month, like when I was in college, I
worked at Abercrombie & Fitch and
Chick-fil-A. Those jobs kind of sucked.
I mean, they were fine. I've had worse.
But if you're telling me that I could be
making videos about fitness, or design,
or whatever I was into at the time, and
Tik Tok would pay me, I could make a
thousand dollars. And that's before we
even get into affiliate and Tik Tok
shop, and real money, you best believe I
would be trying to do that. The platform
payouts is another one. YouTube has
payouts as well, also pretty low. So
again, you're not going to make some
amazing living off this, and you should
not base this as an income source for
your creator. This should always be
looked at as like some extra. It's not a
primary monetization model for anybody,
and should not be. But it exists and is
worth understanding. So then we have the
more common than brand deals way to
actually work with brands, and that is
affiliate marketing. So what do we mean
by this? Tik Tok shop, as well as
platforms like ShopMy and LTK, and just
direct affiliate programs. So affiliate,
when you make content about a brand or a
thing, and you give somebody a link, and
they buy from it, and you get paid. So
Tik Tok shop has made this super easy.
You tag a product on Tik Tok shop, you
get paid out pretty high percentages,
higher percentages than anywhere else.
It's why it's so dominant. And you will
make money off those sales, and there
are endless creators making 10K plus,
and way more creators than you would
ever expect making 100K plus. If you
doubt this, you want to validate this,
just go and you can go into Kelo data,
not an ad, just a platform that sources
this. We use it to find creators. The
previous position I worked at because it
will show you every brand. You can go
and you can look up Maybelline. Like who
is Maybelline's top creator this month?
Who are their other 10 top creators? How
much are they making on revenue from
just Maybelline? You can go to the
creator themselves and see what that is.
All those numbers are aggregated out
there. And it's not completely right,
because sometimes there are separate
retainer systems, whatever, but it gives
you a rough idea, and the numbers are
staggering. But affiliate isn't just Tik
Tok shop. That's a very particular world
to live in. You have to be a great
TikTok Shop creator. A lot of other
creators, we'll dive into this in the
niches when I rank them, just make
content and link it. So, ShopMy and LTK
let you put together a catalog of
products. So, things that you recommend,
your picks, the things you like in your
home. I wanted this microphone, this
candle, my MacBook, whatever it is. You
could put that in my ShopMy or my LTK.
And when someone asks me, "Where did you
get that sweater?" I go, "Hey, it's in
my ShopMy." And then, I would click
through and you get a small percent,
right? It's like 3%, 10%, 12%. Pretty
minor, but it adds up if people take
your recommendations. And if you make
content specifically around it. Tons of
creators do this. This is a real revenue
source. You do it on Instagram, you do
it on YouTube, you can do it direct with
a brand. I'll talk about how brands run
programs for this later. And so much
stuff gets sold on the internet through
pretty direct content about it or
through indirect content. Yeah, I'm just
going to put up the things you see in my
house or my filming setup, whatever it
is. So, it doesn't feel as much like an
ad, it's just a way to help monetize.
This is a huge program for our creators
to make money. And I could not recommend
highly if you are doing that in your
niche to set that up and run that and
learn good at it, whether just casually
recommending it or actually making
dedicated videos about stuff you get a
percentage on. Because you don't have to
wait for a brand deal. You're rewarded
on it. You might be surprised at how it
performs. And we have UGC. This is
basically when you make content for
brands. It doesn't even go on your feed.
So, there are a lot of platforms out
there, endless ones. Super affiliate,
Trend IO, hundreds. You can just search
UGC videos, UGC platform, that offer the
ability for you to make videos for
brands for basically the low hundreds of
dollars. $50, $100, $200, $300. The
brands used to run as ads inside their
various networks. This is a common ad
type that most brands use. And if you're
not, you really should be testing. It is
an affordable way for them to get
creative, and creators who are good at
this can begin to command more and more
money. But, this is another very common.
It doesn't even have to go on your feed
or it can be some sort of combo, but you
are basically leveraging your talents at
making content to make it for brands.
And the best way to begin working in
this, you go get listed on those
platforms and have some examples. Then
you can actually get work as a creator.
You may have seen I've done multiple
videos on Cash App's page where I'm
functioning as a creator on their social
media feed, a recurring voice. And I'm
doing that cuz I can discuss nuanced
topics in an interesting way. And that's
a skill that's helpful on that page. And
there are brands in all types of
industries that do this. And sometimes
it's in a collab with your actual
creator account. Sometimes it's just
purely separate, but everything from
marketing to HR to individual products
to technology to government to news
media pay creators to do this. And it
becomes great because you get basically
it's like like having a recurring client
where you can work out a deal and begin
to get a predictable amount of revenue
for X videos a month. And the last way
we'll talk about is info products where
you're selling whether it's PDFs or
courses or guides, direct calls, etc.
Which if you actually have something
useful to say and you're an expert and
you have something not available
elsewhere is a great way to monetize and
how you see a lot of people scale. Cuz
if you have knowledge that's worth like
$30, charge for it. And you'll see I
have done all of these personally. Many
of you seen Cut 30, that is an info
product I wrote to other creators. I get
payouts on YouTube from the platform.
I've done affiliate content. I was one
of Erwan's first TikTok Shop affiliates.
I've done UGC for Roku. It wasn't on my
feed, but they've run them as an ad.
Brand deals with Anthropic, Google,
CarGurus, Claude. It's endless. And so
we've learned a lot about what makes
these good and bad. But quickly we're
going to talk about how you get started
doing this. Now I'm going to rank all
the niches. So the first thing is if you
want to get this, if you want people
reaching out to you about affiliate
deals, so you can go hunt them down
yourself obviously or just put up a Shop
My LTK. If you want brands to reach out
to you about influencer stuff or to hire
you for UGC and you want them to come to
you directly, they need to be able to
find you in platforms. You got to
realize that they are using search
platforms, Later, all this kind of stuff
like that that will allow you to find
creators. Meta has a creator search.
TikTok has a creator search. Yuka. All
these platforms search and so you have
to be able to show up when they search.
So if they're searching skincare
products or their competitors products,
you need to have made videos about those
things or you won't show up inside the
system. And then, if those videos are
good, you will obviously be higher
weighted in it. They'll see the
engagement, they'll see the views. So,
that is your number one responsibility
if you want to actually get those types
of inquiries is to make content about
that niche. They're not just going to
come to you if you've never made it
before. You have to be currently making
it, and it has to be good. And we will
get a lot of creators who will wonder,
"Why don't our brands ever reach out?"
Well, have you made content in that
niche about those products? Like, no.
Well, then they're not going to reach
out until you've done that. And then
they'll be like, "Well, I've made that
content." Well, is it good?
like it? Do they respond to it? There
has to be some level of natural
attraction. Achieve those, and those
will come. And if you want to wait for
that, you can go out bound. There's a
great book called Sponsor Magnet that a
cut 30 grad wrote that you should check
out if you want to learn how to go out
bound and pitch your own deals. And
there are a lot of people There are so
many people hiring creators in this Dark
Room who I work with, the agency I work
with. They're always hiring creators.
I'll link their stuff there the air form
down here below, too, if you're a
creator you need it. There are so many
opportunities. You have to hunt them.
Now, let's break into the best niches
for creators to make money. I am going
to tier these out, A, B, and C. And D.
I'm going to go from the lowest money to
the highest money, and I'm going to base
that money primarily on brand deals, but
we're going to talk about all this other
stuff, all those other programs within
it. But it's easier to tier them based
on one thing. So, will brands pay you
money for stuff? We're going to start
there. So, first is the lowest tier, the
bad tier. If you do the news, you talk
about news, politics, you do media,
sports, you talk about art, mindset, and
inspirational content, carousel
accounts, and aggregation of stuff
that's happening, automotive and cars,
music, gaming, comedy, any faceless
content, AI content, not content about
AI, but content that are made using AI.
This is the worst niche. This is the
bottom of the barrel. Almost no one
wants this content, and when they do,
they pay the least amount of money for
it. If you become the biggest, if you
become the top 1%, like you are in
sports, you can get these deals, but
they're going to be like words I can't
say or this video will get you listed.
This is common denominator stuff. You're
competing with news media, stuff that's
commodified. It's pretty much useless.
If you're doing this for brand deals,
it's not great. You got to be doing that
for the love of the game. If you're
doing it for payouts, maybe you'll get a
little bit of money. There's also
basically no UGC stuff in here. There is
some creator stuff, right? Cuz there are
companies in gaming and music, etc., who
are hiring creators. One of your best
bets, if you're in any of these niches,
is to try to get companies that are
working in that to retain you to make
content on their main feed, become a
recurring voice on their feed. It's one
of the only good options you have for
monetization. And even affiliate,
there's just not a ton of options here.
And towards the top of this, basically I
would put them in this kind of bad
niche, but there's still something
there, is travel and food. Where there's
a lot of good creators on there, there's
more opportunities to make money. There
is some level of brand, but it's so
commoditized, it's so competitive, that
it's kind of at that lowest tier here.
So, if you're making content in that, I
have to tell you, you got to be making
content for the love of the game, or be
a top 1%, or it's just probably not
going to work out. Your audience, I hate
to be the first to break it to you, is
probably not worth a lot. And however
much it's worth now, it's going to be
worth less every single day. How easy
these niches are to operate in. Then we
go up a tier, what I call the lifestyle
niches. Travel and food is kind of at
the top of the last one and the bottom
of this one. Then we go into fashion and
fitness on the bottom here. In the
middle, motherhood, pet, and kind of at
the top we'll get into like local
content, interior design content. There
are brand deals out here. You can get
brand deals in fashion and fitness.
They're going to suck. They're going to
be low-paid. You can get UGC jobs in
this, too. They're going to be
mediocrely paid, right? You can pursue
your passion here, but there's a ton of
creators. It's the easiest stuff to do,
right? If you're mildly good-looking or
mildly in shape, you can do fashion and
fitness content. And even if you are
great in those, you're still competing
with a lot of people. You get slightly
better in like the motherhood and pet
niches, it kind of gets up to its best
in interior design and local content,
right? Local content is better than
travel content for monetization. Cuz a
lot of local places, if you are making
content about Orange County or LA or New
York, or whatever, there are a lot of
businesses that want to reach out
locally when they have an event, or if
there's a local business that wants to
promote, you have a lot of interesting
monetization opportunities there if you
specialize in an area. And this is all
okay. You can begin to make actual money
here. You get a little bit of brand
deals, you get a little bit of UGC. Your
best bet in these is to go the info
products route. People are developing
affinity with you, you need to sell them
something direct. That'll be your best
chance to make the most money. And it's
the hardest cuz lifestyle people in
general, people who make this kind of
content, are the ones who tend to feel
the worst about this or be the weirdest
about it when it's just like just
monetize, just make money, sell the PDF,
sell the courses, whatever it is, if you
want to actually get something off this.
And as opposed to the the niche below
where it's like the top 1% can get some
real deals. Here it's like the top 10%
can get some real deals. Then we go up
into the great tier. This is what I call
business adjacent. So basically, you're
providing value that who market to
businesses could sell into. This is when
you start to get into real money niches
I highly recommend for people. This is
the design niche. Design niche is great.
And it first I forgot about photography
and stuff. I put that in the in the
lowest niche. Terrible terrible niche to
be in. Videography, content creation,
right? Content creation, you're you're
basically selling courses at best. Hard
niche. But this niche, design is the
kind of a lower tier of it. And design
is great. You have a lot of these
brands, you have Photoshop and all the
Adobe products and Canva and a bunch of
these that that do good brand deals. All
the creative markets of the world and
different types of gear. They've So if
you create really compelling content
around kind of design and the use of
design and how-tos and whatnot, there is
a bunch of brands that do stuff in
there. But there's not like a ton,
right? And there's a lot of really high
talent. Now, if you're willing to do
that and you are able to talk
competently about using AI to do that
and do that without some huge backlash,
which is there's some nuance to it, then
you can make a lot of money. But now,
anything else business adjacent. You can
you talk about marketing, email
marketing, paid ads. A lot of what I
talk about, the core of my content falls
inside this niche. Then you can get a
lot of marketing software that wants to
offer deals. Same thing goes for HR. If
you're running HR inside of a company,
there's a lot of those, the the Gustos
of the world, all the different HR
software and hiring software and
recruiting platforms, all through
education that will do that. AI in
business is a huge one. You can talk to
business decision makers how to
incorporate ChatGPT and Claude and
Lovable and all that. Amazing highly
monetized niche. So, anything that has
that business layer that's not just
selling it to like want-to-be
entrepreneurs, but selling it to
established business people who need to
make a choice, usually about software.
This is real bread and butter. This is
where all the good creators are making
half a million, million dollars plus.
And entry-level and new creators can get
to those like 10K a month on brand
deals. And where when you're doing UGC,
you're doing it for stuff with some
nuance where it doesn't even have like
there's there's a lot of of money there
to do that. If you have info products in
those niches, that's also more of a
business decision. You can offer those
at higher price points. Affiliate
matters a lot less here. Affiliates for
the niches down below. There here you
can really focus in on you creating for
other brands. Are you doing influence,
etc. And then payouts is going to be the
least cuz this content does not get a
ton of views, right? It's more focused
on who those views are for. And then the
highest here, the best tiers, finance,
personal finance especially. You help
people with credit card points, making
decisions about where they invest, and
you do that authentically. Medical,
another one. Medical devices, specific
problems, pharmaceuticals, really
nuanced niche. That is the highest end
of this when people are making banking
and health and money decisions. And you
need kind of the least amount of money.
As I go through these and rank these,
one thing to bear in mind, just because
you make content in those niches doesn't
mean you get money. It doesn't mean that
money is there for you. It has to be
good. It has to be resonant. You have to
have fans. I would ask yourself, are
there recurring people that comment on a
lot of my content all the time? Those
are fans. Do you have more DMs than you
can kind of keep up with reasonably? You
have a fan base. Does your content
always getting roughly above 20,000
views on TikTok and Instagram? At least
above 10. Okay, now you're in the game.
If none of those things are true, you
got work to do still. To get to those
places, I would be sharpening your
toolkit with affiliate stuff to make
money while you're doing it. If you
absolutely have to make money, but more
often be focused on just crushing out
your content. So, how do I know all
this, right? So, as many of you know,
we've run Cut 30 now. We are just
finished our 22nd session. We're in the
middle of the 22nd. Almost 3,000 people
have graduated from it. In all of these
niches, we follow all their arcs. They
are all tracked in video based at org.
We've run Cut 30 Legends, which is the
program we do for people that are going
really well, and they want to learn more
about it. We talk about monetization.
People workshop their brand deals. And I
work with Darkroom, who I mentioned here
before, on their creator programs, how
brands hire from this. And then did that
on the PE side. And when I was working
as a marketing leader and did this in
the toy category, did this in surf, did
this in consumer electronics. I have
been on both sides. I have done this as
an influencer. I have worked with the
influencers and creators on it. And I've
done it as a brand. And I'm extremely
tapped in on this. And there will always
be exceptions, some person who's amazing
at whatever who makes more or less. But
this is the average for the majority of
these. And if I didn't name your niche,
and you're curious about your niche,
drop it in the comments. I will answer
as many of those as I can about how you
should think about it from a
monetization standpoint. So in a moment,
we are going to talk about how brands
leverage this. How do brands even think
about having these conversations? What
do they do? What are the platforms they
use? How do they make money off this
entire creator economy? But first, I
want to talk to you about Framer. So if
you are a creator or an influencer, and
you want to make a website for yourself
or a portfolio, and I would highly
recommend it. You having a domain and
email at your own domain, and having a
website where you put up the brands that
you've worked with and key examples of
your content, so people can quickly
browse and be like those are the couple
best videos, is an awesome thing for you
to have in your bio. If you want to do
this, you should be using Framer to do
it. Framer has amazing templates that
you can pull from. You've seen my
websites for Framer templates forever
before I actually got a Framer pro to go
design nicer stuff with me for all the
websites I have now. So you can see that
on creativedirector.net or cut 30
website, etc. They have templates you
are able to edit. They are responsive
out of the box. You can search for
things like landing pages, get beautiful
designs, and you do not have to be a
developer to use this. They have
extremely thorough tutorials, and you
can build good-looking sites fast that
actually have some sauce to them. It's
not just your average template you've
seen a thousand times before. Two of the
free templates that I like are this
Draftline template and this Julian
template. I also like this Creator Cut
template. It's $29. If you really want
to dive in, this Kim template is sick.
Challenge yourself. Pick one of these
templates and say, "I am going to spend
one of your evenings. Kick off at 6:30
and be like, I'm not going to go to
sleep until I finish getting this
website up." Break your phone. Just get
what you specialize in, some of your top
content, easy ways to contact you, and
what you're looking for on a single
page. You can do all that in Framer.
More info inside the description. All
right, so we are going to end with how
do brands utilize the creator economy?
If you're a brand, how can you make
money from creators? If you're a
creator, how can you understand how they
work? So, the ways that we're going to
run through this. First is creators on
staff. If your social media sucks, get a
creator, get them on four videos or
eight videos a month once or twice a
week to make content for your brand. You
will see this as a constant focus. If
you watch a bunch of my other videos, I
have tons of examples of this. Brands
will eventually have multiple creators,
especially if there's any nuance to your
brand. One of the ones I love to call
out is Rarify. I believe they have
either a creator or their employees were
making content or just describing the
chairs and the things that they sell. If
you have any brand that has design or
nuance or a wide product catalog, you
can get someone to just explain those
things and the decisions behind them and
the history around it. I have whole
videos on the topics and all the things
to do there. I won't get into that. But
basically, getting someone recurring on
a retainer to make content for you is
going to be better than the content you
have already. It's the easiest layup for
brands to help solve their social media.
Second thing is UGC for ads, super
common. You are running meta ads, you
are running TikTok ads, get creators to
be contributing content. Same thing, you
can buy one-off videos, you can use any
of the sites I mentioned prior on this.
Mini Socials is a great one to start.
Get some ads, get some briefs out there,
get those back, put them in your ad
account, and you'll be able to see kind
of the power of having different voices
work by that. And you'll see a lot of
brands start to begin building armies of
these. Oh, I have an ASMR creator, I
have a vlog creator, I have old
creators, young creators, men, women,
backgrounds, skin types. Begin to build
out a wide swath to help create ads.
This is how people really scale their ad
spend up significantly and they begin
sharing briefs briefs and tips within
that. Now, how do you find those? How do
you get those? Again, there's all those
UGC platforms, and you can just search
UGC platform. And like a reminder, if
you want to show up on those as a
creator, you have to be making content
about these brands and categories with
those keywords that people can
recognize. Those are usually the two
biggest layouts. Get some UGC into your
ad account. It's usually only a couple
hundred bucks a video if even, and you
can begin to test and see if those
assets work, and then get a creator on
your main feed, then get the creator
doing some of those UGC assets, too, is
another little cheat code. Then there is
affiliate, using creators to help sell
your product. Social Snowball is a
platform for this. They'll let you
search through databases and databases
of creators to be able to bring
affiliates on, get them their own links,
get them their own landing pages,
monitor that data, go through an
onboarding process. You can integrate it
to your checkout on your Shopify store,
so people can get their own affiliate
codes and post on their own or casually.
You want to be in a constant recruitment
cycle for this. Cuz what you'll notice,
big programs who are doing this don't
just have 20 affiliates, 50 affiliates.
You look at Comfort, Dad Gang, Cowboy
Colostrum, Grunt, these brands,
thousands of affiliates. So, it's that
constant recruitment cycle, pedal to the
metal on it, and the sales all add up,
and then a lot of those good assets
those affiliates are making, you have a
dollar value you're willing to pay for
that for an ad asset, just like you do
UGC. The ones that are winning on that,
get those in your ad account, pay extra
for that. Then we have anchor
influencers, big influencers. If you're
doing a campaign and you want to get
affiliates excited, to get the word out
there, that's what big influencers are
for. You will see me doing anchor
influencer work for a lot of big
marketing launches. And how good
influencer campaigns run is they usually
have a handful of anchor influencers up
top, big people they know are going to
perform, they can help put up the views,
put up the results, and get other people
excited to be a part of the campaign.
And they have ripple effects from
association, it's the power of your kind
of larger influencers, and you
supplement that with a bunch of micro
influencers, like the sub 100k, sub 50k
people inside that niche, you get a
bunch of them. Those are like shots on
goal to complement the anchor, where
you're like, all right, it's not about
having every one of them hit, you pay a
relatively low amount, but you're
throwing a lot of influencer content out
there and kind of seeing who the stars
are, then getting those into recurring
programs with you. It's a great way to
think about influence, begin building a
team. You have your big athletes on the
team, the way Nike would have Jordan,
and you have a bunch of people you're
bringing in, nurturing up in that as
well. Now, platforms for this stuff,
you're trying to find influencers, you
want a basically agency to help you
curate those campaigns. Later is a great
platform for that. It's like a platform
plus they have the managed service to
help you run the campaign. If you're
looking for an agency that helps you do
affiliate and will help you do
influencer programs like that, Align
Growth Management are friends of mine.
If you're a big brand that's doing big
creator campaigns, want to run those
through performance and ads as well,
then you go to Darkroom. I'll link all
these people down below. Social
Snowball, like I mentioned for
affiliate, you're trying to find more
creators on TikTok Shop that is Yuka.
You want to find more creators you can
use for ads on Instagram, for ads and
affiliate, Tribe with a Y is a new and
up-and-coming platform people like for
that. The Tribe people are seeing that,
I want to invest, holler at me. And that
is your toolkit for the creator economy.
Now, I'll remind you, just like I did at
the start of this video, we are at this
part of the bell curve. People think
it's over here, it's too saturated, it
is not. There are still so many media
dollars in television, banner ads, media
sites with interstitials and pop-ups no
one ever looks at, terrible display
inventory. The biggest agencies you know
are selling these huge blocks of just
terrible ad inventory that they're
responsible for. They have these big
enterprise deals with, they're packaging
that and giving it to clients and
basically taking their money for no
result because it's hard to do good
creator marketing. But if you want to do
the hard thing, there is so much more
alpha and value because the lazy, bigger
brands just buying those programmatic
blocks, getting agencies that don't know
what they're doing, there is infinite
alpha there to the tune of billions,
tens of billions of dollars right now.
So, we are purely at the beginning of
this. Brands are just beginning to catch
on, they're building influencer teams,
have creators on main. If you watch my
YouTube, you've seen five plus of my
videos, you are so far ahead of these
people. Do not let that get to your
head. Remember, you are ahead of the
curve and act accordingly. That is your
alpha. I'll shout out Vevant for letting
me rant about this in front of a large
audience in the UK. Reminder, my next
community call, we're going to do a
training on creative direction here in a
few weeks. You can find that below as
well. And I appreciate y'all so much for
watching.