So, in the past few years, we've had
what I call little treat culture. This
is where people have chosen to spend
their money on fancy snacks, fancy
beverages, little purchases, $5, $20 to
basically get that little dopamine hit,
make them feel better about their lives.
This is a cultural trend. But right now,
we're seeing a shift into what I like to
call little luxuries. You've seen this
term likely online. But this is the idea
that you can purchase an everyday item
that is elevated. You basically overpay
for it, pay a premium, but it is
something that is special and appeals to
you. You really care about that
particular part of your day. This could
range anything from like a little shower
head that gives you an amazing
experience with your water to like a
sleep cover to something fun for your
home. Basically, this idea that a better
user experience and a more premium
aesthetic justifies a more premium price
point and why people choose to buy like
that. So, in this video, I'm going to
talk about how we got here. How did this
become such a dominant trend and how to
think about this as a person if you're
actually trying to decide if you want to
buy one and then show you the playbook
if you're developing a brand, how you
participate in this little luxury
culture. Now, I'm going to break down a
dozen brands in the category from tool
kits to laundry detergent sheets to
vegetables. I actually can't wait cuz
these are some of the funnest best
brands to talk about that you are going
to learn from and then you might
actually want to buy. And you can sign
up for a recap of this where I'll
actually list out all those brands and
this playbook in next week's hyper that
is in the description. If you ever want
something like my videos all written
out, I'm going to start providing that
in the newsletter each week. But we're
going to kick off with how we got here.
Why did we get to this little luxury
culture? Let's lock in. So, first let's
talk about the cheapification. I don't
even know if that's a word of
everything. And this comes down to
Amazon and availability of the global
economy. Not to get macroeconomic here,
but there was a massive sea change in
our entire world when Alibaba was
invented. We all know the term Alibaba,
but we aren't super ingrained into what
happened. Really, what happened there is
a platform was created that opened up
factories across the world to the United
States and to entrepreneurs in the
United States. Prior to that, you have
to actually go to China and hunt down a
factory, which is significantly harder
than going online and browsing materials
and communicating through chat. And the
cost savings of this was so massive. You
saw all these new entrepreneurial
businesses pop up. And at the same time,
we had Amazon where anything could get
delivered to your door. And so we saw
people saying, "Hey, I can launch a
brand and just by availability on
Amazon, I can be a choice." Amazon took
off. Everyone wanted to start a business
on there. And this applied to people
that were arbitrageing goods from China
and applied to Chinese brands too where
people said, "We can by virtue of cost
put something online." And so much of
the population buys so many of their
things from Amazon and so much is a
function of price. It led to the overall
quality and then the cost of brands just
continuing to decrease and decrease. It
was all about who could offer something
10 cents cheaper. How can you bundle
more packs inside of it, it became a
genuine race to the bottom. And then
with the shipping scenario, the last few
kind of pre-tariff worlds and Timu and
Shien, all of a sudden they said, "Hey,
we can actually ship goods direct from
China to your door. we can offer even
greater savings on so many things versus
importing cartons and warehousing. And
this has led to basically everything we
consume online a huge chance that there
is kind of like a trash really cheap
item because of the culture associated
with this and these big macroeconomic
shifts. I'm going to take my
macroeconomic hat off real quick and
then we're going to dive into the
entrepreneur hat. So what does that mean
for you? It used to mean if you want to
enter a category as a new brand, one of
the best positions you could take was to
go cheaper. Basically say, "Hey, this
hammer is 20 bucks. I'm going to get it
from China. I'm a smaller business. I
can actually sell that at 18 bucks and I
can get that customer who wants it to be
cheaper. Now that cheap trying to sell
something at a lower cost that is done.
You cannot win in basically any category
on price. It is a horrible method with
which to compete. Instead, what we're
seeing is the idea that hey, well, the
hardest thing to replicate is actual
user experience, aesthetics, content,
all the things that I talk about on this
channel. So, the idea is to make it as
good as you can. Take an item and make
it amazing and then charge a premium for
it. And now there's an erosion of the
middle ground. on the middle ground all
went to the bottom and then all the
people that provide a premier user
experience at the top. And so the brands
that really win kind of live in that
middle to high-end where they get that
premium experience but don't charge an
overweight for it because they've been
able to achieve some scale. This is a
sweet spot for success in the west right
now with a brand versus just with a
product sold on price. And all of these
brands I'm going to show here today are
examples of that. So what is the recipe?
There's a recipe for these products that
will help make them successful. The
first is experience. basically offering
a proumer level product and education
about why it's so good. So let's look at
the coffee machine market for instance.
So you now see these super automatic
machines like the Terra Cafe, you see
Jura, you see Fellow, a bunch of these
companies that came about saying we have
better looking machines. They're easier
to use. They p perform at a proumer
level and they aren't presented or
marketed like the previous generation of
brands and they differentiate purely
through that kind of better super
automatic experience. The second level
is performance. basically quality and
durability. It's doing better than what
you did prior. It filters your water
better. You have a candle that burns
longer. Whatever it is is saying we are
going to have better performance than in
the existing tier of the market. And
these two things go together. And with a
third thing that is mandatory and all
this, that is aesthetic. It's basically
performative, but this idea of the
aesthetics of everything. How can you
make everything in your home or
everything you choose to interact with
more beautiful? One of the items I'm
going to walk through here today is
called the Tinker Toolkit. Is literally
a tool kit that has been like
millennialified. It does have some
experience pluses and the grips and the
way it's put together, but literally
it's just a more beautiful looking
nature of an existing thing in your
home. And there are hundreds of examples
of products like that. And the three of
these together, experience, performance,
and aesthetic, are the holy grail of
being able to market an item that you
can charge a premium for. And one of the
reasons for that is if you have those
three things, they is built for standout
content. You're able to constantly
explain in ads why it's better because
of the experience you provide, because
of the performance it delivers. You have
actual stats you can rattle off and say
this is why this is worth more money.
And then you have the nature of hey,
this is a beautiful looking thing. So it
immediately hooks better and looks
better in content, which is an innate
advantage. Take a little break for a
personal anecdote about how I learned
this. So I used to uh be a partner in an
agency called Gwyn Partners when I lived
in Texas. We were a product development
agency and we did some go to market as
well. I was working on this with an
entrepreneur friend of mine named Colin
Gwyn who is a person who has been the
most obsessed with user experience in
hardware product and product overall of
anyone I've ever met. He is lives in the
religion of product experience
development. It's what he thinks about
how he thinks the way I can ideulate and
think about content and give you an idea
or a strategy in seconds. He thinks that
way about product. And one of the things
that we worked on there in addition to
applying that methodology to a lot of
products and he'd worked on things like
the DJI Phantom when it initially came
out as one of his projects. So was a DJI
Inspire. He's also the person that came
up with the idea for Gel Blaster and how
it was packaged in the United States.
Many people know I worked there too. It
actually spun out of that agency. But we
developed Gel Blaster because he saw
that vision in the internal hours of the
company. So we would dedicate a certain
percentage of hours at our agency to our
internal projects. There's a couple
interesting ones of those. The current
really interesting one is actually a
diagnostic software for any piece of
hardware with a smart battery. That's
probably for a different video. But the
gelb blaster one was 100% based on if
you have kids and you have Nerf, you
know, it doesn't really live up to the
potential of it experience. And then
when you actually look at the
competitors, they all look like real
weapons, which is not something that you
want to sell. So this idea that you
could have a better experience and have
it look cool like a video game and
potentially video gamify it was the
entire road map for a better aesthetic,
better performance, and a better
experience than you were having with
this existing world of Nerf. And that's
how Gel Blaster, which is a tens of
millions of dollars a year business, was
built out of. It's a Walmart, Costco,
etc. And watching that come from this
guy's head into reality and the
relentless focus on experience,
performance, and aesthetic throughout
that company is a big part of why those
fundamentals like live with me in every
project today. So next, let's actually
dive into some of these brands. I'm
going to break down what makes them
special and what you can learn from
them. All right, so first I want to talk
about vacation. Many of you have heard
of this brand or know this brand, ultra
popular, but they basically took the
aesthetic part of this playbook and a
bit of the experience part and made a
incredible brand out of it. This is an
aestheticsdriven brand that people will
pay a slight premium for over existing
products to basically change a category
to change the entire sunscreen category.
In some cases, it offers a slightly
better experience, but 90% of this is
aesthetics driven. And you look at any
traditional category like that where on
the shelf, everything looks kind of
boring. Really, the other best company
in this category is SunBum, which is a
company I consume a lot of. It's really
popular out here in Orange County where
they are also kind of like a more
modern, fun version of your average
sunscreen. Everything else on shelf is
painfully dullled. Then you have these
two brands, you can kind of choose your
route between a sunbum and a vacation.
And you see when you see it on shelf or
you go into these displays inside any
retail store that is a purely you're
magnetically driven to the aesthetic of
this and this aesthetic then enables
better content. I have a viral video
with this whipped cream sunscreen. This
is a form factor play where they're now
adding the aesthetic and a bit of the
experience where when you come out it
looks like whipped cream. I did the
video talking about this packaging and
putting it on my hand. It blew up cuz
people are basically getting into that
dissonance of chaos packaging and it has
a viral factor and you want to buy it
for that and it's fun when you do bring
it out. And same thing now with the
scents and the approaches they've had to
more traditional '8s things. They're
adding a product element to it. But this
is one of the best basic ideas think
people can learn from this if you have
aesthetic mastery in your toolkit. A lot
of brands I talked to want to be like a
vacation but they don't understand
aesthetics on this level and don't have
the ability to retain design talent. A
brand like this comes about because the
people inside of it from the highest
level to the lowest level live and
breathe lifestyle and aesthetic. Now, if
you are like that, if you are in a
design firm, you have a design-driven
group of friends or entrepreneurs, you
can probably execute something
conceptual like this. But if everyone is
not obsessive at this level, there's no
way to contrive something that goes as
deep into it as this does. I want to
follow this up with Jolie. Jolie is a
product I have a complicated
relationship with because I am a very
anti subscription products. And so, for
reference, this is a shower head. It is
a $152
shower head and they're selling you a
subscription for the filters in it to
give you filtered water. And they're
basically saying the water coming out of
your shower is really dirty. You should
do something about that. Also, you're
going to get the benefit. It's going to
improve your skin and hair by doing
something about it. So, there's a
consumer benefit. And they market that
relentlessly, really, really well.
Again, shower head, something we all
have. You may have thought of replacing
it for a basically a different type of
water flow or maybe you want a certain
look, but that's probably the most
anyone's ever spent thinking about it.
and they said, "Hey, let's monetize this
category better by offering a better
experience. Also looks pretty good.
There's this color element to it." And
they're kind of getting into this
performance. Cut down hair shedding,
frizziness, dry skin, and acne. Uh
that's a pretty good value proposition
when you really start looking at the
stats. Uh if they can back that up, but
it's a subscription product. And there's
so many of these products now. Uh eight
sleep is another one where I even though
I know you're getting value out of I
know it's a good experience, they're
trying to charge you every month to have
a shower or whatever that looks like is
I have like an intrinsic problem with. I
know this one is filter based, so maybe
you can do that every year or whatever,
but the subscription model does get to
me a little bit, but this is an amazing
example. They identified a category,
said, "How can we improve it?" And
they're monetizing at the best level
because they have a recurring sale as
part of that with these filters. And I
do think there is a world of hardware
from sconces to door handles to every
little thing that we use in the world
that has the potential for someone to
say, "We're going to improve the
aesthetic. We're going to increase the
user experience the way Jolie did." I'm
going to bring out the Tinker box I
mentioned before, but basically this is
a hardware tool kit. It has the grips
like the OXO good grips that are really
easy to use. Actually got this because
my son, I wanted him to have a tool kit
that he could feel good about using.
They've really thought through the how
all this works from the different heads
of the screwdriver and how they come in
and out. Here there's a really well put
together tool kit, but looks nothing
like the DeWalt or the tool kits you
have. Like if I was to show you the tool
kits in the rest of my shed, it's
literally like most dudes like just a I
have a DeWalt box and like a box of
hammers, you know, like that's not
exactly the uh the the millennial
aesthetic dream and they've kind of
built something that fits this aesthetic
with a few different colors. But I want
to talk about this because I think this
is a really important one to think about
is there is a huge generation we don't
think about a lot, especially if you did
have a background like this. Like I
don't know, I had a very uh I had a very
hands-on father who built things. He had
construction as one of the summer jobs
he I like watched him build a house, how
to like a workshop and a woodshed. I
learned a lot about everything from
changing a car oil to being able to use
a multitude of tools from that
experience. But there's a huge
generation of people and especially now
some Gen Z and Gen Alpha people who just
did not have that upbringing or care
whatsoever. And there's a whole cottage
industry of content around that that's
popping up. and guy, a creator who's on
my same management agency. This guy Drew
Hungrenson. He's one of several who've
blown up by basically making content
that teaches Gen Z basic life skills
like, "Hey, how to clean your bathroom,
how to clean dishes, how to steam your
clothes, how to take care of your
girlfriend, how to get rid of pit
stains." This is his content and it
rips. And I think and this is really big
because it's this niche you have of
like, "Hey, did you not have parents who
educated you on this?" Cuz a good
percent of the population didn't. it is
what it is. They're filling that gap
with like, "Hey, I'm a friendly person.
Who's going to teach you these
essentials of life? This is this is how
a gas grill works, right? This is a
cottage industry of content." And cuz
there's a lot of people that just don't
know. And then there's now a industry of
the things for those people to buy when
they do choose to do it because it may
be intimidating for them to go in and
purchase a DeWalt tool set. And they may
want something that is a little more
along the lines of their minimalist or
aesthetic home. And that's where you get
a brand like Tinker comes in. And when
you combine the two into the education,
like for instance, their videos they're
coming out with are like building my at
home gym, painting hacks, assembling
furniture, and you know, a new shower
head and how you and using the toolkit.
They are leaning into educationbased
content around this in a way that you're
going to see very little of from the
traditional brands. And that is where
the alpha is the combination of
aesthetics. As you can see here, they're
kind of playing into this baby blue,
these different colors, the blue tool
set that I have. And they're basically
helping enable a generation to DIY with
the product and the content. And it's
smart positioning. And so if you see
something, it was one of the first
things I thought of when I saw Drew's
content. And so I was like, "Oh man, the
TAM, the total available market of
people that learned nothing from their
mothers and fathers is probably
massive." And then if you want to sell
into that with tools enabled by content,
there is something absolutely massive
there. And either existing brands will
capitalize it or new ones will. And
another brand I want to talk about is
DeadCool. Dead Cool is a really, really
interesting brand to me. Oddball name,
but Dead Cool is a scent in a fragrance
company. That's one of the most
fascinating categories. I don't think
there's enough interest for me to do an
entire video on fragrance. I would love
to, but they're one of the most
interesting because this is a hyper
competitive category, right? Gen Z is
extremely into fragrance. People are
more into fragrance than ever. Companies
are marketing them hard. They sell a ton
of them on Tik Tok shop. There's cottage
Tik Tok related to fragrance. People are
more into it than ever. But if you're
just selling a candle, if you're a new
candle brand or a new fragrance brand,
you're in for a world of hurt. That is a
hard hard market to work in. It's ultra
competitive. Then also people need to
experience your product. And how are you
going to let them do that? But what
DeadCool's done that's really
interesting is like I don't even
particularly like the branding, but
they've got a killer scent. They have uh
this extra milk scent. This was a
sleeper forever now. It's one of like
the most popular scents in the world. Is
a truly incredible scent. And then what
they do is they don't actually just put
out a single item for it. Every time
when you go to a fragrance, you can shop
by extra milk. And what here they've
done is they've productized it. So I can
get lotion, I can get laundry detergent,
hand cream, linen spray. I don't even
know what that is. that say I'm I'm I'm
too straight for linen spray, dryer
sheets, body wash, hand wash, refills,
and then the actual traditional
fragrance, plus these scrubs, mini
sizes. They basically said if we get a
good scent, we're going to productize
that across 20 things cuz you know what?
I have too many fragrances. I've got so
many fragrances, especially from like
the influencer flow that comes in. Like
I'm never going to purchase one again
likely. But you know what? If I really
like this scent, what will I will get?
Like, okay, it's a consumable. Laundry
Sheets is a consumable. So, if I every
next time I'm out and I'm thinking about
it or the brand pops on my feed, that's
a way for me to experience it. I think
that's a really smart thing for a
fragrance brand or a brand in general to
think about if you have a killer
category is how do you spread it wide
into the different ways people actually
consume. And so, I want to check in on
them. They are also on particle and
let's see exactly kind of how that's
doing and what that does inside this
category and kind of a little bit of uh
maybe even how they how they market. All
right. So, I want to look at here. Let's
look at yeah the assets here. This is
the interesting part of this one is so
Particle will actually go in and tell
you the different things that happen. So
like you can look at their SMS
marketing. So I can actually literally
pull up all the SMSs that they've sent.
I can look at the IG posts and I can
look at their homepage changes. They
take screenshots of that every X days
whenever they change the pop-up and kind
of piece together the story of what
they're doing to promote these products.
And same thing going back to Vacation.
One thing I think every brand should do
who's trying to be interesting is go in
here and look at Vacation's email in
particular and their homepage changes
like changes to their popup. You can see
them like promoting their Awan smoothie
like via email. The aesthetics of what
they're doing. They are the best company
in my opinion to pull from if you have a
nice visual world for examples of what
your brand can do. So anyway, all that
is within particle. One of the other
things that's interesting within
particle too is you're trying to be
like, hey, if I want to start a brand or
I want to work on a brand, what do I do
within there? They have this trend
section which I love to browse which is
just rise in search volume. I always
like to set this to two years. You can
see seasonality like what people buy
during the summer, people buy during the
winter. like you see these big dips, but
are people looking for you like dog
shirts is like obviously trending up?
There could be a lot of reasons for any
of these. Remember, I'm just kind of
like looking browsing for ideas or like
in category. It's worth kind of going in
here. You can go into some like
different categories, break some
different things down, and you can begin
to see, okay, like ceilings,
decorations. This is like a category
that's on the rise. That's one where I
would I think is an interesting one to
invest in. Septum rings, you know, let's
go having a comeback. Like what can you
do for a brand there? Just another one
of these tools that makes an investment
in a market research tool like this
useful beyond just that initial data
grab. So anyway, you can learn more
about Particle at the link down below
and I appreciate them for sponsoring
this video. And then that ties into this
sleepwware moment. Business of fashion
had this came out talking about brands
like Lake Everj, Sleepy Jones, Petite
Plume that basically uh how big
sleepwear is getting inside its
category. And this is a great example of
that little luxury concept where your
sleep time, how you want to be the most
comfortable or feel the best about
yourself. if you sell luxury sleepwware.
So, as many of you know, I work with a
brand called understated leather. We
sell a lot of sleepwware. It's we've
been on this trend for since ahead of
the curve really. It's been about
probably a year and a half, two years
we've been on sleepwware. Jen, the
designer there, always like works way
ahead of the curve in terms of what she
understands, but people really want to
have like a cute sleep set. We actually
had organic posts from celebrities like
reading books or lounging about in our
sleepwear because it's comfortable and
it's a luxury. You're like, "Hey, you
know what? I sleep every night. I
deserve a $150 set of PJs or whatever it
And it's just a great example of that in
a non- tech category or a non-h hardware
category. But in fashion, what is that
experience that we are going to turn
into a luxury? That already happened.
You athleisure did that with an entire
category. People now spend way more
money on active wear and their shorts
and their tank tops than ever. But every
little piece of the human experience is
going to get that moment and brands are
going to be created for it. And that's
not to say that everyone needs that.
They certainly don't. But it's all about
the choosing those one or two things
that mean a lot to you and choosing
where you have those little luxuries.
Another one to bring up around the home
is this brand, Goodland. They do hot and
cold tubs, but they also do this
everlasting garden hose. And this was
one that was a painoint for me cuz I got
a hose. Uh I we still wash our own cars.
I like to wash my car with my son. Uh I
think it's a fun bonding experience.
Feels good to complete something with
your own hands every once in a while.
And I found that like we just couldn't
get a hose with good pressure and good
options. I ordered like multiple hoses
on Amazon, went to Home Depot.
Everything was kind of cheap Chinese
crap. And so I went to when I saw this
product, I'm like, "Okay, it's $125,
four times the expense of any Oz I
bought or at least double, but lifetime
warranty, made in Canada, small batches,
guaranteed to rip. It's going to clean
the car, right?" Uh, and you looks good,
will look good on the side of the house
versus the ones I have probably don't.
Again, that is an example of a product
that like I am all in on the experience
and on the aesthetic of what this
enables. And it's really interesting. I
think about every single one of these
items like is a category in itself. So,
a few others to call out who I think do
a really good job, interesting job with
marketing. I'll lean on that angle for a
second. One is Techla. So, Techla is a
fabrics company. They are kind of a
legendary home textile group. They have
one of the best brands in the space.
Everything is super high quality. You
can feel the way it comes through in
their photo and video. But they sell
very abstractly. They remind me if Stuy
was, you know, appealing purely to a uh
again their marketing to me is very like
is very Stucy just withdrawn into this
like backend world into this world of
like more suburban, more casual. It
doesn't have to feel cool. It just has
to feel like real life. So, they've done
a good job there and they are literally
selling with shadows and imagery and
some of the toolkit of kind of creating
a really artful look at a home textile.
And it's not like any of the content is
crazy viral or anything, but it is
thought through enough that it is
appreciated. And the people that
appreciate things like this are probably
the people that spend $240 on, you know,
a set of sheets or a $90 House of
Voltater times Techla beach towel. So
now I want to talk about Flamingo Estate
and I also want to talk about Dead Cool.
They're two really interesting brands to
me. I'm going to use Particle for some
of this too. Particle is the sponsor of
this video, but they show data behind
the scenes on what these companies do.
So we're actually going to look at some
of that as well. So, Flamingo Estate, I
want to start with if you're familiar
with this company or not, they are a
company that started as a vegetable
delivery service in LA has expanded to
really beautiful homegoods. But even
that initial start, it's basically
saying, "Hey, do you want to get your
vegetables yourself or do you want a box
of vegetables delivered to you boutique
by people in LA is 100% a little luxury.
And now you see everything from creams
to every bath substance you like under
the sun to honey. They have honey from
specific celebrity uh maybe from
celebrity bees or bees that go in
celebrity gardens. Every single item
inside this website is a little luxury,
like a crazy jam. I've brought I've
bought these spicy guillo strawberries.
I know I butchered the pronunciation
there. I know they're like $82. They're
amazing. If you're doing like an ordev
uh platter, they're incredible. But
every single thing that they sell falls
in this category where you're paying a
premium for something really special,
presented really special that they have
taken the time to source and put
together. And so when I talk about this
category a lot, people are always like,
"Well, how much money could this
category possibly make? What could
people possibly do? What could possibly
sell for people like this?" And so
that's why I love to use Particle. I'm
going to drop into the software here.
We're actually going to look at Flamingo
Estate. And we're going to look at the
last four weeks. Particle and this data
will be like directionally correct.
Doesn't have to be perfect. 4.8 million
this month online just on the website
and they're in stores and they do like
all these pop-ups and stuff. Let's look
at what's actually selling. I can
actually dive into this. Okay, what is
the top selling product by volume? It's
actually these gift sets. They are
selling a hell of these gift sets. Those
are bundled products doing hundreds of
thousands of dollars. They're selling 90
plus of a day. And that's a really
interesting thought. If you're not
bundling, if you have a product with
multiple sets, I obviously bundle on
valuable now. You can get multiple bags,
you can get multiple shirts, but if you
have sell multiple products online,
you're not creating bundles like this
with like a specialized package, like
just take a look at this flamingo
estate. Like they are all of their top
products are duos or tours, which are
like multi-bundles. Every one, all the
top five products by volume. This isn't
even top five products by by dollar. And
then you go down into candles, 2,000
plus candles a month for each of these
flavors. And you keep scrolling down,
they're putting up serious sales across
every single one of these categories.
And it just goes to show you that I
think the market for these little things
where, you know, I think people have
prolonged now these big purchases. They
say, you know what, I'm never going to
own a house. I'm not filling my
retirement account. I'm not here to
argue for the good or ills for society
of these things. But but basically, the
solution for a lot of people is, you
know what, the happy thing for me is I'm
going to keep this apartment, but I'm
going to be able to buy the candle that
I love or the wash set or whatever it
is. And there is now a huge economy
around enabling that. So, I want to uh
end with an example of uh starting some
of this from scratch. So, this is a
brand that was in Cut 30 the other month
called Hashi Home, and they sell premium
ceramics and premium things for the
house. It's a great brand. I believe is
just the one woman who's doing
everything from the design. She's
packing orders and she's making stuff on
Instagram. But I want to talk about
content strategy for something like
this. And uh what she ended up working
on through Cut 30 and has really popped
off. She's now gotten to about 9,000
followers. she was starting from from
very low is she basically made a set in
her home that she can entertain and make
content on. It's all about this kitchen
table and this dinner table and
basically saying, "Hey, I'm going to use
this place in our house. I'm going to
film content there." Again, this is just
her kitchen. I'm going to host on it and
I'm going to be able to make content.
And she's kind of making skits and ideas
around that that attract people that are
interested in hosting. That is the top
offunnel content. And there's more
educational content in there, like how
do you create a sexy dinner party to
behind the scenes of her actually making
and documenting the brand, talking about
different types of decor, and then
funneling all this into actually selling
the product, packing an order with her,
getting a real glimpse at the things you
buy. I think this is the formula. If you
are selling within this, you have one of
these aesthetic, a seriousdriven
objects, get a set, a place in your
house or a place in the office where you
can tell the story dynamically and then
use that combination of humor,
information, and documentation to tell
that via short form video. And it is a
recipe for success. And to end with this
and talk through the category, one of
the things that uh I think is most
impactful, one of the biggest trends
we're going to see is that people are
spending so much money on fashion, it's
overwhelming. Now, I think there's going
to be a trend where people are going to
be almost stopping that, looking back at
what they have in their closet and
reinvigorating that. I think designers
are seeing this, too. And you see this
with JW Anderson and Jonathan Anderson,
who basically said, "Hey, we're
switching our whole brand." He moves
into Dior, moves to luxury. We're
switching our brand to objects to things
that are personally crafting spaces.
He's selling spoons, all kinds of like
accutramonts that are uh accessories
that match the existing kind of clothing
for the brand, but they are moving into
objects and things for the home. And
that idea of these spaces and these
things being like the next kind of
aesthetic frontier that people are going
to be buying into, I think is very real.
If you want to be in the home space and
selling things into that, I think that
is the space to be activating on in
these next like 18 months versus in CPG
or in apparel. Just my two cents. But
anyway, that was this video on little
luxuries. Like I mentioned, I will
summarize this with every brand that I
talk through and a link to that kind of
playbook I overview. All that's going to
be in this week's hyper newsletter that
is in the bio as well as info on
particle for sponsored this video. If
you have any questions about this or you
have brands or interesting little
luxuries you feel other people would
want to check out, please drop them in
the comments. I want to see them and I'm
sure other people would be interested as
well. For me to dive deeper on anything
around this. I'm kind of planning out
these next videos. Feel free to let me
know. I hope you found some value as
both a consumer and someone working on
brands or on creative things in this
video. Thank you so much.
[Music]