today we're going to talk about why most
brand content sucks and what to do about
it I am still here in sunny London
having some tea as one does and I fired
up because again and again I go into
workshops with brands of all sizes and
shapes and they are thinking about
content incorrectly here's how to think
about it your brand is a television show
I have a previous video I'll link that
talks about how you can do an exercise
mapping out your characters and your
sets Etc but on this video we're going
to zoom in to creating a series for your
brand and how to make it stand out I am
working on one of these myself myself
for my brand currently I'm workshopping
multiple of these with Major Brands and
we're going to get into the intricacies
I'm going to talk about how small Brands
can do this affordably we're going to
talk about how big Brands can think
about building a real campaign around it
we're going to talk about where to draw
info the current state of social media
and how Services business product Brands
whatever it is need to think of their
content like a television series and how
to do it let's lock in so I had a
watershed moment the other day as many
of you know I work with a number of
Cosmetics companies it's a niche dab
done reports on and similar and all
everyone was a buzz about 2 weeks ago
because Sephora announced they're doing
a show on Hulu so why is this important
why is this critical because a brand and
Sephora at the end of the day retail
store buts also a brand is entering
content in the most major way they are
saying we are moving from what we put on
our social media to Netflix Hulu Disney
plus a True Entertainment equivalent
this is a major cultural shift I believe
is happening across any number of things
but the idea for a lot of brands that
there would be maybe get ready with me
style content happening on Hulu people
are engaged with with a retailer with
product focuses is changes the way that
Brands want to be featured in content
and think about content so this brings
me to all of these brands that are
creating content like a television
series and how you can do that too and
why so let's start with an example and a
lower budget example so this is Brooklyn
coffee BK coffee project you may have
seen them on Instagram they are getting
millions of views with these scenarios
so the owner of the coffee shop who is a
smaller influencer and it's London
streets are [ __ ] Savage
bro
mandm damn England long story England
really fumbled the
back the owner of Brooklyn coffee
project is a a smaller influencer in her
own right she has her friend who is a
barista and they have a Cadre of people
come in including influencers to present
these really surreal scenarios where
they'll basically act like they're in
2030 or say they don't serve this blank
because it's not fair trade enough
whatever it is they will have these
really out there particularly crazy
scenarios they're awkward they get
walked through in content that feels
like a series right it's just like
you're having your futuristic subsection
of Seinfeld and someone walks in every
day to the same scenario you know what
to expect it's a different personality
it's going to be funny in a different
way and they created the format you can
expect to see on their social that is
inherently viral it's driven almost too
much traffic to their store why I want
to call this out is this isn't a major
company they don't have huge content
budgets this is shot with two camera
angles with the same people with some
great lighting with a series of guests
and yes you could find a production
company who will shoot this for $25,000
an episode and yes you could find
somebody who will shoot the same exact
thing for 500 per this is the world we
live in now where these eras are getting
progressively closer together in terms
of who will do what at what cost what
camera equipment can do and what some
thought and intention can get for your
business I also like to highlight this
because it's a Services business a
retail location not some super cool
product brand or whatever it is let's
look at a few more examples really the
person who jump started this trend and
probably the best to do it in my opinion
is Alexis patar they are a New York City
jewelry brand been around for a long
time well regarded nice stuff but they
introduced a series on Instagram
featuring socialite characters in the
New York scene overlap with the stylus
Community with the drag community and
created a storyline between this woman
and like an aging socialite and her
assistant who have like a borderline
abusive relationship and put them into
all these funny real New York scenarios
shot in these little vignettes from 60
seconds to 3 minutes and put on
Instagram that blew up and people want
to immerse themselves in these
characters in their lives really rich
script writing Rich ideas I believe it
was conceived by the brand founder
himself and then it spiraled into a life
of its own so things would happen
virally in New York like the woman who
runs the sou bees auctions kind of went
viral for some of the things she was
doing and she became a character La
Roach The Stylist you does like zanda he
was appeared as a character inside of it
playing himself so they were able to
basically create a cultural moment
around a series they had in their
Instagram and they also did breakdown
videos behind it they also post some of
their standard content but there is this
through line of a television show and
characters of their own creation Now
this one is a step up right there are
real actors and actresses involved there
there is like production and sets this
is probably a pretty significant
undertaking but certainly less than
doing a whole TV show for themselves but
it has created a world that you could
see stretching over you could watch
their eight episode version of this on
Netflix and people would probably be
into it I'm going to hit a few more
examples but I let's dive into some of
the tactics here the idea is instead of
just creating content about our products
or cool little snippy videos what is a
narrative through line that builds a
world that is entertaining that's the
number one thing you've heard me talking
all these social videos you either make
value content that people will save that
helps them or you make entertainment
content that people assume that competes
with Netflix or you fail that middle
ground is a failure zone right I make
value content I don't try to do anything
in the middle like that why my content
does well this is True Entertainment
content you are watching this and
enjoying it similar to what you would do
scrolling through funny videos on Tik
Tok that is what a brand should be
approaching at ass and then to do that
you need to give yourself a way to keep
people engaged and the way this content
succeeds is you could watch any episode
whether it's your first time seeing it
or your 10th time and still be
entertained that's where someone like BK
coffee project crushes it because
there's a joke every time you may not
know the character but the jokes will
still work and someone like Alexis Batar
you get some setup on each episode and
you begin to wonder like oh I'm in this
world now I want to learn more I want to
go watch more of it but each of these
being able to succeed Standalone or as
part of the series is a critical point
but what story can your brand create and
how can you make it either easy
production that you can repeat like
using your retail location or your
office or whatever it is and then just
weaving that in as a component of your
Brand's content strategy and then also
showcasing that adding into your email
newsletters having a little section on
your website with all the episodes
adding that World building into this
like as a brand and you'll notice for BK
coffee project they're selling the
coffee shop you can physically go to
this place you see in the videos and
people do Alexis patar the jewelry is
always their jewelry the little things
that come from this that also make it a
product showcase one of my favorite
examples is there are all of these car
dealerships on Tik Tok they are
basically replicating the office they
will go run the same scenarios where
someone like looks at a camera or where
there's this awkward piece sometimes
they'll even remake exact episodes but
any of these offices where you have a
lot of downtime or things like that are
perfectly right if you have a couple
funny personalities to put something in
the world that's out there and again you
may get attention beyond what you're
looking for right not everyone's going
to go visit North Dakota Ford dealership
because it but certainly going to get
them some attention in the neighborhood
that they're in another great example on
the highest of production end is Ritz
Carlton and I actually think hotels is
one of the entertainment in general like
Hospitality entertainment is putting the
worst content niches possible they're
still stuck in 2017 taking these Oddball
photos of their places maybe having an
influencer or two you have an amazing
set to make content now I've talked
about Ritz London before who you know
will show you their their tea service
things like that but Rich Carlton
basically got an A-list actress they got
Peter from The Hunger Games I don't know
his real name and then set up a whole
scenario with like a family and a whole
series of stuff to promote a merch drop
right and the idea of think about this
as a micro idea as well you have a big
initiative or a campaign dropping five
or six episodes that go with that and
then the behind the scenes all of a
sudden you've now made your campaign but
it's more compelling and narrative
driven than just dropping another photo
shoot so how do you get inspiration for
this how do you find this so one of my
favorite Tik Tok series is this series
called boym where a comedian goes to
visit male apartments in like nework New
York and Philly for like single 30s
males which is like it's basically a
horror show and a comedy show like
matched into one but they have thought
of a repeatable thing that they can go
do and it's also very sponsor ready
right you could go do that with a
interior design company and all of a
sudden it's a redo or whatever it looks
like but all this comes down to very
similar formats to what we've seen in
the past basically looking at existing
TV and reality TV and being like what
matches well with our business and so if
you look at anything from Pimp My Ride
to West Coast Choppers to room Raiders
to anything on HGTV to any office based
reality show there is a framework with
which you can basically strip it down to
work for your brand and so I would
highly recommend doing that exercise of
what are all the sets we have in our
world what's our office look like what's
our studio look like do we rent a place
frequently does our owner have a house
like do we have any relationships like
what is our potential for filming look
like then look at your characters okay
who and on our team actually has enough
personality to do this do any of our
influencers have it we can work that
into our influencer deals or would we
recruit from it and who would we recruit
from down to then like establishing the
plot which I would literally be pulling
a bunch of references of shows either
exist today or older shows and being
like what can we pull from to make a
through line and then test right testing
for a campaign is the easiest one shoot
five or six episodes in a particular
style around a drop or you already have
to do content to see if it works for you
but this is the approach finding that
series that works for you building the
rest of your Social content out
surrounding it so it all operates in the
same world so those people might cross
over into one of your influencers videos
or into ugc building those universes
because brands are basically becoming
more and more like entertainment because
they're on the same feed as
entertainment and need to think that way
so hopefully this shifted your
perspective a bit about what good brand
content looks like we'll make sure all
the examples are linked in the
description of this and thank y'all so
much for watching
[Music]